<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Receiving and Inspecting New Vehicles</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Receiving and Inspecting New Vehicles</title>
        <para>Each receiving location must have employees who are familiar with receiving procedures and who are
            qualified to perform a competent inspection. For complete instructions of the receiving procedures, please
            refer to the New Vehicle Processing Manual, CTS-1029, and the Warranty Procedures and Administrative
            Policies Manual, CTS-1100. Vehicles are to be inspected as soon after receipt as possible since tariff
            regulations permit the carrier to charge for excessive delay beyond the one-hour free waiting time. This
            one-hour gratis time begins after all vehicles have been unloaded. Be sure vehicles are clean enough for a
            good inspection, removing any snow, ice, and excessive dirt, as the carrier is responsible for obvious body
            damages. Trucks not built to spec are not a carrier issue. Please refer to the New Vehicle Processing
            Manual, CTS-1029 and the Warranty Procedures and Administrative Policies Manual, CTS-1100 for "Vehicles Not
            Built To Order" with complete information on claim handling.
        </para>
        <para>A carrier delivery receipt (form JTC 501) will accompany each vehicle on delivery. This form will need to
            be properly filled out and signed by the dealer or dealer agent and the delivery driver of the vehicle for
            proper claim processing. A copy of this delivery receipt is given to the dealer and one copy stays with the
            driver. The driver turns this delivery receipt in at his terminal after his delivery is complete.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
