<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Deliveries to Body Companies</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Deliveries to Body Companies</title>
        <para>Each chassis delivered to a body company must receive a careful inspection and the carrier's freight bill
            must be annotated to show a description of the damage or the shortage, whichever is applicable. This
            notation must be signed by the individual receiving the vehicle(s) and co-signed by the carrier
            representative at the time of delivery.
            <emph type="bold">If concealed damage is found, the same rule applies as if received at a dealership.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>A vehicle belonging to a dealer but delivered and consigned to a body company or fleet location has been
            delivered to the dealer's agent.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is the dealer's responsibility to instruct the body company on proper
                receiving/inspection procedures, and to file the DDEW Warranty Claim for exceptions and other losses on
                the vehicle via International.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is the responsibility of the body company to have an employee to receive and carefully
                inspect each vehicle or chassis delivered there. This person should also record damages and shortages on
                the carrier's delivery receipt, co-sign the delivery receipt, and get the carrier's (driver's)
                signature. Please refer to the New Vehicle Processing Manual, CTS-1029 and the Warranty Procedures and
                Administrative Policies Manual, CTS-1100.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque all axle shaft nuts and or u-joints to specification per Preparation and Delivery (P&#38;D)
                guidelines before moving the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If concealed damage is found, follow the instructions under "CONCEALED DAMAGE" above for the
                proper handling for notification of concealed damage.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
