<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual</stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcman mantype="truck" id="S10005" date="11/13/2007"/>
    <title>New Vehicle Processing Manual</title>
    <introduction>
        <geninfo>
            <para>The New Vehicle Processing Manual is designed to aid Dealership personnel to correctly process new
                International vehicles. Current International policy is reflected in this Manual, covering all phases of
                vehicle processing from undecking to delivery. The intent is to ensure that our Customers are completely
                satisfied with the Dealership, with the vehicles they receive, and with their delivery experience.
            </para>
            <para>The Dealership Sales and Service departments are actively involved in processing new vehicles. They
                must work together to ensure that the vehicles they deliver to our customers meet or exceed their
                expectations.
            </para>
        </geninfo>
    </introduction>
    <safety>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Carefully read and follow these instructions and procedures.</para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>The information contained in this International Service Manual Section was current at the time of printing
            and is subject to change without notice or liability.
        </para>
        <para>You must follow your company safety procedures when you service or repair equipment. Be sure to understand
            all of the procedures and instructions before you begin work on the unit.
        </para>
        <para>Some procedures require the use of special tools for safe and correct service. Failure to use these
            special tools when required can cause injury to service personnel or damage to vehicle components.
        </para>
        <para>International uses the following types of notations to give warning of possible safety problems and to
            give information that will prevent damage to the equipment being serviced or repaired.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A warning indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. Personal injury or possible death
                    can occur if the procedure is not followed.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>A caution indicates procedures that must be followed exactly. If the procedure is not followed,
                    damage to equipment or components can occur.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A note indicates an operation, procedure or instruction that is important for correct service.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>This service manual section is intended for use by professional technicians, NOT a "
            <emph type="bold">do-it-yourselfer</emph>." It is written to inform these technicians of conditions that may
            occur on some vehicles, or to provide information that could assist in the proper service of a vehicle.
            Properly trained technicians have the equipment, tools, safety instructions, and know-how to do a job
            properly and safely. If a condition is described, DO NOT assume that the service section applies to your
            vehicle. See your International Truck Dealer for information on whether this service section applies to your
            vehicle.
        </para>
    </safety>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_0.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_S10005_1.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
