<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>3200 Integrated Mobility Option Service Manual - Hadley Smart Air Management System - SAMS Height Sensor
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SAMS Height Sensor</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>This section is written to provide a basic understanding of the SAMS Height Sensor. The content is not
                intended to be all inclusive, but is to provide basic knowledge for mounting the sensor, the sensor
                function, and to provide a basic troubleshooting procedure.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Theory of Operation</title>
            <para>The height sensor is used by the system ECU (electronic control unit) to monitor and control the
                vehicle ride height. The sensor arm moves in reaction to the suspension movement and provides a voltage
                signal that is proportional to the ride height at any given time. Typically, while the vehicle is in
                operation, the ECU will default to and maintain a programmed ride height. The system design requires a
                three sensor configuration: one front sensor and two rear sensors to provide the 3-point control.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor contains three wires (red, black, blue) that interface with the system ECU through the
                supplied main wiring harness. The red wire provides an ECU generated reference voltage, typically 5VDC
                (+/- 2%). The black wire provides the ground and the blue wire provides the voltage signal back to the
                ECU. This voltage is proportional to the position of the sensor arm within its range of travel.
            </para>
            <para>The sensor arm is typically installed to be in the center of its travel, when the vehicle is at normal
                ride height. This would provide a voltage signal on the blue wire that is one-half of the supplied
                reference voltage (approximately 2.4VDC - 2.6VDC). As the sensor arm moves clockwise, the voltage on the
                blue wire would continue to increase until the sensor arm reaches approximately +45 degrees of rotation
                from the center position. At the +45 degrees of rotation, the voltage on the sensor's blue wire would be
                approximately 4.4VDC to 4.6VDC. The sensor arm travel in the clockwise direction would be typical in a
                decrease situation from the normal vehicle ride height.
            </para>
            <para>As the sensor arm moves counter-clockwise, the voltage on the blue wire would continue to decrease
                until the sensor arm reaches approximately -45 degrees of rotation from the center position. At the -45
                degrees of rotation, the voltage on the sensor's blue wire would be approximately 0.4VDC to 0.6VDC. The
                sensor arm travel in the counter-clockwise direction would be typical in an increase situation from the
                normal vehicle ride height.
            </para>
            <para>It is important to clarify that the sensor only monitors the ride height and provides feedback to the
                ECU through only 90 degrees of movement. In other words, from the center position, a change in the ride
                height of +45 degrees to -45 degrees of sensor arm movement provides a signal to the ECU. Movement
                either above or below this range provides no additional feedback to the ECU. Therefore it is important
                to install the sensor correctly to obtain the correct linkage arm inclination (see SAMS Height Sensor
                Arm and Linkage Installation procedure outlined in Appendix C). Improper linkage installation can result
                in sensor damage and result in improper system control and incorrect vehicle ride height.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1001828" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG10/G1001828.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Mounting</title>
            <para>Care must be taken when mounting the sensor to the vehicle frame. The mounting surface must be flat so
                the sensor body is mounted flush to the vehicle surface. It is recommended that two button head cap
                screws, &#188;" - 20 thread, be used to mount the sensor to the vehicle and the screws be tightened to
                60-80 inch/lbs. of torque. If the frame mounting holes are a through-hole (non-threaded), a nylon style
                of locknut is also recommended to maintain the tightening torque.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">It is important to clarify the above mounting information, otherwise distortion or
                    breakage of the sensor body is possible when tightening the mounting hardware. Not having the sensor
                    flush can distort the sensor body resulting in breakage as well as over-tightening can crack the
                    housing. Damage to the senor will result in improper system control and incorrect vehicle ride
                    height.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>After the sensor is mounted to the vehicle, connect the sensor wiring female connector to the
                respective vehicle wiring harness male connector. The center wire of the vehicle wiring harness
                connector will be color coded to identify the respective location on the vehicle. The system vehicle
                wiring harness center wire configuration is as follows:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Wiring harness blue wire = front sensor connector</line>
                <line>Wiring harness yellow wire = rear drive sensor connector</line>
                <line>Wiring harness green wire = rear curb sensor connector</line>
            </verbatim>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Prior to connecting the wiring harness to the sensor connectors, be sure to apply a good brand
                        of moisture displacement lubricant to the connectors. This will help prevent moisture from
                        entering the connections and affecting system operation due to the low current and voltage
                        application of the sensor.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Test Procedure</title>
            <para>The ECU monitors the system and can identify voltages that are below 0.4VDC (short to ground, broken
                wire, disconnected harness connector, etc.) or voltages equal to the supply reference (short to supply
                voltage). Voltages associated with these conditions would generate a sensor alarm. The alarm would be
                displayed by flashing a fault code on the system supplied LED. However, voltages that are above 0.4VDC
                and below the supply reference from the ECU fall within the normal operating parameters of the sensor
                and are not subject to alarm. If a sensor is identified to be faulty, a test can be performed to
                validate its functionality. The following step by step process outlines that test procedure:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect power from the system prior to performing any repairs or component
                    removal/replacement. This will prevent any possible short circuits that could result in component or
                    supply voltage damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the sensor 3-wire connector from the supplied main wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the linkage from the sensor arm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unbolt the sensor from the vehicle frame and remove the sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Obtain a DC voltage power supply capable of supplying a regulated 5VDC supply.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the red lead from the power supply to the red wire on the sensor connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the black lead from the power supply to the black wire on the sensor
                    connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Obtain a voltmeter to monitor the DC feedback voltage.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the red lead of the voltmeter to the sensor blue wire and the black lead to the
                    sensor black wire.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Orientate the sensor so the lever arm faces up, points to your left, and the sensor
                    wiring is to your right.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the sensor in the mid-range of its travel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn on the DC power supply and adjust the voltage to 5VDC, if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the sensor arm in the center position, the voltage on the blue wire should read
                    approximately one-half of the 5VDC supply; i.e., 2.4VDC to 2.6VDC.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly rotate the senor arm in the clockwise direction and observe the voltage reading
                    on the voltmeter. As the sensor arm is rotated clockwise, the voltage on the blue wire should
                    increase until approximately +45 degrees of rotation from center is reached. At the +45 degrees of
                    rotation, the voltage should read approximately 4.4VDC to 4.6VDC. If rotation continues above this
                    point, no additional increase in voltage should be observed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The voltage should increase steadily, with no loss in the voltage signal, no erratic changes
                        should occur, or the voltage should not read +5VDC or 0VDC at any point throughout the range of
                        movement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After verifying the voltage increase, slowly rotate the sensor arm counter-clockwise. As
                    the sensor arm is rotated counter-clockwise, the voltage on the blue wire should decrease until
                    approximately -45 degrees of rotation from center is reached. At the -45 degrees of rotation, the
                    voltage should read approximately 0.4VDC to 0.6VDC. If rotation continues below this point, no
                    additional decrease in voltage should be observed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The voltage should decrease steadily, with no loss in the voltage signal, no erratic changes
                        should occur, or the voltage should not read 0VDC or +5VDC at any point throughout the range of
                        movement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the sensor fails to test as described, then replacement is necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing the sensor (or upon re-installation in the event of a satisfactory test), be
                        sure to adhere to the installation instructions mentioned earlier in this document. Proper
                        installation is necessary to prevent damaging the sensor. Proper sensor operation is necessary
                        to provide accurate feedback to the ECU for correct vehicle height control.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Summary</title>
            <para>This completes the basic installation, operation, and troubleshooting information on the height
                control sensor. All information contained in this document is of equal importance and should not be
                ignored. Time spent by installation and service personnel to better understand component operation will
                ensure a properly installed and serviced system, thereby providing correct system operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
