<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 MODELS -
        7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 Model INSPECTION INSTRUCTIONS (REPORT S00023) - AFTER ROAD TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
        <title>AFTER ROAD TEST</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Position the vehicle on a level surface and perform the following operations.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>41.
            <emph type="italic">Program keyless entry remote (if applicable).</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Transmitter Learning</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Before the transmitter can be used for the first time, it has to be learned to the receiver. Up to
                    6 transmitters with different identification codes can be learned to a single RKE Pod.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Programming requires bus interface.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The following steps must be used in order to "Learn" a transmitter to an RKE pod:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn key to ACC or ON position</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>On passenger pod with RKE; depress and hold the Window Up, Window Down, and Unlock
                            buttons.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>While hold the buttons down in step two depress and hold the Lock button for at least 5
                            seconds.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>At the end of 5 seconds, the RKE pod will enter "Learn Transmitter" mode and stay there
                            for exactly 10 seconds (the RKE pod buttons may be released).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>During this 10 second period the Transmitter should be keyed at least twice.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The following steps shall be used in order to erase all "Learned" transmitters to an RKE pod:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn key to ACC or ON position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>On the driver pod; depress and hold the Window Up, Window Down, and Unlock buttons.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>While holding the buttons down in step two depress and hold the Lock button for at least 5
                            seconds.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>At the end of 5 seconds all learned transmitters will be erased from the passenger pod
                            with RKE.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>42.
            <emph type="italic">Check for active fault codes.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>With key in the ON position (engine not running) press and hold the cruise control ON and RESUME
                    switches simultaneously for at least 3 seconds. If no active engine faults are present, 111 will
                    flash on the WARN ENGINE lamp. NO FAULT will appear on the odometer when no codes are present in the
                    truck Electrical System Controller (ESC). Note any active fault codes and refer to the appropriate
                    service manual for additional information.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Inspect for...</emph>:
        </para>
        <para>43.
            <emph type="italic">Exhaust leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Inspect visually for signs of exhaust leakage.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>44.
            <emph type="italic">Air leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Inspect for air leaks.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>45.
            <emph type="italic">Fluid leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect for any fluid leaks.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>46.
            <emph type="italic">Air system drain valve(s) for proper operation.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Operate all air tank bleed valves, verify operation and shut off.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>47.
            <emph type="italic">Wash vehicle, inspect for interior leaks, and remove plastic seat covers.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>48.
            <emph type="italic">Verify that the proper vehicle certification label is affixed. Refer to the NEW VEHICLE
                PROCESSING MANUAL.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>49.
            <emph type="italic">Add PDI location code and date to Vehicle Identification Decal.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>50.
            <emph type="italic">Fill out and affix Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker CTS-1122 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000716">Figure 12)</hotlnk>
                to the inside of the vehicle's windshield (optional).
            </emph>
        </para>
        <figure id="f1000716" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="472px"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker (CTS-1122)</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>51.
            <emph type="italic">Transfer all items marked under A, F, or R to the comments section on the first page.
                Include a brief explanation of each problem in the space provided.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Do not use the "A" to indicate a required PDI adjustment has been made. For further
                explanation on when each inspection code should be used, refer to the General Information portion of
                this manual.
            </emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10011_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
