<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Vehicle Safety Certification - VEHICLE SAFETY CERTIFICATION - PENALTIES FOR
        VIOLATIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PENALTIES FOR VIOLATIONS</title>
        <para>Any violation of the provisions of the Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards law is subject to a fine of
            up to $5,000 per vehicle or other violations up to a maximum of $15,000,000 for a related series of
            violations. The following are subject to these penalties:
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Any manufacturer who knowingly produces for sale a motor vehicle subject to the law, but which
                    does not meet all the applicable provisions of the law;
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Any party who sells or offers for sale a motor vehicle built after the effective date of a
                    standard which in the knowledge of the selling party does not comply with the standard;
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Any party (manufacturer, dealer, body builder or other) who completes a vehicle for sale in
                    compliance with the law, but fails to certify the completed vehicle in the prescribed manner;
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Any party who knowingly certifies a vehicle as complying which does not in fact meet the
                    requirements of the law.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>The U.S. Department of Transportation has declared its intent to institute procedures periodically to
            inspect vehicles subject to the law, and to implement enforcement procedures which will permit detection of
            violations.
        </para>
        <para>The requirements of the law are stringent and the penalties for violation are severe. It is therefore
            mandatory that all personnel involved in:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Sale</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Preparation for delivery</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Modification or conversion</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Installation of bodies or equipment</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Final manufacture</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Maintenance and repair</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>of motor vehicles become familiar with the provisions of the law as they relate to their
            responsibilities.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">COMPLIANCE WITH THE LAW IS AN ABSOLUTE MUST!!</emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
