<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Pre-Delivery Inspection Master Instruction Manual</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S10023" division="truck" date="06/23/2008">
        <title>Pre-Delivery Inspection Master Instruction Manual</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL INFORMATION</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <important>
                            <para>Use these instructions along with the applicable vehicle specific Pre-Delivery
                                Inspection Report Form when inspecting a vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </important>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>These instructions explain how to inspect the vehicle and use the Pre-Delivery Inspection
                        Report Form to be sure the vehicle is ready for delivery to the customer. Each inspection
                        operation on the report has a corresponding procedure on the following pages in this
                        Pre-Delivery Inspection Master Instruction Manual.
                    </para>
                    <para>The original Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form should be retained at the PDI Facility.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Fill in the information block on the report after the vehicle is driven into the
                                inspection area.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>The instructions described in this manual follow the order of operations listed in the
                        Pre-Delivery Inspection Report. If a question arises while performing an inspection, use the
                        Pre-Delivery Inspection Report Form Task Reference number as a reference to find the
                        corresponding procedure instructions and specifications in this manual required to properly
                        complete the inspection line item.
                    </para>
                    <para>EXAMPLE: For a question about engine oil level, refer to the Task Reference number on the
                        form: number 11.50. Then refer to Task Reference number 11.50 in this manual for details on how
                        to correctly complete the task. Applicable NOTES, specifications, and warranty information are
                        also included.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <title>Non-Reimbursement Statement</title>
                    </para>
                    <para>Labor time and or materials for procedures in addition to inspections which are included as a
                        part of the PDI
                        <emph type="boldital">(not reimbursable as PTD 03 Warranty expense)</emph>include but are not
                        necessarily limited to the following:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>PDI Preparation</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor to retrieve and return vehicle at PDI location and prepare inspection
                                        service bay, supplies, and tools for PDI
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Clerical Work</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and office materials to acquire and complete forms, instructions,
                                        labels, and vehicle history.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor to complete and affix labels and file paperwork.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Vehicle Completion</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and materials to install parts and/or materials shipped with or for
                                        vehicle that were not installed/ properly installed due to complications
                                        associated with vehicle delivery practices, etc.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Reversal of Vehicle Driveaway Company effects</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and materials associated with retorquing fasteners, installing
                                        temporarily removed components, replacing rearmost axle flange gaskets (on
                                        certain specified models: See Instructions for Task Reference number 7.25. Where
                                        replacement is required during PDI, replacement parts are shipped with the
                                        vehicle so no claim for service parts is needed.). If the vehicle is received
                                        from the Driveaway company in an unacceptable condition, follow practices
                                        outlined in the New Vehicle Processing Manual.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>General Procedures</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and material expenses associated with battery charging, and general
                                        non-inspection steps, etc., necessary to complete the PDI.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Adjustments</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor associated with adjusting fluid levels, tire pressures (and steering
                                        wheel alignment and clutch adjustment on some models: See Instructions for the
                                        specific task)
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Retorques</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor associated with retorquing items such as spring U-bolts, wheels, axle
                                        flanges, hose clamps, etc.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Programming</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor associated with initial programming/ reprogramming standard and optional
                                        equipment such as engines, transmissions, various ECU's, theft deterrent
                                        systems, idle reduction systems, remote keyless entry key fobs, AWARE, etc. Some
                                        recall/ update programming may be covered under PTD 03 warranty.
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                                        If labor time of programming specific optional equipment is deemed to be
                                        excessive, the labor expense should be applied to the purchase cost of the
                                        vehicle by the Dealer Sales Department.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Tie Wrapping and Routing and Clipping Adjustments</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and materials associated with adjusting routing and clipping and tie
                                        wraps or added clipping materials.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Reconnecting loose Electrical Connectors</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor associated with re-connecting electrical connectors that were
                                        inadvertently left disconnected or may have come apart during shipment.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Lubrication</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and materials (grease, etc.) associated with lubricating various vehicle
                                        chassis and body components.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Road Test</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor associated with conducting a vehicle road test as specified in the road
                                        test instructions in this manual.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Vehicle Cleaning and Protective Coatings Removal</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Labor and materials (water, soaps, solvents, polishes, etc.) associated with
                                        the effective removal of protective coatings and their adhesives, and shipping
                                        blocks, as well as washing and cleaning the entire vehicle inside and out as
                                        needed for full customer satisfaction.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Consumables such as windshield washer solvent, diesel fuel, coolant additives, etc.
                                and inspections of those items are not included in the PDI and also will not be
                                reimbursed as warranty expense.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Added engine oil (qts.), transmission fluid (pts.), drive axle oil (pts.), wheel hub
                                oil (oz.) - materials only - will be reimbursed as 03 warranty expense. Only the cost of
                                the quantity of fluid used should be charged as opposed to charging for the cost of the
                                entire fluid container.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Damage due to shipping should be claimed with the shipping carrier. All other repair
                                operations should be charged to the appropriate OEM or supplier warranty.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <para>Navistar, Inc. reserves the right to change these specifications and content at any time.
                    </para>
                    <table id="t1002301" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                        <title>Suggested PDI Tools</title>
                        <tgroup cols="2">
                            <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                            <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                            <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Grease Gun</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Midtronics Smart Charger</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Tire Pressure Gauge</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Ultrasonic Leak Detector</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Coolant Refractometer</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Creeper</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Wrenches</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Axle Flange Nut Socket</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>1/2" Drive Ratchet</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>3/4" or 1/2" Drive, 12" Socket Extension</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>400 LB-Ft Torque Wrench</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Flat Screwdriver</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>CD to Test CD Player</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>EZ Tech and Cable</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Watch with Second Hand</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>6" (150mm) Ruler/ Tape Measure</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Shop Trouble Light</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Flashlight (head-mounted is best)</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Ball Joint Nuts Socket</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Steering Intermediate Shaft Pinch Bolts Socket</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Spare Cotter Pins</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Transmission Bulk Oil Pump</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Oil Drain Pan</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Drive Axle Bulk Oil Pump</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Channel Locks</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Tape Measure</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Fluid container with pour spout</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry></entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                        <para>2594108C1 Female Compucheck fitting that can be used to air up the
                                            ProStar.
                                        </para>
                                        <para>Basic Tool Kit to install Dealer-Installed components and perform minor
                                            corrections.
                                        </para>
                                        <para>Pump-Spray Bottle with soapy water to check for air leaks.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10023_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
