<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - After-Hours Delivery</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>After-Hours Delivery</title>
        <para>Should special arrangements be made for after-hours delivery, the following procedures should be
            observed:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">An employee must be on the premises to receive and sign the carrier's receipt for
                delivery.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">This receipt should be signed with time and date specified, along with the notation, "
                <emph type="bold">Received Subject to Working Hours Inspection</emph>", "
                <emph type="bold">STI</emph>" for short.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Two copies of the delivery receipt should be held by the receiving location.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A thorough inspection must be made of the vehicle(s) on the first working day following the
                after-hours delivery.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A copy of the delivery receipt containing all exceptions is to be sent by Certified Mail to
                the carrier within
                <emph type="bold">48 hours</emph>
                of the after-hours delivery.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Any after-hours deliveries to body companies and fleet locations that are noted as "
                <emph type="bold">STI</emph>" should be transmitted to the ordering dealer immediately, to allow them
                time to respond to the carrier within the 48-hour time frame.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Notating a carrier's delivery receipt "STI"
                <emph type="bold">DOES NOT INSURE</emph>
                the payment of the claim. The claim may still be denied by the carrier or the International Warranty
                Center pending further review.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque all axle shaft nuts and or u-joints to specification per Preparation and Delivery (P&#38;D)
                guidelines before moving the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If concealed damage is found, follow the instructions below for the proper handling for
                notification of concealed damage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Vehicles should never be received and noted "STI" during normal receiving hours.</emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
