<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 - General - Jacking and Lifting - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="3">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Jacking Points</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not run the engine when jacking the vehicle. The wheels contacting the ground could cause
                        the vehicle to move.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Make sure the jack is correctly positioned to prevent the vehicle from falling.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wheel chocks should be used to prevent the vehicle from rolling and falling off the jack.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f000201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0017271.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Jacking Points</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Position the floor jack and raise the vehicle at the points shown.</para>
            <figure id="f0002002" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0017270.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Support Points</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>After the vehicle is raised, properly support the vehicle with jack stands at the support points
                shown.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the owner guide for additional information on vehicle jacking.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lifting</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When raising a vehicle on a twin-post hoist, use care when positioning the vehicle so that the
                        hoisting forks do not interfere with the shock absorber mounting brackets or stabilizer mounting
                        brackets (if so equipped) or cause damage to the axle carrier or rear cover.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Damage to suspension, exhaust and steering linkage components can occur if care is not
                        exercised when positioning the hoist adapters prior to lifting the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0002003" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0017269.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Lifting Points</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Raise the vehicle at the lifting points shown.</para>
            <para>Hoist adapters for heavy-duty hoists must be positioned according to the hoist manufacturer's
                recommendations. Make sure the hoist has an adequate lifting capacity for the vehicle being lifted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000216.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000409.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
