<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR FBC/BUS/STRIPPED CHASSIS - INSPECTION - AFTER ROAD
        TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
        <title>AFTER ROAD TEST</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Position the vehicle on a level surface and perform the following operations.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>62.
            <emph type="italic">Check for fault codes and remove EST</emph>.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Inspect for:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>63.
            <emph type="italic">Fluid leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>64.
            <emph type="italic">Exhaust leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>65.
            <emph type="italic">Air leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify/Adjust:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>66.
            <emph type="italic">Automatic transmission fluid level if so equipped.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>67.
            <emph type="italic">That the proper vehicle certification label is affixed. Refer to the New Vehicle
                Processing Manual.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>68.
            <emph type="italic">Add PDI location code and date to Vehicle Identification Decal.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>69.
            <emph type="italic">Fill out and affix the Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker (CTS-1122) (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000415">Figure 15</hotlnk>) to the inside of the vehicle's windshield (optional).
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>70.
            <emph type="italic">Transfer all items marked with an A, F, or R to the following comments section on the
                back of this form. Include a brief explanation of each problem in the space provided.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>The &#8224; (check) stands for Satisfactory. It should be used on any inspection that is performed
                    which does not uncover something wrong; it is OK.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The A code stands for Adjustment Made. It should be used only when a technician made an adjustment
                    during the pre-delivery inspection.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The F code stands for Fluid Low/Leaks. It should be used only when a low fluid condition in a
                    reservoir is noticed or a leak is found.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The R code stands for Repair Needed. It should be used only when a problem is found that does not
                    require an adjustment to fix; a repair must be made after the pre-delivery inspection.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The N/A code stands for Not Applicable. It should be used only when an inspection (Items 1 through
                    67) cannot be performed because the vehicle does not have that feature.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <figure id="f1000415" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000415.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                     scalefitheight="432px"/>
            <caption>Figure 15. Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker (CTS-1122)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
