<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - FASTENER TORQUE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s10003" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5142" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>FASTENER TORQUE</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>GENERAL</title>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Selection and correct installation of threaded fasteners are essential parts of any assembly
                        or rebuild procedure. Fasteners hold much of a vehicle together. If a fastener fails to do its
                        job properly, it can cause a minor problem such as a loose mirror, or a large problem, such as
                        loss of steering control.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Because there are so many styles of fasteners, in various sizes and quality grades (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000301">Figure 1</hotlnk>,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000302">Figure 2</hotlnk>and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000303">Figure 3</hotlnk>), a mechanic must have a working familiarity with
                        the fasteners commonly used in vehicles. Only in this way can the correct selection and
                        installation of the proper fastener be assured. Each fastener is intended to do a particular
                        job, and is selected by the vehicle manufacturer for its suitability for that job.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1000301" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000301" filename="../figg10/G1000301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Hexagon Flanged Capscrew</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f1000302" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000302" filename="../figg10/G1000302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Flanged 12 Point Capscrew</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f1000303" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000303" filename="../figg10/G1000303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. Hexagon Socket Head Capscrew</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Equally important as the selection of the correct fastener is its proper installation.
                        Improperly installing a correct fastener is just as bad as using an incorrect one.
                        Undertightening and overtightening both result in an improperly installed fastener. When
                        threaded fasteners are tightened, a slight stretching of the fastener occurs, and it is this
                        elongation that binds the assembly together. If too little tightening occurs, the slight
                        stretching does not happen, and the joint is not clamped securely. If too much tightening
                        occurs, the fastener will be stretched too much, causing narrowing of the fastener and possible
                        breaking. Correct and consistent use of a torque wrench will assure that the fasteners are
                        properly tightened, and therefore are clamping the pieces of the assembly together properly.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>FASTENER SIZES AND TYPES</title>
                    <para>The first and most important fact that the mechanic must know about a fastener is whether it
                        is a U.S. (Inch System) or a metric thread (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000304">Figure 4</hotlnk>). Next, the mechanic must know the size of the
                        fastener, which is usually determined by the diameter of the shank; the length of the fastener,
                        which is usually measured from the bottom of the head to the end of the thread; and the pitch of
                        the threads.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1000304" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000304" filename="../figg10/G1000304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4. Metric/U.S. (Inch) System</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The pitch of U.S. (Inch System) fasteners is measured by determining the number of threads per
                        inch. The two pitches commonly used in vehicles are coarse thread, officially called Unified
                        National Coarse (UNC), and fine thread, officially called Unified National Fine (UNF).
                    </para>
                    <para>The pitch of metric fasteners is measured by determining the millimeters per thread. For
                        example, a bolt with 0.8 pitch would have 125 complete threads in a 100 millimeter section (100
                        mm divided by 125 threads equals 0.8), and a bolt with 1.0 pitch would have 100 threads in a 100
                        millimeter section. Pitch may be measured directly, using a ruler and counting the threads.
                        Also, thread pitch gauges are available for both U.S. and metric threads, which make it easy to
                        check the pitch of a fastener.
                    </para>
                    <para>In the U.S. system, a typical designation would be: 7/16-20 x 1. This describes a bolt that is
                        7/16 inch in diameter, has 20 threads per inch, and is one inch long. The metric system is
                        similar. A typical metric designation would be: 10 x 0.8 x 25 mm. This describes a bolt that is
                        10 mm in diameter, has a thread pitch of 0.8 (0.8 mm per thread), and is 25 mm long.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Washers</title>
                        <para>Inch system and metric lock washers and flat washers should have the same inside diameter
                            opening as the outside diameter of the bolt being used in the assembly.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>FASTENER GRADES</title>
                    <para>A fastener must be strong enough to do the intended job. U.S. and metric systems both separate
                        their fasteners into grades according to strength and quality (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000305">Figure 5</hotlnk>). In the U.S. system, slash marks are used on bolt
                        heads to indicate grade. SAE Grade 1 and 2 use no slash marks, and these "hardware grades" are
                        used only in the least demanding applications. SAE Grade 5 uses three slash marks on the head,
                        and these are the most commonly used for vehicle applications. SAE Grade 8 uses six slash marks
                        on the head, and these high strength bolts are used where conditions require very high torque.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1000305" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000305" filename="../figg10/G1000305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5. Fastener Grades</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Locknuts are also divided into grades, called A, B, and C. Grade A locknuts are intended for
                        use with SAE Grade 1 and 2 bolts, and the nuts are not marked for identification. Grade B
                        locknuts are intended for use with SAE Grade 5 bolts, and are marked either with the letter "B"
                        or three equally spaced symbols (dot, line, letter, or other character). Grade C locknuts are
                        intended for use with SAE Grade 8 bolts, and are marked either with the letter "C" or six
                        equally spaced symbols (dot, line, letter, or other character). Another marking alternative is
                        having notches cut circumferentially into each of the six corners of the locknut at
                        approximately mid-height, one row of notches for Grade B and two rows for Grade C.
                    </para>
                    <para>Metric threaded fasteners are also separated into grades according to strength and quality.
                        Bolts commonly used in vehicles are Metric Class 8.8, Metric Class 9.8, and Metric Class 10.9.
                        These metric bolts are identified by the class number stamped on the head of the bolt. Metric
                        nuts commonly used are Class 9 and Class 10 (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000306">Figure 6</hotlnk>). The metric nuts also have the class number stamped
                        on them for easy identification.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1000306" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000306" filename="../figg10/G1000306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6. Hexagon Flanged Nut</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Metric Grade 9 nuts are intended to be used with metric grade 9.8 and 8.8 bolts, while metric
                        grade 10 nuts are intended to be used with metric grade 10.9 bolts.
                    </para>
                    <para>Class 8.8 is approximately equal to SAE Grade 5, and class 10.9 is comparable to SAE Grade 8
                        fasteners.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>PREVAILING TORQUE FASTENERS</title>
                    <para>A prevailing torque nut is designed to develop an interference between the nut and bolt
                        threads. This is most often accomplished by distortion of the top of an all metal nut or by
                        using a nylon patch on the threads in the middle of the hex flat. A nylon insert may also be
                        used as a method of interference between nut and bolt threads.
                    </para>
                    <para>A prevailing torque bolt is designed to develop an interference between bolt and nut threads,
                        or the threads of a tapped hole. This is accomplished by distorting some of the threads or by
                        using a nylon patch or adhesive.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Recommendations for Reuse</title>
                        <para>Clean, unrusted prevailing torque nuts and bolts may be reused as follows:</para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Clean dirt and other foreign material off nut or bolt.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Inspect nut or bolt to assure there are no cracks, elongation, or other signs of
                                    abuse or overtightening. If there is any doubt, replace with a new prevailing torque
                                    fastener of equal or greater strength.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Assemble parts and hand start nut or bolt.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Observe that before the fastener seats, it develops torque per the following
                                    chart. If there is any doubt, replace with a new prevailing torque fastener of equal
                                    or greater strength.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Tighten fastener to torque specified in appropriate section of this manual.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>Bolts and nuts that are rusty or damaged should be replaced with a new prevailing torque
                            fastener of equal or greater strength.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Prevailing Fastener Torque Chart</title>
                        <table id="hl1000301">
                            <title>Prevailing Fastener Torque Chart</title>
                            <tgroup cols="20">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="5" colname="5" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="6" colname="6" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="7" colname="7" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="8" colname="8" colwidth="0.32in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="9" colname="9" colwidth="0.25in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="10" colname="10" colwidth="0.24in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="11" colname="11" colwidth="0.18in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="12" colname="12" colwidth="0.18in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="13" colname="13" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="14" colname="14" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="15" colname="15" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="16" colname="16" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="17" colname="17" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="18" colname="18" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="19" colname="19" colwidth="0.37in"/>
                                <colspec colnum="20" colname="20" colwidth="0.37in" colsep="1"/>
                                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="20" spanname="sqspan1-20"/>
                                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="12" spanname="sqspan1-12"/>
                                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="8" spanname="sqspan1-8"/>
                                <spanspec namest="9" nameend="12" spanname="sqspan9-12"/>
                                <spanspec namest="13" nameend="14" spanname="sqspan13-14"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="20" spanname="sqspan1-20" align="center">
                                            <para>INCH SIZES</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="12" spanname="sqspan1-12" align="center">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="13">
                                            <para>.250</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="14">
                                            <para>.312</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>.375</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>.437</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>.500</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>.562</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>.625</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>.750</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para>NUTS AND ALL METAL BOLTS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>N&#8226;m</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="13">
                                            <para>0.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="14">
                                            <para>0.6</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>1.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>1.8</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>2.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>3.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>4.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>6.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>In-Lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="13">
                                            <para>4.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="14">
                                            <para>5.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>12</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>15</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>20</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>27</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>35</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>51</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para>ADHESIVE OR NYLON COATED BOLTS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>N&#8226;m</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="13">
                                            <para>0.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="14">
                                            <para>0.5</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>1.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>1.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>1.8</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>2.6</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>3.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>5.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>In-Lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="13">
                                            <para>4.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="14">
                                            <para>5.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>9.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>12</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>15</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>22</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>28</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>43</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="20" spanname="sqspan1-20" align="center">
                                            <para>METRIC SIZES (mm)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="12" spanname="sqspan1-12" align="center">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan13-14" align="center">
                                            <para>6 &#38; 6.3</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>8</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>10</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>12</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>14</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>16</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>20</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para>NUTS AND ALL METAL BOLTS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>N&#8226;m</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan13-14" align="center">
                                            <para>0.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>0.8</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>1.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>2.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>3.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>4.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>7.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>In-Lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan13-14" align="center">
                                            <para>4.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>7.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>12</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>18</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>25</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>35</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>57</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8" align="center">
                                            <para>ADHESIVE OR NYLON COATED BOLTS</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>N&#8226;m</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan13-14" align="center">
                                            <para>0.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>0.6</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>1.2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>1.6</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>2.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>3.4</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>5.6</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry colspan="8" spanname="sqspan1-8">
                                            <para></para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="sqspan9-12" align="center">
                                            <para>In-Lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan13-14" align="center">
                                            <para>4.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="15">
                                            <para>5.0</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="16">
                                            <para>10</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="17">
                                            <para>14</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="18">
                                            <para>20</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="19">
                                            <para>28</para>
                                        </entry>
                                        <entry colname="20">
                                            <para>46</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>APPLYING TORQUE</title>
                    <para>Properly tightening a bolt requires a clean nut and bolt, free from rust, scale, previously
                        crossed threads, or any other damage. If locking compound has been used, the threads should be
                        cleaned. Fastener torque is greatly dependent upon whether or not the threads are lubricated.
                        The mechanic must read the torque tables carefully to be sure whether the torque value specified
                        is for dry or lubricated threads. Most bolts used internally in engines, transmissions, rear
                        axle carriers, transfer cases, power take-offs, etc. are unplated. Most bolts used in general
                        chassis applications are zinc plate and clear chromate coated. Some platings, such as cadmium,
                        act as lubricants, and care must be taken not to overtighten those fasteners. In the event that
                        an anti-galling compound is used between steel and aluminum parts, be sure the threads of the
                        bolt are cleaned thoroughly. These compounds can act as extreme lubricants, and incorrect torque
                        values will be obtained, resulting in possible thread stripping or over-stretching the fastener.
                        Wherever possible, hold the bolt stationary and apply the torque to the nut. Apply torque
                        smoothly and evenly, without "jerking" the torque wrench.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Castellated (Slotted) Nut</title>
                        <para>When tightening a castellated (slotted) nut to be secured with lock wire or a cotter pin,
                            tighten to the minimum torque specified. Then check the alignment of the slots with the hole
                            in the bolt. If the alignment is not correct, continue tightening the nut, up to the maximum
                            allowable torque, until the slots and hole align. Do not tighten past the maximum allowable
                            torque. If alignment has not been achieved, use a new nut.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>TORQUE WRENCH USE</title>
                    <para>When tightening a fastener, it is important to use a steady pull on the torque wrench. Only in
                        this way can accurate torque values be achieved. If the torque value required cannot be obtained
                        with the existing torque wrench, a longer wrench should be used. Dial indicator type torque
                        wrenches can be used accurately when an extension is added to the handle, to gain more leverage.
                        With most click type torque wrenches, however, accuracy can be obtained only if the point of
                        pull remains at the center of the hand grip area. Therefore, no handle extension can be used
                        with most click type torque wrenches, unless the tool is designed and calibrated for this
                        purpose. Consult the manufacturer's instructions for proper use, if allowed, of handle
                        extensions.
                    </para>
                    <para>When an adapter is attached to the square drive end of a dial indicator type torque wrench,
                        the dial reading (compared to the actual torque applied) will be affected if the leverage length
                        of the torque wrench is increased. A correction factor is then needed to achieve an accurate
                        dial reading. Obtain the correction factor as follows (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000307">Figure 7</hotlnk>):
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1000307" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1000307" filename="../figg10/G1000307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="192px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7. Obtaining Correction Factor</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <lev2>
                        <para>1. Divide total length "A" by torque wrench length "B."</para>
                        <table id="hl1000302">
                            <tgroup cols="1">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in" colsep="1"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Example:</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Total Length A = 24"</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Torque Wrench Length B = 12"</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>&#160;</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>A divided by B =</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>24" divided by 12" = 2 (Quotient)</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <para>2. Multiply the dial reading times the Quotient found above to determine the torque at the
                            end of the adapter.
                        </para>
                        <table id="hl1000303">
                            <tgroup cols="1">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in" colsep="1"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Example:</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Dial Reading = 50 lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Quotient = 2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>&#160;</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Torque at End of Adapter =</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>50 x 2 = 100 lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <para>3. If the required torque is known, divide by the Quotient to determine what the torque
                            reading should be.
                        </para>
                        <table id="hl1000304">
                            <tgroup cols="1">
                                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in" colsep="1"/>
                                <thead valign="bottom">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Example:</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </thead>
                                <tbody valign="top">
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Required Torque = 100 lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Quotient = 2</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>&#160;</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="0">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>Desired Torque Reading =</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                    <row rowsep="1">
                                        <entry>
                                            <para>100 divided by 2 = 50 lbs.</para>
                                        </entry>
                                    </row>
                                </tbody>
                            </tgroup>
                        </table>
                        <specpara>
                            <note>
                                <para>It is recommended that torque wrenches be checked on a regular basis for correct
                                    calibration.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10003_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
