<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - New Vehicle Processing Manual - NEW TRUCK RECEIVING AND
        DAMAGE CLAIM PROCESSING - INTRODUCTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>New vehicles from Chatham, Springfield, and Garland assembly plants are delivered to the Consignee
                (Dealer, body builder or Fleet), by a Carrier. The Carrier, ATC Leasing, is the parent company to the
                affiliates Active USA, Inc., Active Canada, Inc., Provincial America, and Dallas and Mavis Forwarding.
                The Carrier, ATC Leasing, is responsible for transportation loss or damage affecting any vehicle in its
                possession, PROVIDING THE CONSIGNEE REPORTS THE LOSS OR DAMAGE ON THE DELIVERY RECEIPT.
            </para>
            <para>This manual details proper procedures for vehicle receiving inspection, and for filing loss and damage
                claims:
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exceptions</title>
            <para>A copy of the original Bill of Lading from the applicable plant is often found inside the cab. This
                may assist in the receiving process as it may reflect attachments such as radio, spare wheel, etc. The
                Consignee receives and inspects the vehicle, noting any transportation damage and loss (Exceptions) on
                the Delivery Receipt (501). The Carrier representative (the driver) and the Consignee (the person
                receiving the vehicle) both sign the Receipt. A Consignee signature on the Receipt with no Exceptions
                noted, acknowledges all items on the Delivery Receipt are accepted; no further action may be taken
                against the carrier or International. Damage claims for corrections not noted on the Delivery Receipt
                will be denied. The Consignee receives compensation for Exceptions by filing a DDEW Warranty claim with
                International Warranty Claim Center (WCC).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Concealed Damage:</title>
            <para>Damage that cannot be seen during a normal inspection is considered "concealed". Typical locations are
                the oil pan, inside the sidewalls of tires, the bottom side of fuel/air tank, etc. CONCEALED DAMAGE MUST
                BE REPORTED WITHIN 48 HOURS OF DELIVERY TIME; THE BURDEN OF PROOF IS ON THE CONSIGNEE. The Consignee
                must file a claim with ATC Leasing; refer to
                <hotlnk document="s10005_16.xml" xrefid="x1000502">CONCEALED DAMAGE.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>COLLISION DAMAGE OR TOTAL LOSS CLAIMS: In case of collision damage or total loss of a vehicle,
                        DO NOT BEGIN ANY REPAIRS; NOTIFY THE CARRIER IMMEDIATELY by calling the ATC Leasing Claims
                        Department toll-free Hot Line at 1-800/558-3271, or call 414/658-4831 during regular business
                        hours (7:30 - 4:30 Central Standard Time), for billing instructions. INTERNATIONAL WILL NOT
                        REIMBURSE DEALERS OR OTHER REPAIR LOCATIONS FOR EXPENSE OF COLLISION DAMAGE OR TOTAL LOSS OF
                        VEHICLE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
