<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Undecking and Storage - UNDECKING AND STORAGE - UNDECKING PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="3">
        <title>UNDECKING PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Undecking Sling, ZTSE4280, for use on Series 1000 through 4000, 7000, 8000, 9000i:</title>
            <para>The chain and hardware are made of special alloy steel, engineered for a combination of strength,
                lightness and durability. The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000506">nylon portion of the sling hooks to the front springs</hotlnk>
                behind the forward shackle.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000506" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000558.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Sling Hook Up</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The sling has a working load rating of 16,000 lbs. at a 45 degree angle. The rating is marked
                        on the sling. DO NOT EXCEED the working load rating of the sling; to do so could cause damage to
                        the vehicle and possible personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the sling to the lifting hook. Then put the hooks and chain through the tow hook
                    openings in the bumper as shown in the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000506">Figure above.</hotlnk>
                    Positioning the sling under the bumper will bend it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wrap the chain around the spring so it rests just behind the front shackle. Hook the
                    grab-hook onto the link of chain closest to the spring, as shown in the following
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000507">Figure</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1000507" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000507.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Secure the Chain on the Sling</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the protective sleeves to cover the contact areas that could damage the sling.
                    Be sure there are no twists in the sling. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000508">Figure 5.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly put enough tension on the sling to take the weight of the vehicle off the towing
                    saddle. Unhook the axle from the saddle, then lift the vehicle high enough to move the drive truck
                    from under the undecked unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the undecked vehicle and remove the sling.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Inspect the sling before undecking the next unit.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Keep clear of vehicles already suspended or being lifted.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1000508" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000508.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Sling Positioned Through The Bumper Opening</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ZTSE4441,
                <hotlnk document="s10005_6.xml" xrefid="f1000504">Undecking Adapter</hotlnk>
                For Use On 2000, 5000i, and 9400i Models With Center Tow Pin Front Bumper
            </title>
            <para>PROCEDURE</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove tow pin from bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert ZTSE4441 lifting bracket into tow hook opening on bumper.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install tow pin in bumper through hole in lifting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove clevis pins on lifting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place lifting chains/straps through both clevises.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install clevis and clevis pins on lifting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply pressure to hold tool up under front portion of tool until initial tension is set
                    on hoist.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recheck all connections and attachments prior to lifting unit off ground.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Failure to do Step 7 will allow a portion of the pin to rise above the bumper. While the pin
                        will not come out of the bracket, it is recommended that upward pressure be applied while chain
                        becomes taut. This will not allow the pin to move.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
