<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR FBC/BUS/STRIPPED CHASSIS - INSPECTION - UNDER HOOD
        INSPECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>UNDER HOOD INSPECTION</title>
        <para>8.
            <emph type="italic">Verify that operator's manuals and other required documents are in the vehicle.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The following documents should be included in this package:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Operator's Manuals: vehicle and engine.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Component manufacturer - supplied manuals and warranties like Fuller or Allison transmission
                    maintenance manuals, for example.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Incomplete vehicle documents.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>9.
            <emph type="italic">Record anti-freeze protection level: -20&#176;F (-29&#176;C) or -40&#176;F
                (-40&#176;C).</emph>Circle one on the form. Check DCA levels and record: 1.5-3.0 units per gallon.
        </para>
        <para>10.
            <emph type="italic">Verify proper coolant level. Fill as required</emph>.
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>It should be about 1 inch (25 mm) below the filler neck opening or between min-max indicators on
                    transparent surge tanks. Refer to the operator's manual for more information.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use only Fleetrite antifreeze or equivalent that meets International B-1 specification.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>11.
            <emph type="italic">Re-tighten all cooling system hose clamps.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>For constant torque hose clamps (T-bolt, spring style and non-spring styles), re-tighten to 50 to
                    60 in-lbs. (5.6 to 6.8 Nm).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For other hose clamps up to 1-3/4 inch diameter, re-tighten to 70 to 80 in-lbs. (7.9 to 9.0 Nm).
                    Clamps larger than 1-3/4 inches, re-tighten to 80 to 100 in-lbs. (9.0 to 11.3 Nm).
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>12.
            <emph type="italic">Pressure check cooling system. Inspect for leaks.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Use a pressure tester such as ZTSE-2384 or an equivalent to pressure check the cooling system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Follow the instructions supplied with the pressure tester to perform this operation.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The ZTSE-2384 unit has a heavy-duty pump and adapters for remotely applying pressure to the
                    cooling system at the radiator fill neck. It includes a pressure gauge, manual pressure relief valve
                    and hose assembly with a twist-on clamp bracket to receive the adapters for various sizes of filler
                    necks. Adapter ZTSE-23841 is needed for systems with threaded caps.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>13.
            <emph type="italic">Inspect starter/alternator harness cable end tightness, cable routing, support and
                clearance.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>14.
            <emph type="italic">Verify that wiring harnesses are clear of moving parts, sharp edges, and heat sources.
                Relocate harnesses if necessary.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify and Inspect:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>15.
            <emph type="italic">Proper engine oil level.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>If the oil level is low, add oil. DO NOT OVERFILL. Fill to the FULL mark on the dipstick.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Refer to the operator's manual for specific engine oil recommendations and filling procedures.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>16.
            <emph type="italic">For oil, fuel, and coolant leaks</emph>.
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect all hoses for leaks near the engine and near the oil system, fuel system, cooling
                    system, brake system, and air system components.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>17.
            <emph type="italic">All fuel, air and coolant hoses for clearance from moving parts, sharp edges, and heat
                sources; also for proper routing and clipping. Relocate as needed.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect and relocate hoses if necessary to avoid moving objects, sharp edges, and heat
                    sources.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>18.
            <emph type="italic">Freedom of movement and full throttle position of accelerator pedal.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect position of pedal. It must be able to move freely through its entire range
                    without interference. Rotate pedal on accelerator rod and move pedal through full travel to verify
                    that it doesn't hang up on floor panel, engine cover, etc.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify and Inspect:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>19.
            <emph type="italic">Re-tighten all air induction system clamps.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Re-torque hose clamps (T-bolt, spring style and non-spring styles):</para>
                <para>On aluminum pipe, re-tighten to 50-60 in-lbs. (5.6-6.8 Nm).</para>
                <para>On steel pipe, re-tighten to 70-75 in-lbs. (7.9-8.4 Nm).</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>20.
            <emph type="italic">Engine air cleaner element in position.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Verify that the element is in its proper position and sealing by looking in the air intake opening
                    on the canister. Some models do not have this opening, so the canister cover has to be removed.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>21.
            <emph type="italic">Air inlet pipe clearance.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect the inlet pipe to make sure it is not too close to moving objects and surfaces
                    that it could rub against.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>22.
            <emph type="italic">Power steering reservoir fluid level.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect the fluid level by removing the reservoir cap and noting where the fluid is on
                    the dipstick (attached to the reservoir cap). Fill if necessary. Refer to the operator's manual for
                    specific procedures and correct fluid to use.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>23.
            <emph type="italic">Adjustment of front axle wheel stop setting/steering gear end of travel relief.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>The Ross TAS-40, TAS-45, TAS-55 and TAS-65 power steering gears are equipped with automatic
                    unloading (poppet) valves that automatically set to furnish power steering pump protection and
                    reduce pressure to unload steering linkage at vehicle axle stop settings. These valves are
                    automatically set to axle stops after installation in a vehicle at first full right and full left
                    turns.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>To check or adjust the front wheel turning angle and resulting stop setting, turn the wheels to
                    the extreme right until the steering bottoms out. The clearance between the tire and any
                    chassis/linkage parts must be 1/2 inch to 1 inch (12.7 to 25.4 mm). Check both front wheels and
                    adjust to specifications if necessary.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>With the engine at idle and the vehicle unloaded, turn the steering wheel full travel in one
                    direction until the steering fully bottoms against the axle stop. Maximum input of torque to be
                    applied during this procedure is 25 ft-lbs. (33.9 Nm) or 30 ft-lbs (13 kg) rim pull on an 18-inch
                    (457 mm) diameter steering wheel. This will automatically position the poppet adjuster seat and
                    sleeve assembly in relation to the axle stop.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: If excessive input shaft torque or rim pull is encountered prior to reaching
                        the axle stop, allow the vehicle to roll forward or jack up the vehicle at the front axle.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Follow the same procedure while turning the steering wheel in the other direction. The poppet
                    valves are now positioned to trip and reduce pressure as the front wheels approach the axle stops in
                    either direction. Refer to the Service Manual for proper instructions if turn angle is to be
                    reduced.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>24.
            <emph type="italic">All steering hoses for clearance from moving parts, sharp edges, and heat sources; also
                for proper routing and clipping. Relocate as needed. Re-tighten all hose clamps.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect and relocate hoses if necessary to avoid moving objects, sharp edges, and heat
                    sources.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For constant torque hose clamps, re-tighten to 90 in-lbs. (10 Nm).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For other hose clamps re-tighten to 70 to 80 in-lbs. (7.9 to 9.0 Nm).</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>25.
            <emph type="italic">That cotter keys/lock tabs are installed and properly spread on all steering/brake
                components and clutch linkage.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Replace all missing or damaged cotter keys or lock tabs.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>26.
            <emph type="italic">Steering shaft pinch bolt head twisted off at both ends of I-shaft.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Examine the steering intermediate shaft and ensure that the pinch bolt heads have been twisted off
                    at both ends of the shaft.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
