<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - New Vehicle Processing Manual - VEHICLE SAFETY
        CERTIFICATION - CERTIFICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="9">
        <title>CERTIFICATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>It is important to remember that every vehicle manufactured for sale and sold for use in the United
                States or Canada must both comply with the applicable federal safety standards and must be certified
                that it does comply. This compliance may be accomplished as described below for complete and incomplete
                vehicles.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Complete Vehicles - Certified at the Assembly Plant</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Definition</emph>
            </para>
            <para>A complete vehicle is a unit which is deliverable and road-ready. International vehicles which are
                complete when shipped from the Assembly Plant are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Truck Tractor with fifth-wheel installed.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Certification of Complete Vehicles</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Certification is completed by installing a paper label permanently secured to either the hinge pillar,
                door-latch post, or the door edge that meets the door-latch post, next to the driver's seating position.
                The label is constructed of adhesive-backed paper which cannot be removed from the vehicle without being
                destroyed. The current labels for
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000521">U.S. manufactured vehicles (1659611-C1)</hotlnk>
                and for
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000522">Canadian manufactured vehicles (1652154-C1)</hotlnk>
                are shown below.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Complete Vehicle Certification Labels</title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000521" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000521.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="490px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. U.S. - 1659611C1 Certification Label</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1000522" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000522.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="490px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Canada - 1652154C1 Certification Label</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>All vehicles produced for sale in Canada, including incomplete vehicles with supporting documents,
                must have the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000523">Canadian mark (436030-C1)</hotlnk>
                installed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000523" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000523.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="216px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Canadian Mark - 436030-C1</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Any party who replaces, adds, removes or modifies components on the vehicle that might affect
                        the vehicle GAWR or GVWR (i.e., tires, springs, axles, etc.) must recertify the vehicle GAWR and
                        GVWR.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Incomplete Vehicles - Certified by the Final Stage Manufacturer</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Definition</emph>
            </para>
            <para>An incomplete vehicle is a unit which leaves the Assembly Plant as a:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Chassis-Cab</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flat back or windshield cowl chassis</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chassis only.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>It is assumed that a body or other equipment will be mounted on the chassis by others prior to
                delivery of the vehicle to the end user. Such units are therefore classified as incomplete vehicles. It
                is obviously impossible for a flat back cowl chassis to comply with windshield glass standards, or for
                the chassis-cab to meet body lighting requirements. Therefore, these incomplete vehicles will be built
                with all appropriate safety items and will comply with the requirements of the law insofar as the
                vehicle state of completion permits. Incomplete vehicles shipped from the Assembly Plant are provided
                with a notification that the vehicle is incomplete. This notification is in the form of a 3- or 4-page
                document furnished with each incomplete vehicle containing the following information:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Name and mailing address of manufacturer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Date of production</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle Identification Number</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>GAWR (Gross Axle Weight Rating) for each axle</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>GVWR (Gross Vehicle Weight Rating)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle type</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tire and rim choice with inflation pressure</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>List of all federal safety standards applicable to above type of vehicle. (Those standards
                        already complied with as the vehicle is produced at the Assembly Plant will be identified.)
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Certification of Incomplete Vehicles</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Each International Chassis-Cab built for sale in the U.S. must have one of the following labels
                installed:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For vehicles built in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000524">Canada (1652150-C1)</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For vehicles built in the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000524">U.S. (1659607-C1)</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>and the proper incomplete vehicle document. This label will identify those standards already complied
                with in the Chassis-Cab as produced at the Assembly Plant. It will also identify those standards to
                which the vehicle will comply if the vehicle is completed in accordance with the instructions contained
                in the incomplete vehicle document. Do not cover this label with any other label.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000524" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000524.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="432px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Incomplete Vehicle Certification Labels - U.S. And Canada</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>In flat back cowls, the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000525">incomplete vehicle document</hotlnk>
                is placed in a clear plastic envelope and strap locked to the radiator stay rod.
            </para>
            <para>In all other vehicles, the incomplete vehicle document is placed in the left hand door dispatch
                compartment.
            </para>
            <para>There are various incomplete vehicle documents provided with the vehicle. The specific document
                provided is dependent upon the country of manufacture, country of destination and type of vehicle.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000525" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000525.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Incomplete Vehicle Document Sample</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Intermediate Manufacturer</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Definition</emph>
            </para>
            <para>An Intermediate Manufacturer is a manufacturer, other than the Incomplete Vehicle Manufacturer or
                Final Stage Manufacturer, who performs manufacturing/assembly operations on an incomplete vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Modification to Incomplete Vehicles - If the Intermediate Manufacturer makes any changes in the
                vehicle which affect the validity of the statements in the incomplete vehicle document provided by
                International, that Intermediate Manufacturer must furnish an addendum to the incomplete vehicle
                document providing mailing address and an indication of all changes that should be made to the
                incomplete vehicle document to reflect changes made to the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Certification</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Chassis-Cabs built for sale in U.S. - In addition to furnishing the addendum above, each Intermediate
                Manufacturer must also affix an
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000526">Intermediate Manufacturer Certification Label</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000526" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000526.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Intermediate Manufacturer Certification Label</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Intermediate Manufacturers should seek legal counsel to determine the type and wording of such
                certification when required. If it is determined that a International-supplied label will meet their
                needs, Intermediate Manufacturers may secure labels from International. Specify Part No. 501657C1 and
                protective cover Part No. 575023-C1 for use on chassis-cabs only.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Final Stage Manufacturer</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Definition</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Any party performing manufacturing/assembly operations to an incomplete vehicle and making it
                road-ready is considered the Final Stage Manufacturer. This includes any International facility,
                independent dealer, body builder, or equipment supplier. The party installing a body, equipment, a fifth
                wheel, etc. to complete the vehicle for delivery and make it road-ready is responsible to see that the
                complete vehicle meets all applicable safety standards, including certification.
            </para>
            <para>The only exception is the situation where the end-user (owner) chooses to install his own body,
                specialized equipment, or fifth wheel on an incomplete vehicle. (Vehicles which are sold and delivered
                to end-users and which lack a body or other equipment necessary to make the vehicle complete and
                road-ready cannot be certified by the seller as a complete vehicle. A final certification label will not
                have been installed and all incomplete vehicle documents will have been left in the vehicle.) The owner
                is advised to retain these documents on file.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A chassis-cab intended for use as a tractor and built with all normal tractor equipment
                        (trailer connections, lights, etc.) is not considered road-ready and complete until a fifth
                        wheel has been installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Certification</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Final Stage Manufacturer is responsible for installing an appropriate certification label,
                securely and permanently fixed to the complete vehicle. When acting as a Final Stage Manufacturer,
                International facilities should use a label as described under Section A for complete vehicles. The
                label is available to all Company retail outlets. For U.S. manufactured vehicles, use label 1659611-C1 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000521">Figure 20</hotlnk>). For Canadian manufactured vehicles, use label 1652154-C1
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000522">Figure 21</hotlnk>). Protective cover 435654-C1 must be installed over the
                label.
            </para>
            <para>Any party other than a International facility who certifies a complete vehicle should seek legal
                counsel to determine the type of label construction, material and method of label attachment required as
                well as to determine the appropriate wording for the certification label to be installed. If it is
                determined that the type of label and wording of the label (shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000521">Figure 20</hotlnk>) meets the needs of a Final Stage Manufacturer, a label may
                be obtained from International in which the name of the manufacturer is left blank by ordering label
                part number 436076-C3 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000527">Figure 26</hotlnk>) and protective cover 435654-C1. THIS LABEL IS TO BE USED
                ONLY ON VEHICLES THAT WERE NOT CERTIFIED AS A CHASSIS-CAB MANUFACTURED BY INTERNATIONAL FOR SALE IN THE
                U.S.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000527" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000527.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="440px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Final Stage Manufacturer Certification Label, 436076-C3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Chassis-Cabs manufactured by International for sale in the U.S. will contain either of the following
                labels:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">1659607C1 Chassis-cabs built in the U.S.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">1652150C1 Chassis-cabs built in Canada.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>To complete the certification of vehicles containing label 1659607C1, attach label 1659609-C1 (refer
                to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000528">Figure 27</hotlnk>). To complete the certification of vehicles containing
                label 1652150C1, attach label 1652152-C1 (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000528">Figure 27</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000528" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000528.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Chassis/Cab Certification Labels - U.S. And Canada</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Modifications To Factory-Installed Items - Certified by Modifier</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Definition and Labeling</emph>
            </para>
            <para>If a complete vehicle is shipped from the Assembly Plant, but is subsequently modified, altered or
                added to by a party for further resale, the responsibility for compliance of the modified vehicle with
                the law rests with the party performing the modification, alteration, or addition. In such cases, the
                certification originally furnished by International with the vehicle must be supplemented by an
                additional certification by the party making the alteration. This certification should state:
            </para>
            <para>This vehicle was altered by (name of modifier) in (month and year in which alterations were made) and
                as altered, it conforms to all applicable Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards affected by the
                alteration and in effect on the date of original manufacture.
            </para>
            <para>This label (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000529">Figure 28</hotlnk>) is available under Part No. 449893-C4 for US vehicle
                alterers and Part No. 1676840C1 for Canadian vehicle alterers. Protective cover 435654-C1 should be
                installed over this label.
            </para>
            <para>VEHICLE MODIFIER CERTIFICATION (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000529">Figure 28</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000529" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000529.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="478px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. Vehicle Modifier Certification - U.S. And Canada</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Additional Certification Label Information And Instructions</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All labels must be fully filled out.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All labels must be affixed to the vehicle in accordance with FMVSR Parts 567.4, 568.5,
                    568.6, 568.7 and 568.8 or CMVSR, Sections 4 and 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No label shall be installed over another label.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">It is unlawful to affix an incorrect certification label to a vehicle. NON-INTERNATIONAL
                    MANUFACTURERS, INDEPENDENT DEALERS, BODY BUILDERS, EQUIPMENT SUPPLIERS, ETC. SHOULD NOT USE LABEL
                    PART NUMBERS 1652150-C1, 1659607-C1, 1652154-C1 OR 1659611-C1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">INSTALLING IMPROPER CERTIFICATION LABELS CONSTITUTES A VIOLATION OF FEDERAL MOTOR
                    VEHICLE SAFETY STANDARDS LAW. Any violation of this law is subject to a fine of up to $1,000 per
                    vehicle with a maximum of $800,000 for a related series of violations. The requirements of the law
                    are stringent and the penalties are severe. It is therefore extremely important that persons
                    involved with installation of certification labels become fully familiar with the law as it relates
                    to their responsibilities.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Glider Kits - Certification Not Required</title>
            <para>Glider Kits are not considered vehicles by Federal Law. Glider Kits are a service part and assume the
                identity of the original vehicle being rebuilt. The rebuilt vehicle must then comply with the same
                Federal Law as the original vehicle. Local laws may involve additional regulations concerning glider
                kits. These laws may consider glider kits as other than service parts. Installers and users of glider
                kits must check with local authorities regarding licensing and other legal requirements.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
