<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 - General - Driveline System - General Information - Driveline System Diagnosis and Testing
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="27">
        <title>Driveline System Diagnosis and Testing</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Special Tools</title>
            <table id="t050004">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.97*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.03*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figST1/ST1622A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inclinometer</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figST1/ST1266A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Dial Indicator Gauge with Holding Fixture</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figST2/ST2207A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vibration Analyzer</para>
                                <para>ZTSE4580</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figST1/ST1802A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Holding Fixture, Drive Pinion Flange</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driveline System Inspection and Verification</title>
            <para>Certain axle and driveline symptoms are also common to the engine, transmission, wheel bearings, tires
                and other parts of the vehicle. For this reason, make sure that the cause of the trouble is in the axle
                before disassembling, adjusting or repairing the axle. For additional information, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000409.xml" xrefid="x1000409">Noise, Vibration and Harshness</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Noise Acceptability</emph>
            </para>
            <para>A gear-driven unit will produce a certain amount of noise. Some noise is acceptable and audible at
                certain speeds or under various driving conditions, such as a newly paved blacktop road. Slight noise is
                not detrimental to the operation of the axle and is considered normal.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Universal Joint (U-Joint) Inspection</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Raise and support the vehicle. Rotate the driveshaft by hand. Install a new U-joint if it shows signs
                of seizure, excessive wear or incorrect seating. For additional information, refer to
                <exhotlnk document="../S06/S06002.htm" bookname="S06002">Driveshaft in S06002</exhotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Inspection For Bent Rear Axle Housing</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the vehicle in NEUTRAL, position it on a hoist. For additional information, refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000216.xml" xrefid="x1000216">Jacking and Lifting</hotlnk>. Allow the
                    axle to be freely suspended.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use white chalk or paint to mark a vertical line on the center of each rear tire.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050001" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0781A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust both wheels so that the markings face the front of the vehicle. With a tape
                    measure, measure the distance between the marks and record this reading (front reading).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050002" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figA00/A0012007.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the rear wheels so the markings are directly underneath the vehicle. Measure the
                    distance between the marks and record this reading (bottom reading).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050003" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figA00/A0012008.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the rear wheels so the markings face the rear of the vehicle. Measure and record
                    the distance between the marks (rear reading).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050004" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figA00/A0012009.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare the front and the rear readings (Steps 3 and 5) to find the toe-in or toe-out
                    condition.
                </para>
                <para>&#8226; Toe-in occurs when the front measurement is less than the rear measurement.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Toe-out occurs when the rear measurement is less than the front measurement.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To determine camber, find the average of the front and the rear measurements (Steps 3
                    and 5). Subtract the bottom reading (Step 4) from this number.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Positive (+) camber is when the bottom reading is less than the average of the front and
                    rear readings. Negative (-) camber is when the bottom reading is greater than the average of the
                    front and rear readings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The results of the calculations in Steps 6 and 7 must conform to the following
                    specifications:
                </para>
                <para>Toe-in: 0-1.6 mm (0-1/16 inch).</para>
                <para>Toe-out: 0-4.8 mm (0-3/16 inch).</para>
                <para>Camber: 0 &#177; 4.0 mm (0 &#177; 5/32 inch).</para>
                <para>If the differential housing does not meet these specifications, install a new differential
                    housing. For additional information, refer to
                    <exhotlnk document="../S14/S14020.htm" bookname="S14020">Rear Drive Axle/Differential in
                        S14020</exhotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analysis of Leakage</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Clean up the leaking area enough to identify the exact source. An axle leak can be caused by the
                following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Axle lubricant level is too high</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Worn or damaged axle shaft seals or differential seals</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Differential housing is cracked</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flange yoke seal is worn or damaged</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pinion flange is scored or damaged</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Axle cover is not sealed</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Repair the axle as necessary. Make sure the axle lubricant is at the correct level. For additional
                information, refer to Specifications in this section.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Flange Yoke Seal</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Leaks at the drive pinion seal originate for the following reasons:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Drive pinion seal was installed incorrectly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Poor quality drive pinion seal journal surface</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Any damage to the drive pinion seal bore (dings, dents, gouges or other imperfections) will distort
                the drive pinion seal casing and allow leakage past the outer edge of the drive pinion seal.
            </para>
            <para>The rubber lips can occasionally become hard and crack at the oil lip contact point. The contact point
                on the pinion flange may blacken. Marks, nicks, gouges or rough surface texture on the drive pinion seal
                journal of the pinion flange will also cause leaks.
            </para>
            <para>Install a new pinion flange if any of these conditions exist.</para>
            <para>When a drive pinion seal leak occurs, install a new drive pinion seal and check the vent and the vent
                hose to verify that they are clean and free of foreign material.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Wheel Hub Oil Seals</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Wheel hub oil seals are susceptible to the same kinds of damage as drive pinion seals if installed
                incorrectly. The wheel hub oil seal bore must be clean and the lip handled carefully to avoid cutting or
                tearing it. The spindle journal surface must be free of nicks, gouges and rough surface texture. For
                additional information, refer to Wheel Hubs and Bearings in S14020.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Analysis of Vibration</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Few vibration conditions are caused by the rear axle. On a vibration concern, follow the diagnosis
                procedure in
                <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000409.xml" xrefid="x1000409">Noise, Vibration and Harshness</hotlnk>
                unless there is a good reason to suspect the axle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Tires</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not balance the wheels and tires while they are mounted on the vehicle. Possible tire
                        disintegration/differential failure could result, causing personal injury/extensive component
                        damage. Use an off-vehicle wheel and tire balancer only.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Most vibration in the rear of the vehicle is caused by tires or driveline angle.</para>
            <para>Vibration is a concern with modern, high-mileage tires if they are not "true" both radially and
                laterally. They are more susceptible to vibration around the limits of radial and lateral runout of the
                tire and wheel assembly. They also require more accurate balancing. Wheel and tire runout checks, truing
                and balancing are normally done before an axle inspection. For additional information, refer to Wheels
                and Tires in S17002.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Driveline Angle</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Driveline angularity is the angular relationship between the engine crankshaft, the driveshaft and the
                axle pinion. Factors determining driveline angularity include ride height, rear spring and engine
                mounts.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050005" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0020270.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Driveline Angle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Bottom of the frame (0 degree reference)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Engine crankshaft centerline</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Engine angle (to frame reference)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Driveshaft centerline</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Driveshaft angle (to frame reference)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Rear axle pinion centerline</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Axle pinion angle (to frame reference)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Calculate the driveline operating angles as follows.</para>
            <para>1. Preliminary setup procedures.</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect the U-joints for correct operation.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface such as a drive-on hoist, or back onto a front end
                        alignment rack.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the curb position ride height is within specifications with the vehicle unloaded, and
                        all of the tires inflated to their normal operating pressures.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Rotate the transmission output yoke until vertical. This will simplify taking measurements.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Calibrate the special tool by placing tool on clean, flat level section of the frame rail and
                        press the ALT-ZERO button.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>2. Using the special tool, measure the slope of the components. Record the measurements and the
                direction of the component's slope.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050006" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0020271.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f050007" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0020272.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Example for Calculating U-Joint Operating Angles</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Output yoke slope</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Driveshaft slope</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">The driveshaft slope minus the output yoke slope equals the
                        transmission/driveshaft operating angle
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Pinion flange slope</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">The driveshaft slope minus the pinion flange slope equals the
                        driveshaft/axle operating angle
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>3. Calculate the difference in the slope of the components to determine the U-joint operating angle.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When 2 connected components slope in the same direction, subtract the smaller number from the
                        larger to find the U-joint operating angle. When 2 connected components slope in the opposite
                        direction, add the measurements to find the U-joint operating angle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The U-joint operating angle is the angle formed by 2 yokes connected by a cross and bearing
                        kit. Ideally, the operating angles on each end of the driveshaft must:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>be equal or within one degree of each other.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>have a 3 degree maximum operating angle.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>have at least 1/2 of one degree continuous operating angle.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the tires and driveline angle are not the cause, carry out the NVH tests to determine whether the
                concern is caused by a condition in the axle. For additional information, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000409.xml" xrefid="x1000409">Noise, Vibration and Harshness</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Drive Pinion Stem and Pinion Flange</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Check the pinion flange runout when all other checks have failed to show the cause of vibration.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Coupling Shaft/Center Bearing Alignment</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Vehicle noise and vibration can be caused by a dislodged or failed driveshaft center bearing support
                rubber insulator, a contaminated driveshaft center bearing support or excessive compression of the
                rubber insulator. For additional information, refer to Driveshaft in S06002.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Bearing Shimming</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Drive-away shudder is the predominant symptom associated with driveline angles condition on vehicles
                with 2-piece driveshafts. Drive-away shudder can usually be corrected by shimming down the driveshaft
                center bearing bracket. For additional information, refer to Driveshaft in S06002.
            </para>
            <para>If the drive-away shudder cannot be corrected by shimming down the driveshaft center bearing bracket,
                check the driveline angles as described in this section.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Axle Noise</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before disassembling the axle to diagnose and correct gear noise, eliminate the tires,
                        exhaust, trim items, roof racks, axle shafts and wheel bearings as possible causes. Follow the
                        diagnostic procedures in
                        <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000409.xml" xrefid="x1000409">Noise, Vibration and Harshness</hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The noises described as follows usually have specific causes that can be diagnosed by observation as
                the unit is disassembled. The initial clues are the type of noise heard during the road test.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Gear Howl and Whine</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Howling or whining of the differential ring gear and pinion is due to an incorrect gear pattern, gear
                damage or incorrect bearing preload.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Bearing Whine</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Bearing whine is a high-pitched sound similar to a whistle. It is usually caused by worn/damaged
                pinion bearings, which are operating at driveshaft speed. Bearing noise occurs at all driving speeds.
                This distinguishes it from gear whine, which usually comes and goes as speed changes.
            </para>
            <para>As noted, pinion bearings make a high-pitched, whistling noise, usually at all speeds. If, however,
                there is only 1 pinion bearing that is worn/damaged, the noise may vary in different driving phases. Do
                not install new pinion bearings unless bearings are scored or damaged or there is a specific pinion
                bearing noise. A worn/damaged bearing will normally be obvious at disassembly. Examine the large end of
                the rollers for wear. If the pinion bearings original blend radius has worn to a sharp edge, install a
                new pinion bearing.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A low-pitched rumble normally associated with a worn/damaged wheel bearing can be caused by
                        the exterior luggage rack or tires.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>A wheel bearing noise can be mistaken for a pinion bearing noise. Check the wheel bearing for a
                spalled cup and spalled/damaged rollers. Install a new wheel bearing and cup if any of these concerns
                are detected.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050008" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figDE1/DE1352A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Chuckle</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Chuckle that occurs on the coast driving phase is usually caused by excessive clearance between the
                differential gear hub and the differential case bore.
            </para>
            <para>Damage to a gear tooth on the coast side can cause a noise identical to a chuckle. A very small tooth
                nick or ridge on the edge of a tooth can cause the noise.
            </para>
            <para>Clean the gear tooth nick or ridge with a small grinding wheel. If the damaged area is larger than 3.2
                mm (1/8 inch), install a new gearset.To check the differential ring gear and pinion, remove as much
                lubricant as possible from the gears with clean solvent. Wipe the gears dry or blow them dry with
                compressed air. Look for scored or damaged teeth. Also look for cracks or other damage.
            </para>
            <para>If either gear is scored or damaged badly, install a new differential ring gear and pinion.</para>
            <figure id="f050009" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE1/GE1438A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>If metal has broken loose, the differential housing must be cleaned to remove particles that will
                cause damage. At this time, any other damaged components in the differential housing must also be
                discarded and new components installed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Knock</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Knock, which can occur on all driving phases, has several causes including damaged teeth or gearset.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050010" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0793A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>A gear tooth damaged on the drive side is a common cause of the knock. This can usually be corrected
                by grinding the damaged area.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050011" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0792A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Clunk</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Clunk is a metallic noise heard when the automatic transmission is engaged in REVERSE or DRIVE. The
                noise may also occur when throttle is applied or released. It is caused by backlash somewhere in the
                driveline or loose suspension components; it is felt or heard in the axle. For additional information,
                refer to Total Backlash Check in this section.
            </para>
            <para>Additionally, clunk may be heard upon initial drive-away. This occurs as engine torque shifts vehicle
                weight, forcing changes in driveline angles, preventing the driveshaft slip-yoke from sliding on the
                output shaft. To correct this condition, lubricate the slip-yoke splines. For additional information,
                refer to Driveshaft in S06002.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Bearing Rumble</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Bearing rumble sounds like marbles being tumbled. This condition is usually caused by worn/damaged
                wheel bearing. The lower pitch is because the wheel bearing turns at only about one-third of the
                driveshaft speed. Wheel bearing noise also may be high-pitched, similar to gear noise, but will be
                evident in all 4 driving modes.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Total Backlash Check</emph>
            </para>
            <para>1. Raise and support the vehicle. For additional information, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s10019_X1000216.xml" xrefid="x1000216">Jacking and Lifting</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>2. Remove the driveshaft. For additional information, refer to Driveshaft in S06002.</para>
            <para>3. Install the special tool.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Clamp a rigid bar or pipe to the tool. Clamp the other end of the bar or pipe to the frame or
                        a body member in order to prevent movement of the pinion flange.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f050012" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/n0023498.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>4. Lower the vehicle so that one rear wheel is resting on a wheel chock to prevent it from turning.
                The other rear wheel will be used to measure total axle backlash.
            </para>
            <para>5. Rotate the free wheel slowly, by hand, until the feeling of driving the axle is encountered. Place
                a mark on the side of the tire, 305 mm (12 inches) from the center of the wheel, with a crayon or chalk.
            </para>
            <para>6. While holding the crayon or chalk against the tire, rotate the wheel slowly in the opposite
                direction until the feeling of driving the axle is encountered again.
            </para>
            <para>7. Measure the length of the crayon or chalk mark on the tire.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the length of the mark is 25.4 mm (1 inch) or less, the axle backlash is within allowable
                        limits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the chalk mark is greater than 25.4 mm (1 inch), check for these conditions:</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Elongation of the differential pinion shaft and holes in the differential case.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Missing differential pinion thrust washer or differential side gear thrust washer.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Galling of the differential pinion shaft and bore.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Excessive ring gear and pinion backlash. Follow the procedure for the type of axle to
                                check backlash.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Symptom Chart</title>
            <table id="t050003" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.07*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Possible Sources</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Action</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Lubricant leaking from the pinion seal, axle shaft oil seals</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Vent</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Damage in the seal contact area.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CLEAN the differential housing vent and the vent hose.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL a new seal and mating surface if damage is found.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Differential side gears/pinion gears are scored</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Insufficient lubrication.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Incorrect or contaminated lubricant type.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL new gears. REFER to Rear Drive Axle/ Differential in S14020. FILL
                                            the axle to specification.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL new gears. REFER to Rear Drive Axle/ Differential in S14020. CLEAN
                                            and REFILL the axle to specification.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Axle overheating</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Lubricant level too low.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Incorrect or contaminated lubricant type.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Bearing preloads too high.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Excessive gear wear.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Incorrect ring gear backlash.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the lubricant level. FILL the axle to specification.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the axle for damage. REPAIR as necessary. CLEAN and REFILL the
                                            axle to specification.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>CHECK the ring and pinion for damage. INSPECT the ring and pinion wear
                                            pattern. ADJUST the preload as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT all the axle gears for wear or damage. INSTALL new components as
                                            necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the ring gear for scoring. INSPECT the ring and pinion wear
                                            pattern. ADJUST the ring gear backlash as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Broken gear teeth on the ring gear or pinion</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Overloading the vehicle.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>INSTALL a new ring and pinion. REFER to Rear Drive Axle/ Differential in S14020.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Axle shaft broken</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Overload the vehicle.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Misaligned axle shaft tube.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSTALL a new axle shaft. REFER to Wheel Hubs and Bearings in S14020.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>INSPECT the axle for damage. CHECK axle shaft tube alignment. INSTALL a
                                            new axle shaft. REFER to Wheel Hubs and Bearings in S14020.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Tests - Driveline Vibration</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An analysis of driveline vibration can also be conducted using the Vibration Analyzer and
                        following the manufacturer's directions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Driveline vibration exhibits a higher frequency and lower amplitude than does high-speed shake.
                Driveline vibration is directly related to the speed of the vehicle and is usually noticed at various
                speed ranges. Driveline vibration can be perceived as a tremor in the floor pan or is heard as a rumble,
                hum or boom. Driveline vibration can exist in all drive modes, but may exhibit different symptoms
                depending upon whether the vehicle is accelerating, decelerating, floating or coasting. Check the
                driveline angles if the vibration is particularly noticeable during acceleration or deceleration,
                especially at lower speeds. Driveline vibration can be duplicated by supporting the axle upon a hoist or
                upon jack stands, though the brakes may need to be applied lightly in order to simulate road resistance.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the vehicle promptly after road testing. Use twin-post hoist or jack stands to
                    prevent tire flat-spotting. Engage the drivetrain and accelerate to the observed road test speed to
                    verify the presence of the vibration. If the vibration is not evident, check the non-driving wheels
                    with a wheel balancer to rule out imbalance as a possible cause. If necessary, balance the
                    non-driving wheels and repeat the road test. If the vibration is still evident, proceed to Step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the relative position of the drive wheels to the wheel bolts. Remove the wheels.
                    Install all the wheel nuts in the reversed position (wheel nuts can be installed in their normal
                    orientation on axles with dual rear wheels) and repeat the road speed acceleration. If the vibration
                    is gone, refer to the tire and wheel runout procedure in Wheels and Tires in S17002. If the
                    vibration persists, proceed to Step 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the driveshaft(s) (for signs of physical damage, missing balance weight,
                    undercoating, incorrect seating, wear and binding universal joints). Clean the driveshaft and
                    install new universal joints or a driveshaft if damaged. Check the index marks (paint spots) on the
                    rear of the driveshaft and pinion flange. If these marks are more than one quarter turn apart,
                    disconnect the driveshaft and reindex it to align the marks as closely as possible. After any
                    corrections are made, recheck for vibration at the road test speed. If the vibration is gone,
                    reinstall the wheels and road test. If the vibration persists, proceed to Step 4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the vehicle on a hoist and remove the wheels. Rotate the driveshaft by turning the
                    axle and measure the runout at the front, the center and the rear of the driveshaft with the
                    indicator. If the runout exceeds 0.50 mm (0.020 in) at the front or center, install a new
                    driveshaft. If the front and center are within this limit, but the rear runout is not, mark the rear
                    runout high point and proceed to Step 5. If the runout is within the limits at all points, proceed
                    to Step 7.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050013" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0795A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Check the U-joints during re-indexing. If a U-joint feels stiff or gritty, install new
                        U-joints.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Scribe alignment marks on the driveshaft and the pinion flange. Disconnect the
                    driveshaft, rotate it one-half turn and reconnect it. Circular pinion flanges can be turned in
                    one-quarter increments to fine tune the runout condition; half-round pinion flanges are limited to 2
                    positions. Check the runout at the rear of the driveshaft. If it is still over 0.50 mm (0.020 inch),
                    mark the high point and proceed to Step 6. If the runout is no longer excessive, check for vibration
                    at the road test speed. If vibration is still present, reindex the driveshaft slip-yoke on the
                    transmission output shaft one-half turn and road test the vehicle. If the vibration persists,
                    proceed to Step 7.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Excessive driveshaft runout may originate in the driveshaft itself or in the pinion
                    flange. To determine which, compare the 2 high points marked in Steps 4 and 5. If the marks are
                    close together, within about 25 mm (1 inch), install a new driveshaft and road test the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050014" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0796A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>If the marks are on opposite sides of the driveshaft, the pinion flange is responsible for the
                vibration.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0797A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>When installing a new pinion flange, the driveshaft runout must not exceed 0.50 mm (0.020 inch). When
                runout is within limits, recheck for vibration at road speed. If vibration persists, balance the
                driveshaft.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To balance the driveshaft, install 1 or 2 hose clamps on the driveshaft, near the rear.
                    Position of the hose clamp head(s) can be determined by trial-and-error.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark the rear of the driveshaft into 4 approximately equal sectors and number the marks
                    1 through 4. Install a hose clamp on the driveshaft with its head at position No. 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0798A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Check for vibration at road speed. Recheck with the clamp at each of the other positions to find the
                position that shows minimum vibration. If 2 adjacent positions show equal improvement, position the
                clamp head between them.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vibration persists, add a second clamp at the same position and recheck for
                    vibration.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f050017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0799A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>If no improvement is noted, rotate the clamps in opposite directions, equal distances from the best
                position determined in Step 8. Separate the clamp heads about 13 mm (1/2 inch) and recheck for vibration
                at the road speed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f050018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0800A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Repeat the process with increasing separation until the best combination is found or the vibration is
                reduced to an acceptable level.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the wheels and road test (vibration noticeable on the hoist may not be evident
                    during the road test). If the vibration is still not acceptable, install a new axle driveline
                    vibration damper first, if so equipped. If the vibration is still not acceptable, refer to Rear
                    Drive Axle/ Differential in S14020. For differential case and ring gear runout checks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Tests - Tooth Contact Pattern Check - Gearset</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To check the gear tooth contact, paint the gear teeth with the special marking compound.
                    A mixture that is too wet will run and smear; a mixture that is too dry cannot be pressed out from
                    between the teeth.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a box wrench on the ring gear bolts as a lever to rotate the differential ring gear
                    several complete revolutions in both directions or until a clear tooth contact pattern is obtained.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Certain types of gear tooth contact patterns on the differential ring gear indicate
                    incorrect adjustment. Incorrect adjustment can be corrected by readjusting the differential ring
                    gear or the pinion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Contact Pattern Location</emph>
            </para>
            <para>In general, desirable ring gear tooth patterns must have the following characteristics:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Drive pattern on the drive side differential ring gear well centered on the tooth</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coast pattern on the coast side differential ring gear well centered on the tooth</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clearance between the pattern and the top of the tooth</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No hard lines where the pressure is high</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Acceptable differential ring gear tooth patterns for all axles.</para>
            <figure id="f050019" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0807A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Correct backlash with a thinner pinion position shim as necessary.</para>
            <figure id="f050020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0808A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Correct backlash with a thicker pinion position shim as necessary.</para>
            <figure id="f050021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0809A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Correct pinion position shim that requires a decrease in backlash.</para>
            <figure id="f050022" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0810A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>Correct pinion position shim that requires an increase in backlash.</para>
            <figure id="f050023" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figGE0/GE0811A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019_X2050062.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
