<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LUBRICATION, SEALERS AND MAINTENANCE INTERVALS - ENGINE OIL
        SPECIFICATIONS - OIL QUALITY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OIL QUALITY</title>
        <para>An oil container symbol system has been developed to help you choose the proper oil. The top portion of
            the symbol shows the oil quality, such as API Service CG-4/SH (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1000101">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The symbol may show additional categories, such as API Service
            SG/CE, SF/CE. The center portion will probably show viscosity grade, such as SAE 15W-40 (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1000101">Figure 1</hotlnk>). If the lower portion shows "Energy Conserving II," be sure the
            upper and center portions show the correct API service category and proper SAE viscosity grade recommended
            for your engine.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1000101" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Oil Identification Symbol</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Oil quality is described by API (American Petroleum Institute) engine service categories. API categories
            are defined by oil performance (deposits and wear) measured in standard engine tests. API "S" category SH
            describes oils for spark ignition (gasoline) engines, while "C" categories (CF-4, CG-4) describe oils for
            diesel engines. Oils with both "S" and "C" categories (such as CG-4/SH) are suitable for both spark ignition
            and diesel engines. Sometimes, the "S" and "C" categories are reversed (such as SH/CG-4).
        </para>
        <para>The oil quality recommended depends on engine type and engine design. There are many supplementary fuel
            and oil additives for sale. If you follow the lubricant and oil change interval recommendations, your engine
            will not require these additives.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The use of inappropriate API category engine oils will severely compromise engine life. It is very
                    important to use an oil with the recommended or the acceptable alternate API category shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1000102">Figure 2</hotlnk>when selecting engine oil.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1000102" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. API Categories</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do NOT use oils specifically marketed by suppliers for stationary, marine, or railroad diesel
                    engines, or for stationary natural gas engines, even though they are marked API category CD or CE.
                    Such oils can cause excessive valve train wear and combustion chamber deposits. (These oils are sold
                    only in drums or bulk.)
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10006_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10006_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
