<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>3200 Integrated Mobility Option Service Manual - Hadley Smart Air Management System - Description</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Description</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Scope</title>
            <para>The Hadley system is designed to maintain a predetermined vehicle ride height automatically and
                provides a means to temporarily lower or raise the ride height, when necessary. The system provides for
                side to side height control on respective axles containing two height sensors, as well as front to back
                control. A visual indication is also provided to determine mode selection and system malfunction
                detection.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Definition</title>
            <para>The Smart Air Management System (SAMS) contains three vehicle height sensors, a pneumatic manifold
                assembly, an electronic control unit (ECU), the necessary wire harnessing, an LED, two user supplied
                switches, and the necessary vehicle interface hardware to provide the defined modes of operation. One
                switch will serve as control power ON/OFF and the second for temporarily raising the vehicle to overcome
                an obstacle (lift-off). The location and mounting of these switches will be at the discretion of the
                integrator. The angle sensors will be mounted on the vehicle frame in a 3-point configuration: rear (2);
                front (1). The wire harnessing will provide the necessary connections for providing DC electrical
                control power and ground to the SAMS system (from a suitable vehicle power source), provide the
                necessary height sensor connectors, provide the pneumatic manifold wiring interface, provide the
                necessary color coded wires for vehicle hardware integration, and provide the electrical connections for
                the LED (light emitting diode). The LED will serve as a visual indication of the selected mode status
                and provide error code display. Functionally, the system will provide the following modes of operation;
                i.e., normal, front kneel, rear kneel, and lift-off. This information is further defined in the
                following sections.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Normal Mode</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">In order to enter this mode of operation, the Power ON/OFF switch needs to be "ON"
                    while operating the vehicle.
                </emph>
                This mode of operation requires no further interaction by the vehicle operator. The ECU monitors the
                feedback signals from the height sensors during normal vehicle operation. Should any of the three
                signals dictate that the vehicle is above or below the programmed ride height; the ECU will energize the
                necessary manifold valve coils to either fill or exhaust the respective air bag(s) to bring the vehicle
                back to the correct vehicle height. The system will stay in this mode of operation unless conditions are
                satisfied to enter the other modes of operation, as defined in the following three sections.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When towing, jacking, or raising the vehicle for service, the Power ON/OFF switch must be
                        turned to the "OFF" position. This will prevent the SAMS system from operating and eliminating
                        the potential for unexpected suspension movement.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Kneel Mode</title>
            <para>This mode of operation is automatically performed by the system ECU when the proper conditions have
                been satisfied. The ECU will automatically lower the front of the vehicle when the "passenger loading
                door" is opened, the power ON/OFF switch is turned "ON", and the engine running. The ECU will lower the
                front of the vehicle in order to reduce the passenger step height for entering the vehicle and the LED
                will blink slowly as a visual indication the front kneel mode is active.
            </para>
            <para>The front of the vehicle will lower until a preset pressure is reached. This pressure does not
                completely exhaust the air in the front airbags, which allows the system to more quickly raise the front
                of the vehicle, when returning to the normal mode of operation. The system automatically returns to the
                normal vehicle ride height when the "passenger loading door" is closed.
            </para>
            <para>This mode of operation is automatically enabled by an active low signal (ground) being detected by the
                SAMS ECU on the system's control wiring harness green wire (door open) and does not require any further
                interaction from the vehicle operator. This mode is automatically cancelled by the ECU and returns the
                system to normal ride height when an active low signal is detected on the system's control wiring
                harness violet wire (door close) and does not require any further interaction from the vehicle operator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Kneel Mode</title>
            <para>This mode of operation is automatically performed by the system ECU when the proper conditions have
                been satisfied. The ECU will automatically lower the rear of the vehicle when the "passenger loading
                door" is open (front kneel mode is active), the power ON/OFF switch is turned "ON", the "ramp extend"
                switch is activated, and the engine running. The ECU will then lower the rear of the vehicle to allow
                wheel chair access to the vehicle and the LED will blink slowly as a visual indication the rear kneel
                mode is active.
            </para>
            <para>This mode of operation will lower the rear of the vehicle to a pre-determined position. This position
                does not completely exhaust the air in the rear airbags, which allows the system to more quickly raise
                the rear of the vehicle, when the "ramp retract" switch is activated. The system ECU automatically
                returns the rear of the vehicle to the normal vehicle ride height as the operator is retracting the
                vehicle ramp.
            </para>
            <para>This mode of operation is automatically enabled by an active low (ground) signal being detected by the
                SAMS ECU on the system's control wiring harness
                <emph type="bold">green wire</emph>
                (door open) and
                <emph type="bold">yellow wire</emph>
                (ramp extend) and does not require any further interaction from the vehicle operator. This mode is
                automatically cancelled by the ECU and returns the rear of the vehicle to the normal ride height when an
                active low signal is detected on the system's control wiring harness
                <emph type="bold">blue wire</emph>
                (ramp retract) and does not require any further interaction from the vehicle operator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lift-Off Mode</title>
            <para>This mode of operation is used for "temporarily" increasing the normal vehicle ride height. The mode
                of operation is not automatic and must be selected by the operator of the vehicle. This mode of
                operation is manually activated by actuating the user supplied "lift-off" switch, with the power ON/OFF
                switch turned "ON," and the engine running. Once activated, the LED will blink slowly as a visual
                indication the lift-off mode is active.
            </para>
            <para>The vehicle by design has a low profile for easier accessibility. By activating this mode of
                operation, the vehicle ride height will be increased "temporarily" to provide additional ground
                clearance. This will increase the normal ride height by approximately 1.5 to 2 inches and the system
                will stay at this position for approximately 30 seconds. This time should allow the vehicle operator
                sufficient time to clear the desired obstacle. After this time period has elapsed, the system ECU will
                automatically return the vehicle to the normal ride height. If additional time is required, the operator
                will need to re-initiate the mode. Additionally, the vehicle operator could hold the "lift-off" mode
                switch in the activated position. This would extend the temporary raised position time, thereby keeping
                the vehicle raised to the preset ground clearance height for additional time intervals.
            </para>
            <para>Activating the "lift-off" switch applies an active low (ground) signal to the gray wire of the system
                control wiring harness. This active low signal will cause the ECU to override the normal ride height and
                <emph type="bold">temporarily</emph>
                raises the vehicle the predefined distance. The system will remain in this mode of operation for the
                preset time interval and then will automatically return the vehicle to the normal ride height and does
                not require any further interaction from the vehicle operator.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In order to assist with loading the vehicle for transport shipping, the "lift-off" mode may be
                        utilized. After activating the mode and loading the vehicle onto the transport, immediately turn
                        the ON/OFF switch to the "OFF" position. This will allow the system to remain in this mode while
                        transporting the vehicle to provide additional clearance beneath the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The below schematic illustrates the control harness wiring as defined in the previous
                        associated sections for mode operation. This harness is necessary to integrate the vehicle
                        hardware signals with the SAMS ECU.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1001825" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG10/G1001825.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Visual Indicator (LED)</title>
            <para>As explained in earlier sections of this document, if either the front kneel mode, rear kneel mode, or
                lift-off mode of operation is selected, the system supplied LED will flash. This section further
                clarifies the visual rate of the blink and the associated system mode of operation or interpreted
                function.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Short blink - long pause: either the front kneel mode, lower kneel mode, or lift-off mode has
                        been selected
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No blink (LED off): the vehicle is operating at the normal mode and is at normal ride height
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blinking not defined above: the ECU has detected a problem and is blinking an error code
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following section provides more information regarding the error codes.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Error Codes</title>
            <para>The ECU has the ability to monitor the SAMS system and detect electrical problems. Should the ECU
                detect a problem, a visual indication will be given by flashing the system supplied LED in such a manner
                as to represent a two-digit code. The first number of the two-digit code can be identified by counting
                the first series of flashes. It will be followed by a short pause, and then provide a second series of
                flashes to represent the second number of the two-digit code. For example one flash, followed by a short
                pause, and then three additional flashes would illustrate a code 13.
            </para>
            <para>In the event of more than one detected problem, the ECU will cycle through this process and flash an
                individual error code for each identified problem. The ECU will continue to flash the error code(s)
                until the problem(s) have been corrected. Once the problem(s) are corrected, the ECU will proceed to
                turn off the LED. A list of potential error codes and their probable cause are as follows:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>11 (eleven) - Rear Driver Height Sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12 (twelve) - Rear Curb Height Sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>13 (thirteen) - Front Axle Height Sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>14 (fourteen) - System Pressure Error</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>21 (twenty-one) - Door Open Switch and Door Close Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>22 (twenty-two) - Ramp Extend Switch and Ramp Retract Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>23 (twenty-three) - Lift Mode Switch and Ramp Extend Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>24 (twenty-four) - Lift Mode Switch and Door Open Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>31 (thirty-one) - Door Closed Switch and Ramp Extend Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>32 (thirty-two) - Door Open Switch and Ramp Retract Switch are Both Activated</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Each time the engine is started, the LED will be illuminated for approximately 15 seconds.
                        During this time interval, the ECU will gather information from the system sensors. After the
                        time interval has elapsed the ECU will turn off the LED. This is a normal "power-up" function
                        and should not be confused with a system problem.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
