<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR 4100, 4200, 4300, 4400 MODELS - 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400 Model INSPECTION INSTRUCTIONS (REPORT S00021) - UNDER HOOD INSPECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>UNDER HOOD INSPECTION</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Verify and Inspect...</emph>
        </para>
        <para>13.
            <emph type="italic">Hood operation, opens and closes without interference</emph>.
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Insure hood opens and closes without binding or interfering with other components.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Hood should be evenly aligned with the cowl and bumper.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Hood must be firmly attached.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>14.
            <emph type="italic">Under hood inspect Air/ Brake/ Coolant/ Fuel/ Refrigerant/ Steering lines, hoses, and
                piping clearance from moving parts, sharp edges, heat sources, and chafing.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Air inlet and charge air cooler piping and hoses.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Brake lines - air and hydraulic.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine coolant pipes and hoses.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine fuel lines and piping.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Air conditioning refrigerant hoses and piping.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Power steering hoses and piping related to steering and brake system.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All clamps and clipping are secure and properly positioned.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>15.
            <emph type="italic">Wiring harnesses are clear of moving parts, sharp edges, and heat sources. Relocate as
                needed.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Inspect wiring and harnesses, apply tie straps where required.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Insure clipping is secure and properly positioned.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>16.
            <emph type="italic">Cotter keys/lock tabs are installed and properly spread on all steering/brake components
                and clutch linkage.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Inspect for missing, damaged, or improperly installed cotter keys/pins.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>17.
            <emph type="italic">Steering shaft pinch bolt head twisted off at both ends of I-shaft.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Examine the steering intermediate shaft and ensure that the pinch bolt heads have been twisted off
                    at both ends of the shaft.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>18.
            <emph type="italic">Proper engine oil level.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check that the engine oil level is within the operating range on the oil level gauge. If the oil
                    level is below the range, add oil to bring near the full mark. DO NOT OVERFILL.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>19.
            <emph type="italic">Automatic transmission fluid level, if so equipped.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>With the park brake applied and the transmission in neutral, follow the fluid level checking
                    procedures provided by the transmission manufacturer. Add fluid if required.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>20.
            <emph type="italic">Proper coolant level and freeze protection.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Check that the coolant level is in the operating range within the coolant reservoir. Add proper
                    coolant if required. Refer to Owners Manual for information on coolant specifications.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Measure freeze protection using a refractometer for glycol concentration. It should be -40&#176;F
                    &#177; 4.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>21.
            <emph type="italic">Steering reservoir fluid level</emph>.
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Visually inspect the fluid level by removing the reservoir cap and noting where the fluid is on
                    the level gauge. Fill if necessary. Refer to the Owners Manual for fluid specifications.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>22.
            <emph type="italic">Brake master cylinder fluid level, if equipped.</emph>
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Remove each cap and inspect that the fluid is to the bottom edge of the ring on each reservoir
                    fill port. DO NOT FILL TO THE TOP OF THE RESERVOIR. Refer to the Owners manual for specifications.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009_X1000703.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10009.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
