<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S10013" division="truck" formnum="CTS-1157" date="06/26/2003">
        <title>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <para>The purpose of this manual is to outline the proper procedures that should be followed for proper
                claims processing for damages and/or shortages on vehicles delivered by Active Transportation
                Corporation, Dallas &#38; Mavis, Kenosha Auto Transport, Automotive Carrier Services, Provincial
                American Truck Transporters of Chatham, and Provincial American Truck Transports, Inc. It should be
                noted that all claims involving damages and/or shortages with these transportation companies should be
                filed directly with the International Truck and Engine Corporation Warranty Claims Center in
                Warrenville, Illinois via DDEW. Claims involving vehicles delivered by transportation companies other
                than the ones listed above must be filed directly with that carrier. Claims involving a total loss of a
                vehicle, accidents, or fuel conditions must be filed directly with the carrier.
            </para>
            <para>New vehicles are exposed to certain transportation hazards, which often lead to damage of varying
                degrees. A common carrier is liable for any damage or shortage to material in its possession with
                certain exceptions to include acts of God or acts of the shipper. How the consignees (dealers, or their
                agent in body companies and fleets) react to this loss or damage determines whether or not they will be
                credited for their claims. Damages resulting from acts of God; i.e., instances where a hailstorm has
                caused damage to a vehicle, should not be filed as a warranty claim through International or for the
                carrier. These types of occurrences should be filed directly with the insurance company of the dealer or
                receiving location.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
