<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - New Truck Receiving and Damage Claim Processing - NEW TRUCK RECEIVING AND
        DAMAGE CLAIM PROCESSING - AFTER-HOURS DELIVERY
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>AFTER-HOURS DELIVERY</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Carriers are not to "drop off" vehicles after Receiving Location business hours unless special
                    arrangements have been made:
                    <emph type="italic">NO EXCEPTIONS.</emph>
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Should special arrangements be made for after-hours delivery, the following procedures should be
            observed:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>An employee must be on the premises to receive and sign the carrier's receipt for delivery.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>This receipt should be signed with time and date specified, along with the notation, "
                    <emph type="bold">Received After Hours, Subject to Inspection</emph>", "
                    <emph type="bold">STI</emph>" for short.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>One copy of the delivery receipt should be held by the receiving location.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A thorough inspection must be made of the vehicle(s) on the first working day following the
                    after-hours delivery.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A copy of the delivery receipt containing all exceptions is to be sent by Certified Mail or faxed
                    (262-605-6073) to the carrier within
                    <emph type="bold">48 hours</emph>
                    of the after-hours delivery.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Any after-hours deliveries to body companies and fleet locations that are noted as "
                    <emph type="bold">STI</emph>" should be transmitted to the ordering dealer immediately, to allow
                    them time to respond to the carrier within the 48-hour time frame, weekends and holidays excluded.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Notating a carrier's delivery receipt "STI"
                    <emph type="bold">DOES NOT INSURE</emph>
                    the payment of the claim. The claim may still be denied by the carrier or the International Warranty
                    Center pending further review.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Torque all axle shaft nuts and or propshaft u-joint retaining hardware to specification per
                    Preparation and Delivery (PDI) guidelines before moving the vehicle.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If concealed damage is found, follow the instructions below for the proper handling for
                    notification of concealed damage.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>If transportation-related exceptions are detected that are not noted on the Carrier's Delivery Receipt,
            within 48 hours of an after-hours delivery, weekends and holidays excluded, call ATC Leasing toll-free
            (U.S.: 1-800/558-3271; Canada: 262/658-4831).
        </para>
        <para>MAIL ATC LEASING A COPY OF THE DELIVERY RECEIPT with all Exceptions reported, along with photos of the
            damage. Send by certified mail to:
        </para>
        <verbatim>
            <line>ATC Leasing</line>
            <line>625 55th Street</line>
            <line>Kenosha, WI 53140</line>
            <line>ATTN: Claims Department</line>
        </verbatim>
        <para>
            <emph type="boldundersc">OR</emph>
        </para>
        <para>FAX ATC LEASING A COPY OF THE DELIVERY RECEIPT: Fax 262/605-6073.</para>
        <para>BODY COMPANY OR FLEET LOCATION: If transportation-related exceptions are detected that are not noted on
            the Carrier's Delivery Receipt, transmit the Delivery Receipt for any after-hour deliveries to the ordering
            Dealer AS SOON AS POSSIBLE, to allow time for them to respond to ATC Leasing within the 48-hour time limit.
            Be sure to enter "RECEIVED AFTER HOURS, SUBJECT TO INSPECTION" on the Receipt.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Never enter "RECEIVED AFTER HOURS, SUBJECT TO INSPECTION" on Delivery Receipts for vehicles
                    delivered during normal working hours.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
