<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - LUBRICATION AND SEALERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="S10001S" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5065S" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>LUBRICATION AND SEALERS</title>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>New vehicles are lubricated before they are delivered. After the vehicle is placed in
                        operation, regular lubrication intervals, based on the type of service and road conditions,
                        should be established.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Choosing an engine oil of correct quality and proper viscosity, and following recommended oil
                        change intervals are essential to Low Cost of Ownership. Using the recommended oil change
                        intervals will result in good engine starting, performance, and long term durability.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The interval between lubrication periods, oil changes, etc. depends entirely upon operating
                        conditions. The loads carried, speed, road and weather conditions all contribute to the
                        frequency of lubrication periods.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>In some types of operation, and where operating conditions are extremely severe (such as in
                        deep water, mud or unusually dusty conditions), the vehicle may require lubrication after every
                        twenty-four (24) hours of operation.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Only lubricants of superior quality, such as Fleetrite&#174; lubricants, should be used. The
                        use of inferior products will reduce the service life of the vehicle or result in failure of its
                        components.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>International recommends the use of Fleetrite&#174; lubricants.</para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The lubrication specifications refer only to the viscosity (SAE) and type to be applied. The
                        viscosity numbers have been adopted by the Society of Automotive Engineers to classify
                        lubricants according to viscosity and do not cover any other properties.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Unless otherwise specified, never add lubricant unless it is the same grade as that which is
                        already in use. If the grade is unknown or not available, drain, flush and refill with new
                        lubricant.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The lubrication intervals specified should be performed at whatever interval occurs first,
                        whether it is months, miles (kilometers) or hours.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10001s_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10001s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
