<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>PRE-DELIVERY/QUALITY INSPECTION INSTRUCTION MANUAL FOR FBC/BUS/STRIPPED CHASSIS - INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>INSPECTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INITIAL INSPECTION</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Complete this initial inspection before driving the vehicle to the PDI area.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Verify or Inspect:</emph>
            </para>
            <para>1.
                <emph type="italic">Air/hydraulic brake pressure indicator lights and/or warning buzzer operation.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hydraulic Brake Pressure Warning Light and Buzzer</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>With the key switch in OFF position; the light must be off.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn the key switch to ON position (engine off); the light and buzzer should be on until the
                        engine is started.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start the engine and let it run; the light and buzzer must be off.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Air Brake Low Air Pressure Warning Light and Buzzer. Turn key switch to ON.</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>The light and buzzer must be on when the brake system air pressure is below 70 &#177; 6 psi
                        (483 &#177; 41 kPa).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The light and buzzer must go off once the air pressure in both systems reaches 70 &#177; 6 psi
                        (483 &#177; 41 kPa).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>2.
                <emph type="italic">Hydraulic brake back-up motor and indicator light operation.</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>With the key switch in OFF position, the motor will operate when the brake pedal is pressed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn the key switch to ON position (engine off, pedal released); the motor will operate
                        continuously.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start the engine and let it run; the motor must be off.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">3. Park brake light operation.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Hydraulic Brakes Only</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>With the park brake engaged and the key switch in OFF or ACC position, the light must be off.
                        Turn the key switch to ON; the light must go on.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start the engine. The light will remain on if the parking brake is applied (it will illuminate
                        during engine cranking, then go off once engine starts if the parking brake is not applied).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Press the brake pedal and disengage the park brake; the light must go off.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>4.
                <emph type="italic">Operation of instruments and all lights.</emph>
                Refer to the operator's manual for specific operation information.
            </para>
            <para>Turn signal switch and hazard warning flashers.</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Turn signal switch must self-cancel if equipped with self-cancelling switch.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hazard warning flashers must operate with key switch either off or on.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Instrument panel lights, headlights, tail lights, etc., including daytime running lights if
                equipped.
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Headlights must work with key switch either off or on.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>5.
                <emph type="italic">Horn, windshield wiper and washer operation.</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Press down on steering wheel center to verify operation of electric horn.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify operation of the windshield wipers and washers. Refer to the body company operator's
                        manual for specific operation instructions.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>6.
                <emph type="italic">Ignition key operation. Also inspect automatic transmission neutral safety or clutch
                    safety switch operation if so equipped.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Set parking brake and position the automatic transmission selector lever in reverse or a drive
                        position, or manual transmission in neutral without clutch pedal depressed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Attempt to start engine. Engine should not crank.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Position the automatic transmission selector lever in neutral, or depress the clutch pedal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Start engine.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>7.
                <emph type="italic">Clutch pedal free travel. Adjust as required.</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Depress the pedal until resistance is felt. If free play is less than 1/2 inch or greater than
                        1-1/2 inches, adjust.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
