<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Preparation and Delivery - PREPARATION AND DELIVERY - CTS-1100 - New Vehicle
        Pre-Delivery Service
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="3">
        <title>CTS-1100 - New Vehicle Pre-Delivery Service</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>A complete review has been made of the pre-delivery service operations and sequential procedures
                established for the inspection of new vehicles to ensure customers receive vehicles in the best possible
                condition.
            </para>
            <para>Separate procedures have been established and are covered by the forms which are available on the ISIS
                Home Page. PDI locations are to retain copies of Pre-Delivery Inspection forms. Instructions concerning
                record-keeping are on the forms.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pre-Delivery Inspection (PDI) Reimbursement (U.S. Only)</title>
            <figure id="f1000530" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000530a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Delivery Notice and Warranty Application</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>International will reimburse only one Dealer for preparation and delivery service performed on a
                vehicle prior to delivery to a customer. The Delivery Notice and Warranty Application information should
                be entered via your online DTU system. Upon receipt of this info by the International Accounting Center
                (IAC), the Dealer's account will be credited for this expense. Except in unusual circumstances,
                pre-delivery inspections are not to be performed in advance of sale of the vehicle to the ultimate user.
            </para>
            <para>The International Accounting Center will credit the Dealer for preparation and delivery service based
                on the time schedule in effect for the particular model and the Dealer's approved hourly customer labor
                rate.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Non-Reimbursement Addendum</title>
            </para>
            <para>Adjustments which are a part of the PDI (
                <emph type="boldital">not reimbursable as PTD warranty expense</emph>) are as follows:
            </para>
            <randlist type="dash">
                <item>
                    <para>Fluid level adjustments - Labor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Wire harness route and clip - Tie Strapping</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tire inflation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Re-torque operations</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Installation of loose shipped items (except air deflector)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Chassis Lubrication</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Consumables such as windshield washer solvent, diesel fuel, coolant additives, etc. will not be
                reimbursed as warranty expense.
            </para>
            <para>Damage due to shipping should be claimed with the shipping carrier. All other repair operations should
                be claimed to PTD 03 warranty.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Allied Equipment Or Body Manufacturer Chassis</title>
            <para>Allied equipment or body manufacturers extensively modify vehicles sold to them by International; thus
                there is usually a considerable delay in delivering the completed vehicle to the ultimate user. Because
                of this delay, normal pre-delivery inspections and adjustments are not performed until the ultimate user
                purchases the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>School Bus Chassis</title>
            <para>Special service agreements have been negotiated with the Dealers located in the area of the following
                school bus body manufacturers:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>IC Corp</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blue Bird Body Company</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Mid Bus</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Les Enterprises Michel Corbeil, Inc.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Names and addresses of these Dealers may be found in the warranty policy letter.</para>
            <para>It is the responsibility of the Dealer holding the special services contract, along with the Regional
                Service Manager, to establish an effective program which will ensure that every bus is given complete
                and acceptable pre-delivery service prior to its release.
            </para>
            <para>School bus chassis are not to be pre-delivery serviced prior to the installation of a school bus body.
                Any pre-delivery service expense incurred prior to the final body assembly will be the servicing
                location's responsibility.
            </para>
            <para>All complete school bus chassis will be pre-delivery serviced prior to their release from the school
                bus manufacturer by the Dealer holding the special school bus service contract only. This policy applies
                regardless of the method utilized in transporting the completed unit from the body manufacturer to the
                ultimate user.
            </para>
            <para>Upon completion of the pre-delivery inspection, the servicing location will submit a service invoice,
                along with a copy of the completed Pre-Delivery/Quality Inspection Report, to the International
                Accounting Center (IAC) for payment.
            </para>
            <para>Should it be determined that warranty service is required at time of pre-delivery service, a separate
                warranty claim should be prepared and submitted directly to the Warranty Claims Center via Direct Data
                Entry Warranty (DDEW).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>"Will Call"- Truck Sales Process Center (TSPC)</title>
            <para>In the United States and Canada, all Dealer and customer "will call" units that are to be used as a
                power source for transporting vehicles or driven singly will receive pre-delivery service prior to being
                released.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle Identification Label</title>
            <para>The vehicle identification label attached to the left door has been designed to provide a permanent
                record for preparation and delivery of all vehicles.
            </para>
            <para>Dealers are to insert the last five (5) digits of their account code in the space under "PD LOC" on
                the identification label followed by the month, day, and year under the word "DATE," meaning the date
                the Pre-Delivery Inspection (PDI) service was performed.
            </para>
            <para>The most common method for writing on the VIN plate is with ball-point pen, writing directly on the
                plate.
            </para>
            <para>Should it become necessary to replace a vehicle identification plate, it can be obtained by providing
                a copy of the line set ticket, original invoice, or vehicle title to the Administration Manager,
                Springfield TSPC, 5975 Urbana Road - Highway 68N, Springfield, Ohio, 45502-1006. A charge, as specified
                in a current applicable Parts Policy letter, will be assessed to the ordering Dealer's account for each
                new data plate requested.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000531" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000531a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="360px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Vehicle Identification Label</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CTS-1122, Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker</title>
            <para>A Pre-Delivery Identity Sticker, CTS-1122 (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1000532">Figure 18</hotlnk>), has been developed for use as an easy visual
                identification of vehicles which have been serviced.
            </para>
            <para>All servicing locations are instructed to complete the required information on the sticker and place
                it on the inside, lower right-hand corner of the windshield of all pre-delivery serviced vehicles.
            </para>
            <para>The sticker may be utilized as a consistent method of identifying stock units which have been serviced
                for delivery.
            </para>
            <para>Vehicles that are serviced for display or demonstration purposes should also have the sticker affixed
                for easy identification.
            </para>
            <para>Information on the purchase of these forms can be found on the internationaltrucks.com web site.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1000532" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/G1000532.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="424px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Pre-Delivery Service Identity Sticker</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>New Vehicle Processing Documentation</title>
            <para>The Pre-Delivery/Quality Inspection Reports incorporate and replace any previous pre-delivery and
                quality inspection documents and are available on the ISIS Home Page.
            </para>
            <para>Pre-Delivery/Quality Inspection Instruction Manuals explain in detail the proper use of these forms.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Quality Inspection Report</title>
            <para>The Quality Inspection Report is used to indicate product deficiencies that require repair or
                adjustment beyond normal pre-delivery inspection, and functions as an "early warning" to factory and
                engineering managers of product issues.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_S10005_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
