<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>3200 Integrated Mobility Option Service Manual - Hadley Smart Air Management System - Appendix B - SAMS
        Pneumatic Installation Precautions
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Appendix B - SAMS Pneumatic Installation Precautions</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the air supply provides sufficient pressure to allow for proper system operation,
                typically 95 - 130 psi. Pressures excessively above or below this range can affect system performance
                and can result in incorrect ride height.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If an existing air reservoir is to be used for providing the source air supply, be sure to
                tap into the source at some point above the bottom of the tank. Moisture settles to the bottom of the
                tank and the ports in this location are best suited for drain valves.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the source air supply is as clean and dry as possible. The air supply should be
                equipped with an industry standard filtration system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the SAMS system manifold higher than the lowest point in the air system to reduce the
                possibility of catching air system contamination.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mount the SAMS air tank (if applicable) so as not to interfere with the suspension or frame
                movement. The tank should be orientated as such in order to place the drain valve(s) facing toward the
                ground, beneath the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure to use either Teflon tape or a heavy duty thread sealing compound on any field
                installed air fittings prior to installation, (if the fittings are not already provided with sealant on
                the threads). Either sealant type can be purchased from any local hardware store.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the use of Teflon tape or a heavy duty thread sealing compound is required, care should be
                        taken with its application so as not to obstruct the air passage in the fitting or clog the
                        manifold port screens.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The tubing should be installed to adhere to the following routing and connections:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Supply Inlet Port = Supply Line from Vehicle Source</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Rear DVR (Drive) = Rear Driver Air Bag</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Rear Curb = Rear Curb Air Bag</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Manifold Front1 and Front2 = Front Air Bags</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Route the tubing away from engine exhaust manifolds, mufflers, exhaust pipes, catalytic
                converters, and other heat generating components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Keep the tubing away from pinch points and sharp and jagged edges to prevent crushing,
                pinching, or puncturing of the tubing. Tubing that is damaged in this way can reduce air flow and
                results in poor system performance.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow sufficient bend radii, where applicable, to prevent sharp bends and kinks in the
                tubing. The tubing manufacturer recommends a minimum bend radius of 1-1/4" for tubing with an outside
                diameter (O.D.) of 3/8" (0.375").
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If a kink should occur during the installation process, the tubing must be carefully inspected
                        in the area of the kink for possible permanent damage and/or obstruction. The kink can weaken
                        the tensile strength of the tubing and create a weak spot where a leak could develop. Also the
                        tubing must be free of obstructions which can reduce the amount of airflow and affect system
                        performance.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow sufficient slack in the tubing to prevent damage at points of vehicle horizontal
                and/or vertical movement and deflection. This will allow the tubing to move with the vehicle and prevent
                crushing and/or fatiguing of the tubing.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Caution should be taken as not to leave excessive slack which could cause the tubing to become
                        snagged while the vehicle is in motion, especially in off road conditions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the tubing every few inches (typically 6 -12") with nylon straps.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The nylon straps should be snug enough to hold the tubing in the desired position, but not
                over-tightened, which can otherwise distort the tubing and restrict air flow.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To prevent leaks, be sure the tubing end is cut square and the tubing is free from nicks,
                cuts, abrasions, and any contaminates (such as rust-proofing) at least 3 - 4 inches from the squarely
                trimmed end, prior to attaching the tubing to the fittings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A tubing cutter with a sharp blade is recommended to properly cut the tubing end. (A good
                        tubing cutter can be purchased from either MSC Industrial Supply, P/N 79814323, or from Parker
                        Hannifin Corporation). It is not recommended to use any other device for cutting the tubing. If
                        an improper tool is used, uneven cuts, jagged edges, or distortion of the tubing can result,
                        thereby affecting the ability for the tubing to fully engage the fitting. The tubing must fully
                        engage the fitting and be free from damage for air leak prevention.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If circumstances arise which requires disconnecting the tubing from a PTC fitting, careful
                        examination of the tubing end is required. It is possible for the tubing end to become distorted
                        and irregularities may be present in the tubing wall. If any distortion or irregularities are
                        present, it will be necessary to trim off the damaged end (typically &#189;" is sufficient) by
                        using a good tubing cutter. Removal of the damaged end and using the appropriate tool will
                        ensure a positive seal between the tubing wall and the inside diameter of the PTC fitting. Be
                        sure to check the area with a good leak detection solution after pressurizing the system to
                        ensure that no leak is present. If a bubbling of the inspection solution is present, it may be
                        necessary to replace the PTC fitting, as well.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the tubing into the fitting (compression fittings): (A) Slide the fitting nut over
                the end of the tubing (threaded end facing the fitting), making sure the insert is in place inside the
                fitting; (B) Insert the tubing inside the fitting and push down as far as possible. (C) Secure the nut
                to provide a positive seal between the insert, the tubing, and the nut.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the tubing into the fitting (manifold fittings): Simply push the hose completely
                into the fitting until it locks. This style of fitting is of a push-to-connect (PTC) design. When
                properly installed, the tubing will not pull from the fitting unless the release mechanism is depressed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After completing the installation and verifying system operation, the entire air system
                should be inspected for leaks utilizing a suitable leak detection solution. This may include a soap,
                water, and glycerin mix, Oatey All-Purpose Leak Detector, or Nu-Calgon Gas Leak Detector (the Oatey and
                Nu-Calgon products are available through MSC Industrial Supply).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is important to pay particular attention to the vehicle air springs/bags. Leaks in these
                        areas will affect the SAMS system operation and performance and often go undetected, unless the
                        leak is severe enough to cause the vehicle to lean. During the inspection of the air
                        springs/bags, pay particular attention to the interface of the upper bead plate to the air
                        spring/bag lip area. Should a leak be detected in the air spring/bag, it must be replaced as
                        defined by the vehicle manufacturer's warranty procedure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <para>Detecting air leaks and taking corrective action will optimize system performance, eliminate unnecessary
            troubleshooting, prevent system rework, and prevent unnecessary air compressor wear due to excessive
            cycling.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10018.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
