<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - SFN 01-32</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SFN 01-32</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SFN Number: 01-32</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SFN Date: December, 2001</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Subject File: GENERAL</emph>
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>SUBJECT</title>
        </para>
        <para>Decked 4X2 Trucks Shipped with Pulled Drivelines Instead of Axle Shafts</para>
        <para>
            <title>DISTRIBUTION</title>
        </para>
        <para>Please distribute to:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>All International Dealers</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Service Managers</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>On November 12, 2001 International Truck and Engine Corporation gave approval to Active Transportation
            Corp. to move forward with shipping decked 4X2 trucks with pulled drivelines instead of axle shafts. Pulling
            drivelines reduces the need for extra gaskets for delivery, eliminates environmental concerns with oil
            spillage and removal, increases delivery efficiency, eliminates rear axle lube level concerns, reduces axle
            flange gasket leak concerns and increases Pre-Delivery/Quality inspection efficiency.
        </para>
        <para>Once the carrier completes the driveline reassembly process, it is required that the receiving Dealer or
            Dealer's agent (i.e., Body company) to inspect and torque the driveline joint. Inspect the driveline joint
            for assembly correctness, noting any exceptions or concerns on the New Truck Delivery receipt.
            <emph type="bold">Please refer to CTS-1029 - New Vehicle Processing Manual section New Truck Receiving and
                Damage Claim Processing.
            </emph>
            Failure to document driveline exceptions during the New Vehicle Inspection process will result in Loss and
            Damage claim and/or Warranty claim denial. If exceptions are found and documented, the dealer is responsible
            to properly prepare a Loss and Damage claim per CTS-1100W section 9.2./1. Repairs and claims must be
            completed and submitted within thirty (30) days for consideration for warranty payment. Claims must be
            supported by proper evidence or claims will be charged back to the submitting dealer per CTS-1029.
        </para>
        <para>Once again the dealer or the dealer's agent is responsible to set the torque on the four fasteners. Please
            refer to CTS-1029 - New Vehicle Processing Manual and Supporting Pre-Delivery Quality Inspection Manuals for
            the required torque values.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>It is very important that the torquing process occur before the truck is driven or damage may
                    occur.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
