<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Undecking and Storage - UNDECKING AND STORAGE - DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES FOR
        UNDECKING EXPENSE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DEALER RESPONSIBILITIES FOR UNDECKING EXPENSE</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Dealers must maintain undecking facilities which meet OSHA requirements, and assist the
                Carrier driver with undecking procedures.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>If a Dealer does not have adequate undecking facilities, the Carrier is authorized to engage
                    proper facilities or services and apply the tariff charge to the Dealer.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When a Dealer has a vehicle delivered to an intermediate agent, such as a body company, and the
                    agent refuses the Carrier the use of its undecking facilities or charges for the use, the Carrier
                    incurs this undecking expense, then bills it to International. International then debits this
                    Dealer's open account.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Undecking delay charges over standard wait times (1 hour per delivery) are incurred by the
                    carrier, who then bills International. These charges could be passed on to the Dealer, if the Dealer
                    is found to be at fault.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If a wrecker (tow truck) is used, the wrecker driver is considered to be the Dealer's agent, and
                    any undecking damage to the delivered vehicle(s) must be recovered from the wrecker driver's
                    employer.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>UNDECKING CHARGES apply to the Dealer whose unit is delivered at the Location the undecking
                    expense is incurred. This applies whether the unit being delivered is a drive truck or a decked
                    unit. For example, the undecking expense incurred to free a drive truck for delivery applies to the
                    Dealer receiving the drive truck.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
