<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Final Delivery Guidelines - FINAL DELIVERY GUIDELINES - FINAL DELIVERY
        GUIDELINES
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="4">
        <title>FINAL DELIVERY GUIDELINES</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Introduction</title>
            <para>The customer's first experience with the vehicle and your Dealership makes a lasting impression that
                contributes to the overall image of the product and dealership personnel. Ensuring every International
                vehicle is ready for the customer, making the delivery a positive experience, and providing superior
                service after the sale all contribute to customer satisfaction. REMEMBER, EVERY CONTACT WITH THE
                CUSTOMER IS AN OPPORTUNITY TO PROVIDE SATISFACTION.
            </para>
            <para>Customers are much more likely to be satisfied with a dealership that takes responsibility at delivery
                time for new vehicle operation and appearance. This kind of commitment to product quality gets respect
                in the marketplace. To make the delivery experience the best it can possibly be, perform the following
                steps to help ensure your customers' satisfaction with the delivery process, and with the new vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CSP - Strategic Initiative</title>
            <para>As dealers, you are a vital link in creating the ultimate customer experience. This strategic
                initiative was designed to help you improve customer retention and exceed your market performance. In
                support of this strategy, the CSP process has been created to deliver the following program benefits:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Provide a direct communications link between customers, dealers and International Truck and
                        Engine Corporation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Establish a continuous measurement and benchmark tool to assess progress.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Confirm that critical sales and delivery steps are completed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Enable early detection of customer dissatisfaction.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Measure satisfaction with service and parts department.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Identify unmet customer needs for dealer support and future product features.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Provide an effective means to listen and learn from your customers.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before Vehicle Pick-Up Or Delivery</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">ORDER SPECIFICATION VALIDATION - Verify the vehicle(s) matches the customer's order for
                    all specifications and the selected options.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">PREPARATION and DELIVERY - Ensure all required vehicle PDI procedures have been properly
                    completed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>During Vehicle Pick-Up Or Delivery</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">WALK-AROUND PRESENTATION - Present the vehicle by walking around it with the customer,
                    describing the order specifications, and the operating and safety features.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">DEALERSHIP INTRODUCTIONS - Introduce your customer to dealership personnel, including
                    management, and provide a Dealership Fact Sheet for each vehicle, and the office.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">WARRANTY EXPLANATION - Review the standard warranty package with the customer, and
                    inquire if any Optional and/or Customer Service Contract coverage is needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">DTU COMPLETION - Fill out the Delivery Notice and Warranty Application, DGE-1050. Be
                    sure to enter the name and telephone number of the customer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SURVEY NOTIFICATION - Inform the customer that International will send a Customer
                    Satisfaction Survey to the Business Contact within 90 days, and ask that they complete and return
                    the survey.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>How To Know When You're Satisfying Your Customers</title>
            <para>To know how well your customers are satisfied with your dealership, you should ask them. Since you
                don't have time to interview every Customer, International "asks" for you by way of the Customer
                Satisfaction Process (CSP). CSP is a direct means of requesting your customers' feedback, with the
                purpose of gaining understanding of customer needs and expectations. Through recognition of your strong
                and weak points you can improve dealership performance, so you will better satisfy your customers.
            </para>
            <para>CSP provides many benefits: satisfied customers gain a favorable impression of the dealership, and are
                more likely to return for future purchases; also, they will convey their positive experiences and
                opinions to other prospective buyers. Customer satisfaction means new business, repeat business, and
                positive referrals.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>International Customer Satisfaction Process (CSP)</title>
            <para>
                <title>Overview</title>
            </para>
            <para>International Customer Satisfaction Process (CSP) is a major part of our commitment to provide our
                customers with the highest quality vehicles and services in the transportation industry. CSP enhances
                mutual dealer/company efforts to achieve the highest levels of customer satisfaction possible.
            </para>
            <para>The Customer Satisfaction Process is a method of obtaining customer opinions and reporting the results
                to International dealers. Major features of CSP are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>There is no cost to International dealers for participating in the process.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All postage and other expenses are paid by International.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All International dealers are automatically enrolled in the process.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The Customer Satisfaction Process consists of:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A DELIVERY experience survey, to be completed by the customer 90 days after delivery
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A PARTS AND SERVICE survey, to be completed by the customer after one year of
                    ownership
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reporting, in the application that helps you identify your dealership's strengths and
                    opportunities for improvement.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>The Surveys</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DELIVERY Survey</emph>: Within 90 days after vehicle delivery, International mails a
                personalized Customer Satisfaction Survey questionnaire to each dealership customer taking delivery of
                an International vehicle. This DELIVERY survey identifies the selling dealership and the purchased
                vehicle; the customer is asked to complete and return the questionnaire. The DELIVERY survey assesses
                the level of customer satisfaction in several essential areas:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Sales and delivery experience</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle preparation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Overall dealership satisfaction</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Customer interest in extended warranties</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Product quality and performance.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>A sample DELIVERY survey follows.</para>
            <figure id="f1000539" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000559.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1000540" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000560.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Figure 23.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1000541" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000561.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Figure 24.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1000542" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000562.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Delivery Survey Page 3</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
