<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Delivering Carrier's Unloading Responsibilities</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Delivering Carrier's Unloading Responsibilities</title>
        <para>Listed below are the specific items that have been agreed to as the driver's responsibility to perform
            when unloading units at destinations. Please refer to the New Vehicle Processing Manual, CTS-1029 and the
            Warranty Procedures and Administrative Policies Manual, CTS-1100 for complete details.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unload units and remove saddles and wood blocks from the frame.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall wheels if removed, and tighten the mounting hardware.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall stacks and antennas. (Canadian delivered vehicles are not responsible for this)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reinstall Axles. Install new axle gaskets on the rear hubs and tighten in a "star pattern".
                These gaskets are sent with the vehicles.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>IT IS THE DEALER'S RESPONSIBILITY TO TORQUE THE AXLE SHAFT NUTS AND/OR U-JOINTS TO
                        SPECIFICATION PER PREPARATION AND DELIVERY (P&#38;D) GUIDELINES, NOT THE CARRIER'S. THIS MUST BE
                        DONE BEFORE MOVING THE VEHICLE.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install pulled drivelines on decked 4X2 if removed. (SFN 01-32)</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all grease from the wheels and rims that resulted from the axle shaft removal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unhook the tandems when chained to the frame.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-connect and tighten the air brake lines that were removed for transporting.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If spring brakes were manually released, return them to normal working position and install
                dust caps.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install tail lights in their proper position. Re-connect all wiring, and test for proper
                operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove temporary mud flaps, lights, wiring, and air hoses.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If removed, re-install rear spring rebound pins in the proper position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install all components removed by the Carrier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean up the unloading area; place items in the area designated by the Consignee.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>Keep in mind that the units should be left in the same condition as when received by the carrier from the
            plant. If not and you have questions, you should contact the carrier before signing the delivery receipt on
            the ATC Dealer Quality Assurance number at
            <emph type="bold">(800) 527-0491</emph>.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
