<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Concealed Damage</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Concealed Damage</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">DAMAGE THAT CANNOT BE SEEN DURING A NORMAL INSPECTION</emph>
            is considered "concealed". Typical locations are the oil pan, inside the sidewalls of tires, the bottom side
            of fuel/air tank, etc.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">REMEMBER, ON A CONCEALED DAMAGE CLAIMS, THE BURDEN OF PROOF LIES WITH THE CLAIMANT, NOT
                THE CARRIER.
            </emph>
            Please refer to the New Vehicle Processing Manual, CTS-1029, and the Warranty Procedures and Administrative
            Policies Manual, CTS-1100.
        </para>
        <para>When concealed damage is found after initial inspection, ATC must be notified using one of the three
            methods listed below.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">NOTIFY THE CARRIER WITHIN 48 HOURS OF DELIVERY TIME</emph>, by calling the ATC Leasing
                Claims Department, toll-free at 1-800-451-7560 during regular business hours, 7:30am-4:30pm Central
                Time, Monday through Friday. (i.e. Vehicle delivered Friday at 3:00, dealer has until Tuesday at 4:30 to
                notify carrier of concealed damage.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">NOTIFY THE CARRIER WITHIN 48 HOURS OF DELIVERY TIME</emph>, via fax, at 262-605-6073.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">NOTIFY THE CARRIER WITHIN 48 HOURS OF DELIVERY TIME</emph>, by letter via certified
                mail at:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Active Transportation</line>
                <line>Attn: Claims Department</line>
                <line>625 55th Street</line>
                <line>Kenosha WI 53140</line>
            </verbatim>
        </step1>
        <para>When notifying the carrier of damages or shortages, be prepared to supply the following information:
        </para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Name and location of dealer</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Vehicle identification number</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Date and time of delivery</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Approximate cost of repair</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Explanation as to why the damage was not detected at time of delivery.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">PLEASE NOTE: NOTIFYING THE CARRIER OF DAMAGES OR SHORTAGES OF A CONCEALED NATURE DOES NOT
                INSURE THE PAYMENT OF THE CLAIM. THE CLAIM MAY STILL BE DENIED BY THE CARRIER OR THE INTERNATIONAL
                WARRANTY CENTER PENDING FURTHER REVIEW. IN THE EVENT A CLAIM IS DENIED, YOU SHOULD CONTACT THE CARRIER
                DIRECTLY INSTEAD OF FILING AN APPEALS CLAIM OR CONTACTING INTERNATIONAL WARRANTY.
            </emph>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
