<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Undecking and Storage - UNDECKING AND STORAGE - CORRECT UNDECKING FACILITY
        CONFIGURATION
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CORRECT UNDECKING FACILITY CONFIGURATION</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Locate undecking facilities on your property to allow reasonable maneuverability of vehicles.
                    Provide a trash bin for discarded materials, and a sign telling where to put removed saddles.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">MINIMUM CAPACITY AND CONFIGURATION for specifying or upgrading undecking equipment to
                handle vehicles with design features such as aerodynamics, set-back axles and/or 102-inch width:
            </emph>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">HOIST STRUCTURE: A-frame or I-beam rails, to be 15 feet (inside dimension) wide, 14 feet
                from ground level to the underside of the upper bar, if the hoist can be moved to the side;
                <emph type="underscr">OR</emph>
                15 feet (inside dimension) wide x 14 feet from ground level to the chain hoist hook on a stationary
                center-mount hoist. With the stationary center-mount hoist, install a pulley/cable device to hold the
                chains and hook to the side, so vehicles can be pulled through under the hoist without damage to paint
                or accessories.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">CHAIN HOIST CAPACITY: 5 tons minimum (suggested 7 tons)</para>
            <para>&#8226; must meet OSHA requirements</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">CHAIN HOIST FALL LENGTH: 10 foot drop and lift</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">LIFTING MECHANISMS: International prescribes the following undecking tool sets, available
                through the International's tool supplier:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE4280
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000502">Undecking Sling</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    , a combination nylon/chain sling, designed for lifting and lowering Models 1000 through 4000, 7000,
                    8000, and 9000i without damage to the front bumper, grille or hood.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">ZTSE4441
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1000504">Undecking Adapter</hotlnk>
                    </emph>
                    for undecking 2000, 5000i, and 9400i models with center tow pin front bumper.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1000502" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. ZTSE4280 Undecking Sling</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1000504" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/g1000564.gif" type="gif" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. ZTSE4441 Undecking Adapter</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
