<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Loss and Damage Procedures Manual - Instruction for Carrier's Delivery Receipt Form (JTC 501)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Instruction for Carrier's Delivery Receipt Form (JTC 501)</title>
        <para>The five-digit damage coding is used throughout the truck transport industry and is designed to simplify
            the recording of damages or shortages on the transporter's delivery receipt. The use of this coding allows a
            detailed description of the area, type, and severity of the damage or shortage.
        </para>
        <para>The five-digit damage code consists of the following:</para>
        <randlist type="dash">
            <item>
                <para>Damage Area Code: 2 Digits</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Damage Type Code: 2 Digits</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Severity Type Code: 1 Digit</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The first two numeric digits of the five-digit code identify the area of the vehicle having damage or
            shortage. The third and fourth digits identify the type of damage; i.e., 01 = Bent, 02 = Broken, etc. The
            fifth and last digit of the code identifies the severity of the damage; i.e., 1 = less than 1" in length or
            diameter, 2 = 1" to 3" in length or diameter, etc.
        </para>
        <para>In the event there are multiple instances of damage to the same area of the vehicle (same damage area
            code), then a five-digit damage code should be entered on the delivery receipt describing each damage. The
            additional damage code should be entered in the blank spaces provided at the bottom of the damage code
            portion of the delivery receipt or in the dealer remarks section of the delivery receipt.
        </para>
        <para>Examples of proper coding of damages are as follows:</para>
        <randlist type="dash">
            <item>
                <para>Windshield Broken: 20210</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Bumper Bent: 03016</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Left Door Scratched 2": 10122</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Light Cable Missing: 47080</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>For a detailed listing of all the damage codes, please refer to the illustration of the delivery receipt
            below.
        </para>
        <para>To further assist the dealer in the inspection of trucks, the damage area section of the delivery receipt
            is designed to inspect in a clockwise direction starting at the front of the truck.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Any damages or shortages not appearing in the listing on the carrier's form can be recorded in the
                    dealer remarks section.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1001301" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/G1001301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="562px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Carrier's Delivery Receipt, Form: JTC 501 (Front)</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1001302" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg10/G1001302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="562px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Carrier's Delivery Receipt, Form: JTC 501 (Back)</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
