<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - Vehicles Not Built to Order - VEHICLES NOT BUILT TO ORDER - TRUCKS NOT BUILT
        TO ORDER - U.S. AND CANADA
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TRUCKS NOT BUILT TO ORDER - U.S. AND CANADA</title>
        <para>The purpose of this policy is to provide procedures for Dealer submission of claims for expense incurred
            when trucks are not built to accepted plant orders. Claims not submitted according to this policy will not
            be honored.
        </para>
        <para>When trucks are received from the plants with incorrect, incomplete, or excessive components, the reason
            usually falls into one of the following categories:
        </para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Ordering location ordered incorrectly</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Publication specification errors or changes</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Plant did not build to specifications.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>If the component(s) on the vehicle match those shown on the Order Content Confirmation report, the error
            is due to failure on the ordering location's part to verify the Order Content report against their original
            order. Corrective measures will be at the ordering location's expense. If the vehicle matches the ordering
            location's original order, a source ordering error is indicated and no claim should be filed.
        </para>
        <para>ALL OTHER DEFICIENCIES (
            <emph type="bold">parts</emph>
            of: coded items, standard equipment, package items) are to be reported to the Customer Service Engineer
            (CSE) for processing to the Warranty Processing Center per established Warranty procedures.
        </para>
        <para>Dealers are responsible for tracking and confirming that order changes are processed.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
