<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - New Truck Receiving and Damage Claim Processing - NEW TRUCK RECEIVING AND
        DAMAGE CLAIM PROCESSING - CONCEALED DAMAGE
    </stitle>
    <svcman/>
    <svcproc id="x1000502" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CONCEALED DAMAGE</title>
        <para>DAMAGE, due to its location, THAT CANNOT BE SEEN DURING A NORMAL INSPECTION is considered "concealed."
            Typical locations are the oil pan, inside the sidewalls of tires, the bottom side of fuel/air tank, etc.
            Missing items or interior damage does not qualify as concealed damage.
        </para>
        <para>REMEMBER, ON A CONCEALED DAMAGE CLAIM, THE BURDEN OF PROOF LIES WITH THE CLAIMANT, NOT THE CARRIER.</para>
        <para>WHEN CONCEALED DAMAGE is found, use the following procedure:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">NOTIFY THE CARRIER WITHIN 48 HOURS of delivery time, weekends and holidays excluded, by
                calling the ATC Leasing Claims Department toll-free Hot Line: 1-800/558-3271, or call 262/658-4381
                during regular business hours, 7:30-4:30 C.S.T.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SEND A FOLLOW-UP LETTER BY CERTIFIED MAIL, SEND A FAX, OR E-MAIL WITHIN 48 HOURS of the
                delivery time, weekends and holidays excluded. Mail the letter to:
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>ATC Leasing</line>
                <line>625 55th Street</line>
                <line>Kenosha, WI 53140</line>
                <line>Attn: Claims Department</line>
                <line>ATC Leasing Claims Department FAX is: 262/605-6073.</line>
            </verbatim>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">INCLUDE THE FOLLOWING DOCUMENTATION with the letter or FAX:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Name and location of the Dealer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle identification number</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Date and time of delivery</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>501 Delivery Receipt number</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Approximate cost of repairs</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Reason the damage was not detected at delivery</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Photographs of the damaged area: at least one photo close-up enough to show the specific
                        damage; at least one photo from far enough away to show the entire damaged part, and marked to
                        point out the location of the damage.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When you file the DDEW Warranty Claim, you must retain a copy of the follow-up letter with your
                    claim file copy. If International needs a copy, you will be instructed to either mail or fax it to
                    the appropriate number.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s10005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
