<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: MIDLAND MODELS EL-1300 AND EL-1600 - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <para>Air filters should be cleaned or replaced when the filter causes restriction exceeding 20 inches (508mm)
            of water. The restriction should be measured at the compressor inlet between the filter and air compressor
            while the compressor is pumping to atmosphere at 2400 RPM.
        </para>
        <para>Maximum recommended reservoir working air pressure is 125 psi.</para>
        <para>Type of air cleaner, operating conditions and experience may dictate additional service activity.</para>
        <para>Check compressor mounting to be sure it is tight. Be sure the drive pulleys are in proper alignment and
            belt tension is properly adjusted. Refer to GROUP 12 - ENGINE, Cooling Section in the CTS-5000 Master
            Service Manual for detailed information on belt tension procedures. Make sure the coolant lines and oil
            lines are in good condition and not restricted, and that the engine oil is changed at regular intervals.
        </para>
        <para>If the air compressor fails to maintain sufficient pressure or supplies excessive air pressure, the
            governor and unloader components should be inspected.
        </para>
        <para>The unloader components can be serviced or replaced without removing the compressor from the vehicle's
            engine.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
