<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - PRESSURE PROTECTION VALVE - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block vehicle wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be sure the vent hole is not obstructed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Bleed off main air supply.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the air outlet side of valve. Install an accurate air pressure gauge with a
                shut-off valve. Start engine and allow air pressure to build up. Observe gauge on instrument panel and
                at valve outlet.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery pressures,
                    gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                </para>
                <para>You should not have air pressure at test gauge until main air reservoir pressure reaches 65 to 75
                    psi. Then the pressure protection valve opens and both test gauge and gauge on vehicle should record
                    approximately the same.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stop engine and open the shut-off valve at test gauge. Air should exhaust until air pressure
                on vehicle reaches a pressure of approximately 20 psi below opening pressure, then close shut-off valve.
                If the valve performs as described, the valve is functioning properly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Bleed off main air reservoir pressure and remove shut-off valve and test gauge. Reconnect line to the
            auxiliary equipment.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
