<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK MODULATOR ASSEMBLY: BENDIX M-21 AND M-22 - OPERATION - ANTILOCK EXHAUST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ANTILOCK EXHAUST</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403007">Figure 7</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403007" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403007" filename="../figg04/G0403007.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 7. Antilock Exhaust</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When wheel lock is detected, or imminent, the antilock controller simultaneously energizes both the supply
            and exhaust solenoids in the modulator. Energizing the supply solenoid causes its exhaust to close and inlet
            to open. With the inlet of the supply solenoid open, application air is permitted to flow to the control
            side of the supply diaphragm. Air pressure acting on the supply diaphragm causes it to close the supply and
            prevent further delivery of air to the brake chamber.
        </para>
        <para>Energizing the exhaust solenoid closes its inlet and opens its exhaust. By closing the exhaust solenoid
            inlet, application air is prevented from flowing to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm. Air pressure,
            which was present on the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, flows out the exhaust port of the modulator.
            With control air pressure removed from the exhaust diaphragm, brake application air forces the exhaust
            diaphragm to unseat, which allows it to flow out the modulator exhaust port. The modulator will remain in
            the Antilock Exhaust mode until the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has increased. The modulator
            can enter the Antilock Hold or Re-apply mode from the Antilock Exhaust mode.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
