<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AUTOMATIC DRAIN VALVE (DV-2) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="4">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>With no pressure in the air system, the inlet and exhaust valves are closed (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400207">Figure 7</hotlnk>
            ).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400207" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400207" filename="../figg04/g0400207.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption>Figure 7. Inlet and Exhaust Valve Closed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When charging the air system, a slight pressure opens the inlet valve which permits air and contaminants
            to collect in sump (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400208">Figure 8</hotlnk>
            ).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400208" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400208" filename="../figg04/g0400208.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Contaminants Collect in Sump</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The inlet valve remains open while pressure rises in the system until maximum governor cut-out pressure is
            reached. The spring action of the valve guide in the sump cavity closes the inlet valve. The inlet valve and
            exhaust valve are now closed (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400209">Figure 9</hotlnk>
            ).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400209" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400209" filename="../figg04/g0400209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Inlet and Exhaust Valve Closed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When reservoir pressure drops slightly (approximately 2 psi), air pressure in the sump cavity opens the
            exhaust valve allowing moisture and contaminants to be ejected until pressure in sump cavity drops
            sufficiently to close the exhaust valve (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400210">Figure 10</hotlnk>
            ). The length of time the exhaust valve remains open and the amount of moisture and contaminants ejected
            depends upon the sump pressure and reservoir pressure drop that occurs each time air is used from the
            system.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400210" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400210" filename="../figg04/g0400210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                     scalefitheight="208px"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Contaminants Ejected</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Manual draining can be accomplished by inserting a tool in the exhaust port so that the wire in the port
            may be moved up and held until draining is completed.
        </para>
        <para>The heated automatic drain valve will activate the heating element when the valve body is warmed to 85&#176;F
            (30&#176;C).
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
