<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 550 AND TU-FLO 750 - ASSEMBLE - PISTON RINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>PISTON RINGS</title>
        <para>Check each ring end gap in a cylinder bore before installation. Place the ring in the top of the cylinder
            bore and using the piston, push the ring to the midpoint of the cylinder bore and check the ring gap. If the
            end gaps are incorrect, either the wrong repair size has been purchased or the compressor is worn beyond
            specification and should be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Install the rings on the pistons per the following instructions starting at the center of the piston and
            moving outward.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400316">Figure 16</hotlnk>for all item numbers in parenthesis unless otherwise stated.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the spacer and segment rings as follows. Place the spacer ring (Item 3,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400316">Figure 16</hotlnk>) in the piston groove; the ends of the spacer must butt and
                not overlap. Install the top segment (Item 4) by inserting one end above the spacer in the ring groove,
                120 degrees from the spacer ends and wind the segment into position. Install the bottom segment in the
                same manner beneath the spacer, making sure the gap is staggered 120 degrees from both the top ring
                segment and the spacer end gaps. Before using, be sure both painted ends of the spacer are visible and
                butted (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400316">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400316" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0400316.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Piston and Rings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. COMPRESSION RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SEGMENT RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SPACER RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SEGMENT RING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the compression rings (Item 1,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400316">Figure 16</hotlnk>) in the proper grooves with the bevel or pip mark (if any)
                toward the top of the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Check the ring side clearance of each ring in the piston ring groove (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400316">Figure 16</hotlnk>). If the side clearance is too large, the piston ring groove is
            worn beyond specifications and the piston must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Rotate the piston rings in their respective grooves so that each end gap is at least 90 degrees from the
            previous ring's end gap.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04003r_20.xml" xrefid="f0400313">Figure 13</hotlnk>for all items in parentheses.
        </para>
        <para>Lubricate the wrist pin (Item 27) and wrist pin bushing in the connecting rod with engine oil. Assemble
            the upper portion of the connecting rods and the pistons with the wrist pins. Insert the wrist pin buttons
            (Item 28) in the ends of the wrist pin. Lubricate the pistons and rings with engine oil and insert the
            piston in the cylinder bore.
        </para>
        <para>Turn the crankshaft so that one of its connecting rod journals is in the downward, center position.
            Install the crankshaft journal bearing segments (Item 38) on the connecting rod (Item 37) and connecting rod
            cap (Item 39). Tighten the connecting rod bolts (Item 40) evenly to 150 to 170 in-lbs. (16.947 to 19.155 N&#8226;m).
            Install the other connecting rod and piston in the same manner. It is recommended that new connecting rod
            capscrews be used.
        </para>
        <para>Before replacing the cylinder head on the crankcase, ensure the correct pistons have been used by turning
            the crankshaft one complete revolution such that each piston moves to its maximum upward stroke. At the
            maximum upward stroke position, each piston should move to the top of the crankcase. If the piston does not
            approach the top of the crankcase, the piston is incorrect and if not replaced could result in compressor
            damage.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_36.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_38.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
