<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - FAULT DETECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FAULT DETECTION</title>
        <para>The EC-30 contains self-testing diagnostic circuitry that continuously checks for proper operation of the
            ABS/ATC components and wiring. The EC-30 controls dash mounted warning lamps to advise the driver of the
            status of the system.
        </para>
        <para>When the EC-30 senses an erroneous system condition, it stores the fault code in memory, activates the
            appropriate warning lamp and disables all or part of the affected ABS or ATC functions. The faulted
            component is also identified on the diagnostic display on the EC-30.
        </para>
        <para>In most cases, the EC-30 will automatically reset (self-heal) the active fault code when the fault is
            corrected. However, repeated occurrences of a given fault will cause the fault code to latch. Once the fault
            code is latched, a manual reset is required. Latching of faults can assist in the troubleshooting of
            intermittent faults. The fault code is stored in the EC-30 memory, even when power is removed.
        </para>
        <para>After repair, latched fault codes can be reset by briefly holding a magnet on the reset location of the
            EC-30 diagnostic display. Fault codes can also be reset with the blink code switch or with a diagnostic
            tool.
        </para>
        <para>When a fault self-heals or is manually reset, the fault code remains in fault history. Fault history can
            be retrieved by using blink code diagnostics or a diagnostic tool.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
