<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING - diagnosis</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048501" graphiccount="0">
        <title>diagnosis</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Effective diagnosis of a malfunctioning system begins with observing the faults recorded by the system
                ECU. The faults, and their associated Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC's), are read using the EZ-TECH
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                service tool, running the TOOLBOX&#8482; program. The TOOLBOX&#8482; screen that displays the faults and
                their DTC's, also displays the appropriate Repair Instructions for the selected fault. A printed list of
                the faults, their DTC's, and the repair instructions is also provided in
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048A00.xml" xrefid="hl04048A00">APPENDIX A</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Detection</title>
            <para>The ECU uses a set of software algorithms to control the Full Power Brake System. Some functions of
                the ECU software are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Keep the full power brake system operating within its optimum range by controlling the cycling
                        of the pump motors to maintain the optimum quantity of pressurized brake fluid in the
                        accumulators. The typical operating pressure range for the accumulators is 1770 to 2320 psi.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Monitor the wheel speed sensors to detect an imminent wheel lockup (an ABS event). Then,
                        prevent the lockup by controlling the pressure of the brake fluid routed to each wheel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Detect faults or abnormal conditions within the full power brake system.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Maintain safe braking abilities by deactivating the ABS circuits when a serious fault
                        condition is detected.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Generate diagnostic trouble codes that may be used to diagnose and isolate problems in the
                        system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>To perform these functions the software system in the ECU monitors signals from the brake system and
                its environment. When certain fault conditions are detected, the software system will keep the ABS
                system enabled while it stores a diagnostic trouble code in its memory, identifying the fault. A
                detected fault will also result in the ECU sending a J1939 message to the gauge cluster, via the ESC/BC,
                to activate one or more of the warning indicators used to advise the driver of the status of the system.
                If a more serious fault condition is detected, in addition to generating DTC's and activating warning
                indicators, the software system will disable all or part of the affected ABS or ATC functions.
            </para>
            <para>The table in
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048A00.xml" xrefid="hl04048A00">APPENDIX A</hotlnk>
                lists which indicators are lit during each listed fault.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TOOLBOX&#8482; Software</title>
            <para>TOOLBOX&#8482; is a diagnostic program that runs in Windows&#174; 98, 2000, NT, or XP. The program
                displays system faults, fault codes and repair instructions. System operating conditions such as wheel
                speed data and accumulator pressures can be monitored in real time. In addition, various system
                electrical components can be activated to verify the individual components, as well as, installation
                wiring. The TOOLBOX&#8482; software is available from SPX Service Solutions, 1-800-328-6657.
            </para>
            <para>For complete instructions for using this program, refer to the User's Manual, TP-99102. Contact
                Meritor WABCO at 1-800-535-5560 (or www.meritorwabco.com) for information about TOOLBOX&#8482; Software.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
            <para>When a fault condition is detected, the ECU will generate a diagnostic trouble code (DTC). The unique
                DTC identifies the probable cause of the fault. When any brake system DTC is generated it is stored in
                the ECU memory even if the fault condition is only temporary. If a fault is detected once, and then not
                detected at a later time, the DTC for that fault is identified as a stored (inactive) fault. While a
                fault is present and being detected it is considered an active fault. The troubleshooting table, in
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048A00.xml" xrefid="hl04048A00">APPENDIX A</hotlnk>, lists the brake system
                related DTC's with their corresponding probable faults.
            </para>
            <para>Some DTC's that indicate serious malfunctions are designed to inhibit vehicle operation in some way
                once they have been set. The malfunctions that generate these DTC's must be corrected, and the DTC must
                be cleared from memory, before normal vehicle operation can resume. Prior to clearing a DTC the ignition
                must be cycled off and back on to change the status of the DTC from 'Active' to 'Stored'.
            </para>
            <para>The DTC's are observed by using the EZ-TECH
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                electronic service tool, running the TOOLBOX diagnostic software. While observing the DTC's, the stored
                (inactive) fault codes may be cleared by following the instructions within the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Observing Signals With The EZ-Tech
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                Service Tool
            </title>
            <para>To display operational information: the EZ-TECH
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                service tool must be connected to the vehicle; the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic program must be running;
                and the vehicle ignition must be ON.
            </para>
            <para>In addition to observing recorded faults, the EZ-TECH
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                electronic service tool, running the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic software, allows the servicer to observe
                (and control) some of the signals in the brake system. Refer to the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT
                DIAGRAMS manual and/or ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS. When used in conjunction
                with these manuals the EZ-Tech
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                allows the servicer to isolate electrical faults efficiently. Refer to the user manuals for the EZ-TECH
                <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                service tool and the TOOLBOX&#8482; software for complete operational information.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Definitions</title>
            <para>Terms related to diagnostic fault codes.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Active Fault:</emph>
                        A condition that currently exists in the brakes system; for example, a sensor circuit
                        malfunction on the left front steering axle. When an active fault has been repaired, it becomes
                        a stored fault after the next ignition cycle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Stored Fault:</emph>
                        A condition that caused the system to register a fault, but
                        <emph type="bold">is no longer being detected.</emph>
                        For example, a loose wire that corrected itself. A stored fault can also be an active fault that
                        has been corrected (refer to Active Fault).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048502.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
