<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - OPERATION - ANTILOCK</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION - ANTILOCK</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PHILOSOPHY</title>
            <para>The Bendix EC-17 antilock system uses individual sensors, modulators and an electronic controller to
                control the four vehicle wheel ends. By monitoring the deceleration rate during braking, and
                subsequently adjusting the brake application pressure at each wheel, the EC-17 is able to improve
                braking between the vehicle tire and the road surface it is on, while maintaining vehicle stability.
            </para>
            <para>The rear axle brakes are controlled independently; therefore brake application pressure at an
                individual wheel is adjusted solely on the basis of its behavior on the road surface on which it is
                traveling.
            </para>
            <para>While each steering axle brake is under the control of an individual modulator, the EC-17 does not
                treat these brakes independently. The EC-17 uses a modified individual control philosophy for the
                steering axle brakes. This is done in order to minimize "steering wheel pull" in the event each wheel is
                traveling on a different road surface (for example, ice close to the curb and a dry crown). Essentially
                the EC-17 controls the braking force differences between the two brakes.
            </para>
            <para>The wheel on dry pavement is initially given less braking force and is brought up to optimum during
                the stop, while the wheel on ice attempts to maintain optimum braking during the entire stop.
            </para>
            <para>In the case of vehicles equipped with tandem rear axles (6x2, 6x4), the wheel speed sensors are
                installed at the wheels on the axle that is most likely to lock first. A single modulator controls both
                curb side brakes on the tandem, and another modulator controls both brakes on the driver's side of the
                tandem. With this arrangement of speed sensors and modulators, both brakes on one side of the tandem are
                treated as one since they will most likely be on the same type of road surface.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
