<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl04051200">
        <title>GENERAL DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The Full Power Brake System is a stored energy, hydraulic brake system which integrates the functions
                of brake actuation, ABS, and traction control (optional), into one unit, referred to as the Hydraulic
                Compact Unit (HCU). A small master cylinder attached to the brake pedal linkage produces signal pressure
                in proportion to driver demand for braking. This signal pressure is sent to the relay valve of the HCU
                which delivers brake fluid to the foundation brakes in proportion to the signal. The following features
                of this system are covered in this manual.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">STANDARD FEATURES</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Carry-over foundation brakes (Bosch pin slide type).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Brakeforce Distribution (EBD). System identifies front to rear wheel slip
                        imbalances due to axle loading and distributes braking forces in proportion to axle loading to
                        render a balanced brake application on the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Antilock Braking System (ABS).</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>ABS prevents wheel lockup during braking.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>During braking, the system monitors each wheel, and reacts to any potential lockup by
                                modulating the brake pressure for the affected wheel.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Recording of brake system operations. Memory within the ECU circuitry maintains a record of
                        brake system operations. These operational records may be used to more efficiently schedule
                        preventive maintenance. Examples of some of what is recorded:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>number of key switch cycles</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>number of service brake applies identified as: 'light to moderate', 'moderate to
                                hard', and 'hard to extreme'
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>motor/pump operational hours.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OPTIONAL FEATURES</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Automatic Traction Control (ATC) with J1939 engine management</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>ATC prevents wheel spin during acceleration.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>During acceleration, the system monitors the wheel speeds, and may react to any loss
                                of traction by applying a limited braking force to the affected wheel, without driver
                                intervention.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If both drive wheels begin to spin, the ATC system sends a signal to the engine to
                                reduce engine torque and allow the drive wheels to regain traction.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Dash mounted Traction Control switch, allows two levels of traction control to be
                                selected (Normal Traction Control or Mud and Snow mode).
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051201.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
