<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>A regular schedule for cleaning, lubrication, adjustment and inspection should be established, usually
                based on past experience and type of vehicle operation. It is difficult to determine an exact
                maintenance "time or mileage" interval since vehicles will be used in a wide variety of operations,
                applications and conditions.
            </para>
            <para>To compensate for lining wear, brakes with manual slack adjusters should be adjusted frequently to
                maintain satisfactory operation and efficient braking. Vehicles equipped with automatic slack adjusters
                will need inspection only and service as necessary.
            </para>
            <para>Drain air reservoirs regularly as required. Local conditions govern frequency. Dry climates require
                less attention than humid areas, where it may be necessary to drain reservoirs daily.
            </para>
            <para>When draining air reservoirs, let all air bleed off and be sure all drainage stops.</para>
            <para>For more details, refer to the appropriate air brake system section in GROUP 04 BRAKES in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE</title>
            <para>Every month or every 4,000 miles (6,000 km), brake chamber push rod travel should be checked. Push rod
                travel should be kept at a minimum without brakes dragging. Excessive travel of brake chamber push rod
                shortens the life of the diaphragm. Over- travel also slows braking response.
            </para>
            <para>Once each year, or every 100,000 miles (160,000 km), brake chambers should be disassembled and
                cleaned, and a new diaphragm installed. Be sure to use the correct diaphragm return springs when
                reassembling chamber or uneven braking may result.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The tamper resistant spring brake has been factory sealed for your protection. There are no
                        user- serviceable parts inside the spring brake chamber. If you experience any damage or failure
                        to the spring brake chamber, replace the complete assem- bly. Never attempt to disassemble the
                        spring brake chamber as serious personal injury or death could result from accidental sudden
                        release of the high energy spring.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>After the brake chamber is installed, the brakes must be adjusted. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04005_HL0400501.xml" xrefid="hl0400501">BRAKE ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
