<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROL RELAY VALVE: BENDIX ATR-2 - OPERATION - SERVICE APPLICATION - BOBTAIL TRACTOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SERVICE APPLICATION - BOBTAIL TRACTOR</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403106">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403106" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403106" filename="../figg04/G0403106.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 6. Service Application - Bobtail Tractor</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When the trailer supply valve (dash control with red octagonal button) is activated to disconnect the
            trailer, air in the ATR-2 control port and trailer supply line is exhausted to the atmosphere. During
            bobtail tractor operation, service application air enters the ATR-2 service port and is conducted to the
            single check valve. The check valve diaphragm flexes in response to the application pressure and seals the
            passage to the open exhaust of the traction solenoid. Application air passes through the blend back piston
            and exerts a force on the full effective diameter of the piston. The blend back piston remains stationary at
            application pressures below approximately 80 psi because of opposing reservoir air acting on the large
            diameter.
        </para>
        <para>Application air flowing through the blend back piston also exerts a force on the small diameter of the
            proportioning piston while simultaneously flowing through the center of it on its way to the inlet and
            exhaust valve. Once past the inlet and exhaust valve, service air pressure exerts a force on the larger
            diameter end of the proportioning piston, which opposes the air pressure and spring force exerted on the
            other end. The proportioning piston inlet valve remains open until a preset, initial application pressure
            has reached the relay piston assuring that the foundation brake shoes are brought into contact with the
            drum. As service pressure begins to exceed the preset initial application, the proportioning piston will
            have moved sufficiently to close its inlet valve without opening the exhaust.
        </para>
        <para>The inlet remains closed, preventing additional air delivery to the relay piston and a subsequent increase
            in brake chamber pressure, until service application pressure exceeds approximately 30 psi (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403107">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Service applications above this pressure will result in a
            proportioned increase of the preset initial brake application to the tractor's rear brakes. Proportioning
            occurs due to the difference in effective area on each end of the proportioning piston. Tractor rear axle
            brake proportioning will occur for all service applications between approximately 30 and 80 psi.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403107" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403107" filename="../figg04/G0403107.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 7. Service Application - Bobtail Tractor</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Service applications of more than 80 psi cause the blend back piston to begin to move. Service air
            pressure acting on the full diameter of the blend back piston overcomes the resistance of reservoir pressure
            acting on the large diameter of the other side. Above 80 psi, the ratio between control and delivered air
            pressure is reduced and "blends back" from a proportioned delivery to a full 1 to 1 delivery. Complete
            "blend back" to a 1 for 1 delivery is achieved when a full brake application is made.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
