<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM WITH TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - 9200, 9300 and 9400 -
        MAINTENANCE - ABS CONTROLLER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ABS CONTROLLER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Every 3 Months, 25,000 Miles, or 900 Operating Hours</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check all wiring and connectors to ensure they are secure and free from visible
                    damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Although the controller incorporates self-check diagnostics, the LED display should be
                    inspected to ensure that the LEDs are functional. With the vehicle ignition ON, a magnet (800 gauss;
                    capable of picking up 3 ounces) held to the LED reset switch should cause all of the LEDs to
                    illuminate.
                </para>
                <para>If one or more of the LEDs do not illuminate and the antilock warning light on the dash indicates
                    the system is functioning properly, the non-illuminated LED(s) should be noted for future reference.
                    Although the diagnostic capabilities will be limited, the system will continue to function as
                    designed.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For the next step, 2 technicians are required: a vehicle driver and an observer.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test the vehicle by making antilock stop from a vehicle speed of 20 miles per hour.
                    When an antilock stop is made, the modulator solenoids pulsate and an audible burst of air can be
                    heard from outside of the cab by an observer. The wheels should not enter a prolonged "lock"
                    condition when vehicle speeds are above seven miles per hour.
                </para>
                <para>Also make a traction control test by accelerating on a road surface with reduced available
                    traction (gravel or other suitable surface). As with ABS, audible bursts of air can be heard when
                    the traction control system is functioning.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04028_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04028_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04028.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
