<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - APPENDIX A</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04050A00" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="14">
        <title>APPENDIX A</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The Automatic Traction Control (ATC) system reflected in this table is optional; therefore, the
                    TRAC CTRL indicator will not be present on all vehicles.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>The Hydraulic Parking Brake (PB) system reflected in this table is not currently available;
                    therefore, the Parking Brake Service Lamp (SERVICE) and Parking Brake Indicator Lamp (PARK) may not
                    function as indicated in this table. Refer to the vehicle Operator Manual for complete information
                    on parking brake indicators.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Effective diagnosis of a malfunctioning system begins with observing the faults recorded by the system
            ECU. The faults, and their associated Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC's), are read using the EZ-TECH
            <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
            service tool, running the TOOLBOX&#8482; program. The TOOLBOX&#8482; screen that displays the faults and
            their DTC's, also displays the appropriate Repair Instructions for the selected fault. A printed list of the
            faults, their DTC's, and the repair instructions is also provided in this appendix.
        </para>
        <para>The information in APPENDIX A is provided only as additional background information. The following is a
            brief description of the APPENDIX A contents.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>General information regarding the driver interface:</title>This short table shows the circuit
            connections used by the system to drive the gauge cluster indicators. The gauge cluster indicators in the
            current full power brakes system are driven via the SAE J1939 data link. Some vehicles are equipped with an
            additional BRAKE indicator located in one of the indicator quadrants below the speedometer and tach. This
            indicator is hardwired to pin 20 or the ECU 31-pin connector. The other hardwired connections listed in the
            table are NOT used.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Troubleshooting Table (System Reaction)</title>This table shows how the system reacts to each of the
            faults listed in the first column (Component). It also lists the Diagnostic Trouble Code (DTC) assigned to
            each fault, and refers the user to the Repair Instruction to be used for troubleshooting. The headings of
            the table are:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Component</emph>
                - This column lists the possible system faults, primarily organized by system component.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">SPN, SID, PID, FMI</emph>
                - These columns list the fields that comprise the DTC assigned to the specific fault listed in the
                Component column.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Repair instruction</emph>
                - This column references the Repair Instruction to be used when troubleshooting the fault listed in the
                Component column. All repair instructions are found in the Repair Instructions table that follows the
                troubleshooting table.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">General Actions</emph>
                - This column briefly describes how the internal operation of ECU changes to react to the fault listed
                in the Component column.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">ABS, ATC EBD, PB</emph>
                - These columns show the status of each of the full power brakes subsystems (including optional
                systems), based on the occurrence of the fault listed in the Component column. The Hydraulic Parking
                Brake (PB) system reflected in this table is not currently available.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Brake Warning Lamp (BRAKE PRESSURE), ABS Warning Lamp, ATC Info Lamp (TRAC CTRL),
                    Audible Warning (Buzzer), Parking Brake Service Lamp (SERVICE), Parking Brake Indicator Lamp (PARK),
                    Brake Fluid Indicator Lamp
                </emph>
                - These columns show the status of each of the indicators, based on the occurrence of the fault listed
                in the Component column. NOTE: The Hydraulic Parking Brake (PB) system reflected in this table is not
                currently available; therefore, the Parking Brake Service Lamp (SERVICE) and Parking Brake Indicator
                Lamp (PARK) may not function as indicated in this table.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>
            <title>Multiple Failures Table</title>This is a supplemental table to the troubleshooting table. This table
            lists the system reaction to multiple faults. The table headings are the same as those described for the
            troubleshooting table.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Special System Conditions</title>This table lists the system reaction to special operational
            conditions. Most of these conditions are not faults. This table simply breaks down how the system reacts to
            the conditions listed. The table headings are the same as those described for the troubleshooting table. Any
            fault conditions listed in this table are also covered in the troubleshooting table.
        </para>
        <para>NOTE: The full power brakes system is a multiplexed (muxed) system.</para>
        <para>
            <title>Repair Instructions</title>This table lists the repair instructions and is organized by Repair
            Instruction (R.I.) number. These repair instructions are referenced from the Troubleshooting and Multiple
            Failures tables. The information in this table is also provided in the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic program.
        </para>
        <figure id="f04050pg1" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048103.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg2" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048104.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg3" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048105.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg4" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg5" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg6" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg7" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048109.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg8" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048110.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg9" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg10" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048112.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg11" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048113.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg13" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg14" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048115.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f04050pg15" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g04048116.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="574px"
                     scalefitheight="650px"/>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050900.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
