<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROL RELAY VALVE: BENDIX ATR-2</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s04031" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5248" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROL RELAY VALVE: BENDIX ATR-2</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>BENDIX</vendor>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>ATR-2</vendcode>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9800</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The ATR-2 Antilock Traction Relay (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403101">Figure 1</hotlnk>) is a specialized air brake valve developed for use on
                Bendix Antilock/Traction equipped tractors only (with bobtail feature).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403101" filename="../figg04/G0403101.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. ATR-2 Antilock Traction Relay Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>It is essentially three separate valves working in combination in a single housing. An R-14 style
                service relay is the base valve and is fitted with a modified cover containing a bobtail tractor brake
                proportioning valve and a traction control solenoid. The ATR-2 contains both air and electric components
                and provides both the service braking and traction control (differential braking) functions. A Bendix
                Antilock Traction controller, such as the EC-16, can be mounted to the ATR-2 or a cover plate can be
                installed and the antilock controller mounted elsewhere on the vehicle. When an ATR-2 is combined with
                an antilock traction controller, the resulting assembly is referred to as an antilock traction assembly.
                For example, when the ATR-2 is combined with the EC-16 electronic controller, the resulting assembly is
                referred to as an AT-2 antilock traction assembly.
            </para>
            <para>The ATR-2 replaces the standard relay valve used to control the rear axle service brakes and performs
                the standard relay function during tractor-trailer operation. During tractor bobtail operation, the
                ATR-2 reduces brake application pressure to the lighter rear axle(s) brakes to improve vehicle
                controllability and minimize rear axle(s) wheel skid before antilock is required. The ATR-2 provides
                added vehicle braking control and reduces the number of times antilock is actually needed.
            </para>
            <para>Like the standard relay valve it replaces, the ATR-2 and its attached antilock controller is normally
                mounted near the service brakes it serves. A mounting bracket, furnished with the valve, permits either
                frame or cross- member mounting. All air connections on the ATR-2 are identified with cast, embossed
                letters for ease of identification and installation. The letter identification and air line connections
                are shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0403101">Table 1</hotlnk>
                for reference.
            </para>
            <table id="hl0403101">
                <title>Letter Identification and Air Line Connections</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>ATR-2 Air Connection</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>Embossed ID</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Supply (to reservoir)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>SUP</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Delivery (to brake chamber)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>DEL</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Service (to brake valve rear delivery)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>SER</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Control (to delivery of trailer supply valve)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>CON</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>The ATR-2 is part of the R-12 family of relay valves which includes the R-12, R-14, BP-R1, and AR-1.
                The internal components of the relay portion of all of these valves are interchangeable with the R-12
                and therefore the same basic components are used to service all of them.
            </para>
            <para>The ATR-2 crack pressure is 4 psi.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
