<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BRAKE BOOSTER AND MASTER CYLINDER - OPERATION - HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BOOSTER AND BACKUP PUMP
        ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BOOSTER AND BACKUP PUMP ASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04017y_6.xml" xrefid="f0401702">Figure 2</hotlnk>
            for all items in parentheses.
        </para>
        <para>The Hydro-Max&#8482; booster (Item 1) amplifies the force that a driver applies to the brake pedal. The
            booster uses flow and pressure from the power steering pump to provide the amplification of the force at the
            brake pedal. The amplified force is transmitted to the primary piston within the master cylinder body (Item
            2).
        </para>
        <para>Power steering fluid flows into the Hydro-Max&#8482; booster inlet port (Item 3), through a throttling
            valve in a piston, and out from the Hydro-Max&#8482; booster outlet port (Item 4). A flow switch in the
            outlet port senses the fluid flow. Pushing on the brake pedal causes the throttling valve to close, which
            causes the power steering pump pressure to rise in proportion to the force applied to the pedal. This
            pressure pushes on the piston inside the booster, and this piston pushes on the primary piston of the master
            cylinder body (Item 2). Releasing the brake pedal causes the throttling valve to open, thus pressure drops
            and the force to the master cylinder primary piston drops, all in proportion to the amount of force
            maintained on the brake pedal.
        </para>
        <para>The backup pump (Item 5) circulates the power steering fluid through the Hydro-Max&#8482; booster (Item 1)
            in the event that the power steering pump is not providing power steering fluid flow. Whenever the flow
            switch (Item 6) senses a lack of flow, it closes an electrical circuit, which turns on the relay (Item 7).
            The relay turns on the backup pump (Item 5). With the backup pump in operation, the booster is able to
            amplify brake pedal force, thus maintaining power brakes even though the power steering pump is not
            providing power steering fluid flow.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
