<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - ANTILOCK AND TRACTION SYSTEM OPERATION DURING COMPONENT FAILURE -
        SINGLE FAILURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SINGLE FAILURE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The following list describes how the antilock and traction systems respond to a specific component
                failure.
                <emph type="bold">(Note: right and left, front, mid and rear are determined from the driver's seat. Left
                    front is therefore the corner closest to the driver.)
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>For example, if the right mid sensor fails, front and rear antilock will still be operative. Traction
                will be disabled. On those axles where antilock is disabled, the system reverts to standard air braking.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Modulator</title>
            <para>If a front modulator fails, antilock on that wheel is disabled. Antilock and traction on all other
                wheels remain active.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Modulator</title>
            <para>A rear modulator failure disables the traction system. Antilock on that wheel will also be disabled,
                but antilock on all other wheels remains active.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Sensor</title>
            <para>The wheel is still modulated using input from the opposite sensor on the front axle. The traction
                system is disabled.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mid or Rear Sensor</title>
            <para>In a four sensor system, antilock on that wheel(s) is disabled, but antilock on all other wheels
                remains active. In a six sensor system, antilock remains active using input from the remaining
                functional sensor. In both the four and six sensor system, traction control is disabled.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Traction Solenoid</title>
            <para>Traction control is disabled. Antilock remains active.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Control Module</title>
            <para>If the engine control module (ECM) or the wiring from the EC-17 to the ECM fails, traction control is
                disabled. Antilock remains active.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltage</title>
            <para>If system voltage is out of range, antilock and traction are disabled. The system reverts to standard
                air braking.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
