<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DOUBLE DIAPHRAGM MGM SPRING BRAKE - REPLACE SERVICE BRAKE DIAPHRAGM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
        <title>REPLACE SERVICE BRAKE DIAPHRAGM</title>
        <para>The removal and installation of the service brake diaphragm can be made easier by "locking off" the
            service chamber piston. To do this apply the service brake by applying the driver's foot brake treadle valve
            and, while applied, clamp vise grip pliers on piston rod to prevent rod from retracting when air pressure is
            released (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402018">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0402018" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 18. Vise Grip Pliers Applied To Piston Rod</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release (cage) the spring brake completely. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_X0402001.xml" xrefid="x0402001">CAGING SPRING</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove both air lines from the chamber.</para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure to mark the air line from the inlet port "SPRING BRAKE" for later re-installation
                        reference.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On Models "TR-T" and "TR-LP3-T" fitted with external breather tubes (Item 10,
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_1.xml" xrefid="f0402001">Figure 1</hotlnk>), disconnect the tube and elbow
                from the service brake chamber housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a 9/16-inch wrench or socket to remove the clamp ring nuts on the service brake clamp
                ring. Then, while holding the spring brake chamber securely in place, remove the clamp ring to allow
                removal of the spring brake chamber from the assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402019">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402019" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Remove Service Brake Clamp Ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Your MGM Tamper Resistant spring brake has been factory sealed for your protection. There are
                        no user-serviceable parts inside the spring brake chamber. If you experience any damage or
                        failure of your spring brake chamber, replace the complete assembly. Never attempt to
                        disassemble the spring brake chamber as serious personal injury or death could result from
                        accidental sudden release of the high energy spring.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>At this time, take the opportunity to inspect all parts in the service brake chamber and
                        replace any parts which may be damaged or worn.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the diaphragm in the bottom recess of the chamber (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402020">Figure 20</hotlnk>) and, with very close attention taken to assure all mating
                parts are aligned straight and the air inlet ports are positioned to mate with the vehicle air supply
                lines, replace the service brake clamp ring (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402019">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402020.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Install New Diaphragm</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-install the clamp ring bolts and nuts.
                <emph type="bold">Alternately tighten each nut in 5 to 10 ft-lbs. (7 to 14 N&#8226;m) torque
                    increments
                </emph>
                while constantly rechecking mating parts alignment. (If re-alignment is required, loosen clamp ring nuts
                and repeat step 5 above.) Firmly tap around circumference of the clamp ring with a hammer to assure the
                full seating of the clamp ring (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_10.xml" xrefid="f0402017">Figure 17</hotlnk>) and
                <emph type="bold">tighten the nuts to 25 to 30 ft-lbs. (34 to 41 N&#8226;m) torque.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Teflon tape or sealing compound to the hose fittings (Item 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml" xrefid="f0402014">Figure 14</hotlnk>) and re-install both of the air
                lines to the chamber, being sure each is mated to the correct air inlet port according to markings made
                earlier.
                <emph type="bold">Tighten the fittings to 25 ft-lbs. (34 N&#8226;m) torque into the chamber air inlet
                    ports.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use vehicle system air to charge the spring brake chamber with full line air pressure
                (minimum 100 psi). Use only soapy water (NEVER ANY TYPE OF OIL!) to inspect for air leaks at the air
                lines and fittings.
                <emph type="bold">If bubbles appear, tighten fittings slightly, but not over 30 ft-lbs. (41 N&#8226;m)
                    torque.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the spring brake still fully charged with full line pressure, apply and hold foot brake
                treadle valve down to charge the service brake chamber.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>At this time, remove the vise grip pliers (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0402018">Figure 18</hotlnk>) from the service piston rod so that the piston can
                        return to a normal position in the chamber. Now test for air leaks around the circumference of
                        the service brake clamp ring. If bubbles appear, firmly tap the circumference of the clamp ring
                        with a hammer and retighten the clamp ring nuts until leaks cease (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_10.xml" xrefid="f0402017">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Tighten the clamp nuts
                        to 25 to 30 ft-lbs. (34 to 41 N&#8226;m) torque.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On "TR-T" and "TR-LP3-T" models fitted with an EXTERNAL BREATHER TUBE, wipe the ends of the
                connector tube clean to be sure that no oil is present. Apply a high quality rubber cement to the tube
                and re-insert tube into flexible elbows with minimum 1/2-inch engagement into both elbows (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402007">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>These units must be mounted with the BREATHER TUBE in the upper half of the non-pressure
                        chamber facing away from the road surface (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402008">Figure 8</hotlnk>) and the tube glued
                        securely into the rubber elbows (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402007">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Failure to comply with
                        these instructions will void any warranty.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With air pressure exhausted from the service chamber, but with line pressure still on the
                spring brake, remove the release nut, flat washer and release bolt. Replace these parts in their storage
                pocket (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_X0402001.xml" xrefid="f0402009">Figure 9</hotlnk>) on the chamber (or in the
                vehicle tool box if a storage pocket is not present on the chamber) and
                <emph type="bold">tighten the nut against the flat washer to 10 ft-lbs. (14 N&#8226;m) torque</emph>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the end cap properly (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402005">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Operating these units without the
                END CAP securely in place will void any warranty.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Operating units without the END CAP securely in place will cause premature failure of the spring
                    brake assembly and will void any warranty.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
