<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION - ANTILOCK EXHAUST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ANTILOCK EXHAUST</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402313">Figure 13</hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <figure id="f0402313" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0402313" filename="../figg04/G0402313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 13. M-21 Antilock Exhaust</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                <callout1>4 . BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>When wheel lock-up is found, or about to happen, the antilock controller simultaneously energizes both the
            supply and exhaust solenoids in the M-21. Energizing the supply solenoid causes its exhaust to close and
            inlet to open. With the inlet of the supply solenoid open, application air is permitted to flow to the
            control side of the supply diaphragm. Air pressure acting on the supply diaphragm causes it to close the
            supply and prevent further delivery of air to the brake chamber.
        </para>
        <para>Energizing the exhaust solenoid closes its inlet and opens its exhaust. By closing the exhaust solenoid
            inlet, application air is prevented from flowing to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm. Air pressure
            which was present on the control side of the exhaust diaphragm flows out the exhaust port of the M-21. With
            control air pressure removed from the exhaust diaphragm, brake application air forces the exhaust diaphragm
            to unseat, which allows it to flow out the M-21 exhaust port. The M-21 will remain in the Antilock Exhaust
            mode until the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has increased. The M-21 can enter the Antilock
            Hold or Re-apply mode from the Antilock Exhaust mode.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
