<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - RELAY VALVE (BENDIX R-12 AND R-14) - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0400203" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation and Leakage Tests</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the wheels; fully charge air brake system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make several brake applications and check for prompt application and release at each
                    wheel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for inlet valve and O-ring leakage.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make this check with the service brakes released when the R-12 is used.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make the check with the spring brakes applied (PARK) when the R-14 is used to
                        control the spring brakes.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Coat the exhaust port and the area around the retaining ring with a soap solution; 1 inch (25 mm)
                bubble in 3 seconds leakage is permitted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for exhaust valve leakage.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make this check with the service brakes fully applied with the R-12 relay valve.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make this check with the spring brakes fully released if the R-14 relay valve is
                        used to control the spring brakes.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Coat the exhaust port with a soap solution; 1 inch (25 mm) bubble in 3 seconds
                        leakage is permitted.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Coat the outside of the valve where the cover joins the body to check for seal ring
                    leakage; no leakage is permitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the R-14 relay valve is used to control the spring brakes, place the park control in
                    the released position and coat the balance/quick exhaust port with a soap solution to check the
                    diaphragm and its seat. Leakage equivalent to a 1 inch (25 mm) bubble in 3 seconds is permitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The air line attached to the balance/quick exhaust port must be disconnected to perform this
                        test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_104.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_106.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
