<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - PRINCIPLES, OPERATION AND SERVICE - REMOVE - ANTILOCK RELAY
        VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block the wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain the air pressure from all vehicle reservoirs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Identify, mark or label all air lines and wiring cables and their respective connections on
                the controller/relay valve assembly to facilitate ease of installation.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Always turn key switch to OFF position before disconnecting any portion of the antilock wiring
                        system. If circuits are disconnected with the key ON, the controller will record the open
                        circuit as a fault condition.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect all air lines and wiring.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note and mark the mounting position of the relay valve/controller assembly on the vehicle.
                Remove and save the relay valve/controller mounting hardware, then remove the controller/relay valve
                assembly from the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all contaminants from the exterior of the controller/relay valve assembly, making
                sure to keep all contaminants from entering the open ports on the assembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note and mark the position of the controller relative to the antilock relay valve for later
                reassembly. Remove the 4 capscrews securing the controller to the relay valve. Carefully separate the
                controller from the relay valve, making sure not to damage the gasket between the 2 components, if
                possible. Peel the gasket from the controller or antilock relay valve and retain for use if it is not
                damaged.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a new gasket if the old gasket is damaged or if a new gasket is readily available.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>For disassembly of the relay valve, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKE COMPONENTS in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
