<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK MODULATOR ASSEMBLY: BENDIX M-21 AND M-22 - OPERATION - NON-ANTILOCK EXHAUST</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>NON-ANTILOCK EXHAUST</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The manner in which air exhausts through the modulator differs, depending upon how rapidly the brake
                application is released by the driver.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Normal Exhaust</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403005">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403005" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403005" filename="../figg04/G0403005.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Normal Exhaust</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>During a normal, relatively "slow" brake release, air moves back through the modulator in the reverse
                direction as it flowed during application. The internal components of the modulator will remain in the
                same position as they assumed during application until air pressure decreases to approximately one half
                psi, at which time the supply diaphragm will seat on the supply passage. Air will generally not be
                expelled from the modulator exhaust port during normal brake release.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rapid Exhaust</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403006">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The Rapid Exhaust operation described in the following text only occurs when the modulator is
                controlling two type 30 (or larger) service chambers. During a very rapid brake release, the modulator
                will exhaust air in a different manner. An example of this would be the case if the driver made a severe
                brake application then lifted his foot from the foot valve. During a rapid brake release, air from the
                exhaust diaphragm flows back through the open exhaust solenoid and to the application device's exhaust.
                With pressure removed from the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, air, returning to the modulator
                from the service chambers, lifts the exhaust diaphragm from its seat. Returning air flows past the open
                exhaust and out the modulator exhaust port. Air will also flow past the open supply diaphragm and back
                to the application device's exhaust.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403006" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403006" filename="../figg04/G0403006.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Rapid Exhaust</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
