<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BRAKE BOOSTER AND MASTER CYLINDER - BRAKING SYSTEM PRESSURE SPECIFICATIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>BRAKING SYSTEM PRESSURE SPECIFICATIONS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Braking System Pressure Chart</title>
            <para>Additional diagnosis may be accomplished by measuring the fluid pressure being generated at a brake
                caliper by the brake master cylinder. To check brake line pressure, install a 0 to 2,000 psi (0 to
                13,800 kPa) gauge at a brake caliper.
            </para>
            <para>Apply the brakes with ignition switch "OFF" (the engine NOT running). The backup pump should start and
                produce up to approximately 800 psi (5,515 kPa) line pressure at the brake caliper.
            </para>
            <para>Operate the engine at idle until the power steering fluid reaches normal operating temperature of 125
                to 135 degrees F, (52 to 57 degrees C). Check temperature by placing thermometer (Kent-Moore No.
                J-5421-02 or equivalent) into power steering pump reservoir. Apply brakes. The line pressure at the
                brake caliper should be able to reach approximately 1,800 psi (12,400 kPa).
            </para>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 05 - STEERING in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the proper procedure to test
                the power steering pump. There should be about a 1:2 ratio between power steering pump pressure and
                master cylinder output pressure. If both power steering pump and master cylinder provide the specified
                pressures, inspect other hydraulic brake system components for cause of poor braking.
            </para>
            <table id="t0401707" tblwidth="full-page">
                <title>Hydro-Max&#8482; Booster Pressure Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.72in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.26in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Hydro-Max&#8482; Booster Approximate Pressure Values</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Hydro-Max&#8482; Booster Input pressure up to approximately 900 PSI (6,205 kPa)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Master Cylinder Output pressure up to approximately 1,800 PSI (12,400 kPA)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Backup Pump operating</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Master Cylinder Output pressure up to approximately 800 PSI (5,515 kPa)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_X0401706.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
