<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - SERVICE CHECKS - BP-R1
        OPERATION TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401207" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BP-R1 OPERATION TEST</title>
        <para>To properly test the function of the BP-R1, a pair of test gauges or gauges of known accuracy must be
            used.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block the wheels and/or secure the vehicle by a
                means other than the air brakes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain air pressure from all vehicle reservoirs.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a "tee" at the BP-R1 service port and at one of the delivery ports, then install a
                gauge in each.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the tractor service emergency "glad hands" (hose couplings) that have been plugged,
                or alternatively, to a trailer. Build the tractor system air pressure to governor cut-out and make 4 to
                5 full brake applications. Check the brake fittings at the BP-R1 for leaks. Correct leak conditions
                noted.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the trailer supply valve (dash control with red octagonal-shaped button) and system
                park control (dash control with yellow diamond-shaped button) activated for tractor/trailer operation,
                apply,
                <emph type="bold">HOLD</emph>, then release the brakes several times varying the application pressures
                while watching the reaction of the gauges installed on the BP-R1. Note that a prompt application of air
                occurs, that the air pressure is sustained during the
                <emph type="bold">HOLD</emph>, and that the air pressure quickly is released when the brakes are
                released.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the BP-R1 differential pressure by applying 10 psi to the service port and noting the
                pressure registered at the delivery port. Subtract delivery port pressure from the 10 psi service
                pressure (applied to the service port) to obtain the differential. The measured differential should be
                approximately 4 psi for the BP-R1 valve installed by International.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make and hold a full (100 psi or greater at service port gauge) brake application and note
                that full pressure (100 psi or greater at the delivery port) is delivered to the brake chambers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Activate the dash mounted trailer air supply valve for bobtail tractor operation. Then make
                a
                <emph type="bold">very slow</emph>
                brake application, increasing the pressure at the BP-R1 gradually to 20 psi while watching the resulting
                change in pressure at the delivery port gauge. Note that the delivery port pressure rises to
                approximately 5 to 10 psi and remains constant while service continues to rise to 20 psi. Release the
                application.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make another brake application and
                <emph type="bold">slowly</emph>
                increase the pressure at the BP-R1 service port to between 60 and 70 psi while observing the delivery
                port gauge. Note that when service port pressure rises to between 20 and 30 psi, delivery pressure
                begins to rise above the initial pressure noted in step 6. The rise of delivery pressure should be at a
                proportioned rate of
                <emph type="bold">approximately</emph>
                3:1. At 70 psi service pressure, delivered pressure should be 15 to 25 psi.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make a full brake application and note that both test gauges register the same pressure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the test gauges from the BP-R1.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>If the BP-R1 fails the OPERATION TEST repair or replace the valve.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401203.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401201.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
