<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - TROUBLESHOOTING - EC-15 DIAGNOSTIC STEPS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="29">
        <title>EC-15 DIAGNOSTIC STEPS</title>
        <svcsubproc id="x0402207">
            <title>Initial Start-Up Self Test Procedure</title>
            <para>For a vehicle
                <emph type="bold">without any system defects</emph>, the following information describes "normal
                behavior" during the engine start-up.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The EC-15 will begin start-up diagnostics when the key is turned to the ON position. However,
                        when the starter is engaged, the crank relay cuts power to the EC-15 during the engine cranking
                        process. When the engine cranking process is ended, power is re-applied to the EC-15 and the
                        "Initial Start-up Procedure" will start over.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Initial Start-Up Self Test Procedure: Normal Start-Up</title>
            <para>Test Explanation - Each M-21 modulator contains (1)
                <emph type="italic">exhaust solenoid</emph>
                and (1)
                <emph type="italic">hold solenoid</emph>. During this test with service brakes applied, the EC-15
                controller will "fire" or energize each solenoid briefly in a test cycle making a "chuff" sound as the
                air exhausts. The exhaust solenoid will be "fired" for 10 milli-seconds, then a pause for only a few
                milli-seconds and the hold solenoid will "fire" for 20 milli-seconds. The two firing in rapid sequence
                produces a single "chuff" sound. If the solenoids are wired incorrectly, or if only one is firing, the
                sound will be distinctly different. The EC-15 will begin at the right front, then go to the left front,
                then the right rear, and finish the cycle on the left rear. It will then repeat the cycle, making two
                complete cycles. The second cycle is a repeat of the first.
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle engine is started (or key switch turned to ON position), the EC-15 first runs a
                series of modulator tests as described in the preceding paragraph. The controller begins at the
                <emph type="italic">right front</emph>
                M-21 modulator and fires each of the (2) solenoids contained in the modulator, then moves to the
                <emph type="italic">left front</emph>
                modulator and fires each of the (2) solenoids in that modulator and moves to the
                <emph type="italic">right rear</emph>
                modulator, again firing both solenoids, and finally moves to the
                <emph type="italic">left rear</emph>
                and fires each of the (2) solenoids in that modulator. The cycle will be repeated one more time, in the
                same sequence.
            </para>
            <para>After the modulator test is complete, the EC-15 will next energize the "Engine Brake Relay" five or
                six times rapidly, causing a "chattering sound" from the relay (if vehicle is equipped with engine
                brake), then the yellow instrument panel warning light will flash twice and then remain on until the
                vehicle speed is increased to at least 7-10 mph for several seconds, then the warning light will "go
                out."
            </para>
            <para>This behavior indicates the antilock system is performing correctly. The EC-15 will continue to
                monitor system performance and illuminate the warning light if a problem is detected.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the vehicle is warm, and shut-off briefly, then restarted and quickly driven past the
                        seven-to-ten miles-per-hour point, the system may not go through the diagnosis process of
                        flashing twice, then staying on until the seven miles per hour is attained.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Initial Start-Up Self Test Procedure: Start-Up With Defect In System</title>
            <para>If the system is started and the instrument panel antilock warning light does not perform as described
                above, a system fault is present. The warning light:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>May not illuminate on at all</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Or may illuminate (but not flash twice) and stay on</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Or may flash twice and illuminate, then after seven to ten miles per hour is reached, remain
                        illuminated or blink intermittently.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Any of the preceding actions indicate that the EC-15 has detected a fault in the system. Perform
                <hotlnk xrefid="x0402209">DIAGNOSING THE INITIAL START-UP TEST PROCEDURE</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0402209">
            <title>Diagnosing The Initial Start-Up Test Procedure</title>
            <para>If the "Initial Start-up Procedure" is performed in a quiet area, and if the technician listens
                carefully, certain activities are accompanied by a particular sound that can assist in diagnosing the
                problem.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the vehicle ignition to the ON or RUN position (do not start) and listen for
                    "specific sounds" made by the ABS components (relays and solenoids), then observe the action of the
                    antilock yellow warning light located on the instrument panel. Go to step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the key is turned ON, the CR-15 will begin a series of tests on the modulators.
                    First, note if the RIGHT FRONT modulator "fires," making a click sound or a "chuff" sound if the
                    service brake air is applied.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was not present, it indicates that the modulator failed to "fire." Note
                        the defect and go on to step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was noted, go on to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note if the LEFT FRONT modulator "fires" making a "click" sound or a "chuff" sound if
                    service brake air is applied.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was not noted, it indicates that the modulator failed to "fire." Note
                        the defect and go on to step 4.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was noted, go on to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note if the RIGHT REAR modulator "fires" making a "click" sound or a "chuff" sound if
                    service brake air is applied.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was not noted, it indicates that the modulator failed to "fire." Note
                        the defect and go on to step 5.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was noted, go on to step 5.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note if the LEFT REAR modulator "fires" making a "click" sound or a "chuff" sound if
                    service brake air is applied.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was not noted, it indicates that the modulator failed to "fire." Note
                        the defect and go on to step 6.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was noted, go on to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Steps 2 through 5 are repeated one time (The EC-15 repeats the same test cycle one
                    additional time).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Also at this time, if the vehicle is equipped with an engine brake, you can hear (or
                    feel) the engine brake relay "chatter."
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If sound (chattering) was not present, it indicates that the relay system may be
                        defective. Note the defect and go on to step 8.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sound was present, go to step 8.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point, the antilock warning light should flash twice, then illuminate and remain
                    illuminated. At the same time the warning light flashes, you can hear the warning light relay
                    "de-energize." It will make a "click" each time the light illuminates. If the relay does not
                    "de-energize," the light will not flash. Note dash light activity.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the dash light does NOT ILLUMINATE AT ALL, stop here and proceed to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x040222a">DASH LIGHT TESTING</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the dash light FAILS to flash twice before illuminating, stop here and proceed to
                        "
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0402221">INSPECT FOR ILLUMINATED LEDs - 1</hotlnk>."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the dash light flashed twice before illuminating and staying on, proceed to step
                        9.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the dash light DID FLASH TWICE and REMAIN ON, start the engine. Starting the engine
                    will cause the EC-15 to reset and begin the "Initial Start-up Procedure" over again. Verify that the
                    original start-up sequence of events that occurred with the key ON are repeated.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the key-on cycle of events is not the same, rerun this test.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the cycle is repeated, then go to step 10.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Increase vehicle speed to above 10 MPH for several seconds and observe the dash light.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the dash light REMAINS ILLUMINATED, proceed to "
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0402222">INSPECTION FOR ILLUMINATED LEDs-2</hotlnk>."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the dash light GOES OUT after vehicle speed reaches 7-10 miles per hour, the
                        system is functioning normally. Make notes of the parts replaced or repaired and all steps taken
                        on the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">Troubleshooting Sheet</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Diagnosing the Initial Start-Up Procedure with Defect in the Antilock System</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402215">Figure 15</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402216">Figure 16</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402217">Figure 17</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402215" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402215.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Diagnosing the Initial Start-Up Procedure With Defect in the Antilock System (Part
                    1)
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402216" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402216.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Diagnosing the Initial Start-Up Procedure With Defect in the Antilock System (Part
                    2)
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402217" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402217.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Diagnosing the Initial Start-Up Procedure With Defect in the Antilock System (Part
                    3)
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x040222a">
            <title>Dash Light Testing</title>
            <para>This test is performed when the warning light fails to illuminate during the "Initial Start-up
                Procedure."
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>This test is for the 96/9700 and 93/9400 models only. References to a particular connector,
                        circuit, etc., by number will be made for the 96/9700 models, with the 93/9400 model reference
                        number in parentheses, if the number is different than the 96/9700 number. For example:
                        "Disconnect harness connector C355 (or C288)...." The C355 refers to 96/9700 models and the C288
                        refers to the 93/9400 models.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before beginning this procedure, turn ignition key to the ON position, and check the
                    EC-15 LEDs. Record on the Troubleshooting Record Sheet the condition of LEDs and action of the dash
                    light. Turn key switch OFF.
                    <emph type="bold">Note all test steps in the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">Troubleshooting Record Sheet</hotlnk>.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition of: the yellow warning light bulb located on instrument panel, and the
                    15A fuse, S18 (or 20A fuse, F4).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the bulb is defective, replace and rerun the "Initial Start-up Procedure." If the
                        fuse is defective, locate the cause for the overload condition and repair. Run the "Initial
                        Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the bulb and/or fuse are not defective, go to the Step 3.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Next step will cause several LEDs to illuminate. Later, clearing of all illuminated LEDs will
                        be required. Be sure that any LEDs illuminated were noted in step 1.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">In this step we will open the ground circuit from the warning light relay to the EC-15
                    controller. This will cause the light to illuminate, if the warning light and relay circuits are not
                    defective. With the key OFF, disconnect C355 (or C288) from the EC-15 harness connector. Turn the
                    key switch ON, and note the yellow warning light on the instrument panel.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light is now illuminated, it indicates the EC-15 is defective.
                        Replace the EC-15 controller. Rerun the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the yellow warning light does not illuminate, DO NOT reconnect the harness to the
                        EC-15 at this time, but go to step 4.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the warning light relay from the wire harness connector C361 (or C285), and turn
                    the key switch ON. Install jumper from harness connector circuit 94E to vehicle ground. The warning
                    light should illuminate.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light does not illuminate, locate the open in the warning light
                        circuit between C361 (or C285) and fuse S18 (or F4). Also verify power from the fuse. Repair the
                        defect, then run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light illuminates, go to step 5.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the warning light relay removed from C361 (or C285) harness connector and the key
                    switch ON, check voltage to ground at the relay harness connector, circuit 94B/94C.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, locate the open in the feed circuit 94B/94D to
                        fuse S18 (or F4). Repair the circuit, then go to step 6.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is present, go to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the warning light relay removed from harness connector C361 (or C285), turn the
                    switch key OFF. Use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at harness connector circuit 94-G.
                    Continuity should be present.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, locate the open in circuit 94-G to ground
                        and repair. Run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, go to step 7.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connector C355 (or C288) was previously disconnected from the EC-15 harness in step 2.
                    With the warning light relay removed from the harness connector C361 (or C285), and the key OFF, use
                    ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at harness connector circuit 94H. The circuit
                    <emph type="bold">should not</emph>
                    have continuity to ground, because C355 (96/9700) or C288 (93/9400) is disconnected from the EC-15
                    harness.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present in circuit 94H, locate the short to ground and
                        repair. Run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present at circuit 94H, go to step 8.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the warning light relay removed from relay harness connector C361 (or C285),
                    install a jumper between the warning light relay connector terminals for circuit 94-G and 94H.
                    (Terminal 3 to terminal 5 as shown in the circuit diagram.) At the chassis antilock harness
                    connector C355 (or C288) use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at circuit 94H (pin K).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, locate the open in the circuit and repair.
                        Go to step 9.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, go to step 9.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove jumper installed in step 8, and re-install warning light relay. Do not reconnect
                    C355 (or C288) to EC-15 harness. Turn key ON and note condition of warning lamp.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If warning light is illuminated, turn key OFF. Re-connect C355 (or C288) to EC-15
                        harness and use magnet to reset LEDs. Run "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light is not illuminated, replace the warning light relay. Run the
                        "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402218">Figure 18</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402219">Figure 19</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402220">Figure 20</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402218" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Dash Light Testing (Part 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402219" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Dash Light Testing (Part 2)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402220" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402220.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Dash Light Testing (Part 3)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection for Illuminated LEDS - 1</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the EC-15 for presence of illuminated LEDs and record on the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">TROUBLESHOOTING SHEET</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note the condition of the Green, VOLT LED and:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is NOT ILLUMINATED, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is FLASHING, perform "TESTING FOR POWER TO EC-15."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is ILLUMINATED and not flashing, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the EC-15 for illuminated RED LEDs.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NO RED LEDs are illuminated, perform "TESTING FOR POWER TO EC-15."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ANY RED LEDs are illuminated, replace the EC-15.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and RECORD condition of all RED LEDs and:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NO RED LEDs are illuminated, proceed to "TESTING FOR FALSE FAILURE INDICATION -
                        CAUSED BY DASH LAMP RELAY."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If any RED LEDs are illuminated, proceed to "INSPECTION FOR ILLUMINATED LEDS- 3."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402221">Figure 21</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402221" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402221.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Inspection for Illuminated LEDs - 1</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection for Illuminated LEDS - 2</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the EC-15 for presence of illuminated LED's and record on the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">TROUBLESHOOTING SHEET</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note the condition of the Green, VOLT LED and:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is NOT ILLUMINATED, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is FLASHING, perform "TESTING FOR POWER TO EC-15."</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the green LED is ILLUMINATED and not flashing, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the EC-15 for illuminated RED LEDs.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NO RED LEDs are illuminated, perform "TESTING FOR POWER TO EC-15.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If ANY RED LEDs are illuminated, replace the EC-15.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and RECORD condition of all RED LEDs and:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NO RED LEDs are illuminated, proceed to "TESTING FOR FALSE FAILURE INDICATION -
                        CAUSED BY DASH LAMP RELAY."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If any RED LEDs are illuminated, proceed to "INSPECTION FOR ILLUMINATED LEDs - 3."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402222">Figure 22</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402222" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402222.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Inspection for Illuminated LEDs - 2</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection for Illuminated LEDS - 3</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note the Red "ECU" LED in the EC-15 diagnostics window. If it is ILLUMINATED, proceed to
                    "Testing For Power To The EC-15." If the ECU LED is NOT ILLUMINATED, proceed to step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">There must be a MINIMUM OF THREE RED LEDs ILLUMINATED and of the three,
                    <emph type="bold">there must be</emph>:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Either a "RIGHT" or "LEFT" plus</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Either a "FRONT" or "REAR" plus</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Either a "MOD" or "SENS".</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there are less than 3 RED LEDs illuminated and/or there is not one LED from each pair
                    above, then replace the EC-15 and repeat the "Initial Start-up Procedure," otherwise proceed to step
                    3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make note of the three illuminated LEDs on the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">TROUBLESHOOTING RECORD SHEET</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the "MOD" LED is illuminated along with the two positioning LEDs ("RIGHT" or
                        "LEFT," plus "FRONT" or "REAR") proceed to "Testing The Modulator."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the "SENS" LED is illuminated along with the two positioning LEDs ("RIGHT" or
                        "LEFT" plus "FRONT" or "REAR") proceed to "Testing The Wheel Speed Sensor."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402223">Figure 23</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402223" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402223.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Inspection for Illuminated LEDs - 3</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing for Power to the EC-15</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Vehicle batteries must be fully charged to perform this test. Check batteries for
                        state-of-charge (Refer to GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL). If not fully charged (checked less than 12.60
                        volts), correct low charge condition before proceeding.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Record ALL test steps and results on the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="x040221a">Troubleshooting Record Sheet</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This test is for 96/9700 and 93/9400 model vehicles. Refer to the circuit diagram for the vehicle
                being tested. References to particular connector numbers, circuit numbers, etc. will be for the 96/9700
                models with the 93/9400 model in parentheses if the number is different. For example: "Disconnect
                harness connector C355 (or C288)...." The C355 refers to 96/9700 models and C288 refers to the same
                actual connector on a 93/9400 model, but is numbered differently.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition of 30 amp in-line fuse (between circuit 94 and 94K).</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If fuse is defective, locate cause of the overload condition and repair, then
                        replace the fuse. Run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the fuse is not defective, verify that battery voltage is present at the fuse.
                        Then go to step 2.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always make certain the key switch is in the OFF position before disconnecting any antilock
                        system electrical connectors. Disconnecting a connector without the key OFF will cause the EC-15
                        to record "open circuit" faults in the system memory.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key switch in the OFF position, disconnect wire harness connector C355 (or
                    C288) from the EC-15 controller harness. All circuit tests will be made using the antilock chassis
                    harness connector end
                    <emph type="bold">and not</emph>
                    the EC-15 controller harness end. Turn the vehicle key switch ON and measure the voltage between the
                    ignition feed, circuit 94L (pin J) and ground circuit 94-G (pin P) at the chassis wire harness
                    connector (not EC-15 harness). The voltage should be the same as battery voltage and
                    <emph type="bold">must be between 11 and 17 volts</emph>.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, use magnet and reset the EC-15, then note the
                        condition of the GREEN LED.
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>If the green LED is flashing, replace the EC-15 controller.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>If the green LED is not flashing, run the "Initial Startup Procedure".</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present (either zero volts or less than battery voltage),
                        go to step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key ON and chassis antilock harness C355 (or C288) disconnected from the EC-15
                    harness, check voltage to vehicle ground at chassis antilock connector C355 (or C288), circuit 94L
                    (pin J).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, locate open or high resistance condition (loose
                        connection, damaged wire, etc.) in ground circuit 94-G, then repair. Run the "Initial Start-up
                        Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With key ON, check voltage to ground at cab to chassis antilock connector C356 (or C282)
                    at circuit 94A (or 94K) of the cab harness side.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, locate the open or high resistance condition in
                        circuit 94A/94L between the cab connector C356 (or C282) and C355 (or C288), then repair. Run
                        the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present (either zero volts or less than battery voltage)
                        go to step 5.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With key OFF, remove the crank relay from the cab antilock cab harness connector C369
                    (or C284). Turn the key ON and check voltage to ground at relay harness connector circuit 94K (or
                    94A). (Circuit 94K (or 94A) is shown at terminal 1 in the circuit diagram.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, locate open or high resistance condition in feed
                        circuit, then repair. When defect is corrected go to step 6.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, go to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With key ON (NOT START POSITION), check voltage to ground at relay harness connector at
                    circuit 94L. (Circuit 94L is shown at terminal 2 in the circuit diagram.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Voltage should only be present when the cranking motor is engaged. Locate the wiring
                        defect or short to "hot" circuit, then repair. Go to step 7 when defect is corrected.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is not present, go to step 7.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key OFF and use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at relay harness connector
                    circuit 94-GA.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, locate open condition and repair. Then go to
                        step 8.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, go to step 8.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At the crank relay harness connector, install a jumper between terminal 3 (circuit 94A
                    (or 94K) and terminal 5 (circuit 94-GA). With the key OFF, at chassis antilock harness connector
                    C355 (or C288), check continuity to ground at circuit 94L (pin J).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, go to step 9.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, go to step 10.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the cab to chassis antilock harness connector C356 (or C282) and at the cab
                    side of the connector, check circuit 94A (or 94K) for continuity to ground.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, locate the open in circuit 94A (or 94K)
                        between C356 (or C282) and the crank relay harness connector C369 (or C284), then repair. Run
                        the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, locate the open in circuit 94L/94A between C356
                        (or C282) and C355 (or C288), then repair. Run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the crank relay and with the key ON, measure voltage between circuit 94L (pin
                    J) and circuit 94-G (pin P) at the antilock chassis harness connector C355 (or C288).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, replace the crank relay. Run the "Initial
                        Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, the battery power to the EC-15 is verified, as is the
                        ground path.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402224">Figure 24</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402225">Figure 25</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402226">Figure 26</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402227">Figure 27</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>This test is for 96/9700 and 93/9400 model vehicles. References to a particular connector,
                        circuit, etc. by number, will be made for the 96/9700 models with the 93/9400 model
                        corresponding number in parentheses if the number is different. For example: Disconnect harness
                        connector C355 (or C288)." The C355 refers to the 96/9700 models and the C288 refers to the
                        93/9400 models.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Vehicle batteries must be fully charged to perform this test. Check batteries for
                        state-of-charge. If not fully charged (less than 12.60 volts), correct condition.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0402224" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402224.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Testing for Power to the EC-15 (Part 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402225" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402225.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Testing for Power to the EC-15 (Part 2)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402226" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402226.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Testing for Power to the EC-15 (Part 3)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402227" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402227.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Testing for Power to the EC-15 (Part 4)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing the Modulator</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Record LEDs that are illuminated before starting the test. Also record ALL test steps and
                        results on the Troubleshooting Record Sheet.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This test is for 96/9700 and 93/9400 model vehicles. Refer to the circuit diagram for the vehicle
                being tested. References to particular connector numbers, circuit numbers, etc. will be for the 96/9700
                models with the 93/9400 model in parentheses if the number is different. For example: "Disconnect
                harness connector C355 (or C288)...." The C355 refers to 96/9700 models and C288 refers to the same
                actual connector on a 93/9400 model, but is numbered differently.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the vehicle ignition key switch OFF and disconnect the chassis antilock brake
                    harness connector from the EC-15 harness as explained in steps A and B.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To test the left or right front modulator, disconnect chassis antilock harness
                        connector C355 (or C288) from the EC-15 harness.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To test the left or right rear modulator, disconnect chassis antilock harness
                        connector C350 (with 96/9700 or 93/9400) from the EC-15 harness.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>To perform step 2, refer to the circuit diagram and note that each antilock brake modulator has three
                circuits: a HOLD circuit, a SOURCE circuit and an EXHAUST circuit. The front modulator circuits connect
                to the EC-15 through connector C355 (or C288). The rear modulator circuits connect to the EC-15 through
                connector C350 (96/9700 and 93/9400).
            </para>
            <para>Refer again to the circuit diagram for the specific circuit number and pin location for the specific
                brake modulator to be tested. This test measures the resistance of the solenoid coils (two are contained
                in each modulator) and tests each modulator circuit (there are three) for any short to ground or short
                to a battery source. An ohmmeter is used to measure the resistance values between the test points listed
                in the following chart. The resistance values specified in the chart are for the M-21 modulator. The
                following example walks you through a brief test for point "A" in the chart.
            </para>
            <para>EXAMPLE: To test the LEFT FRONT MODULATOR on a 9600 model vehicle, turn the key switch OFF and
                disconnect chassis antilock harness connector C355 from the EC-15 harness. The test will be performed on
                the antilock chassis harness connector end (not the EC-15 end). Use an ohmmeter to measure resistance
                between: HOLD (circuit 94AS at pin E) and SOURCE (circuit 97AR at pin M). This measures resistance
                between point B and point C as shown in the modulator in the circuit diagram. If the coil is not
                defective, the resistance will be 3.5 to 5.0 ohms. The other points are tested in the same manner.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the switch key OFF, use an ohmmeter to measure the resistance at each test point in
                    the following chart for each modulator to be tested. Record all measurements on the Troubleshooting
                    Record Sheet.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the resistance readings are correct (as shown in the chart) proceed to step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the resistance readings are not within the specifications, skip step 3 and go to
                        step 4.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0402202" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Modulator System Test Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>TEST POINT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>SPECIFIED RESISTANCE</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>A. HOLD to SOURCE:</para>
                                <para>B. EXHAUST to SOURCE:</para>
                                <para>C. EXHAUST to HOLD:</para>
                                <para>D. SOURCE to BATTERY</para>
                                <para>POWER:</para>
                                <para>E. SOURCE to GROUND:</para>
                                <para>F. HOLD to BATTERY POWER:</para>
                                <para>G. HOLD to GROUND:</para>
                                <para>H. EXHAUST to BATTERY POWER:</para>
                                <para>I. EXHAUST to GROUND:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Read 3.5 to 5 OHMS</para>
                                <para>Read 3.5 to 5 OHMS</para>
                                <para>Read 7 to 10 OHMS</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                                <para>No continuity (open</para>
                                <para>circuit)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key OFF, inspect the connector, then re-connect to the EC-15. Turn the key ON
                    and reset the EC-15 by passing a magnet over the RESET on the EC-15. Note the reaction of the RED
                    LEDs after resetting.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NONE of the RED LEDs are illuminated, repeat the "Initial Start-up Procedure." If
                        after the "Initial Start-up Procedure" the same LEDs are illuminated (if this step has been
                        repeated two times), replace the EC-15.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If DIFFERENT RED LEDs are illuminated, return to "Inspection For Illuminated Red
                        LEDs" and retest.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the SAME RED LEDs are illuminated AND it is one of the FRONT MODULATORS being
                        tested, then TEST THE REAR MODULATOR ON THE OPPOSITE SIDE OF THE VEHICLE BY RETURNING TO STEP 1.
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>If failure persists, replace the EC-15.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move to the suspected modulator and inspect the wiring and connector for clean, secure
                    connections and no cut or damaged wires.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If defects are present, correct and perform step 2 again.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If wiring and connections are good, go to step 5.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to the circuit diagram for the modulator connector number and locate the connector
                    composite. The composite provides the pin/circuit information for the connector. Disconnect the
                    antilock chassis harness connector from the modulator. Use ohmmeter to measure the resistance
                    between the pins on the modulator as shown in the following chart. The resistance values listed in
                    the chart are for the M-21 modulator.
                </para>
                <para>EXAMPLE: To test the right rear modulator valve on a 9600 model, refer to the 96/9700 CIRCUIT
                    DIAGRAM for the connector number. Then locate the connector number in the CONNECTOR COMPOSITE. Use
                    the ohmmeter to measure resistance between HOLD (circuit 94AJ attaches) and SOURCE (circuit 94AH
                    attaches). Resistance should read 3.5 to 5 ohms. Measure the resistance at the other test points as
                    indicated in the following chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0402203" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Modulator System Test Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>TEST POINT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>SPECIFIED RESISTANCE</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>A. HOLD to SOURCE:</para>
                                <para>B. EXHAUST to SOURCE:</para>
                                <para>C. EXHAUST to HOLD:</para>
                                <para>D. HOLD to vehicle ground</para>
                                <para>E. EXHAUST to vehicle ground:</para>
                                <para>F. SOURCE to vehicle ground:</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Read 3.5 to 5 OHMS</para>
                                <para>Read 3.5 to 5 OHMS</para>
                                <para>Read 7 to 10 OHMS</para>
                                <para>Read NO continuity</para>
                                <para>Read NO continuity</para>
                                <para>Read NO continuity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>If the resistance readings are as specified in the chart, proceed to step 6, if not, replace the
                modulator.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the harness connector to the modulator. Turn the ignition ON and reset the
                    EC-15 by passing a magnet over the RESET on the EC-15. Note the reaction of the RED LEDs.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If NONE of the RED LEDs are illuminated, repeat the "Initial Start-up Procedure." If
                        after the "Initial Start-up Procedure" the same LEDs are illuminated (if this step has been
                        repeated two times), replace the EC-15.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the SAME RED LEDs are illuminated, replace the EC-15 controller.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If DIFFERENT RED LEDs are illuminated, return to "Inspection For Illuminated Red
                        LEDs" and retest.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402228">Figure 28</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402229">Figure 29</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402230">Figure 30</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402231">Figure 31</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402232">Figure 32</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402228" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402228.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. Testing the Modulator (Part 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402229" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402229.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 29. Testing the Modulator (Part 2)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402230" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402230.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 30. Testing the Modulator (Part 3)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402231" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402231.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Testing the Modulator (Part 4)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402232" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402232.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Testing the Modulator (Part 5)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing the Wheel Sensor</title>
            <para>If during performance of "Inspection For Illuminated LEDs - 3," the SENS RED LED is illuminated,
                <emph type="UnderScr">and either</emph>
                the FRONT or REAR LED is illuminated
                <emph type="UnderScr">and either</emph>
                a RIGHT or LEFT LED is illuminated, then this test is to be performed.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the key switch ON, and make note of which LEDs are illuminated. Reset the EC-15 by
                    passing a magnet over the RESET in the Diagnostic window. Note the reaction of the RED LEDs.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If no RED LEDs are illuminated, proceed to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the SAME RED LEDs are illuminated, go to step 7.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If DIFFERENT RED LEDs are illuminated (than before resetting), return to "Inspection
                        For Illuminated Red LEDs-3" and retest.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For the following tests, refer to the circuit diagram for the vehicle being tested to identify
                        circuits and connectors referred to in the test steps.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">To check resistance of a FRONT sensor</emph>, turn the key switch OFF and
                    disconnect chassis antilock harness connector C355 (or C288) from the EC-15 harness. Use ohmmeter to
                    measure resistance between "input" pin and the "output" pin at connector C355 (or C288) for the
                    sensor being tested. The resistance for the wheel speed sensor should be between 1500-2500 ohms.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">To check resistance of a REAR sensor</emph>, turn the key switch OFF, and
                    disconnect chassis antilock harness connector C350 from the EC-15 harness. Use ohmmeter to measure
                    resistance between "input" pin and "output" pin at connector C350 for the sensor being tested. The
                    resistance should be between 1500-2500 ohms.
                </para>
                <para>EXAMPLE: To measure resistance of a right front sensor on a 9600 model vehicle, use ohmmeter to
                    measure resistance between circuit 94AU (pin L) and circuit 94AT (pin H) at connector C355, on the
                    chassis antilock harness side of the connector. Tests are not to be made "into" the EC-15.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor resistance is not 1500-2500 ohms, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor resistance is 1500-2500 ohms, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the suspect sensor pigtail connector (two pin connector) from the antilock
                    chassis harness. Inspect the connector and visible part of the sensor lead, then check the
                    resistance between the input terminal and the output terminal on the sensor pigtail connector.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the resistance is not 1500-2500 ohms, replace the sensor and reconnect all
                        harnesses. Turn the key ON, and reset the EC-15. Turn key OFF, and back ON to run the "Initial
                        Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If sensor resistance is 1500-2500 ohms, locate the defect in the chassis antilock
                        harness causing the resistance to be out of specifications and repair. Reconnect all harnesses.
                        Turn the key ON, and reset the EC-15. Turn key OFF, and back ON to run the "Initial Start-up
                        Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the sensor gap by pushing the sensor in as far as it will go. Estimate if the
                    sensor moved more than 0.025". For sensor adjustment refer to "Exciter Ring/Sensor Installation"
                    located in this section.
                </para>
                <para>Check and note wheel bearing end play. If end play is more than 0.005", adjust.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor gap or bearing end play was out of specified limits, run the "Initial
                        Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>If after running the "Initial Start-up Procedure" the SAME LEDs are illuminated, go to
                            step 5.
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>If after running the "Initial Start-up Procedure" different LEDs are illuminated, proceed
                            to "Inspection For Illuminated LEDs - 1."
                        </para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor gap and bearing end play were not out of specified limits, go to step
                        5.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to "Exciter Ring/Sensor Installation." Inspect exciter ring for damage and runout,
                    and inspect the sensor for damage and proper gap to exciter ring. Correct any defects. After
                    reconnecting all electrical connections, turn key ON and reset the EC-15 by passing a magnet over
                    the RESET in the LED window. Turn key OFF, then turn key ON and run the "Initial Start-up
                    Procedure." If the "Initial Start-up Procedure" is unsuccessful, note condition of the LEDs.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If different LEDs are illuminated, perform "Inspection For Illuminated LEDs - 1."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the SAME LEDs are illuminated, go to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the suspect sensor, then turn key on and reset the EC-15. Turn key OFF and then
                    turn key ON and run "Initial Start-up Procedure." If the "Initial Start-up Procedure" is again
                    unsuccessful, note condition of the LEDs.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If different LEDs are illuminated, perform "Inspection For Illuminated LEDs - 1."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the SAME LEDs are illuminated, replace the EC-15 controller. Reset the LEDs and
                        rerun the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">To check resistance of a FRONT sensor</emph>, turn the key switch OFF and
                    disconnect chassis antilock harness connector C355 (or C288) from the EC-15 harness. Use ohmmeter to
                    measure resistance between "input" pin and the "output" pin at connector C355 (or C288) for the
                    sensor being tested. The resistance for the wheel speed sensor should be between 1500-2500 ohms.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">To check resistance of a REAR sensor</emph>, turn the key switch OFF, and
                    disconnect chassis antilock harness connector C350 from the EC-15 harness. Use ohmmeter to measure
                    resistance between "input" pin and "output" pin at connector C350 for the sensor being tested. The
                    resistance should be between 1500-2500 ohms.
                </para>
                <para>EXAMPLE: To measure resistance of a right front sensor on a 9600 model vehicle, use ohmmeter to
                    measure resistance between circuit 94AU (pin L) and circuit 94AT (pin H) at connector C355, on the
                    chassis antilock harness side of the connector. Tests are not to be made "into" the EC-15.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor resistance is not 1500-2500 ohms, go to step 8.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the sensor resistance is 1500-2500 ohms, replace the EC-15 controller and run the
                        "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the suspect sensor pigtail connector (two pin connector) from the antilock
                    chassis harness. Inspect the connector and visible part of the sensor lead, then check the
                    resistance between the input terminal and the output terminal on the sensor pigtail connector.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the resistance is not 1500-2500 ohms, replace the sensor and reconnect all
                        harnesses. Turn the key ON, and reset the EC-15. Turn key OFF, and back ON to run the "Initial
                        Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If sensor resistance is 1500-2500 ohms, locate the defect in the chassis antilock
                        harness causing the resistance to be out of specifications and repair. Reconnect all harnesses.
                        Turn the key ON, and reset the EC-15. Turn key OFF, and back ON to run the "Initial Start-up
                        Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402233">Figure 33</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402234">Figure 34</hotlnk>, and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402235">Figure 35</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402233" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402233.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Testing the Wheel Sensor (Part 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402234" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402234.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Testing the Wheel Sensor (Part 2)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402235" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402235.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Testing the Wheel Sensor (Part 3)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing for False Failure Indication - Caused by Dash Light Relay</title>
            <para>This test is performed when the yellow antilock warning light located on the instrument panel is
                illuminated indicating a system defect, but no red LEDs are illuminated on the EC-15 controller.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the EC-15 LEDs by turning the ignition key ON and holding a magnet on the RESET of
                    the EC-15 diagnostic window, then note that all LEDs should be illuminated while the magnet is in
                    place.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If all the LEDs are not illuminated during the reset, replace the EC-15
                        controller.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If all LEDs illuminate during the reset, go to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the magnet and turn the ignition key OFF. Disconnect the chassis antilock harness
                    at connector C355 (or C288) from the EC-15 harness. Turn the key to the ON position and note the
                    yellow antilock warning light on the instrument panel.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light is not illuminated, replace the EC-15 controller.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the warning light is still illuminated, do not reconnect the chassis harness to
                        the EC-15 harness at this time, but go to step 3.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key switch OFF, remove the warning light relay from the antilock cab harness
                    connector C361 (or C285). Use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at the harness relay connector
                    terminal for circuit 94E. Continuity should not be present.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity is present, locate the short to ground in circuit 94E and repair. Go
                        to step 4.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity is not present, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the warning light relay removed and the key switch OFF, use ohmmeter to check
                    continuity to ground at the relay harness connector for circuit 94-G.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present at circuit 94-G, locate the open in circuit
                        94-G and repair. Then go to step 5.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If circuit 94-G has continuity to ground, go to Step 5.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at circuit 94H or C361 (or C285). There
                    should not be continuity to ground with C355 (or C288) disconnected.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, locate the short to ground and repair. Go to
                        step 6.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, go to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key ON and check voltage to ground at circuit 94B/94C at C361 (or C285).</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, locate open or high resistance condition in
                        circuit 94B and repair. Go to step 7.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, go to step 7.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key OFF and install jumper between circuits 94-G and 94H at C361 (or C285). Then at
                    connector C355 (or C288) use ohmmeter to check continuity to ground at circuit 94H (pin K).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is not present, locate open condition in circuit 94H and
                        repair. Go to step 8.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If continuity to ground is present, go to step 8.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove jumper from previous step and re-install warning light relay. Turn key ON and
                    jumper circuit 94H (pin K) at C355 (or C288) to vehicle ground. Note operation of warning light on
                    instrument panel.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If light remains illuminated with jumper to ground installed, replace the relay.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the light is not illuminated when the jumper to ground is complete, reconnect
                        C355 (or C288) to the EC-15 harness. Turn key ON and reset the EC-15 LEDs. Turn key OFF and then
                        ON and run the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402236">Figure 36</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402237">Figure 37</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>This test is performed when the yellow antilock warning light located on the instrument panel is
                illuminated, indicating a system defect, but NO RED LEDs are illuminated.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402236" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402236.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Testing for False Indication - Caused by Dash Light Relay (Part 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402237" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402237.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Testing for False Indication - Caused by Dash Light Relay (Part 2)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing For False Failure Indication - Caused By Wheel Speed Components</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold a magnet on the RESET of the EC-15 diagnostic window and note that ALL LEDs are
                    illuminated while the magnet is in place.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If all the LEDs ARE NOT ILLUMINATED, replace the EC-15.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If all LEDs are illuminated, go to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the magnet from the EC-15, turn the ignition key to OFF, and inspect the
                    appropriate axle and wheel for the presence of an exciter ring and speed sensor. Check the "gap"
                    (distance between the sensor and the exciter ring) and push sensor in as far as it will go.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the vehicle at 10 mph or faster for 30 seconds or more. Turn off the power, then
                    repeat the "Initial Start-up Procedure."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402238">Figure 38</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402238" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402238.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Testing for False Failure Indication - Caused by Wheel Speed Components</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Testing ABS/Engine Brake Disable Circuits</title>
            <para>With an engine brake and the ABS system installed on a vehicle, whenever the ABS system detects
                impending wheel lockup, the EC-15 will turn the engine brake off and modulate brake service brake
                application. When the antilock system stops modulating the service brakes, the engine brake will be back
                in operation.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04022_15.xml" xrefid="x0402203">Circuit Diagram</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The engine brake system is controlled by the Engine Brake Relay C361 (or C286), that is part of the
                ABS cab harness. Power is delivered to the engine brake relay whenever the key is in the ON position on
                circuit 94E. Note that the relay is normally closed with the switch between relay terminals 1 and 3
                closed. Voltage is delivered to the engine brake system on circuit 24E when the key is ON. When the
                EC-15 determines that a wheel is about to enter a lockup condition, the ground switch in the EC-15
                closes and grounds (circuit 94J) the C361 relay control coil, energizing the relay and opening the
                circuit feeding the engine brake system, disabling the engine brake operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Relay - Test 1</title>
            <para>This test will be performed if, during the "Initial Startup Procedure" (step 6), the engine brake
                relay does not "chatter."
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to the "DIAGNOSING THE INITIAL START-UP TEST PROCEDURE." Notice in step 6 that
                    during the test procedure, the engine brake relay will energize 5 or 6 times, making a "chattering"
                    sound. With engine brake OFF, run the "Initial Startup Procedure" and listen for the chattering of
                    the engine brake relay.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the relay chatters, it would indicate that the relay is functioning properly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the relay did not chatter, go to step 2.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and replace the relay with known good relay. Then run the "Initial Start-up
                    Procedure."
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the relay chatters, it would indicate that the relay is functioning properly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the relay did not chatter, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the engine brake relay from harness connector C361 (or C286). With key ON, check
                    voltage to ground at relay control coil feed circuit, 94C of C361 (or C286).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, locate defect in feed circuit 94C, then repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the relay in C361 (or C286), then remove circuit 94J from C355 (or C288) on
                    the chassis side of the connector. With key ON, check voltage to ground at Circuit 94J.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is present, verify that the relay is not defective. If not defective,
                        replace the EC-15 controller.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is not present, locate the open/short condition in circuit 94J between
                        connectors C361 (or C286) and C355 (or C288), then repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402239">Figure 39</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402239" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402239.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Engine Brake Relay Test 1</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Engine Brake Test 2</title>
            <para>Engine brake does not operate. This test determines if the ABS engine brake relay is providing voltage
                to the Engine Brake System. If voltage is being delivered, and the Engine Brake System does not operate,
                then the problem is not with the ABS circuits, but in the Engine Brake Circuit. Refer to GROUP 08 -
                ELECTRICAL for troubleshooting information.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the engine brake relay C361 (or C286) with another like relay from a different
                    location and retry the engine brake operation. If it still does not operate, go to step 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key ON, check voltage at connection where either:</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">circuit 24E (with 96/9700 model) OR</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">circuit 24A (with 93/9400 models w/electronic engine) OR</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">circuit 24 (with 93/9400 models w/o electronic engines)</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">of the ABS cab harness connects to the primary cab harness. See following table for the
                    circuit number of primary cab harness circuit connecting to circuit 24E of the ABS cab harness.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, the ABS engine brake relay is operating properly,
                        delivering voltage to the engine brake system.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, go to step 3.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0402204" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Primary Cab Harness Circuit Numbers</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="72pt"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="72pt"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="360pt"/>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">ABS CIRCUIT</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">MODEL</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">CONNECTS TO PRIMARY CAB HARNESS CIRCUIT/ENGINE INFO</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>24E</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>96/9700</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24E with CAT 3406B N/PEEC &#38; CUMMINS 91L10 STC &#38; 91N14 STC</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24A with CAT 3176</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24AC with CUMMINS 91L10 CELECT &#38; 91N14 CELECT</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24W/24Y with CAT 3406B PEEC</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>24</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>93/9400</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>13B/24 with CAT 3406B N/PEEC &#38; CUMMINS 91L10 STC AND 91N14 STC</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>24A</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>93/9400</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24A with CAT 3176</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>24AC with CUMMINS 91L10 CELECT &#38; 91N14 CELECT</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key ON, check the voltage to ground at C361 (or C286) harness connector at
                    circuit 24E (96/9700) or 24A (93/9400 w/ electronic engine) or 24 (93/9400 n/ electronic engine).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is not present, locate the open condition in circuit 24E, then
                        repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If battery voltage is present, go to step 4.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the key ON, check voltage at C361 (or C286) at circuits 94C/94F and 94F. (NOTE:
                    With a 93/9400 model with an electronic engine, check circuits 94C and 24.)
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is not present at circuits identified in step 4, locate the open
                        condition in the feed circuit, then repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is present at feed circuits identified in step 4, go to step 5.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove circuit 94J from connector C361 (or C286), with key ON check for voltage at
                    circuit 24E at C361.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is not present, replace the relay.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltage is present at 24E, go to step 6.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With key OFF and circuit 94J removed from C361 (or C286), remove circuit 94J from
                    terminal "B" at at chassis side of C355 (or C288) connector. Then use ohmmeter and check circuit 94J
                    for continuity to ground.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If 94J has continuity to ground, locate the short to ground then repair.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If circuit 94J is not shorted to ground, replace the EC-15 controller.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402240">Figure 40</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402240" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402240.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Engine Brake Relay Test 2</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exciter Ring/Wheel Sensor: Adjustment</title>
            <para>To adjust the wheel sensors, push the sensor into the bushing (on front axle) or into the mounting
                block (rear axle) as far as it will go. The sensor will bottom out against the exciter ring, then as the
                exciter ring rotates, the sensor will self-adjust. To adjust or check adjustment of the rear wheel
                sensor, the brake drum must be removed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exciter Ring/Wheel Sensor: Inspection</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The
                    <emph type="bold">front axle sensor</emph>
                    can be removed from the axle side of the steering knuckle by pulling the sensor out. Inspect the
                    sensor lead, the connector and the sensor for damage. Replace if damaged. To install, push the
                    sensor into the bushing as far as it will go.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The
                    <emph type="bold">rear axle sensor</emph>
                    removal requires that the wheels and brake drum first be removed. Inspect the sensor lead, the
                    connector and the sensor for damage. Replace if damaged. To install, push the sensor into the
                    bushing as far as it will go.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the
                    <emph type="bold">exciter rings</emph>
                    for damage by removing the brake drum from the wheel hub. If damaged, the exciter ring should be
                    replaced. Observe the exciter ring, noting that it is properly seated on the wheel hub. To inspect
                    for exciter ring runout with respect to the installed sensor, (with drum removed) push the sensor in
                    against the exciter ring. Using a feeler gauge, slowly rotate the wheel hub observing the clearance
                    between the exciter ring and the sensor. The gap must be between 0 and 0.025 inch for proper signal
                    output.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exciter Ring/Wheel Sensor: Remove and Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Exciter Ring</emph>
                    - To remove the exciter ring, first remove the brake drum from the wheel hub. Then remove the hub
                    from the vehicle. Using a suitable puller,
                    <emph type="bold">lightly heat</emph>
                    the exciter ring to expand it and remove from wheel assembly.
                </para>
                <para>To install the exciter ring on the wheel, uniformly heat soak the exciter ring to a temperature of
                    approximately 200 degrees Fahrenheit. It is recommended that the exciter ring be heated by placing
                    it in a 200-degree-Fahrenheit (approximate) bath (water or oil) until the desired temperature is
                    achieved. Then install the exciter ring onto the wheel hub, taking care to fully seat the exciter
                    ring, then allow the exciter ring to cool and "shrink fit" on the wheel hub.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not heat with a torch as the exciter ring may develop hot spots, causing the
                        exciter ring to distort.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>Install the hub to the axle (less the brake drum) and adjust the wheel bearings (refer to SERVICE
                    MANUAL, Group 17). The bearing end play should not exceed .005 inch. Install the sensor and then
                    inspect for runout as described in step 3 of "Inspection." Install the brake drum after the
                    inspection is complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Sensor Retainers</emph>
                    - To replace the sensor retainer, remove old retainer and insert new retainer from axle side. Push
                    into sensor bushing (front axle) or into sensor mounting block (rear axle) until retainer tongues
                    are against the sensor bushing or mounting block.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0402241" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402241.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Typical Front Axle, Wheel Sensor Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SENSOR BUSHING (PART OF KNUCKLE ASSY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SENSOR RETAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD (CONNECTS TO CHASSIS ANTILOCK HARNESS)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Front Sensor</emph>
                    - Install the sensor into the retainer and sensor bushing from the backside of the steering knuckle.
                    Push the sensor as far as possible through the sensor bushing. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402241">Figure 41</hotlnk>. No further adjustment is necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Rear Sensor</emph>
                    - Install the sensor into retainer and sensor mounting block from the axle side in a horizontal
                    position with the "cable end" of the sensor positioned as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402242">Figure 42</hotlnk>
                    or
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402243">Figure 43</hotlnk>, depending on suspension type. Push the sensor in as
                    far as possible through the mounting block. No further adjustment is necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0402242" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402242.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Typical Rear Sensor Installation With Air Suspension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REF REAR AXLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SENSOR MOUNTING BLOCK (PART OF AXLE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER (USE ONLY INTERNATIONAL RETAINER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SENSOR SHOWN REMOVED</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. REF AXLE FLANGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES - REF</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402243" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402243.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Typical Sensor Installation With 4-Spring Suspension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REF REAR AXLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SENSOR MOUNTING BLOCK (PART OF AXLE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER (USE ONLY INTERNATIONAL RETAINER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SENSOR SHOWN REMOVED</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. REF AXLE FLANGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES - REF</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x040221a">
            <title>Troubleshooting Record Sheet</title>
            <para>Technician's Name______________________________________________________</para>
            <para>Date ____________________ Time ______________</para>
            <para>Location____________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>Vehicle Number ______________</para>
            <para>Vehicle Mileage _____________Miles</para>
            <para>Check LEDs illuminated:</para>
            <para>__FRONT __MID __REAR __RIGHT __LEFT __NOD __SENS __ECU __VOLT</para>
            <para>Steps Taken, Comments:</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>Check LEDs illuminated:</para>
            <para>__ FRONT __MID __REAR __RIGHT __LEFT __NOD __SENS __ECU __VOLT</para>
            <para>Steps Taken, Comments:</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>Check LEDs illuminated:</para>
            <para>__ FRONT __MID __REAR __RIGHT __LEFT __NOD __SENS __ECU __VOLT</para>
            <para>Steps Taken, Comments:</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
            <para>__________________________________________________________________________</para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
