<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - SYSTEM MAINTENANCE - PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048401" graphiccount="8">
        <title>PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>During bleeding procedures, brake fluid level must not be allowed to fall below the MIN mark
                        on the Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. The MC reservoir should be regularly checked and filled
                        to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid. Failure to keep the brake reservoir level
                        above the MIN mark could result in more air entering the system, making it impossible to
                        effectively bleed the system.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not add fluid above the MAX mark. When the system is depressurized during service, fluid
                        stored in the accumulators is returned to the MC reservoir. If the reservoir is filled above the
                        MAX mark a fluid spill could occur when these conditions exists.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Each bleeding procedure may be performed as a standalone procedure or in conjunction with
                        installation or other bleeding procedures. In this section, the bleeding procedures are provided
                        as standalone procedures including all of the necessary preparation steps. When a bleed
                        procedure is referenced from another procedure, it is not necessary to repeat preparation steps
                        that are duplicated.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Pressure bleeding is REQUIRED to properly bleed the Full Power Brake system. It requires the use of a
                pressure bleeder kit, a regulated, clean pressure source with gauge, tubing and adapter. Pressure
                bleeder kits are available from a number of manufacturers and include instructions for use. Do not
                attempt to use a vacuum bleeder on this system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Required bleed equipment:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>One clean graduated glass or plastic bottle/receptacle. #</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>One rubber/plastic bleed hose (preferably transparent). #</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Suitable crow's foot adapters for torque wrench (bleeder screws and brake lines).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pressurized fill and bleed equipment. Either of the following three types may be used:</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Fluid over fluid. Provides brake fluid (under pressure) from an external tank to the
                                Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. Regulated shop air may be used as the pressure source.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Air over fluid. Pressurizes the master cylinder reservoir with clean, dry, regulated
                                shop air. Air regulator/filter ZTSE4757-1, or equivalent, is required.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Air over fluid. Pressurizes the master cylinder reservoir with regulated dry
                                nitrogen.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>One MC reservoir cap adapter (International Service Tool - ZTSE4678).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A sufficient supply of new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para># (must be impervious to the effects of brake fluid).</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl04048401a">
            <title>Master Cylinder (MC) Circuit Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If the parking brake (SAHR) circuit is to be bled as part of this service, the parking brake
                        cable must be disconnected. If the SAHR canister is operable, this should be done before
                        depressurizing the brake system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl04048401c">SAHR POWERED PARKING BRAKE CIRCUIT BLEEDING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                        for instructions on disconnecting the cable. After the cable is disconnected, return to this
                        point and complete all other bleeding procedures before performing the parking brake bleed
                        procedure.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404833">FIGURE 37</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404833" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404833" filename="../figg04/G0404833.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Location of Motor Fuses In Engine Compartment</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FUSE COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FUSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COWL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FUSE PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404834" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404834" filename="../figg04/G0404834.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Location of Diagnostic Connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DIAGNOSTIC CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DASH TRIM PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER / BODY CONTROLLER (ESC/BC)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404834">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>. Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the brake fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the pressure bleeder according to the instructions provided with the
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a fluid bleeder system is used, fill the pressure bleeder with new specified brake
                            fluid from a sealed container.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If an air bleeder system is used,
                            <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the MC reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                            to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark during the bleed procedure. A
                            typical air-over-fluid bleeder setup using service tools ZTSE4757-1 and ZTSE4678 is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404882">FIGURE 39</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service tool adapter (ZTSE4678) between the bleed equipment and the MC
                    reservoir filler neck. Ensure that the adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler
                    neck.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 2.4 bar (35 PSI) pressure on the MC reservoir with the bleeding equipment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit bleeder hose onto one relay valve bleeder screw located on the HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404835">FIGURE 40</hotlnk>. (NOTE: Both MC circuits can be bled at the same time
                    by connecting two bleeder bottles.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404882" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404880A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Typical Air-Over-Fluid Bleeder Setup</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SERVICE TOOL ADAPTER (ZTSE4678)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR REGULATOR/FILTER (ZTSE4757-1)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404835" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404835" filename="../figg04/G0404835.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Bleeder Screws on HCU</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BLEEDER PORT - PRIMARY MC CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MC INPUT PORT - PRIMARY CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MC INPUT PORT - SECONDARY CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BLEEDER PORT - SECONDARY MC CIRCUIT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Submerge free end of bleeder hose into the bleed bottle. (Note the fluid level in the
                    bottle before starting.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the 7 mm bleeder screw until the fluid begins to flow (about 3/4 turn). After
                    draining 250 cc (8.5 oz) of fluid, check the stream for air bubbles. When no further air bubbles
                    enter the bleed bottle, close the bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bleeder hose and torque the bleeder screw to 4 to 4.5 Nm (35.4 to 39.8
                    Lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If only one MC circuit was bled, repeat the previous four steps with the second bleeder
                    screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the wheel calipers are to be bled, refer to the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl04048401b">BRAKE CALIPER CIRCUIT BLEEDING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the SAHR canister circuit is to be bled, refer to the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl04048401c">SAHR CANISTER CIRCUIT BLEEDING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no further bleeding procedures are to be performed, connect the battery and install
                    the two pump motor fuses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release pressure from the MC reservoir via the bleed equipment. Disconnect bleed
                    equipment from MC reservoir filler neck and install the MC reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill (or drain) the MC reservoir to the MAX mark. Use new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid
                    from a sealed container if filling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the MC reservoir cap is installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you were referred to this procedure from an installation procedure, return to the
                    original procedure now; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), refer to Section
                5,
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl04048401b">
            <title>Brake Caliper Circuit Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404833">FIGURE 37</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404834">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>
                    . Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the brake fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the pressure bleeder according to the instructions provided with the
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a fluid bleeder system is used, fill the pressure bleeder with new specified brake
                            fluid from a sealed container.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If an air bleeder system is used,
                            <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the MC reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                            to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark during the bleed procedure. A
                            typical air-over-fluid bleeder setup is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404882">FIGURE 39</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service tool adapter (ZTSE4678) between the bleed equipment and the MC
                    reservoir filler neck. Ensure that the adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler
                    neck.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 2.4 bar (35 PSI) pressure on the MC reservoir with the bleeding equipment.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If all wheel ends are being bled, they should be bled in the following order: right rear, left
                        rear, right front, left front.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit bleeder hose onto the caliper bleeder screw at the first wheel end.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Submerge free end of bleeder hose into the bleed bottle. (Note the fluid level in the
                    bottle before starting.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the bleeder screw until the fluid begins to flow (about 3/4 turn). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404836">FIGURE 41</hotlnk>. After draining 250 cc (8.5 oz) of fluid, check the
                    stream for air bubbles. When no further air bubbles enter the bleed bottle, close the bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bleeder hose and torque the bleeder screw to 12 to 16 Nm (8.6 to 11.5
                    Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404836" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404836" filename="../figg04/G0404836.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Typical Caliper Bleeding Setup</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 10 through 13 for the other calipers being bled.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If other bleeding procedures are to be performed, proceed to those procedures at this
                    time. If no further bleeding procedures are to be performed, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function from the EOL pull down
                    menu. This function helps clear air from the system by depressurizing and repressurizing both
                    accumulators. A dialog box will indicate when the function is complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release pressure from the MC reservoir via the bleed equipment. Disconnect bleed
                    equipment from MC reservoir filler neck and install the MC reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function again by selecting DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS from the
                    EOL pull down menu.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function has completed, fill (or drain) the MC reservoir
                    to the MAX mark. Use new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container if filling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the MC reservoir cap is installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you were referred to this procedure from an installation procedure, return to the
                    original procedure now; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function in the following steps should correct the problem. After completing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function, both accumulators should be fully charged as indicated on the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                screen. If an accumulator is still not charging correctly refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl04048401c">
            <title>SAHR Parking Brake Circuit Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <para>Before bleeding the SAHR circuit, the parking brake cable must be disconnected from the SAHR canister.
                This ensures that the SAHR piston achieves the full stroke and forces most of the fluid volume out of
                the SAHR canister, thus moving any trapped air into the bleeder screw area.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While removing a parking brake cable, only the threaded rod should rotate. If the cable is to
                        be reused, do not allow the cable to twist during removal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the parking brake cable. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404837">FIGURE 42</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the parking brake system is
                            <emph type="bold">inoperable</emph>, disconnect the cable as follows:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Install wheel chocks, place the transmission in P, PB or N, and turn the key to
                                    OFF.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using a 15 mm wrench to hold the SAHR canister shaft, loosen the jam nut on
                                    the threaded rod with a 16 mm wrench.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using the 15 mm wrench to hold the canister shaft, unscrew the threaded rod
                                    using an 8 mm wrench. The rod must be unscrewed approximately 2.5 inches before the
                                    cable disconnects. The cable will exhibit some resistance while being unscrewed
                                    because it is under tension.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the parking brake system is
                            <emph type="bold">operable</emph>, disconnect the cable as follows:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Install wheel chocks, place the transmission in neutral (N),
                                    <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                                    Park (P and PB), and turn the key ON.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While pressing the brake pedal, press the dash mounted PARK BRAKE switch to
                                    release the parking brake. This will extend the SAHR canister shaft and relieve the
                                    tension on the parking brake cable.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using a 15 mm wrench to hold the SAHR canister shaft, loosen the jam nut on
                                    the threaded rod with a 16 mm wrench.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using the 15 mm wrench to hold the canister shaft, unscrew the threaded rod
                                    using an 8 mm wrench. The rod must be unscrewed approximately 2.5 inches before the
                                    cable disconnects.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Turn the key to OFF.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404837" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404837" filename="../figg04/G0404837.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Park Brake Cable Connection to SAHR Canister</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 16mm JAM NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SAHR CANISTER SHAFT 15mm</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADJUSTMENT INDICATOR, 'HASH' MARK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. THREADED ROD 8mm</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the key is OFF, and place the transmission in either the P, PB or N
                    position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the brake system motors. They are in
                    the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404833">FIGURE 37</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404834">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>
                    . Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the brake fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the pressure bleeder according to the instructions provided with the
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a fluid bleeder system is used, fill the pressure bleeder with new specified brake
                            fluid from a sealed container.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If an air bleeder system is used,
                            <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the MC reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                            to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark during the bleed procedure. A
                            typical air-over-fluid bleeder setup is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404882">FIGURE 39</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service tool adapter (ZTSE4678) between the bleed equipment and the MC
                    reservoir filler neck. Ensure that the adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler
                    neck.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 2.4 bar (35 PSI) pressure on the MC reservoir with the bleeding equipment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit bleeder hose onto the bleeder screw on the SAHR canister manifold. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404838">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>. Submerge free end of bleeder hose into the bleed
                    bottle. (Note the fluid level in the bottle before starting.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the bleeder screw until the fluid begins to flow (about 3/4 turn). After draining
                    250 cc (8.5 oz) of fluid, check the stream for air bubbles. When no further air bubbles enter the
                    bleed bottle, close the bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bleeder hose and torque the bleeder screw to 12 to 16 Nm (8.6 to 11.5
                    Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404838" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G0404838" filename="../figG04/G0404815.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Location of SAHR Bleeder Screw</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. OUTPUT SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MOUNTING STUDS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BLEED PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE FLUID PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CUT-OFF SOLENOID VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. TRAVEL SWITCH</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function from the EOL pull down
                    menu. This function helps clear air from the system by depressurizing and repressurizing both
                    accumulators. A dialog box will indicate when the function is complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release pressure from the MC reservoir via the bleed equipment. Disconnect bleed
                    equipment from MC reservoir filler neck and install the MC reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, deplete the accumulators again by selecting the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS
                    function from the EOL pull down menu.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function has completed, fill (or drain) the MC reservoir
                    to the MAX mark. Use new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container if filling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the MC reservoir cap is installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before installing a parking brake cable, inspect the cable strands where visible. If the
                        strands are damaged or starting to unwind, replace the cable.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While installing a parking brake cable, only the threaded rod should rotate. Do not allow the
                        cable to twist during installation.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the parking brake cable to the SAHR canister as follows:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place the transmission in neutral (N),
                            <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                            Park (P or PB), and turn the key ON.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>While pressing the brake pedal, press the dash mounted PARK BRAKE switch to release the
                            parking brake. This should extend the SAHR canister shaft to allow easier connection of the
                            parking brake cable.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>If the SAHR shaft is extended, proceed to step 21E.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If the SAHR shaft is NOT extended, proceed to the following step.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Connect the EZ-TECH
                            <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                            to the diagnostic connector and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use TOOLBOX to release the parking brake (use the 'Component Tests' menu). Releasing the
                            parking brake pressurizes the SAHR canister and extends the canister shaft.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Lubricate the threaded rod end of the parking brake cable by placing a small amount of
                            grease at the point where the threaded rod contacts the 'ball' at the end of the inner cable
                            (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404839">FIGURE 44</hotlnk>). This will prevent the inner cable from
                            twisting when the threaded rod is turned.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Screw the threaded rod end of the cable into the SAHR canister shaft. While using a 15 mm
                            wrench to hold the shaft, use an 8 mm wrench to continue threading the rod into the shaft
                            until the 'hash' mark on the threaded rod is flush with the end of the shaft. Refer to
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404837">FIGURE 42</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>While using the 15 mm wrench to hold the SAHR canister shaft, use a 16 mm wrench to
                            tighten the threaded rod jam nut against the end of the shaft.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the transmission to either the P or PB position (if available) and turn the key OFF.
                    Verify that the parking brake applies.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you were referred to this procedure from an installation procedure, return to the
                    original procedure now; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to ON. Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function in the following steps should correct the problem. After completing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function, both accumulators should be fully charged as indicated on the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                screen. If an accumulator is still not charging correctly refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404839" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404839" filename="../figg04/G0404839.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 44. Parking Brake Cable Lubrication Point</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PARKING BRAKE CABLE SHEATH</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. THREADED ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INNER CABLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LUBRICATE ON THIS SIDE OF CABLE END BALL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048400.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048402.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
