<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - BENDIX E6-TREADLE AND E7-SUSPENDED PEDAL TYPE (FOOT) BRAKE VALVES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>BENDIX E6-TREADLE AND E7-SUSPENDED PEDAL TYPE (FOOT) BRAKE VALVES</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="2">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The (foot) brake valve is the control unit of the air brake system. It provides the operator of the
                vehicle a means of applying or releasing the vehicle brakes.
            </para>
            <para>The two types of Bendix (foot) brake valves used are E6 treadle type (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400218">Figure 18</hotlnk>
                ) and E7 suspended type (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400219">Figure 19</hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400218" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400218" filename="../figg04/G0400218.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Bendix E6-Treadle (Foot) Brake Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PRIMARY DELIVERY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SECONDARY DELIVERY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SECONDARY SUPPLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0400219" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400219" filename="../figg04/G0400219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Bendix E7-Suspended Pedal Type (Foot) Brake Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SECONDARY SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY DELIVERY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PRIMARY SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PRIMARY DELIVERY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Both the treadle and suspended (foot) brake valves are equipped with two separate supply and delivery
                circuits for service and emergency braking, each providing the driver with a graduated control for
                applying and releasing the vehicle brakes.
            </para>
            <para>The primary circuit is that portion of the valve between the spring seats which contacts the plunger
                and the relay piston. The secondary circuit is that portion between the relay piston and exhaust cavity.
            </para>
            <para>The primary circuit is similar in operation to a standard single circuit air brake valve. Under normal
                operating conditions, the secondary circuit is similar to a quick release valve.
            </para>
            <para>Both the primary and secondary circuits of the (foot) brake valve use a common exhaust check valve.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_47.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_49.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
