<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - DISASSEMBLY - CYLINDER HEAD</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CYLINDER HEAD</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04004_19.xml" xrefid="f0400411">Figure 11</hotlnk>for all numbers in parentheses.
        </para>
        <para>Remove the four cylinder head cap screws (12) and tap the head with a soft mallet to break the gasket
            seal. Scrape off any gasket material from the cylinder head and crankcase.
        </para>
        <para>Before disassembling the discharge valve mechanism, measure and record the discharge valve travel (from
            closed to completely open).
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">lf the measured discharge valve travel
                <emph type="bold">does not exceed</emph>
                .032 inches, the discharge valve stop need not be removed. lt is recommended that the cylinder head body
                be replaced if the discharge valve stop requires replacement. In the event this is not possible the
                following procedure can be followed.
            </para>
            <para>To remove the discharge valve stop (15), support the machined surface of the cylinder head on an arbor
                press bed and gently press the stop from the top of the head and out the bottom. Be sure to allow
                sufficient clearance for the stop between the press bed and the bottom of the cylinder head. The valve
                stop bore in the cylinder head must be inspected for excessive scoring. A new cylinder head body must be
                used if scoring is excessive.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a 9/16" Allen wrench, remove the discharge valve seat, valve, and valve spring (18,
                17, 16).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the unloader stop and 0-ring (11, 13).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the unloader piston and 0-ring (4, 3).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert the lugs of a spanner wrench into the holes of the inlet valve stop (10) and remove
                the inlet valve stop along with the inlet valve (8), valve seat (7), unloader gasket (6) and spring (5).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Reference Williams adjustable face spanner #483.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the unloader piston bushing (2) for nicks, wear, corrosion and scoring. lt is
                recommended that the cylinder head body be replaced.if it is determined that the unloader piston bushing
                requires replacement. lf this is not possible, the bushing can be pressed out of the head using the same
                procedure presented in Step 2 of this disassembly section.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>lf the bushing is pressed out and the cylinder head casting is damaged in the process,
                        cylinder head repair is not recommended. Pressing in the replacement bushing will result in air
                        or water leakage.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
