<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - HCU PUMPS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04050611" graphiccount="0">
        <title>HCU PUMPS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The full power brake system is a pressurized system that achieves pressures of up to 2320 psi.
                        This pressure
                        <emph type="boldundersc">IS NOT</emph>
                        reduced by switching the ignition off or removing battery power. Prior to servicing this system,
                        the depressurization procedures
                        <emph type="boldundersc">MUST BE PERFORMED EXACTLY AS PRESENTED</emph>. Failure to depressurize
                        the system may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Both pumps are located in cavities in the HCU, and are accessed from the bottom of the HCU. The
                retaining plug for the secondary system pump is visible on the bottom of the HCU (
                <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405048">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>). While this pump is
                located nearest the front of the HCU, it pressurizes the rear axle brake system.
            </para>
            <para>The retaining plug for the primary system pump is located under the relay valve assembly. This pump
                pressurizes the front axle brake system. Accessing the primary system pump requires moving the relay
                valve assembly. This can be done without disconnecting the master cylinder brake lines; therefore, it is
                not necessary to bleed the master cylinder circuit after performing this procedure.
            </para>
            <para>If both HCU pumps are being replaced, replace the secondary pump first. It is unnecessary to perform
                the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS steps after replacing the first pump. After replacing the first pump proceed
                directly to the removal of the second pump, skipping any common preparation steps. Performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS steps after replacing the second pump will remove air from both pump circuits.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Secondary HCU Pump Removal and Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses (A3 and A4) that provide
                    power to the brake system motors. The fuses are in the Power Distribution Center (PDC) located near
                    the master cylinder (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050601.xml" xrefid="f0405032">FIGURE 32</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose at the inlet to the HCU reservoir. Place the
                    clamp midway between the HCU reservoir inlet and the crossmember, being careful not to damage the
                    reservoir inlet. In some vehicle applications the rubber section of the low pressure hose is too
                    short to provide a leakproof clamp at this location. If necessary, clamp the low pressure hose 4 or
                    5 inches below the master cylinder outlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050605.xml" xrefid="f0405038">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unlatch and disconnect both electrical connectors from the ECU module, and position the
                    loose harnesses out of the way. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405048">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050606.xml" xrefid="f0405039">FIGURE 39</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the bottom surface of the HCU. Be careful not to contaminate the
                    connectors/pins of the ECU.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before performing the following steps, position a container to collect any drained or spilled
                        brake fluid to ensure that no fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare a replacement pump for installation by lubricating both pump O-rings with clean
                    brake fluid; and then actuating the pump several times by depressing the spring-loaded pump button
                    by hand. Note: The initial force required to actuate the pump (depress the pump button) may be high.
                    After the first actuation the force required to depress the button should be reduced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 6 mm Allen wrench, remove the secondary pump retaining plug from the HCU (
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405049">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The condition of the pump bore is very important. Do not allow tools to damage the surface of
                        the bore.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following steps, do not damage the pump O-rings while installing the replacement pump.
                        The O-rings must be lubricated with clean brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <important>
                    <para>To minimize the amount of brake fluid spilled, insure that the replacement pump is prepared
                        and within reach
                        <emph type="bold">before</emph>
                        removing the pump.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using clean needle nose pliers (with a good grip) remove the secondary pump from the
                    bore. Allowing the pliers to slip could create metal shavings that must be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Immediately install the replacement pump. Carefully seat the pump into the bore, using
                    light hand pressure only. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405049">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the retaining plug is clean; then install the plug and torque it to 20 to 24
                    Nm (14.8 to 17.7 lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean spilled brake fluid from the surface of the HCU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the primary pump is being replaced, proceed directly to the PRIMARY HCU PUMP REMOVAL
                    AND INSTALLATION procedure, and complete the entire procedure. It is not necessary to return to this
                    procedure.
                </para>
                <para>If the primary pump is not being replaced, proceed to the next step.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>In the following step, insure that the ECU connectors are properly installed and latched to
                        prevent them from becoming disconnected. Failure to securely connect AND LATCH the ECU
                        connectors could result in loss of braking functions during vehicle operation. Failure to follow
                        this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the 2 electrical connectors to the HCU ECU. Secure the electrical connectors by
                    engaging the latches. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405048">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050606.xml" xrefid="f0405039">FIGURE 39</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamp(s) used to pinch the low pressure hose during removal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the MC reservoir up to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a
                    sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The fluid level in the MC reservoir may drop when pressure is applied in the following step.
                        Whenever the MC reservoir is pressurized with air
                        <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                        to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark. If necessary, remove pressure from the
                        reservoir and add brake fluid to the MAX mark.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using service tool adapter ZTSE4678 and regulator/filter ZTSE4757-1 (or equivalent),
                    pressurize the MC reservoir with filtered air regulated to 35 psi. Ensure that the adapter is
                    securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler neck, and that the air lines and connections are not
                    placing undue stress on the MC reservoir filler neck. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050401.xml" xrefid="f0405026">FIGURE 26</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the fluid level in the MC reservoir. If necessary, remove air pressure from the
                    reservoir and fill to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container.
                    Repressurize the MC reservoir to 35 psi, as in step 19.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function from the EOL pull down
                    menu. This function helps clear air from the HCU by depressurizing and repressurizing both
                    accumulators. A dialog box will indicate when the function is complete.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles equipped WITH ATC</emph>
                            - Select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;.
                            No user input is required. The changes in the accumulator pressures can be observed on the
                            TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic screen.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles WITHOUT ATC</emph>
                            - While depressing the brake pedal, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL
                            pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;. The pedal must remain depressed until the pressure in
                            BOTH accumulators begins to rise (as observed on the diagnostic screen), then release the
                            brake pedal.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the pressure from the MC reservoir and remove the pressure bleeder equipment.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the fluid in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark, then install the MC
                    reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, perform the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function two more times.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of these procedures to verify that the system is depressurized.
                        Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check system for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system before making
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050500.xml" xrefid="hl04050500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function in the following steps should correct the problem. After completing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function, both accumulators should be fully charged as indicated on the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                screen. If an accumulator is still not charging correctly refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050500.xml" xrefid="hl04050500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Primary HCU Pump Removal and Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When moving the relay valve assembly to gain access to the HCU pump,
                        <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                        disconnect the master cylinder brake lines. If these lines are disconnected, the master cylinder
                        circuit must be bled as indicated in the RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY Installation procedures.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare a replacement pump for installation by lubricating both pump O-rings with clean
                    brake fluid; and then actuating the pump several times by depressing the spring-loaded pump button
                    by hand. Note: The initial force required to actuate the pump (depress the pump button) may be high.
                    After the first actuation the force required to depress the button should be reduced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the relay valve assembly from the HCU, but
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                    disconnect the master cylinder brake lines. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="hl04050610">RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</hotlnk>
                    Removal procedures .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Taking care not to kink or bend the brake lines, reposition the relay valve assembly (
                    <emph type="bold">with brake lines attached</emph>) to allow access to the bottom of the HCU.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 6 mm Allen wrench, remove the primary pump retaining plug from the HCU (
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405049">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The condition of the pump bore is very important. Do not allow tools to damage the surface of
                        the bore.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following steps, do not damage the pump O-rings while installing the replacement pump.
                        The O-rings must be lubricated with clean brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <important>
                    <para>To minimize the amount of brake fluid spilled, insure that the replacement pump is prepared
                        and within reach
                        <emph type="bold">before</emph>
                        removing the pump.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using clean needle nose pliers (with a good grip) remove the primary pump from the bore.
                    Allowing the pliers to slip could create metal shavings that must be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Immediately install the replacement pump. Carefully seat the pump into the bore, using
                    light hand pressure only. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="f0405049">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the retaining plug is clean; then install the plug and torque it to 20 to 24
                    Nm (14.8 to 17.7 lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the relay valve assembly. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml" xrefid="hl04050610">RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</hotlnk>
                    Installation procedures . If the master cylinder brake lines were not disconnected, it is not
                    necessary to bleed the master cylinder circuit; however, the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR steps must be
                    performed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050612.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
