<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - EC-30 DIAGNOSTIC DISPLAY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EC-30 DIAGNOSTIC DISPLAY</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The EC-30 diagnostic display consists of nine red fault LEDs, one green power LED and an internal,
                magnetic reset switch. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404309">Figure 9</hotlnk>
                for illustration.
            </para>
            <para>No tools are needed to read the EC-30 diagnostic display. A fault displayed on the LEDs will always be
                accompanied by the illumination of the ABS warning lamp and/or the ATC active/warning lamp.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404309" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404309.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. EC-30 LED Diagnostic Display</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reading a Fault</title>
            <para>When a fault is detected, the EC-30 identifies the faulted component with the diagnostic LEDs. When a
                wheel speed sensor fault, or an ABS modulator fault is detected, the SEN or MOD LED will be accompanied
                by two location LEDs. An example is FRT-RHT-SEN. When these three LEDs are on, this is an indication of
                a fault on the front axle (FRT), right side (RHT), wheel speed sensor (SEN). For a complete explanation
                and troubleshooting of faults displayed by the LEDs, go to
                <hotlnk document="s04043_27.xml" xrefid="x0404301">Section F, Troubleshooting</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The red diagnostic LEDs only indicate active system faults. When a fault self-heals or is manually
                reset, the fault code remains in fault history. Fault history can be retrieved by using blink code
                diagnostics or a diagnostic tool.
            </para>
            <para>If faults occur on multiple components, the diagnostic LEDs will display one fault at a time. When the
                first fault is repaired and the EC-30 is reset, the next fault will be displayed on the LEDs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault Reset</title>
            <para>After the fault is corrected, the active fault code and LEDs can be reset by briefly holding a magnet
                in place at the RESET location of the diagnostic display. All of the LEDs will be on while the magnet is
                held in place. If one or more LEDs do not go on when the magnet is in place, replace the EC-30. When the
                magnet is removed from the reset location, only the green VLT diagnostic LED should remain on. If red
                LEDs are still on, active faults are still present in the system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An EC-30 self-configuration will occur if a magnet is held at the reset location for greater
                        than 20 seconds.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
