<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - park brake switch and knob (dash mOUNtEd)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048616" graphiccount="1">
        <title>park brake switch and knob (dash mOUNtEd)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The parking brake switch is an electrical switch located on the instrument panel. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404866">FIGURE 72</hotlnk>
                for typical component location information while performing the following procedures.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the knob from the Parking Brake switch. (Push the knob in slightly, rotate it 90
                    degrees counterclockwise and pull.) Retain the knob for use with the replacement switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the center and right wing plastic bezels from the instrument panel. Each bezel is
                    secured with 4 fasteners (one in each corner), and the center bezel must be removed first. Retain
                    all fasteners for use during installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 3 screws and lockwashers securing the switch assembly to the dash panel.
                    Retain the mounting hardware for use during installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the switch from behind the dash panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connector on the switch assembly pigtail from the wire
                    harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404866" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404866" filename="../figg04/G0404866.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 72. Typical Instrument Panel Bezel Removal/Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PARK BRAKE SWITCH LOCATION</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INSTRUMENT PANEL RIGHT WING BEZEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INSTRUMENT PANEL CENTER WING BEZEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a knob is on the replacement switch, remove it. (Push the knob in slightly, rotate it
                    90 degrees counterclockwise and pull.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the connector on the switch assembly pigtail to the wire harness, and position
                    the switch at its mounting location behind the dash panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the switch assembly at its mounting location using the 3 screws and lockwashers
                    removed previously.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the center and right wing plastic bezels onto the instrument panel, using the
                    hardware removed previously. Each bezel is secured with 4 fasteners (one in each corner), and the
                    center bezel must be installed last.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the knob onto the switch shaft by pushing it onto the shaft and rotating it 90
                    degrees in a clockwise direction. The graphics on the knob must be correctly oriented.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048615.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048617.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
