<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - SYSTEM LAYOUT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048208" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>SYSTEM LAYOUT</title>
        <para>A component location diagram of a typical Full Power Brakes system is illustrated in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404802">FIGURE 2</hotlnk>. A schematic diagram of the system is provided in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404803">FIGURE 3</hotlnk>. The Master Cylinder is mounted to the engine side of the cowl,
            in front of the driver. The wheel speed sensors are located at the wheel ends with the calipers and rotors.
            The Body Controller (ESC/BC) is mounted to the inside of the cowl, behind the instrument panel. The PARK
            BRAKE switch for the powered parking brake is located near the center of the dash. The Hydraulic Compact
            Unit is mounted on the inside of the left frame rail, behind the driver's position. The Spring Apply
            Hydraulic Release (SAHR) parking brake canister is mounted on the inside of the left frame rail, just ahead
            of the rear axle. The parking brake drum is located where the driveshaft connects to the rear axle.
        </para>
        <para>A low pressure hose connects the reservoir on the HCU to the reservoir on the master cylinder. This allows
            both reservoirs to be filled from the master cylinder location. Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404804">FIGURE 4</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0404802" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0404802" filename="../figg04/G0404802a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Full Power Brake System Component Layout</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PARK BRAKE SWITCH</callout1>
                <callout1>2. MASTER CYLINDER/RESERVOIR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>3. FOUNDATION BRAKES (ROTORS, CALIPERS, WHEEL SPEED SENSORS)</callout1>
                <callout1>4. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER / BODY CONTROLLER (ESC/BC)</callout1>
                <callout1>5. HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT INCL/ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT</callout1>
                <callout1>6. SPRING APPLY HYDRAULIC RELEASE (SAHR) PARK BRAKE CANISTER</callout1>
                <callout1>7. DRIVELINE PARKING BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0404803" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0404803" filename="../figg04/G0404803A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Figure 3. Schematic Diagram of the Full Power Brake System</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0404804" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0404804" filename="../figg04/G0404804.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Figure 4. Low Pressure Hose Connecting Master Cylinder and Hydraulic Compact Unit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT (HCU)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. MASTER CYLINDER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048207.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
