<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Meritor/WABCO Hydraulic ABS for Medium-Duty Trucks, Buses and Motor Home Chassis - COMPONENT REPLACEMENT -
        Brake Bleeding Procedures
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Brake Bleeding Procedures</title>
        <para>The following brake bleeding methods explain how to bleed the hydraulic ABS modulator assembly during
            installation, or in the event of air in the brake system. There are instructions for both pressure and
            manual bleeding procedures.
        </para>
        <para>These instructions include the procedure for bleeding both the master cylinder and the brake system. In
            some cases, for example, if you are replacing only the modulator assembly, it may not be necessary to bleed
            the master cylinder. If you have any questions, please contact the Meritor Service Center at 800-535-5560.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The modulator assembly must be handled with appropriate care and should not be exposed to
                    excessive impact or compressed air at the hydraulic ports prior to assembly.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Failure to bleed the system whenever any hydraulic system fitting is loosened or disconnected will
                    allow air to remain in the system. This will prevent the hydraulic pressure in the brake system from
                    rising enough to apply the brakes properly. This will cause the stopping distance to increase and
                    can result in serious personal injury.
                </para>
                <para>Properly discard hydraulic brake fluid that is removed from the brake system. Hydraulic brake
                    fluid that is removed can be contaminated and can cause damage, loss of braking and serious personal
                    injury.
                </para>
                <para>Use only the type of hydraulic brake fluid specified by the equipment manufacturer. Do not use or
                    mix different types of hydraulic brake fluid. The wrong hydraulic brake fluid will damage the rubber
                    parts of the brake caliper and can cause damage, loss of braking and serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Use DOT 3 or DOT 4 hydraulic brake fluid. Refer to the vehicle specifications to determine which
                    fluid to use.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Hydraulic brake fluid is a caustic substance. Contact with hydraulic brake fluid can cause skin
                    irritation. Do not let hydraulic brake fluid touch any painted surfaces, as it will remove the
                    paint. Hydraulic brake fluid may also damage certain non-metal surfaces. Do not let fluid get on
                    brake pads, shoes, rotors or disks.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
