<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION - CONTROLLER (ECU)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONTROLLER (ECU)</title>
        <para>The ECU controller houses the electronic control unit that regulates the antilock system. The ECU performs
            a system start-up self diagnostic test whenever the vehicle is started and then continues to monitor the
            antilock system during operation of the vehicle. The ECU uses the yellow instrument panel warning light and
            the warning light relay to communicate system performance to the driver. The ECU also incorporates a
            diagnostic LED window to provide additional system diagnostic information. See
            <hotlnk document="s04023_34.xml" xrefid="hl040231a">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <para>The ECU controller mounts on the antilock relay valve with four capscrews. The ECU is electrically
            connected through a 12-pin and 14-pin connector to the wheel sensors, brake modulators, and the cab antilock
            wire harness. The antilock relay valve functions as a service brake relay valve and contains no electronics
            of its own.
        </para>
        <para>The ECU assembly is supplied with electrical power by the vehicle electrical system. Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s04023_52.xml" xrefid="f0402348">Circuit Diagram</hotlnk>
            for this discussion.
        </para>
        <para>The ignition power source (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402305">Figure 5</hotlnk>
            ) to the ECU in the 8000 vehicle models is the J-1 battery feed stud. Ignition power is delivered from the
            J-1 battery feed stud on circuit 94 through a 30 amp in-line fuse (C298), and then to circuit 94A to the
            power relay (C283). The power relay is energized with the key switch turned to IGN. Voltage from the key
            switch uses circuit 13J to deliver power through an in-line 10 amp fuse (C299) to circuit 13K and through
            the power relay control coil and is grounded via circuit 94-GC and 11-G to G2. Once energized, the power
            relay allows ignition voltage to flow to the crank relay (C285) on circuit 94M.
        </para>
        <para>Power from the crank relay flows to the ECU harness connector (C288) pin J on circuit 94K through
            connector C378, to circuits 94A and 94L. The ECU assembly harness includes a ground cable (circuit 94-G)
            that is grounded to the vehicle frame. When voltage from the start switch energizes the crank relay during
            engine cranking, power to the ECU is shut OFF. The crank relay control coil is grounded through circuit
            94-GA, 94-GB, 94-GC, and 11-G to G2.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>During engine cranking, system voltage will on occasion drop below the operating limits of the
                    ECU. The system avoids this by de-energizing the ECU using the crank relay.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0402305" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0402305" filename="../figg04/g0402305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 5. 8000 ABS Power Circuit</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
