<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - ACCUMULATOR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04051607" graphiccount="2">
        <title>ACCUMULATOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The full power brake system is a pressurized system that achieves pressures of up to 2320 psi.
                        This pressure
                        <emph type="boldundersc">IS NOT</emph>
                        reduced by switching the ignition off or removing battery power. Prior to servicing this system,
                        the depressurization procedures
                        <emph type="boldundersc">MUST BE PERFORMED EXACTLY AS PRESENTED</emph>. Failure to depressurize
                        the system may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>The accumulators MUST NOT be removed until the system has been depressurized as described in
                        the procedures. It is possible for a removed accumulator to retain an internal pressure of up to
                        1087 psi. Before disposing of an accumulator, verify its warranty status. If the accumulator is
                        to be disposed of, it must be depressurized and its pressure chamber must be disabled. Failure
                        to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>New accumulators are precharged to a pressure of 1087 psi. Puncturing or piercing an
                        accumulator may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Because the accumulators are precharged, they have a limited shelf life. When replacing an
                        accumulator, note the expiration date on the replacement accumulator.
                    </para>
                </important>
                <important>
                    <para>Always replace the accumulators in pairs even if only one is diagnosed as defective.</para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. The fuses are bundled in the cowl wire harness located near the master cylinder
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051601.xml" xrefid="f0405132">FIGURE 32</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the outside of the Hydraulic Compact Unit (HCU) around and above the
                    accumulator mounting point.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a container to collect the drained brake fluid in the next step. Ensure that no
                    fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a strap wrench, remove the accumulator, (right hand thread).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the counterbore carefully. Verify that the O-ring seal was removed with the
                    accumulator. Plug the counterbore to ensure that no dust will get into the HCU. If the same
                    accumulator is to be reinstalled, plug the port on the accumulator to prevent contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the second accumulator by repeating steps 6 to 9.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>It is possible for a removed accumulator to retain an internal pressure of up to 1087 psi.
                        Before disposing of an accumulator, verify its warranty status. If the accumulator is to be
                        discarded, it must be depressurized and its pressure chamber must be disabled. Failure to follow
                        this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <important>
                    <para>Before disposing of used components, verify their warranty status. Contact Arvin Meritor
                        OnTrac at 866-668-7221 for instructions. Accumulators still under warranty must be returned
                        without depressurizing. Drilling the accumulators will void the warranty.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the accumulator(s) are to be discarded, perform the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl040516a">ACCUMULATOR DISPOSAL PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                    to depressurize the accumulator and disable its pressure chamber .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A new accumulator is precharged to a pressure of 1087 psi. Puncturing or piercing an
                        accumulator may result in personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug from the accumulator counterbore in the HCU. Clean the HCU counterbore
                    and the surrounding area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the O-ring on the new accumulator with clean brake fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new accumulator and tighten by hand until snug. Then, tighten the
                    accumulator using a torque wrench with a strap wrench attachment. Torque at the accumulator mounting
                    must be 58.8 to 67.8 Nm (43.4 to 50 Lbf-ft). To achieve this using a torque wrench with a strap
                    wrench head, use a torque range of 51.5 to 56.9 Nm (38 to 42 Lbf-ft), while keeping the wrench
                    handle in line with the centerline axis of the accumulator. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405142">FIGURE 42</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405142" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405142" filename="../figg04/g0405142.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Correct Torque Wrench Orientation</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the second accumulator by repeating steps 1 to 3.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure fluid is at or above the MAX mark in the Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. If
                    not, fill the reservoir up to the MAX mark with new, DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed
                    container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. The HCU pump motors will start and run for approximately 45
                    seconds. This will fill the accumulators and pressurize the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After pump motors stop, fill the MC reservoir up to the MAX mark with new, DOT 3 or DOT
                    4 brake fluid from a sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pump the brakes rapidly 4 times to activate both HCU pump motors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After pump motors stop, fill the MC reservoir up to the MAX mark with new, DOT 3 or DOT
                    4 brake fluid from a sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If accumulator leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE
                        making repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl04051607">ACCUMULATOR</hotlnk>
                        Removal procedure to verify that the system is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning
                        could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check accumulator connections for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the
                    system before making repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bleeding the system is not necessary.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl040516a">
            <title>Accumulator Disposal Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Before disabling an accumulator, verify its warranty status. Contact Arvin Meritor OnTrac at
                        866-668-7221 for instructions. Accumulators still under warranty must be returned without
                        depressurizing. Drilling the accumulators will void the warranty.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>An internal chamber in the accumulators is precharged with gas pressure to 1087 psi. Accumulators that
                are to be
                <emph type="bold">discarded</emph>
                must be depressurized and disabled, as described in the following procedure, before they can be
                scrapped.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>It is possible for a removed accumulator to retain an internal pressure of up to 1087 psi. To
                        prevent a discarded accumulator from posing a safety hazard, perform the following steps to
                        depressurize the accumulator and disable its pressure chamber. Failure to follow this warning
                        could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>The appropriate safety measures must be taken when performing the following procedure. Safety
                        goggles (not glasses) must be worn. The accumulator must be oriented correctly (see
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0405143">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>), and securely clamped in the drill press vise to
                        prevent it from rolling or falling. Any liquid spilled or drained from the accumulator should be
                        treated as waste brake fluid, and must be disposed of properly. Personnel should remain a safe
                        distance from the work area during this procedure, and/or a protective shield should be
                        positioned to prevent any projected metal shavings from reaching the drill operator and/or
                        nearby personnel. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal
                        injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0405143" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405143" filename="../figg04/g0405143.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Orientation of Accumulator for Drilling and Disposal</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CENTER-PUNCHED DRILLING POINT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WELDED SEAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREADED PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the accumulator on a drill press table using a vise or clamp that will allow the
                    accumulator to be oriented as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405143">FIGURE 43</hotlnk>. The drilling point will be on the opposite side of the
                    welded seam from the threaded port.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Center-punch the accumulator at the location to be drilled.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, a slight hissing sound may be heard when the wall of the accumulator is
                        pierced. Also, metal shavings may be blown away from the hole.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 3mm drill bit (1/8 inch will work), slowly and carefully drill approximately 1/2
                    inch into the accumulator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After releasing the internal pressure, the accumulator may be scrapped.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051606.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051608.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
