<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BRAKE BOOSTER AND MASTER CYLINDER - OPERATION - MASTER CYLINDER ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MASTER CYLINDER ASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04017y_6.xml" xrefid="f0401702">Figure 2</hotlnk>
            for all items in parentheses.
        </para>
        <para>The master cylinder assembly includes a brake fluid reservoir (Item 8) and a master cylinder body (Item 2)
            that contains both a primary and a secondary piston, forming separate primary and secondary fluid chambers
            respectively. The reservoir and bore are connected by two compensation valves, primary and secondary.
        </para>
        <para>When the brake pedal is pushed, the Hydro-Max&#8482; booster (Item 1) pushes on the primary piston. This
            causes the primary piston to move, which closes the primary compensation valve, sealing off the primary bore
            chamber from the reservoir and pushes brake fluid out to the brakes. As primary pressure builds, with
            increased force on the brake pedal, this pressure begins to move the secondary piston. Then the secondary
            compensation valve closes, sealing off the secondary bore chamber and the secondary piston pushes brake
            fluid out to the brakes.
        </para>
        <para>When the force on the brake pedal is released, springs return the primary and secondary pistons to their
            at-rest positions, which opens the compensation valves. The open compensation valves allow the brake fluid
            in the master cylinder body (Item 2) to expand or contract with changes in temperature, without building
            pressure in the cylinder bore (which could cause brake drag) or causing a vacuum to occur in the master
            cylinder bore (which could suck air into the brake fluid lines).
        </para>
        <para>The primary and secondary systems are isolated from each other by an arrangement of seals. The pressure
            differential switch (Item 9) is exposed to the pressure in each system. The pressure differential switch
            reacts to significant differences in pressure between the primary and secondary systems. For example, if
            there is a significant leak in one system, when the brake pedal is applied, pressure will not build in this
            system but pressure will build in the other system. The pressure differential switch will respond to this
            difference and close an electrical circuit that turns on the warning light in the vehicle instrument panel.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
