<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - EC-30 INPUTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EC-30 INPUTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power and Ground</title>
            <para>Power is supplied to the EC-30 from the ignition circuit through a 30 Amp fuse. The EC-30 is grounded
                to the vehicle chassis. See the EC-30 system schematic for EC-30 power and ground connector pin
                locations. See
                <hotlnk document="s04043_25.xml" xrefid="f0404313">Figure 13</hotlnk>
                for system schematic.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Speed Sensors</title>
            <para>Wheel speed data is provided to the EC-30 from the Bendix WS-20 wheel speed sensor. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404305">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                for WS-20 illustration. Working with an exciter ring, wheel speed sensors provide the EC-30 with an AC
                signal, which varies in voltage and frequency in relation to the speed of the wheel. The EC-30 can be
                configured to receive wheel speed information from 100 or 86 tooth exciter rings. Vehicle axle
                configurations and ATC features determine the number of speed sensors that must be used. A vehicle with
                a single rear drive axle (4x2, 4x4 or 6x2) requires four speed sensors for both ABS and ATC operation. A
                vehicle with two rear drive axles (6x4) can utilize six speed sensors for optimal ABS and ATC
                performance. See
                <hotlnk document="s04043_25.xml" xrefid="f0404313">Figure 13</hotlnk>
                for the EC-30 system schematic for wheel speed sensor connector pin locations.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404305" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. WS-20 Wheel Speed Sensors</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Enable/Disable Switch</title>
            <para>Premium EC-30 models, configured for ATC, monitor an ATC enable/disable switch to +12 VDC, which
                allows ATC to be manually deactivated. The ATC active/warning lamp will be on while the ATC is disabled.
                Pin F2 of the 30-pin connector is the ATC enable/disable switch input.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939 - ATC Enable/Disable Switch</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to receive the status of the ATC enable/disable switch over the SAE J1939
                serial communications link. A vehicle controller will monitor the position of the ATC enable/disable
                switch directly, and broadcast a J1939 message indicating its status. When configured in this manner,
                there will be no wire installed in pin F2 of the 30-pin ECU connector. In the event that J1939
                communications is lost between the EC-30 and the vehicle controller, the EC-30 will disable the ATC
                function.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blink Code Switch</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to support an optional diagnostic blink code switch to ground, which can
                be used to activate several functions available through blink code diagnostics. Pin F3, of the 30-pin
                connector, is the blink code switch input.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Three Position Switch for ATC and Blink Codes</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to receive both the ATC enable/ disable signal and the blink code
                activation signal from a single three-position switch. In this case, the common position of the switch
                is connected to pin F2 of the 30-pin connector. The normally-open switch position is connected to +12
                VDC to disable ATC. The normally-open (momentary) switch position is connected to ground to activate
                blink codes. When configured in this manner, there is no wire installed in pin F3 of the 30-pin
                connector, which is normally used for the blink code switch input.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Switch Input</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to support an optional brake switch input. The brake switch input can be
                used in accordance with ABS and ATC performance. Pin A2, of the 18-pin connector, is the brake switch
                input.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
