<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - ABS AND ATC WIRING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ABS AND ATC WIRING</title>
        <para>The vehicle manufacturer designs and supplies the vehicle harnesses for the EC-30. However, Bendix
            specifies all component connectors. See
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404314">Figure 14</hotlnk>
            for components. The wiring harness and connectors are weather resistant and sealed at the connector
            interface. The wire gauge and insulation type used in the wire harnesses is specific to the circuit
            function, but 16 gauge GXL is most common. Refer to BW-106-A, Bendix ABS Application Guideline, for specific
            wire harness application information.
        </para>
        <para>When troubleshooting ABS wiring, some general rules should be followed where applicable.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check all wiring and connectors to ensure they are secure and free from visible damage.
                Check for evidence of wire chafing due to poor routing or poor securing of wires. Check connectors for
                proper insertion and locking. Verify that the connector leads are properly greased with a nonconductive
                electrical grease compound and do not show signs of corrosion or exposure to the environment.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">During wiring repair, a splice must be properly soldered and made waterproof.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not pierce wire insulation when checking for continuity.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not deform individual pins or sockets during probing with a volt/ohm meter.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Only use the correct crimping tool when replacing wire terminals and connectors.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Properly resecure all wiring harness and sensor leads when repairs are made.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0404314" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404314.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. EC-30 Component Connectors</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
