<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - HCU Reservoir</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04050609" graphiccount="1">
        <title>HCU Reservoir</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Any form of contamination entering the system could prevent the system from operating
                        correctly. Thoroughly clean the area around fittings before disconnecting the fittings. Always
                        plug open ports and lines as quickly as possible. Contamination in the system could result in
                        loss of braking functions during vehicle operation. Failure to follow this warning could result
                        in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Access to the HCU reservoir depends on the body installed on the vehicle; therefore, removal of the
                entire HCU (with reservoir) is required prior to replacement of the reservoir. The reservoir can then be
                replaced on the bench.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the HCU. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050608.xml" xrefid="hl04050608">HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT</hotlnk>
                    Removal procedures . Do NOT remove components from the HCU assembly until instructed to do so in
                    this procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Empty the reservoir (still attached to the HCU) by pouring the brake fluid into a
                    suitable container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the area between the body of the HCU and the HCU reservoir to ensure the area is
                    free of any dirt or other contaminants. Clean if necessary. Do not allow any contaminants to enter
                    the HCU ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a number 4 Phillips-head screwdriver, remove the 4 HCU reservoir mounting
                    screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the reservoir off of the HCU. Some resistance will be felt due to the rubber seals
                    between the HCU and the reservoir. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid=" f0405047">FIGURE 47</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the four rubber seals were removed from the HCU with the reservoir. If not,
                    remove the old seals from the ports on top of the HCU.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the reservoir ports to insure that no contamination will enter the HCU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the top of the HCU that was previously covered by the reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405047" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405047" filename="../figg04/g0405047.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. HCU Reservoir and Reservoir Seals</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Replacement HCU reservoirs are supplied as a kit that includes four seals and four screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the top of the HCU that was previously covered by the reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install four new HCU - to - reservoir seals into the ports on top of the HCU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the reservoir seals with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When installing the reservoir in the following step, insure that it is oriented correctly. The
                        mounting screw holes must line up and the inlet port for the low pressure hose must face the
                        front.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new reservoir by pressing it carefully and fully into the seals.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the four new mounting screws and a Phillips-head screwdriver, attach the reservoir
                    to the HCU. Tighten the screws to 5 to 6.7 Nm (44 to 60 Lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>While performing the following step, it is not necessary to program the ECU after
                        installation, because it was not replaced. However, any brake system related inactive diagnostic
                        codes should be cleared using the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program. If active fault codes are indicated, refer to Section 5,
                        <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050500.xml" xrefid="hl04050500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                        </hotlnk>
                        to make the necessary repairs .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the HCU. Perform the
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050608.xml" xrefid="hl04050608">HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT</hotlnk>
                    Installation procedures .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050608.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050610.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
