<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE: AR-1 - CLEANING AND INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CLEANING AND INSPECTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04026_12.xml" xrefid="f0402606">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                for all item numbers in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using mineral spirits or an equivalent solvent, clean and thoroughly dry all metal
                    parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the interior and exterior of all metal parts that will be reused for severe
                    corrosion, pitting and cracks. Superficial corrosion and\or pitting on the exterior portion of the
                    body (Item 18,
                    <hotlnk document="s04026_12.xml" xrefid="f0402606">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                    ) and cover (Item 7) is acceptable.
                    <emph type="bold">Replace the entire valve if the interior of the body or cover exhibits signs of
                        corrosion or pitting.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the bores of both the body (Item 18) and cover (Item 7) for deep scuffing or
                    gouges.
                    <emph type="bold">Replace the entire valve if either is found.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain all air channels and exhaust passages in the valve cover (Item 7) are clear
                    and free of obstruction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the pipe threads in the body (Item 18). Make certain they are clean and free of
                    thread sealant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash all non-metallic components in a soap and water solution making certain to rinse
                    and dry thoroughly. Inspect each non-metallic component for cracks, wear or distortion.
                    <emph type="bold">Replace the entire valve if these conditions are found.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the valve was equipped with a relay piston spring (Item 17), inspect it for signs of
                    corrosion, pitting and cracks. Replace as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">8.Inspect all air line fittings for corrosion and replace as necessary. Make certain to
                    remove all old thread sealant before reuse.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
