<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s04004" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5058" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>BENDIX</vendor>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>BS-2150</vendcode>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The BX-2150 is a single cylinder, single stage reciprocating compressor with a rated
                        displacement of 9.5 cubic feet per minute at 1250 R.P.M (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400401">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The BX-2150 is constructed from two major
                        assemblies, the cylinder head and the crankcase. The cylinder head is an iron casting containing
                        the inlet, discharge and unloader valving. lt is installed on the crankcase and is secured using
                        four cap screws symmetrically placed. The cylinder head can be, therefore installed in any one
                        of four different positions which are 90 degrees apart.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <figure id="f0400401" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400401" filename="../figg04/G0400401.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. BX-2150 Compressor</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Two governor mounting surfaces, adjacent to the single rectangular inlet cavity, provide a
                        convenient means of mounting the governor to the cylinder head (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400402">Figure 2</hotlnk>). One eighth inch pipe threads in each of the two
                        governor mounting pads allow plugging of the unused port or the installation of a tubing fitting
                        for remote governor mounting. Three 1/2" N.P.T. ports provide the means for the connection of
                        coolant lines and are labeled WATER.Two 1/2" N.P.T. discharge ports are located on the top and
                        side of the cylinder head and are labeled AIR OUT.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <figure id="f0400402" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400402" filename="../figg04/G0400402.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. BX-2150 Cylinder Head</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>The various mounting and drive configurations required by the numerous vehicle engine designs
                        are accommodated by different crankcase castings and crankshafts (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400403">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>Two methods for cooling the BX-2150 are employed. The cylinder head is water cooled using the
                        engine's cooling system, while external fins on the crankcase provide a means for efficient air
                        cooling in that area.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <figure id="f0400403" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400403" filename="../figg04/G0400403.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. Compressor Mounting/Drive Configurations</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <para>All BX-1250 compressors utilize the engine's pressurized oil system to lubricate internal
                        moving parts.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
