<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - WHEEL SPEED Sensor</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048618" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>WHEEL SPEED Sensor</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving. When working under a raised vehicle,
                        support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                        Jacks can slip and fall over. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage,
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact, nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>Clean the area around the wheel sensor before performing service.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404867">FIGURE 73</hotlnk>
                for component location information while performing the following procedures .
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Lube Specification</title>
            <para>Meritor WABCO specifications call for a sensor lubricant with the following characteristics:</para>
            <para>Lube must be mineral oil-based and contain molydisulfide. It should have excellent anti-corrosion and
                adhesion characteristics and be capable of continuous function in a temperature range of -40&#176; to
                300&#176;F (-40&#176; to 150&#176;C).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks and turn the key off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to remove the tire to access the wheel speed sensor, place safety
                    stands under the axle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the fasteners that hold the sensor cable to other components.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the sensor cable from the chassis harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area around the sensor to prevent contamination when the sensor is removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, do not pull on the sensor cable to remove the sensor.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a twisting motion pull the sensor from the sensor bushing. Do not pull on the
                    cable. If necessary, use a suitable lever to gently pry the sensor from the bushing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the sensor and cable from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the sensor bushing.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404867" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404867" filename="../figg04/G0404813.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 73. Typical Speed Sensor Locations</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT SENSOR BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FRONT SENSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. REAR SENSOR CABLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Overtightening the sensor cable tie wraps may damage the cables.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area where the sensor is to be installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the new sensor bushing with the Meritor WABCO - recommended lubricant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the sensor bushing by pushing it into the wheel end bracket. Make sure the
                    sensor bushing tabs are on the inboard side of the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Meritor WABCO - recommended grease to the wheel speed sensor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the sensor completely into the bushing until it contacts the tooth ring. The sensor
                    will self adjust when the vehicle is driven.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the sensor cable to the chassis harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fasten the sensor cable with tie straps every 12 inches. Do not overtighten the tie
                    straps. Correctly bundle and store any excess cable in the sub-frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If tire was removed previously, reinstall tire and remove safety stands.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404844">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>
                    . Start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048617.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048700.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
