<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK MODULATOR ASSEMBLY: BENDIX M-21 AND M-22 - OPERATION, LEAKAGE AND ELECTRICAL TESTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0403003">
        <title>OPERATION, LEAKAGE AND ELECTRICAL TESTS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATION TESTING ("CHUFF" TEST)</title>
            <para>Each modulator valve contains (1) exhaust solenoid and (1) hold solenoid. During this test, the
                controller will "fire" or energize each solenoid briefly in a test cycle making a "chuff" sound as the
                air exhausts. The exhaust solenoid will be "fired" for 10 milliseconds, then a pause for only a few
                milliseconds and the hold solenoid will "fire" for 20 milliseconds. The two firing in rapid sequence
                will produce a "chuff" sound. The controller will begin at the right front, then go to the left front,
                then right rear, and finish the cycle on the left rear. It will then repeat the cycle, making two
                complete cycles.
            </para>
            <para>To properly test the function of the modulator will require 2 service technicians.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block or chock the wheels. Release the parking
                    brakes and build the air system to governor cut-out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the engine ignition key to the OFF position, then make and hold a full brake
                    application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the brake application held and a service technician posted at one of the
                    modulators, turn the vehicle ignition key to the ON position. ONE OR TWO SHORT bursts of air
                    pressure should be noted at the modulator exhaust. Repeat the test for each modulator on the
                    vehicle. If at least a single burst of exhaust is not noted or the exhaust of air is prolonged and
                    not short, sharp and well defined, perform the Electrical Tests.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
