<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3000 - AR - 1 ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE - REMOVE AND INSTALL AR - 1 ANTILOCK
        RELAY VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVE AND INSTALL AR - 1 ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block the wheels and/or hold the vehicle by
                    means other than the air brakes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain the air pressure from all vehicle reservoirs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Identify, mark or label all air lines and wiring cables and their respective connections
                    on the CR - 15 Relay Valve/EC - 15 Controller to facilitate ease of installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always turn key switch OFF before disconnecting any portion of the antilock wiring system. If
                        circuits are disconnected with the key ON, the EC - 15 controller will record the open circuit
                        as a fault condition.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all air lines and wiring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and mark the mounting position of the relay valve/controller assembly on the
                    vehicle. Remove and save the relay valve/controller mounting hardware, then remove the CR - 15 Relay
                    Valve/ECU Controller assembly from the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Completely clean the case of the relay valve/controller assembly, making sure to protect
                    the open ports and connectors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and mark the position of the EC - 15 controller relative to the AR - 1 relay valve
                    for later reassembly. Remove the 4 capscrews securing the controller to the relay valve. Carefully
                    separate the controller from the relay valve, making sure not to damage the gasket between the 2
                    components, if possible. Peel the gasket from the EC - 15 or AR - 1 and retain for use if it is not
                    damaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a new gasket if the old gasket is damaged or if a new gasket is readily available.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For disassembly of the relay valve, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After noting the relationship of the positioning marks made in Step 7 of Removal, above,
                    position the gasket on the EC - 15, then secure the EC - 15 to the AR - 1 antilock relay valve using
                    the 4 capscrews. Torque the capscrews to 50 - 80 Lb. In. (5.6 - 9.0 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install all air line fittings and plugs (as marked during removal) making certain thread
                    sealing material does not enter the valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the assembled CR - 15 Relay Valve/ECU Controller on the vehicle in the position
                    marked during Step 5 of Removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all air lines and wiring cables to the valve and controller assembly using the
                    identification made during Valve Removal Step 3, above.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After installing the valve and controller assembly, test all air fittings for excessive
                    leakage and tighten as needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
