<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - PRINCIPLES, OPERATION AND SERVICE - OPERATION - CONTROLLER/RELAY
        VALVE ( Figure 4 )
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONTROLLER/RELAY VALVE (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402904">Figure 4</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <figure id="f0402904" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402904" filename="../figg04/g0402904.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Controller/Relay Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The controller/relay valve assembly is a controller mounted on a traction modulator and/or antilock
                relay valve.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Controller</title>
            <para>The controller houses the electronic control unit that regulates the functions of the traction control
                and/or antilock brake system. The controller performs a system start-up self diagnostic test whenever
                the vehicle is started and then continues to monitor the antilock system performance during operation of
                the vehicle. The controller uses the instrument panel ABS warning light and Traction Active light to
                communicate system performance to the driver. The controller has diagnostic LEDs to provide system
                diagnostic information. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for more
                detailed information.
            </para>
            <para>The controller mounts on the antilock relay valve. The controller is electrically connected through
                connectors to the wheel sensors, brake modulators, and the cab antilock wire harness. With traction
                control, an additional 2-way connector connects the rear chassis harness to the traction control
                solenoid (part of the controller/relay valve assembly). The relay valve functions as a service brake
                relay valve and contains no electronics of its own.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Controller Power Supply</title>
            <para>The controller receives power from the battery through the ABS ignition relay.</para>
            <para>With the relay energized, battery power from the relay terminal is applied through the cab and chassis
                harness to the controller connector.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Electronic Engines</title>With Electronic Engines, the ABS controller is connected to the engine
                ECM. The ABS J1922 data link is a twisted pair of wires (Red positive and light Blue wire negative).
                When the ABS system sends an engine brake disable signal to the engine ECM, the engine ECM disables the
                engine brake. When the disabling signal is no longer present, the engine brake operation will resume.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Caterpillar 3406C (Mechanical Engine)</title>With the Caterpillar 3406C mechanical engine, an
                Engine Brake Relay is used to disable the engine brake.
            </para>
            <para>When the ABS engine brake relay is not energized, ignition power passes through the ABS engine brake
                relay providing power for engine brake operation.
            </para>
            <para>The controller disables the engine brake by causing the relay to energize, opening the engine brake
                feed circuit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1708/J1587 Data Link</title>
            <para>With electronic and mechanical engines, six-pin data link connector provides access for the Prolink
                Electronic Service tool to the ABS controller. International has Prolink cartridges available for this
                application.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock/Bob Tail Proportioning Relay Valve</title>
            <para>The antilock relay valve is a specialized service brake relay valve. The valve functions as a brake
                relay valve and provides bobtail proportioning as well, if the vehicle is so configured. If traction
                control is included, the antilock relay valve contains an electric solenoid for the feature. Vehicles
                can be configured four ways:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>04AZC - ABS with bobtail proportioning with tractors (04092).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>04AZD - ABS with bobtail proportioning and traction control with tractors (04092).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>04AZA - Straight truck with ABS (04091).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>04AZA - ABS With Tractor (04092) if bobtail proportioning is omitted (04WBN).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>With each of the above installations, a different combination of controller/relay valve is used. The
                porting on the relay valve portion is the same.
            </para>
            <para>The relay valve has a special cover that permits the direct attachment to the controller. When the
                controller and relay valve are assembled together, the assembly is called a controller/relay valve
                assembly.
            </para>
            <para>In the antilock brake system, the controller/relay valve serves as a relay station to speed the
                application and release of the rear service brakes. Incorporated within the relay valve is a quick
                release valve next to the service port, which provides for rapid exhausting of control air pressure from
                above the relay piston. All air connections on the relay valve are identified with cast, embossed
                letters for ease of maintenance. The letter identification of the air ports on the relay valve are
                listed in Table 1.
            </para>
            <table id="hl0402901">
                <title>Function Designation Table</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Function</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Designation</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Supply</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>SUP</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Delivery</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>DEL</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Service</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>SER</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Control</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>CON</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Exhaust</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>EXH</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
