<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, observe the following:</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brakes, and always
                            block the wheels.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Drain the air pressure from all reservoirs before beginning ANY work on the
                            vehicle.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">When working in the engine compartment, the engine should be shut off. Where
                            circumstances require running the engine, EXTREME CAUTION must be used to prevent personal
                            injury resulting from contact with moving, rotating, leaking, heated, or electrically
                            charged components.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip.
                            Never remove a component or plug, unless you are certain all system pressure has been
                            released.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety</emph>
                        <emph type="bold">glasses.</emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until
                            you have read and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper
                            tools and observe all precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use only International approved parts, components, and kits. Replacement hardware,
                    tubing, hose, fittings, etc. must be designed specifically for such applications and systems.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Components with stripped threads or damaged parts should be replaced, rather than
                    repaired. Repairs requiring machining or welding should not be attempted unless specifically
                    approved and stated by International Engineering.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                    restored to their proper operating condition.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with traction control, disable the traction system before
                            performing any dynamic driveline maintenance.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
