<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - OPERATION - ABS BRAKING MODE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="3">
        <title>ABS BRAKING MODE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The antilock brake system will monitor the four wheel speed sensors and control the hydraulic pressure
                changes at each wheel until the vehicle has come to a complete stop or the brake pedal has been
                released.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <title>The system operates through a four step process, which occurs approximately 18 times per
                    second:
                </title>
                <item>
                    <para>Pressure isolate/maintain</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pressure decrease</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pressure increase</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake release (fluid return)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sequence Of Events</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the vehicle at 10 km/h (6 mph) or greater, the driver depresses the brake pedal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The brake switch closes and the wheel speeds begin to decrease as the master cylinder
                    pressure and the brake pressure increase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">As the wheel speed continues to decrease from the vehicle speed (wheels starting to
                    slip), the normally open isolation valve for the affected channel closes to stop additional pressure
                    to the wheel.
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0403905">Refer to Isolation Mode
                        <xref refid="f0403905"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . The master cylinder pressure continues to increase as the driver depresses the pedal. The pressure
                    to the brake is now limited to the ABS system pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the ECU determines the wheel is about to lock up, the normally closed dump valve is
                    opened.
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0403906">Refer to Dump Mode
                        <xref refid="f0403906"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . This bleeds off some of the pressure at the caliper to allow the wheel to return to a speed closer
                    to the vehicle speed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The dump valve is again closed and isolation valve remains closed to allow the wheel
                    speed to completely recover from the lock up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the wheel has recovered from the lock-up tendency, the isolation valve is
                    momentarily pulsed open to allow the master cylinder pressure and pump pressure to reach the brakes
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0403907">Refer to Re-apply Mode
                        <xref refid="f0403907"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . This controlled pressure rise continues until the wheel is at optimum brake output or until the
                    brake pressure is brought up to master cylinder output pressure. The ABS allows the brake fluid to
                    flow to the wheel, to build pressure until the wheels start to slip again, repeating steps 3 through
                    6. The following paragraphs describe the various modes in more detail.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Isolation Mode (Pressure Maintain)</title>
            <figure id="f0403905" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403905" filename="../figg04/g0403905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Isolation Mode (Pressure Maintain)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403905">Isolation Mode
                    <xref refid="f0403905"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . The ECU is armed when the driver applies the brakes and sends a signal to the module to prepare for a
                possible antilock stop. Isolation will occur when the driver applies excessive braking for the given
                road conditions, causing the wheel(s) to decelerate at a rate greater than the vehicle is capable of. If
                the information from the wheel speed sensors indicates excessive wheel deceleration (imminent lock-up),
                the first step in the antilock sequence is to isolate the brake pressure being applied by the driver.
                The ECU sends a voltage, to the coil, to energize and close the isolation valve by pulling down on the
                armature with a magnetic force. This will prevent any additional brake pressure from reaching the wheel.
                Though each channel can operate independently, once any front channel (brake) sees excessive
                deceleration, both front ISO valves are energized and closed. Thus, with the isolation valves closed,
                further unnecessary increases in brake pressure will be prohibited.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dump Mode (Pressure Decrease)</title>
            <figure id="f0403906" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403906" filename="../figg04/g0403906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Dump Mode (Pressure Decrease)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403906">Dump Mode
                    <xref refid="f0403906"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . Once the pressure is isolated, the ECU analyzes the wheel speed. If the wheel speed does not recover
                to the vehicle speed, brake pressure must be reduced in order to get the wheels rolling again. This is
                accomplished by dumping a portion of the brake fluid pressure into a low pressure accumulator (LPA). The
                ECU energizes the dump valve coil(s) to open the dump valve, allowing fluid from the wheels to be dumped
                into the LPA. Very short activation pulses open and close the dump valve passageway to control this
                action. Brake pressure is lowered at the wheel and allows the affected wheel to roll again. The fluid
                from the wheels forces a spring back and is stored in the LPA at approximately 1034 kPa (150 PSI). A
                portion of the fluid also primes the pump so it can begin building re-apply pressure. The dump valves
                are opened independently to control the deceleration of the wheel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Re-Apply Mode (Pressure Increase)</title>
            <figure id="f0403907" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403907" filename="../figg04/g0403907.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Re-apply Mode (Pressure Increase)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403907">Re-apply Mode
                    <xref refid="f0403907"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . The re-apply sequence is initiated to obtain optimum braking at each wheel. The isolation valve is
                momentarily pulsed to allow master cylinder and pump pressure to reach the brakes. This controlled
                pressure rise continues until the wheel is at optimum brake output or until the brake pressure is
                brought up to the master cylinder output pressure. If more pressure is required, more fluid is drawn
                from the master cylinder and applied to the brakes. The driver will feel pedal pulsations, or pedal
                drop. This is normal and expected when in the antilock mode. As fluid is re-applied to the wheels, they
                begin to slow down at an optimum rate. If they approach imminent lock up again, the module will isolate,
                dump, and re-apply. These control cycles (isolation, dump, and re-apply) occur in millisecond intervals,
                allowing several cycles to occur each second. It occurs much faster with more control than manually
                pumping the brake pedal.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Release</title>
            <para>At the end of the antilock stop, when the driver releases the brake pedal, the motor will remain on
                for a short time to help drain any fluid left in the LPA. As the fluid drains back into the system, the
                spring force in the LPA pushes the piston to the home position. When the brake switch opens, the
                isolation valve is turned off and fluid may return through the isolation orifice.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
