<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - CAMSHAFT, BUSHINGS AND SEALS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>CAMSHAFT, BUSHINGS AND SEALS</title>
        <para>The camshaft is actuated by movement of the slack adjuster. The rotating movement of the cam forces the
            shoe rollers away from the cam, thus forcing shoe into contact with drum.
        </para>
        <para>The removal procedure for camshaft assembly is covered in
            <hotlnk document="s04005_HL0400503.xml" xrefid="hl0400503">DISASSEMBLY</hotlnk>. When removing camshaft from
            backing plate or spider, note position of spacing washers to insure correct reinstallation.
        </para>
        <para>Do not remove camshaft bushings from spider and/or mounting bracket unless replacement is necessary.
        </para>
        <para>Do not interchange right and left side camshafts.</para>
        <para>Removal of the brake chamber bracket will be required to replace the bushing in some instances.</para>
        <para>To check bushing to determine if replace- ment is required, insert the camshaft into the bushing and check
            side play. If there is more than .020 inch (.5080mm) on Eaton brakes or .030 inch (.7620mm) on Rockwell
            brakes, the bushings need to be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Install new bushings with a suitable tool like that shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400536">Figure 36</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400536" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400536" filename="../figg04/G0400536.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="152px"/>
            <caption>Figure 36. Recommended Type of Camshaft Bushing Removing Tool</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Install and lubricate new seals. Use NLGI number 1 or equivalent. Install seals with lip of seal toward
            slack adjuster (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400537">Figure 37</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400537" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400537" filename="../figg04/G0400537.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 37. Camshaft Seal Installation</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
