<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - SERVICE CHECKS - LQ-5
        OPERATION TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401205" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LQ-5 OPERATION TEST</title>
        <para>To properly test the LQ-5, use a pair of test gauges or gauges with known accuracy.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the trailer air supply valve pushed in (tractor-trailer mode), install two air gauges
                in the front axle service system: one air gauge between the LQ-5 and the brake control valve (foot
                valve) and one air gauge at a front axle air chamber.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Build system air pressure to governor cut-out setting.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make a
                <emph type="bold">slow, partial</emph>
                service brake application with the brake control valve (foot valve) and have an observer read the
                gauges. When the gauge between the LQ-5 and the brake control valve (foot valve) reaches 40 psi, the
                gauge at the front axle brake chamber should read approximately 20 psi (&#177;5 psi).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make a full service brake application. Both gauges should read the same pressure.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the trailer air supply valve pulled out (bobtail mode), make a 30-40 psi service brake
                application. Both gauges should read the same pressure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the test gauges.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>If the LQ-5 fails the OPERATION TEST, repair or replace the LQ-5.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401201.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401202.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
