<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - HOSES, TUBING AND CONNECTIONS - NYLON TUBING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="3">
        <title>NYLON TUBING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Nylon tubing of varying construction has been used in the trucking industry for a period of time.
            </para>
            <para>Nylon tubing as a replacement for certain copper tubing in chassis air brake system applications is
                acceptable. A superior color coded nylon tubing which is suitable for many applications as well as air
                brake system applications is being used for field service use.
            </para>
            <table id="t0400218" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Color Coded Tubing Chart - Air Brake System</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="4.98in" colsep="1"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="2" spanname="sqspan1-2"/>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="sqspan1-2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">COLOR CODED</emph>TUBING VEHICLES WITH COLOR CODED AIR BRAKE
                                    SYSTEM TUBING
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>GREEN</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Primary Supply and Delivery System</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ORANGE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Secondary Supply and Delivery System</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>YELLOW</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spring Brake System</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>RED</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Trailer Emergency</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>GRAY</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Power Divider Lockout</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>BLUE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Tractor Protection Valve Service</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>BLACK</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Other Systems</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Nylon Tubing Assembly Instructions</title>
            <para>For the most part, nylon tubing in air brake systems is assembled much like copper tubing. The same
                fittings, sleeves and nuts used with copper tubing can be used with nylon tubing. Long or short tube
                nuts may be found on chassis in service with nylon tubing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400298">Figure 98</hotlnk>
                ). Either nut may be satisfactorily used on the nylon lines.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400298" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400298" filename="../figg04/G0400298.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Nylon Tubing Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TUBE SUPPORT OR INSERT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SLEEVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SHORT NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LONG NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. NYLON TUBING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>If copper tubing is being substituted for nylon tubing, the short tube nut
                <emph type="bold">must not</emph>be used. Either the short tube nut or the long tube nut may be used
                satisfactorily with nylon tubing.
            </para>
            <para>A tube support or insert will be used in all applications of the nylon or copper tubing in air brake
                systems. The insert provides a stiff or rigid area for the sleeve to be crimped or compressed on the
                tubing and prevents collapsing the tubing when the nut is tightened. The parts listing notes that there
                are some sizes of tubing used only in accessory piping systems. In repairing accessory piping systems,
                tube supports are needed with all sizes of tubing except 1/8" O.D. if compression-type fittings are
                used.
            </para>
            <para>Once the tubing has been connected and tightened, the sleeve has been crimped on the tubing and
                insert. Since the sleeve has been compressed and distortion of the insert may have resulted,
                <emph type="bold">the sleeve and inserts should never be used a second time.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The sleeve used with fittings has been changed from a barrel type to a flanged sleeve to reduce air
                leaks (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400299">Figure 99</hotlnk>
                ). The nut and insert have not been changed. Use of the flanged sleeve (ferrule) is preferred.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400299" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400299" filename="../figg04/G0400299.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Sleeve Types</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FLANGE TYPE SLEEVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BARREL TYPE SLEEVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>To assemble tubing ends for use with compression-type fittings, the following steps should be followed
                carefully:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove nut from fitting.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull tubing from fitting.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the same operations at other end of tubing. If only one end of line needs
                    repairing, the second end need not be disconnected if line is long enough to permit repairing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut the selected size of tubing to length. Be sure to make smooth, square cuts. Either a
                    sharp knife or hacksaw may be used.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position nut on tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position compression sleeve on tube.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert tube support into tube.*</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the tube, support and sleeve in the fitting. Push fitting into tube until it
                    bottoms.*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>* No tube support is used with 1/8" O.D. tubing. Certain fittings used in accessory piping
                        systems have the tube support as an integral part of the fitting body. These fittings may be
                        reused if no distortion of the tube support has occurred.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and tighten tube nut to secure sleeve on tubing. Tighten tube nut so that no
                    more than two threads are showing between the nut and fitting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f04002a0">Figure 100</hotlnk>
                    ). Do not overtighten nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f04002a0" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g04002a0" filename="../figg04/G04002A0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 100. Tightening Tube Nut</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TUBING SUPPORT OR INSERT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLANGED SLEEVE (FERRULE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TUBING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect tubing connections for air leakage. With the tubing and associated fittings
                    charged to full system air pressure, coat tubing lines and fittings with soap suds to check for
                    leakage. No leakage is permissible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leakage at a tubing fitting is sometimes corrected by tightening the tubing fitting nut.
                    If this fails to correct the leakage, replace the tubing fitting, tubing, or both.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The service nylon tubing will be marked at regular intervals with name, number, type, size and
                manufacturing code designations.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Nylon Tubing Special Instructions</title>
            <para>Nylon tubing should not be substituted in the field for any metallic tubing. In addition, the
                following precautions must be taken with the use of nylon tubing.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not use nylon tubing for any application which would cause it to be exposed to
                    temperatures below -40&#176;F or above +200&#176;F (-40&#176;C or +93&#176;C).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not subject nylon tubing to working pressure in excess of 150 psi.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not use nylon tubing for frame-to-axle, tractor-to-trailer or any similar line where
                    a high degree of flexibility is required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Observe extreme care when welding near nylon tubing. Hot slag or spark will damage the
                    tubing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Protect nylon tubing from battery acid.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_145.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400226.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
