<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: MIDLAND MODELS EL-1300 AND EL-1600 - CLEAN, INSPECT AND REPAIR - PISTONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
        <title>PISTONS</title>
        <para>Inspect pistons for damage, such as cracks or scoring.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure outside diameter of both pistons just below the compression ring grooves, then
                compare this diameter with inside diameter of respective cylinder bore. Be sure to measure the piston at
                a 90 degree angle to piston pin bore to insure correct measurement.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Piston to bore clearance should not exceed .008 inch (0.20 mm). If clearance exceeds .008
                inch (0.20 mm), replace the piston. Also the block must be replaced or bored oversize to 0.020 inch
                (.508 mm). Pistons with 0.020 inch (.508 mm) oversize are available for the EL- 1300 and EL-1600 air
                compressors.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Piston pins must have a light interference fit in piston and a slip fit in the rod. Piston
                pins that have a variation in diameter of more than .003 inch (.076 mm) must be replaced. If the piston
                pin bore or rod bore is worn, the complete piston and rod assembly must be replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check fit of compression and oil rings in the piston ring grooves. Place rings in piston
                ring grooves and measure side clearance. Place rings in respective cylinder bore and measure ring gap as
                shown (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401113">Figure 13</hotlnk>). If measurements are not within
                <hotlnk document="s04011_31.xml" xrefid="hl0401103">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>, replace the rings.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401113" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401113" filename="../figg04/G0401113.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Measuring Ring Gap</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
