<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - SERVICE PROCEDURES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The following disassembly procedure applies to the two piston caliper assembly. The same procedure
                will apply to the single piston caliper except where noted.
            </para>
            <para>The following procedure is for one wheel/ brake assembly only. Repeat same procedure for each
                wheel/brake assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc id="hl0401609" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
            <title>CALIPER AND PADS REMOVAL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position vehicle on floor stands. Remove tire and wheel assembly at axle end to be
                    serviced.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect master cylinder fluid level and remove fluid if necessary. Refer to step 2
                    <hotlnk document="s04016k_11.xml" xrefid="hl0401603">SERVICE PRECAUTIONS
                        <xref refid="hl0401603"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a screwdriver through the opening in the center of the caliper and in one of the
                    rotor cooling fin slots. Be sure caliper will move on V-way surface before prying. Pry the caliper
                    outboard forcing the caliper piston(s) into the cylinder bore(s). This will allow removal of the
                    caliper assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401614">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401614" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0401614" filename="../figg04/G0401614.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Forcing Piston Into Cylinder Bore</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove support key retaining bolt. Using a blunt nose drift punch, lightly tap support
                    key and spring out of caliper assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401615">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401615" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0401615" filename="../figg04/G0401615.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Removing Caliper Support Key and Spring</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the caliper has to be removed, disconnect the hydraulic hose and plug off hose/line
                    from leaking fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the caliper from the anchor plate and support caliper. Do not let the caliper
                    hang by the caliper flex hose or possible damage may occur to the flex hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove inboard pad from the anchor plate and the outboard pad from the caliper
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a suitable metal plate over caliper piston(s). If a metal plate is not available,
                    use the inboard caliper pad metal side against piston face. Using a "C" clamp as shown (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401616">Figure 16</hotlnk>), tighten "C" clamp and press caliper pistons into
                    caliper bores. This action will allow clearance for new pads to clear the rotor on installation. If
                    other calipers have been removed from rotor assembly, place a suitable block between the piston(s)
                    and the caliper housing to keep the caliper piston from being pushed outward when the caliper piston
                    being serviced is compressed.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401616" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0401616" filename="../figg04/G0401616.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Forcing Pistons into Caliper Using Metal Plate</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
