<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - SYSTEM AND COMPONENT OPERATION - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="12">
        <title>COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04022_15.xml" xrefid="x0402203">CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</hotlnk>
                as needed for the following discussions.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Sensor</title>
            <para>The wheel speed sensors are mounted on the axle ends (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402202">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The wheel sensors house a permanent magnet, which creates
                a magnetic field. When the field created by the sensor magnet is interrupted by the teeth of the exciter
                ring moving through it, an A.C. voltage is produced. The frequency of the voltage increases or decreases
                as the wheel speed increases or decreases. The sensor has a pigtail with a two-pin connector that
                connects to the ABS harness mating connector. The sensor signal goes from the sensor, through the ABS
                harness and connects to the EC-15, either with a 12-pin connector or a 14-pin connector, depending on
                the location of the wheel sensor. The left and right front wheel sensors connect to the 14-pin connector
                and the rear chassis sensors (2) connect to the 12-pin connector.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402202" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Typical Front Axle, Wheel Sensor Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SENSOR BUSHING (PART OF KNUCKLE ASSY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SENSOR RETAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD (CONNECTS TO CHASSIS ANTILOCK HARNESS)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exciter Ring</title>
            <para>The exciter ring is machined to close tolerances and has 100 equally spaced teeth (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402203">Figure 3</hotlnk>). The ring is heated and then installed onto the wheel
                assembly. Then as the exciter ring cools, it shrinks on the mating surface of the wheel hub. As the
                wheel rotates, the 100 teeth pass the sensor, each breaking the magnetic field creating the AC signal.
                One hundred cycles or pulses of the signal would indicate one revolution of the wheel. The signal is
                transmitted from the sensor to the EC-15.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402203" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Exciter Ring Installed</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WHEEL SENSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXCITER RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HUB</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Warning (Indicator) Light</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>References to a connector number, fuse or circuit by reference number will be for the 96/9700
                        models with the corresponding reference number for the 93/9400 models in parentheses.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04022_15.xml" xrefid="x0402203">CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</hotlnk>
                for this discussion.
            </para>
            <para>The antilock warning light is located on the instrument panel. When the vehicle is started, the
                "Initial Start-up Self Diagnostic Test" will be run. The test is fully explained in
                <hotlnk document="s04022_10.xml" xrefid="x0402204">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>. The yellow warning light
                also will illuminate if, during operation, the EC-15 senses a system defect.
            </para>
            <para>The yellow instrument panel warning light and the warning light relay control coil receive ignition
                power from fuse S18 (or F4). With the relay in the open position (relay de-activated), the ground for
                the warning light is completed and the light is illuminated.
            </para>
            <para>The warning light relay control coil ground path is controlled by the EC-15, which opens or closes the
                ground (activates or de-activates the relay) to turn the warning light ON or OFF. The warning light is
                ON whenever the relay is de-activated by the EC-15.
            </para>
            <para>During the Self Diagnostic Test when starting the vehicle or if a failure occurs in the antilock
                system, the EC-15 opens the ground path for the warning light relay coil causing it to de-energize,
                resulting in the illumination of the yellow instrument panel warning light.
                <emph type="bold">If the antilock system is operating properly during normal operation, the lamp will
                    not be illuminated.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>The yellow antilock warning lamp, located on the instrument panel, receives ignition voltage from 20
                amp circuit breaker S18 (or 20 amp fuse F4) through the cab harness to circuit 94D of the antilock cab
                harness. Voltage will be present whenever the key switch is in the ON position. The ground circuit for
                the warning lamp is (circuit 94E) through the warning light relay (terminal 1 to 3) then circuit 94-G to
                ground.
            </para>
            <para>When the warning light relay
                <emph type="bold">is not energized</emph>, the warning light will be illuminated. Ignition voltage (same
                source as warning light) is present to the warning light relay control coil whenever the key switch is
                in the ON position. The relay control coil ground circuit (94J) is connected through the cab and chassis
                harness to the EC-15 harness 14-pin connector at pin "E". The EC-15 opens (light ON) or closes (light
                OFF) the warning light relay in response to antilock system conditions as determined by the EC-15.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): EC-15 Controller</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402204">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402204" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402204.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EC-15 CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AR-1 RELAY VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 assembly consists of a EC-15 controller mounted on a AR-1 antilock relay
                valve.
            </para>
            <para>The EC-15 controller houses the electronic control unit that regulates the functions of the antilock
                system. The EC-15 performs a system start-up self diagnostic test whenever the vehicle is started and
                then continues to monitor the antilock system performance during operation of the vehicle. The EC-15
                uses the yellow instrument panel warning light and the warning light relay to communicate system
                performance to the driver. The EC-15 also incorporates a diagnostic LED window in the assembly to
                provide additional system diagnostic information. See
                <hotlnk document="s04022_10.xml" xrefid="x0402204">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>The EC-15 controller mounts on the antilock relay valve with four capscrews. The EC-15 is electrically
                connected through a 12-pin and 14-pin connector to the wheel sensors, brake modulators, and the cab
                antilock wire harness. The antilock relay valve functions as a service brake relay valve and contains no
                electronics of its own.
            </para>
            <para>The EC-15 assembly is supplied with electrical power by the vehicle electrical system. The circuitry
                for the 9300/9400 models is very similar to the 9600/9700 models. For the purpose of this discussion, we
                will use the 9600/9700 model specifics.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04022_15.xml" xrefid="x0402203">CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</hotlnk>
                for this discussion.
            </para>
            <para>With 9600/9700 models, the ignition power source for the EC-15 is the J2 ignition feed stud. Ignition
                power from J2 (on circuit 94) goes through a 30 amp in-line fuse, then (circuit 94K) through the crank
                relay,
                <emph type="bold">only when the relay is not energized</emph>. The crank relay is only energized while
                the engine cranking motor is engaged. Voltage from start switch (output side) is used to energize the
                crank relay and while cranking the engine, the EC-15 power will be OFF. The crank relay control coil
                ground circuit 94-GA is grounded at J14 ground point.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>During the engine cranking, system voltage will on occasion drop below the operating limits of
                        the EC-15 controller. The system avoids this by de-energizing the EC-15 using the crank relay.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the crank relay is not energized, ignition voltage from the crank relay (circuits 94A/94L) is
                delivered to the EC-15 harness connector at pin "J". The EC-15 assembly harness includes a ground cable
                (circuit 94-G), that is grounded to the vehicle frame (J31).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): AR-1 Antilock Relay Valve</title>
            <para>The AR-1 antilock relay valve is a specialized service brake relay valve. The AR-1 contains no
                electronic components and functions as a brake relay valve. The AR-1 is essentially an R-14 relay valve
                with a special cover that permits the direct attachment of the EC-15 controller. When the controller and
                relay valve are assembled together, the assembly is called a CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402205" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402205.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. AR-1 Relay Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>In the antilock brake system, the AR-1 relay valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402205">Figure 5</hotlnk>) serves as a relay station to speed the application and
                release of the rear service brakes. Incorporated within the AR-1 relay valve is a quick release valve
                next to the service port, which provides for rapid exhausting of control air pressure from above the
                relay piston. All air connections on the relay valve are identified with cast, embossed letters for ease
                of maintenance. The letter identification of the air ports on the AR-1 is as follows:
            </para>
            <table id="t0402201" tblwidth="half-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>AR-1 Air Port Identification</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="118pt"/>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>AR-1 AIR CONNECTION</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>EMBOSSED</para>
                                <para>IDENTIFICATION</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Supply (Primary reservoir to relay valve)</para>
                                <para>Delivery (To rear modulators)</para>
                                <para>Service (Brake valve to relay valve)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>SUP</para>
                                <para>DEL</para>
                                <para>SER</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>For complete information on relay valve operation and maintaining the valve, refer to GROUP 04 -
                BRAKES.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA)</title>
            <figure id="f0402206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. M-21 Modulator Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The M-21 antilock system modulator (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402206">Figure 6</hotlnk>) is essentially a high capacity, ON/OFF air valve that
                incorporates a pair of electrical solenoids for control. The solenoids provide the electro-pneumatic
                link between the antilock controller electronics and the air brake system. The M-21 can be used to
                control the braking function (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402207">Figure 7</hotlnk>) on an individual wheel or two service actuators (as with
                6x4). The M-21 is the last control valve that air passes through on its way to the service brake
                actuator(s).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402207" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402207.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. M-21 Air Flow Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. M-21 MODULATORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL CONNECTION TO EC-15 CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. QRV</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CR-15 RELAY VALVE/EC-15</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The M-21 modulator consists of a die cast aluminum body and a solenoid assembly, which contains one
                normally open (NO) solenoid, one normally closed (NC) solenoid, and two inlet and exhaust diaphragm
                valves. A Packard, three pin, 280 series weather resistant electrical connector is an an integral part
                of the M-21 solenoid assembly and serves to carry control commands from the EC-15 antilock controller to
                the M-21 modulator. The Supply, Delivery and Exhaust ports on the M-21 are identified with a cast,
                embossed numeral for positive identification. They are as follows:
            </para>
            <table id="t0402205">
                <title>M-21 Valve Port Identification</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="SQCOLUMN1" colwidth="1in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="SQCOLUMN2" colwidth="2.5in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>IDENTIFICATION</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>VALVE PORTING</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Supply - Incoming air from brake valve through QRV (frt axle) or relay valve (rear
                                    axle).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Delivery - Air delivery to service actuators.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Exhaust - Air exhausted during antilock control.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Non-Antilock Application</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402208">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402208" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402208.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. M-21 Application Of Service Brakes</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>During normal non-antilock braking, both solenoids are de-energized (no electrical power). Brake
                application air enters the Supply port of the M-21 and flows to, and through, the open exhaust solenoid
                then to the exhaust diaphragm. Air pressure, along with spring force, seats the exhaust diaphragm on the
                exhaust passage, thus preventing the escape of service air. Simultaneously, application air flows to the
                supply diaphragm and forces it away from its seat. Air flows past the open supply and out the M-21
                delivery port to the service brake chambers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Non-Antilock Hold</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402209">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402209" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Non - Antilock Holding Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the desired air pressure is attained in the service brake chambers, the brake system is in the
                Holding position. In the Holding position, both solenoids in the M-21 remain de-energized and the
                balance of the internal components remain in the same position as they assumed during application.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Non-Antilock Exhaust</title>
            <para>The manner in which air exhausts through the M-21 differs, depending upon how rapidly the brake
                application is released by the driver.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normal Exhaust</emph>
                - Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402210">Figure 10</hotlnk>. During a normal, relatively "slow" brake release, air
                moves back through the M-21 in the reverse direction as it flowed during application. The internal
                components of the M-21 will remain in the same position as they assumed during application until air
                pressure decreases to approximately one half psi, at which time the supply diaphragm will seat on the
                supply passage. Air will generally not be expelled from the M-21 exhaust port during normal brake
                release.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402210" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. M-21 Non-Antilock Exhaust (Normal)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Rapid Exhaust -</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402211">Figure 11</hotlnk>. The Rapid Exhaust operation described in the following
                text
                <emph type="bold">only occurs when the M-21 is controlling two, type 30 (or larger) service
                    chambers</emph>. During a very rapid brake release, the M-21 will exhaust air in a different manner.
                An example of this would be if the driver made a severe brake application, then lifted his foot from the
                brake pedal (released foot valve). During a rapid brake release, air from the exhaust diaphragm flows
                back through the open exhaust solenoid and to the application device's exhaust. With pressure removed
                from the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, air, returning to the M-21 from the service chambers,
                lifts the exhaust diaphragm from its seat. Returning air flows past the open exhaust and out the the
                M-21 exhaust port. Air will also flow past the open supply diaphragm and back to the application
                device's exhaust.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402211" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. M-21 Non-Antilock Exhaust (Rapid)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Antilock Operation - General</title>
            <para>If a service brake application is made and the antilock system detects an impending wheel lockup, the
                antilock controller will immediately begin modification of the brake application using the M-21
                modulator.
            </para>
            <para>In order to modify the brake application, the coils of the two solenoid valves contained in the M-21
                are energized or de-energized in a pre-programmed sequence by the EC-15 antilock controller. When a
                solenoid coil is energized, a shuttle within the solenoid moves, and depending upon the function of the
                specific solenoid, it either opens or closes, thereby causing the exhaust or re-application of air
                pressure to the brake actuator. The solenoids in the M-21 are controlled independently by the antilock
                controller. By opening and closing the solenoid valves in the M-21 modulators, the antilock controller
                is able to simulate what the driver does when he "pumps the brakes." The antilock controller is able to
                "pump" each modulator, along with the brakes connected to it, independently and with far greater speed
                and accuracy.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Antilock Exhaust</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402212">Figure 12</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>When wheel lockup is detected, or about to occur, the antilock controller simultaneously energizes
                both the supply and exhaust solenoids in the M-21. Energizing the supply solenoid causes its exhaust to
                close and inlet to open. With the inlet of the supply solenoid open, application air is permitted to
                flow to the control side of the supply diaphragm. Air pressure acting on the supply diaphragm causes it
                to close the supply and prevent further delivery of air to the brake chamber.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402212" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402212.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. M-21 Antilock Exhaust</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Energizing the exhaust solenoid closes its inlet and opens its exhaust. By closing the exhaust
                solenoid inlet, application air is prevented from flowing to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm.
                Air pressure which was present on the control side of the exhaust diaphragm flows out the exhaust port
                of the M-21. With control air pressure removed from the exhaust diaphragm, brake application air forces
                the exhaust diaphragm to unseat, which allows it to flow out the M-21 exhaust port. The M-21 will remain
                in the Antilock Exhaust mode until the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has increased. The
                M-21 can enter the Antilock Hold or Re-apply mode from the Antilock Exhaust mode.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Antilock Hold</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402213">Figure 13</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402213" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0402213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. M-21 Antilock Holding Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The antilock controller will place the M-21 in the Hold position when it senses that the correct wheel
                speed (braking force) has been attained. The antilock controller will also place the M-21 in the Hold
                position, prior to entering the Re-Apply, when it detects recovery from a locked wheel condition. In
                this mode of operation, the M-21 supply solenoid remains energized, while the exhaust solenoid is
                de-energized.
            </para>
            <para>De-energizing the exhaust solenoid opens its inlet and closes its exhaust. Opening the exhaust
                solenoid inlet allows application air to flow to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, which then
                seals the exhaust passage. With the exhaust diaphragm seated, further exhaust of brake chamber air
                pressure is prevented. Because the supply solenoid remains energized, the supply diaphragm remains
                seated, thus preventing application air from flowing to the delivery port and out to the brake chamber.
                The M-21 can enter the Antilock Exhaust or Re-apply mode from the Antilock Hold mode.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>M-21 Modulator Valve (with 4-Channel System 04AZA): Antilock Re-Apply</title>
            <para>If the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has increased sufficiently to allow re-application
                of braking pressure, it de-energizes the supply and exhaust solenoids. With both solenoids de-energized,
                the M-21 re-applies air to the brakes in the same manner it did during a Non-Antilock Application.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
