<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - ASSEMBLY - CRANKCASE AND CRANKSHAFT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CRANKCASE AND CRANKSHAFT</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04004_19.xml" xrefid="f0400411">Figure 11</hotlnk>for numbers in parentheses.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">lf the compressor requires a drive end crankshaft oil seal (40), press it into the crankcase
                until it is flush with the crankcase casting. Using clean oil lubricate the sealing lips of the seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">lf the compressor uses a ball type main bearing (29), press the ball bearing onto the
                correct end of the crankshaft. Position the ball bearing and the crankshaft in the crankcase, making
                sure the drive end of the crankshaft is positioned in the crankcase as marked before disassembly.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the case of compressors with a rear main ball bearing, make certain to install the thrust
                        bearing in the crankcase before pressing the crankshaft and ball bearing into place. Carefully
                        press the crankshaft and ball bearing into the crankcase using an arbor press. Make certain not
                        to damage the oil seal, if the compressor is so equipped.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the O-ring seal (32) in the groove around the rear end cover or in the crankcase
                proper in the event a rear main ball bearing is in use. lf the rear end cover contains a precision
                sleeve bearing that serves as the crankshaft main bearing, make certain to install the thrust bearing.
                Install the end cover in the position as marked before disassembly, taking care not to damage the sleeve
                bearing, if so equipped.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the four cap screws or nuts that secure the rear end cover to the crankcase and
                tighten as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_34.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_36.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
