<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - COMPRESSOR DRIVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>COMPRESSOR DRIVE</title>
        <para>Every six months, 1800 operating hours or 50,000 miles, whichever occurs first, check for noisy compressor
            operation. Variations in noise level in conjunction with the compression and unloaded cycles generally
            indicate loose or worn drive components.
        </para>
        <para>On belt drive compressors check for pulley and belt alignment and tension. See
            <hotlnk document="s04004_41.xml" xrefid="hl0400401">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>. Adjust as necessary, paying
            particular attention not to over tighten belt tension. Check for loose and out of aligned pulleys. Adjust or
            replace as necessary. Compressor crankshaft keyway damage indicates a loose pulley and often requires
            compressor replacement. Main bearing failures on belt driven compressors often indicate excessive belt
            tension.
        </para>
        <para>A thorough inspection, and possible replacement, of drive components should be made at each compressor
            change. Special attention should be given to drive gears and couplings on compressors which have been
            operated at high discharge pressures due to a blocked or frozen discharge line.
        </para>
        <para>Check all compressor mounting bolts and retighten evenly as necessary. Check the condition of all
            compressor mounting brackets, tighten hardware as necessary, and replace if damaged.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
