<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATIONAL CHECKS OF SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL OPERATIONAL CHECK OF SPLIT
        AIR SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL OPERATIONAL CHECK OF SPLIT AIR SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels to prevent vehicle from moving.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect primary and secondary reservoir check valve operation.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Build 110 psi (758 kPa) of air in system.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With ignition switch "ON," open drain cock at service (wet) air reservoir and
                        completely drain reservoir. Low air pressure buzzer should come on at approximately 70 psi (483
                        kPa).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both primary and secondary reservoirs should retain air pressure.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If loss of air is noted in either system by observing the air gauges, the check
                        valve could be faulty.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the park brake control on tractors (yellow) and trailer supply control (red) in
                    released position (in), open drain cocks in primary and secondary reservoirs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <title>Straight Trucks</title>The park brake control (yellow) knob should automatically apply
                    between 25 - 35 psi (172 - 241 kPa).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>Tractors All</title>The red knob should pop out (exhaust position) when reservoir with
                    highest pressure reaches 40
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (276
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa). The red knob could pop immediately if air is depleted quickly at the trailer supply
                    (emergency) line.
                </para>
                <para>When air pressure in reservoir with higher pressure reaches 30
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (207
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa), the yellow knob may pop out. When air is depleted to 25
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (172
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa), the yellow knob must pop out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all reservoir drain cocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build up air supply in chassis system to approximately 110 psi (758 kPa).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With red knob pushed in, disconnect trailer emergency coupling from bracket. The red
                    knob should pop out instantaneously.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If red knob pops out, reconnect trailer emergency coupling. Push yellow knob (in) and
                    pull red knob (out).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check air pressure for leakage by observing air gauges on instrument panel. Leakage
                    should not be greater than 2 psi (13.8 kPa) in one minute.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open drain cock in secondary air reservoir. Drain cock must be opened all the way for
                    quick loss of air.
                </para>
                <para>You will note loss of air by observing air gauges. One system will show a loss of air. With
                    ignition switch on, low pressure indicator buzzer should sound at approximately 70 psi (483 kPa).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply service brakes and observe the slack adjusters and service brake chamber push
                    rods. Movement of the brake chamber push rods should occur at axles as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rear axles on all 4x2 vehicles.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Both rear axles on 6x4 vehicles.</para>
                    <para>If movement is noted at other axles, the primary reservoir was bled. Refer to Step 13. If
                        brake chamber push rod travel movement is as described, the primary system is good.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close drain cock in secondary air reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build air supply in air system to 110 psi (758 kPa).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open drain cock in primary reservoir. Observe opposite air pressure indicator for loss
                    of air. Be sure to open drain cock all the way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply service brakes and observe the slack adjusters and service brake chamber push
                    rods.
                </para>
                <para>There should be movement of brake chamber push rod travel as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Steering axle on all 4x2 vehicles; the spring brakes will apply and release until
                        air pressure drops to 25-35 psi (172-241 kPa), then full parking (spring) brake application will
                        occur.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Steering axle and any axle equipped with spring parking brake on 6x4 tractors.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When checking the system, the parking brakes will automatically apply on tractors when
                    air pressure is depleted to 25
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (172
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If movement of brake chamber push rods is as described, the secondary system is
                    functioning as it should.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all drain cocks and return vehicle to service.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
