<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - INVERSION VALVE (BENDIX SR-1) - REASSEMBLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <para>Prior to reassembly of the SR-1 inversion valve, lubricate all O-rings, O-ring grooves, piston bores and
            metal-to-metal moving surfaces with the silicone base lubricant packaged in the repair kit or Item 3 in
            <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400209.xml" xrefid="hl0400209">
                <xref refid="hl0400209"/>LUBRICANT SPECIFICATIONS
            </hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <para>The torque values listed in the assembly procedure are assembly torque values and can be expected to
            lighten following assembly. Do not retighten following initial assembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble check valve, valve spring guide and valve spring, and insert them in body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply pipe sealant to socket head pipe plug and install it in the body. Tighten to 130 to
                170 in-lbs. (15 to 19 N&#8226; m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place inlet and exhaust valve assembly into valve body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install exhaust diaphragm in exhaust cover.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position exhaust cover on body and secure cover with two screws. Tighten screws to 20 to 30
                in-lbs. (2.3 to 3.4 N&#8226; m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place inlet exhaust valve in body and install valve spring and valve stop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install O-ring on the cap nut and install the cap nut in body. Tighten to 100 to 125 in-lbs.
                (11 to 14 N&#8226; m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position small and large O-rings on small diameter piston and insert piston in body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install large and small O-rings on large diameter piston and insert the piston in body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position piston springs in their respective pistons.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure cover to body with four screws and lockwashers. Tighten four screws to 50 to 80
                in-lbs. (5.7 to 9 N&#183;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_68.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_70.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
