<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04051610" graphiccount="2">
        <title>RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The full power brake system is a pressurized system that achieves pressures of up to 2320 psi.
                        This pressure
                        <emph type="boldundersc">IS NOT</emph>
                        reduced by switching the ignition off or removing battery power. Prior to servicing this system,
                        the depressurization procedures
                        <emph type="boldundersc">MUST BE PERFORMED EXACTLY AS PRESENTED</emph>. Failure to depressurize
                        the system may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. The fuses are bundled in the cowl wire harness located near the master cylinder
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051601.xml" xrefid="f0405132">FIGURE 32</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose at the inlet to the HCU reservoir. Place the
                    clamp midway between the HCU reservoir inlet and the crossmember, being careful not to damage the
                    reservoir inlet. In some vehicle applications the rubber section of the low pressure hose is too
                    short to provide a leakproof clamp at this location. If necessary, clamp the low pressure hose 4 or
                    5 inches below the master cylinder outlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051605.xml" xrefid="f0405138">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the relay valve assembly and the area around it. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405148">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405148" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405148" filename="../figg04/G0405148.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. HCU Bottom View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ECU</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ORIENTATION TAB ON SEAL PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ECU ELECTRICAL HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RETAINING PLUG FOR SECONDARY (REAR) SYSTEM PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. RETAINING PLUG FOR PRIMARY (FRONT) SYSTEM PUMP (UNDER ITEM 1)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before performing the following steps, position a container to collect any drained or spilled
                        brake fluid to ensure that no fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both master cylinder brake lines from the relay valve assembly on the HCU.
                    Plug the brake lines and position them out of the way. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051608.xml" xrefid="f0405145">FIGURE 45</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 4 mm Allen wrench, remove the 5 screws that attach the relay valve assembly to
                    the HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405149">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405149" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405149" filename="../figg04/G0405149.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. HCU Exploded View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ECU</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HCU</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SECONDARY (REAR SYSTEM) PUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PUMP RETAINING PLUG</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY SEAL PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the relay valve assembly is to be re-used, no rubber or other material must be allowed to
                        enter the orifices on the top of the assembly.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rubber coated relay valve seal plate. Bend the seal plate to prevent re-use,
                    and discard.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If it is necessary to clean the mating surfaces of the HCU and relay valve assembly, use
                        denatured alcohol and a lint-free cloth.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <important>
                    <para>The relay valve seal plate must be positioned with the orientation tab in the correct
                        location,
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the mounting screw holes aligned with those in the relay valve assembly.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a new seal plate on the relay valve assembly, as follows;</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Insert two mounting screws into the relay valve assembly. In order for the screws to
                        protrude through the relay valve, they must be held with Allen wrenches or other tools.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using the screws as a guide, position the new, clean seal plate onto the top of the
                        relay valve assembly with the orientation tab located as indicated in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0405148">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Position the relay valve assembly against the bottom of the HCU, and thread the 2
                        screws into the HCU. Finger tighten only.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the remaining 3 mounting screws, and torque all 5 screws to 8.0 Nm (70.8 lbf-in)
                    in a two step process. Torque each screw twice following the sequence indicated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405148">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the master cylinder brake lines to the relay valve assembly as indicated in
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051608.xml" xrefid="f0405145">FIGURE 45</hotlnk>
                    . Torque these fittings to 12.2 to 19 Nm (9 to 14 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamp(s) used to pinch the low pressure hose during removal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the master cylinder reservoir up to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake
                    fluid from a sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The fluid level in the MC reservoir may drop when pressure is applied in the following step.
                        Whenever the MC reservoir is pressurized with air
                        <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                        to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark. If necessary, remove pressure from the
                        reservoir and add brake fluid to the MAX mark.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using service tool adapter ZTSE4678 and a regulator/filter (such as ZTSE4757-1, or
                    equivalent), pressurize the MC reservoir with filtered air regulated to 35 psi. Ensure that the
                    adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler neck, and that the air lines and
                    connections are not placing undue stress on the MC reservoir filler neck. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051401.xml" xrefid="f0405126">FIGURE 26</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds)*.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the fluid level in the MC reservoir. If the fluid level is at or below the MIN
                    mark, remove air pressure from the reservoir and fill to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake
                    fluid from a sealed container. Repressurize the MC reservoir to 35 psi, as in step 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function from the EOL pull down
                    menu. This function helps clear air from the HCU by depressurizing and repressurizing both
                    accumulators. A dialog box will indicate when the function is complete.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles equipped WITH ATC</emph>
                            - Select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;.
                            No user input is required. The changes in the accumulator pressures can be observed on the
                            TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic screen.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles WITHOUT ATC</emph>
                            - While depressing the brake pedal, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL
                            pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;. The pedal must remain depressed until the pressure in
                            BOTH accumulators begins to rise (as observed on the diagnostic screen), then release the
                            brake pedal.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the pressure from the MC reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the fluid in the MC reservoir is at or near the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, perform the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function two more times.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the master cylinder circuits. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051401.xml" xrefid="hl04051401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of the RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY REMOVAL procedures to verify that
                        the system is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage,
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check system for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system before making
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function in the following steps should correct the problem. After completing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function, both accumulators should be fully charged as indicated on the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                screen. If an accumulator is still not charging correctly refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051609.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051611.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
