<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAMONDLIFE&#8482; (BOSCH PIN SLIDE) DISC BRAKES For Vehicles Built Before June 3, 2002 - REMOVE - DISC
        BRAKE PADS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0404001" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="8">
        <title>DISC BRAKE PADS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>There are three types of lining materials available for the hydraulic pin slide brake system.
                HX-7A1-EE brake pads and softer lining brake pads identified by lining code 7610 with smooth backing
                plates for heavy duty braking applications and HX-402-EE brake pads for light duty braking applications.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The HX-7A1-EE lining material of inboard disc brake pad
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_3.xml" xrefid="f0404003">(Item 1, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404003"/>
                        and outboard disc brake pad
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_3.xml" xrefid="f0404003">(Item 2, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404003"/>
                        are chamfered and are marked with an "ARROW" and the word "FORWARD" for proper installation.
                        Brake pads are NOT interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The optional HX-402-EE lining material of inboard and outboard disc brake pads
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_3.xml" xrefid="f0404003">(Item 3, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404003"/>
                        are NOT chamfered and ARE interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The optional SOFTER lining material of inboard and outboard disc brake pads
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_3.xml" xrefid="f0404003">(Item 3, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404003"/>
                        are NOT chamfered and ARE interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>As lining wears on disc brake pads, brake fluid level in the reservoir will lower. Before servicing
                the calipers, inspect the fluid level. If the fluid level is at or near proper fluid level, remove some
                brake fluid from the reservoir, using a siphon or syringe. When the pistons are pushed back into the
                caliper piston bores the fluid will be pushed back to the reservoir and may overflow if not removed.
                Discard the used fluid removed from the master cylinder.
            </para>
            <para>If inspection reveals that caliper piston boots are worn or damaged, replace them. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404002.xml" xrefid="x0404002">CALIPER, Remove
                    <xref refid="x0404002"/>
                </hotlnk>
                ,
                <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404005.xml" xrefid="x0404005">CALIPER, Disassemble
                    <xref refid="x0404005"/>
                </hotlnk>
                ,
                <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404007.xml" xrefid="x0404007">CALIPER, Clean and Inspect
                    <xref refid="x0404007"/>
                </hotlnk>
                ,
                <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404010.xml" xrefid="x0404010">CALIPER, Assemble
                    <xref refid="x0404010"/>
                </hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="x0404013">CALIPER, Install
                    <xref refid="x0404013"/>
                </hotlnk>
                to remove, disassemble, clean and inspect, assemble and install to repair or replace caliper.
            </para>
            <para>During service procedure, keep grease and other foreign material from caliper assembly, disc brake
                pads, brake rotor and external surfaces of hub. Handle parts carefully to avoid damage to caliper,
                rotor, disc brake pads and brake lines.
            </para>
            <para>The following steps refer to only one wheel. The same procedure will need to be performed at each
                wheel.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position vehicle on suitable floor stands and remove wheel (tire and rim). Refer to
                    GROUP 17 - WHEELS in the Master Service Manual for proper wheel (tire and rim) removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A jack must never be used alone to support a vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                        performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle
                        with suitable floor stands.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect master cylinder fluid level and remove fluid if necessary as described above.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a screwdriver in one of the rotor cooling fin slots and pry the caliper outboard
                    pushing the caliper pistons into the piston bores. This will allow removal of caliper
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404013">(Figure 13)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404013" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Push Caliper Outboard Pushing Pistons into Piston Bores</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404014">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On front axles only, remove hex nut and lock washer (Item 1) and lift brake line
                    retaining clip (Item 2) off threaded stud (Item 3) on the steering knuckle hose support bracket
                    (Item 4). This will allow the brake line hose to hang free.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404014" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Removing Brake Line Retaining Clip from Front Axle Hose Support Bracket</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>DRIVER SIDE FRONT SHOWN</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. HEX NUT AND LOCK WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE LINE RETAINING CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREADED STUD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HOSE SUPPORT BRACKET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404015">Figure 15</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On rear axles only, if vehicle is equipped with ABS brake system and/or air suspension
                    system, note that the brake line hose (Item 1) is attached to ABS sensor cable (Item 2) with tywrap
                    straps (Item 3) from retaining clip (Item 4) on axle (Item 5) to disc brake assembly (Item 6).
                    Remove hex head bolt (Item 7) from retaining clip (Item 4). Remove hex head bolt (Item 8) and brake
                    line retaining clip (Item 9) from caliper (Item 10). This will allow the brake line hose to hang
                    free while rotating the caliper down to replace disc brake pads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If it becomes necessary to cut any of the tywrap straps (Item 3) to allow caliper to rotate
                        all the way down during disc brake pad replacement, note the location of the tywrap strap before
                        cutting it off, so it can be replaced in the proper place after service is completed.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0404015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Removing Brake Line Retaining Clips from Rear Axle and Caliper</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRAKE LINE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ABS SENSOR CABLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TYWRAP STRAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. RETAINING CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. AXLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. DISC BRAKE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. HEX HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. HEX HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. RETAINING CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. CALIPER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never remove lower (bottom) hex mounting bolt securing caliper to anchor plate during disc
                        brake pad service procedure. The caliper will not rotate over top center and will fall, which
                        may cause personal injury
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0404016">(Figure 16)</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0404016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. DO NOT Raise Caliper as Shown</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404017">Figure 17</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper (top) hex mounting bolt (Item 1) securing the caliper (Item 2) to the
                    anchor plate (Item 3), driver side front brake shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When servicing disc brake pads only, loosen and remove the upper (top) caliper hex mounting
                        bolt (Item 1) only. Do not loosen lower (bottom) hex mounting bolt (Item 4). For proper
                        tightening and torquing sequence refer to install section for disc brake pads.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0404017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Remove Upper Hex Mounting Bolt to Lower Caliper to Replace Disc Brake Pads</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>DRIVER SIDE FRONT (66 mm) SHOWN</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. UPPER HEX MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CALIPER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ANCHOR PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER HEX MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404018">Figure 18</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully rotate the caliper (Item 1) open about the lower (bottom) hex mounting bolt
                    and guide pin (Items 2 and 3).
                </para>
                <para>Do not allow the brake line hose (Item 4) to become pinched or kinked, driver side front brake
                    shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use care to avoid damaging or dislodging the upper (top) or lower (bottom) guide pin boots
                        (Items 5 and 7). Do not pull on guide pins (Items 3 and 6), this may dislodge guide pin boot
                        from guide pin or anchor plate grooves. If boot is dislodged, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404006.xml" xrefid="x0404006">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                            Disassemble
                            <xref refid="x0404006"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        ,
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404009.xml" xrefid="x0404009">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Clean
                            and Inspect
                            <xref refid="x0404009"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404011.xml" xrefid="x0404011">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                            Assemble
                            <xref refid="x0404011"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        to disassemble, clean and inspect and assemble to repair or replace guide pin boots.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0404018" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Rotate Caliper Open About Lower Hex Mounting Bolt and Guide Pin</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>DRIVER SIDE FRONT (66 mm) SHOWN</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. CALIPER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LOWER HEX MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LOWER GUIDE PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE LINE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. UPPER GUIDE PIN BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. UPPER GUIDE PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. LOWER GUIDE PIN BOOT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404019">Figure 19</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove inboard and outboard disc brake pads (Items 1 and 2) from anchor plate pad
                    abutment slippers (Item 3), driver side front and rear brake shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove anchor plate pad abutment slippers (Item 3) from anchor plate pad abutment,
                    driver side front and rear brake shown. New anchor plate pad abutment slippers are supplied with new
                    disc brake pad sets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404019" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Remove Inboard and Outboard Disc Brake Pads</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. INBOARD DISC BRAKE PAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. OUTBOARD DISC BRAKE PAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ANCHOR PLATE PAD ABUTMENT SLIPPER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. GUIDE PIN BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. UPPER GUIDE PIN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use care to avoid damaging or dislodging the guide pin boots
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0404019">(Item 4, Figure 19)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404019"/>
                        while cleaning machined surfaces of caliper, guide pin mounting face and anchor plate with hand
                        held wire brush. If boot is damaged or dislodged, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404006.xml" xrefid="x0404006">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                            Disassemble
                            <xref refid="x0404006"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        ,
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404009.xml" xrefid="x0404009">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Clean
                            and Inspect
                            <xref refid="x0404009"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404011.xml" xrefid="x0404011">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                            Assemble
                            <xref refid="x0404011"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        to disassemble, clean and inspect and assemble to repair or replace guide pin boots. Do not get
                        solvent on guide pin boots, damage to boots will occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check machined surfaces of caliper, guide pin mounting face and anchor plate. If any
                    rust or corrosion is present, use a hand held wire brush to clean these surfaces. It is important to
                    clean those areas of the caliper, guide pins and anchor plate that are in contact with the brake
                    pads or each other. If leading or trailing guide pins have rust or corrosion and can not be cleaned,
                    it is recommended that the guide pins and hex mounting bolts be replaced. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404006.xml" xrefid="x0404006">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                        Disassemble
                        <xref refid="x0404006"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    ,
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404009.xml" xrefid="x0404009">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Clean and
                        Inspect
                        <xref refid="x0404009"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404011.xml" xrefid="x0404011">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Assemble
                        <xref refid="x0404011"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    to disassemble, clean and inspect and assemble to replace guide pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect caliper for leakage, damage or defects to piston boots or pistons. If
                    leakage, damage or defects are found, repair or replace as required. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404002.xml" xrefid="x0404002">CALIPER, Remove
                        <xref refid="x0404002"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    ,
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404005.xml" xrefid="x0404005">CALIPER, Disassemble
                        <xref refid="x0404005"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    ,
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404007.xml" xrefid="x0404007">CALIPER, Clean and Inspect
                        <xref refid="x0404007"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    ,
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404010.xml" xrefid="x0404010">CALIPER, Assemble
                        <xref refid="x0404010"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="x0404013">CALIPER, Install
                        <xref refid="x0404013"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    to remove, disassemble, clean and inspect, assemble and install to repair or replace caliper.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a metal plate over both caliper pistons, then use a "C" clamp to push both
                    pistons into the caliper
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404020">(Figure 20)</hotlnk>. Pushing the caliper pistons into the caliper will
                    provide clearance for new disc brake pads when caliper is rotated back into position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404020" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404020.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Push Both Pistons Into Caliper</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Several changes have been incorporated within the anchor plate assembly and caliper mounting
                        bolts on vehicles manufactured after June 3, 2002. It is important to recognize that these
                        changes are not found on disc brakes on vehicles manufactured before June 3, 2002, unless a
                        complete rebuild of the anchor plate assembly was performed on the vehicle. The components that
                        have changed are the leading and trailing guide pins
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404067">(Figure 67)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404067"/>
                        and
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404068">(Figure 68)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404068"/>
                        and caliper mounting bolts
                        <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404071">(Figure 71)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f0404071"/>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect anchor plate for damage or defects to mating surfaces at anchor plate
                    pad abutment slippers
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404019">(Item 3, Figure 19)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404019"/>
                    and upper guide pin head
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404019">(Item 5, Figure 19)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404019"/>. Check that the upper guide pin is free to slide and rotate, making sure
                    the upper guide pin head, upper hex mounting bolt and mating caliper surfaces are clean and free of
                    grease or foreign substances. Also check that lower guide pin is free to slide and rotate before
                    moving to next step. If guide pins are not free to rotate or slide or if other damage or defects are
                    found, repair or replace as required.
                </para>
                <para>If it is necessary to replace the guide pins, it is recommended that the old guide pins
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404067">(Figure 67)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404067"/>
                    be replaced with the new guide pins
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404068">(Figure 68)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404068"/>. When the guide pins are changed, it will be necessary to replace the old
                    hex mounting bolts with the new hex flanged mounting bolts
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404013.xml" xrefid="f0404071">(Figure 71)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404071"/>. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404006.xml" xrefid="x0404006">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD,
                        Disassemble
                        <xref refid="x0404006"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    ,
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404009.xml" xrefid="x0404009">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Clean and
                        Inspect
                        <xref refid="x0404009"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404011.xml" xrefid="x0404011">ANCHOR PLATE AND SPLASH SHIELD, Assemble
                        <xref refid="x0404011"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    to disassemble, clean and inspect and assemble to repair or replace guide pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect rotor for scoring, warping, cracks, bluing, heat spots or other damage
                    or defects. If any damage or defects are found, repair or replace as required. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404003.xml" xrefid="x0404003">ROTOR AND WHEEL HUB ASSEMBLY, Remove
                        <xref refid="x0404003"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404014.xml" xrefid="x0404014">ROTOR AND WHEEL HUB ASSEMBLY, Install
                        <xref refid="x0404014"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404002.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
