<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The EC-16 is an electronic antilock controller. In addition to the antilock function, the EC-16 can be
                assembled and programmed to provide an optional traction control feature.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                shows the basic EC-16 configuration.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403201" filename="../figg04/G0403201.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. EC-16 Electronic Antilock Controller</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Designed to minimize potential brake lock- up on all wheels during aggressive braking, the EC-16-based
                antilock system (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403202">Figure 2</hotlnk>) provides the vehicle with a high degree of stability and
                steerability during braking. In most cases, vehicle stopping distance is also reduced. The antilock
                portion of the EC-16-based system minimizes wheel skid during hard or aggressive braking. By controlling
                wheel skid at all wheels on the vehicle, optimum steering control and stopping distance is obtained.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403202" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403202" filename="../figg04/G0403202.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. EC-16-Based Antilock System</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Traction control, an optional feature in the full-vehicle wheel control antilock system, helps improve
                vehicle traction during acceleration in adverse road conditions. Integrated with antilock logic,
                traction control monitors wheel speed information from the sensors during acceleration, as well as
                braking. The system helps maintain vehicle stability on hazardous road surfaces and improves
                driveability and safety.
            </para>
            <para>The EC-16 electronics are contained in a die-cast aluminum housing and are environmentally protected
                by a self-healing silicone compound. The metal housing and the design of the digital electronics are
                intended to provide a high degree of protection from radio and electromagnetic interference.
            </para>
            <para>The light emitting diode (LED) display and a magnetically actuated reset switch is incorporated in the
                housing for troubleshooting and diagnostic purposes.
            </para>
            <para>Two electrical connectors, located in the controller housing opposite the diagnostic display, connect
                the EC-16 to antilock and traction system components: one 30-pin and one 18-pin Packard Electric 150
                series "Metri-pack" connector
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>. In addition to these two housing mounted connectors, the
                EC-16 also uses a 2-pin Deutsch connector when programmed with the optional traction control feature.
                The 2-pin connector is linked to a traction solenoid, which is located in the upper portion of the
                antilock traction relay valve assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403204">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403203" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403203" filename="../figg04/G0403203.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Connector Schematic</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0403204" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403204" filename="../figg04/G0403204.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Antilock Traction Relay Valve Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
