<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - USING ACOM FOR WINDOWS SOFTWARE - ACOM INFORMATION MENU</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="9">
        <title>ACOM INFORMATION MENU</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ACom Information menu offers 6 possible options. 5 of the 6 options can be accessed both in or out
                of the Diagnostic Mode. The Current Faults option cannot be accessed in the diagnostic mode (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403839">Figure 39</hotlnk>). See Mode Menu for Entering and exiting the Diagnostic
                Mode.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403839" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403839.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. ACom Information Menu</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Firmware Version Selection</title>
            <para>Clicking the Firmware Version selection initiates an interrogation of the antilock controller. The
                version number assigned to the ABS controller on the vehicle is then displayed in a window.
            </para>
            <para>This information may be required when calling for technical support. For additional help, see the ACom
                help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403840">Figure 40</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403840" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403840.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Firmware Version Selection</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Change Reference Number Selection</title>
            <para>Clicking the Change Reference Number selection initiates an interrogation of the antilock controller.
                The reference number assigned to the vehicle's ABS controller is obtained and then displayed in a
                window. This information may be required when calling for technical support. For additional help, see
                the ACom help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403841">Figure 41</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403841" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403841.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Change Reference Number Selection</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Current Faults Selection</title>
            <para>Use the Current Faults option under the Information menu to display a detailed list of the vehicle's
                current faults. The Current Faults selection displays a detailed list of the current faults for the ABS
                and traction control system. The list of current faults displays:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The number of times that a fault has been reported since the last time the list was cleared.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The location of the fault.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A description of the fault.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>After you diagnose and fix a fault, you should clear the current fault list. If there are multiple
                faults, any faults that still exist will be reinstated on the list. Faults are cleared by clicking the
                CLEAR button on the window. A confirmation box will appear and OK should be selected if clearing the
                faults is still desired. For additional help, see the ACom help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403842">Figure 42</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403842" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403842.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Current Fault List</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fault History Selection</title>
            <para>The Fault History selection provides a means of managing a historical record of vehicle faults. The
                ABS controller maintains a record of vehicle faults in memory. A list of the faults that occurred on the
                vehicle in the past (as well as the faults that currently exist on the vehicle) can be generated. The
                list contains details that include the time of the last vehicle powerup when the fault occurred and a
                description of each fault (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403843">Figure 43</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403843" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403843.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Fault History</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Using the Fault History dialog box, the technician can:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Generate a list of historical faults.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clear the fault history.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Save the fault history to a file.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Open an existing fault history file.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Print the fault history.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>After opening the Fault History window, one of two actions may be taken.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The current history can be obtained by clicking the "Read" button.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A past history can be opened up by clicking the "Open" button and selecting a previously
                    saved history (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0403844">Figure 44</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0403844" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403844.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 44. Past History</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Once the faults are read into the history window the technician can print the history, enter a
                Description of the inspection and save the fault history to a file on the computer hard drive or
                diskette. While the faults can be cleared in this window after completing the repairs, it is not
                necessary to do so after repairs are completed (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403841">Figure 41</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>Once saved the file can be re-opened for reference. For additional help, see the ACom help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403845">Figure 45</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403845" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403845.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 45. Re-Open File for Reference</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Occurrence Counts Selection</title>
            <para>The Occurrence Counts selection functions much the same as the Fault History selection. The technician
                generates a list that includes the number of faults that have occurred on the vehicle, a description of
                each fault, and an indication of whether the fault is still active on the vehicle. As with the Fault
                History the occurrence count list can be saved and printed. Also like the Fault History selection, once
                the window is opened, one of two actions may be taken.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The current fault occurrences can be obtained by clicking the "Read" button.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A past history can be opened up by clicking the "Open" button and selecting a previously
                    saved occurrences file.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>For additional help, see the ACom help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403846">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403846" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403846.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Occurrence Counts</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Speeds Selection</title>
            <para>ACom for Windows allows the technician to monitor wheel speeds to make sure that all the wheel speed
                sensors are adjusted and functioning properly. The ABS controller obtains wheel speeds from wheel speed
                sensors installed on the vehicle axles. When the wheel rotates, the wheel speed sensors generate AC
                signals which are sent to and interpreted by the ABS controller. The ABS controller can use the
                information to command the antilock brake and traction control system accordingly.
            </para>
            <para>Using the Wheel Speed option under the Information menu, the technician can:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Record and play back wheel speeds.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Save a wheel speed recording to a file.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Open an existing wheel speed recording.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Print a wheel speed recording.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The Wheel Speed Data dialog box functions much like a tape recorder with a Play button, Rewind button,
                etc. The technician can record and play back the speed of all the vehicle's wheels at once or play back
                only the speed of individual wheels. The wheel speeds are displayed on a line graph with different
                colors to represent each wheel. The X in the check box next to the wheel name indicates that the graph
                will display the speed of the wheel on the graph. The number below the check box shows the wheel's speed
                at the time at which the recording is stopped. For additional help, see the ACom help menu (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403847">Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403847" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403847.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Wheel Speed Data</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_43.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_45.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
