<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - Master cylinder (MC)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048601" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Master cylinder (MC)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact, nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>This component has a limited shelf life. When replacing this component, note the expiration
                        date.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Removing the master cylinder involves removing the master cylinder reservoir. If the old
                        reservoir is going to be installed onto the new master cylinder, care must be taken during the
                        removal process. Do not install a damaged reservoir.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404843">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404843" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404843" filename="../figg04/G0404833.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="256px"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Location of Motor Fuses</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FUSE COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FUSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COWL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FUSE PANEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404844" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404844" filename="../figg04/G0404834.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="256px"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. Location of Diagnostic Connector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DIAGNOSTIC CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DASH TRIM PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER / BODY CONTROLLER (ESC/BC)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404844">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>. Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the outside of the MC/reservoir assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connections from the brake light switch on the MC, and the
                    fluid level switch on the MC reservoir. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404845">FIGURE 50</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose near the outlet of the MC reservoir, being
                    careful not to damage the reservoir outlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404845">FIGURE 50</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404845" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404845" filename="../figg04/G0404845A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Low Pressure Hose Clamped at the Master Cylinder Reservoir</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MASTER CYLINDER RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BRAKE LIGHT SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FLUID LEVEL SENSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RESERVOIR MOUNTING NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. LOCKING CLAMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before performing the following step, position a container under the MC to collect any drained
                        or spilled brake fluid. Ensure that no fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint. Up
                        to 3.4 liters (1 gal) of brake fluid will be drained.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the low pressure hose from the MC reservoir. All the fluid coming out of the
                    MC reservoir should drain into the container. Plug the low pressure hose to prevent contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cap on the MC reservoir to assist draining.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the reservoir cap and plug the reservoir outlet to prevent any remaining fluid
                    from spilling during removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Some brake fluid will remain in protected areas of the MC reservoir.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 2 brake tubes from the MC. Plug the brake tubes and the MC ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the MC push rod clevis from the brake pedal by removing the clevis pin and
                    spring retainer/clip. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404846">FIGURE 51</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404846" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404846" filename="../figg04/G0404846A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. Connecting Master Cylinder Clevis to Brake Pedal Arm</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CLEVIS PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. RETAINING CLIP FOR CLEVIS PIN
                        <callout2>A. To attach, insert main shaft into hole, slip forward tang and loop over end of
                            shaft
                        </callout2>
                        <callout2>B. Latched, but unlocked</callout2>
                        <callout2>C. To lock, place forward tang under main shaft</callout2>
                        <callout2>D. Locked position</callout2>
                        <callout2>E. To unlock, place forward tang over main shaft</callout2>
                        <callout2>F. Latched, but unlocked</callout2>
                        <callout2>G. To remove, lift loop and forward tang, and remove ring</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CLEVIS ON MASTER CYLINDER PUSHROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE PEDAL ARM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unbolt the MC reservoir from the mounting bracket (1 nut). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404847">FIGURE 52</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unbolt the MC from the mounting bracket (2 nuts). Remove MC and reservoir from
                    bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pour any brake fluid remaining in the MC/reservoir assembly into a suitable container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, care must be taken to protect the reservoir mounting tabs from
                        excessive deflection when removing the roll pins. One method is to back up the mounting tab with
                        a socket or similar object that allows the pins to be driven through the tab without deflecting
                        the tab. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0404848">FIGURE 53</hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the MC/reservoir by driving out the 2 roll pins securing the reservoir to the
                    MC. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404847">FIGURE 52</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the reservoir off of the MC. Some resistance will be felt due to the rubber seals
                    between the MC and the reservoir.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0404847" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="G0404847" filename="../figG04/G0404847A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="256px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 52. Roll Pins Securing Reservoir to Master Cylinder</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. RESERVOIR MOUNTING NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. FLUID LEVEL SENSOR CONNECTOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. ROLL PINS</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. BRAKE LIGHT SWITCH CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0404848" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="G0404848" filename="../figG04/G0404848.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 53. Suggested Method of Installing Roll Pins to Connect Master Cylinder Reservoir
                    </caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. MASTER CYLINDER RESERVOIR (NOT TO SCALE)</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. ROLL PIN</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. MASTER CYLINDER BODY (NOT TO SCALE)</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SOCKET (OR OTHER SUITABLE OBJECT) PRESSED AGAINST RESERVOIR MOUNTING TAB</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the new MC and reservoir.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate 2 new black rubber MC-to-reservoir seals with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake
                        fluid.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the new seals into the ports on top of the MC.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the reservoir by pressing it carefully and fully into the seals.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>In the following step, care must be taken to protect the reservoir mounting tabs from
                                excessive deflection when installing the roll pins. One method is to back up the
                                mounting tab with a socket or similar object that allows the pins to be driven through
                                the tab without deflecting the tab. It is important to line up the pin with the holes in
                                the tabs. Refer to
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404848">FIGURE 53</hotlnk>.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the 2 roll pins from the replacement parts kit to attach the reservoir to the
                        MC.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the MC/reservoir assembly so that the stud on the bracket is inserted into the
                    reservoir mounting tab, the MC base slips over the 2 mounting studs on the bracket, and the MC
                    clevis passes through the hole in the cowl.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using 2 mounting nuts, secure the MC base to the bracket. Torque the nuts to 61 to 68 Nm
                    (45 to 50 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using 1 mounting nut, secure the reservoir to the bracket. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404847">FIGURE 52</hotlnk>
                    . Torque the nut to 29 to 32 Nm (21 to 24 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the MC push rod clevis to the pedal assembly using the clevis pin and the spring
                    retainer/clip. Lock the spring retainer/clip. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404846">FIGURE 51</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the primary and secondary brake tubes to the MC. Tighten to 17 to 22.5 Nm (12.5
                    to 16.5 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the low pressure hose to the MC reservoir using the existing hose clamp. Remove
                    pinch clamp from hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>In the following step the electrical connection must be reconnected to the brake light switch
                        on the MC to insure that the brake system ABS functions operate correctly. Failure to follow
                        this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical connections to the brake light switch on the MC, and the fluid
                    level switch on the MC reservoir. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404847">FIGURE 52</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed MC circuit. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048401.xml" xrefid="hl04048401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKES
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of the MASTER CYLINDER REMOVAL procedures to verify that the
                        system is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage,
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check system for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system before making
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048600.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048602.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
