<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSTICS - DIAGNOSTIC LEDS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC LEDS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403206">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>There are ten LEDs plus a magnetically actuated reset switch in the EC-16 diagnostic display. The
                first six LEDs locate a condition to a specific area of the vehicle, and the next three indicate the
                condition component or its wiring. The LEDs are software-driven and are either ON or OFF depending upon
                their monitor function.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403206" filename="../figg04/G0403206.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Diagnostic LEDs</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Right and left, front and rear are determined from the driver's seat.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <table id="hl0403203">
                <title>Diagnostic LEDs</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.48in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="2.52in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="2" spanname="s1t2"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>FRT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>MID</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED*</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>RER</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>RHT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>LFT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>TRC</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>MOD</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>SEN</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>ECU</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Red LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>VLT</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Green LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>RESET +</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>No LED</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="s1t2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">*The MID LED is used with some but not all vehicles. When six
                                        speed sensors are not installed, this LED is not used in the diagnostic process.
                                        However, it will light when a magnet is placed on RESET switch in the diagnostic
                                        display.
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>FRT (Front) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will light in conjunction with either the RIGHT or LEFT LED and the MOD or SEN LED.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MID (Mid Axle) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED is not used in all installations. On those vehicles that have six speed sensors
                installed, this Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem speed sensor or
                its wiring. The MID LED should not illuminate with the MOD LED.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RER (Rear) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will light in conjunction with either the RIGHT or LEFT LED and the MOD or SEN LED.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RHT (Right) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will light in conjunction with either the FRONT or REAR LED and the MOD or SEN LED.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>LFT (Left) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will light in conjunction with either the FRONT or REAR LED and the MOD or SEN LED.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRC (Traction) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate a permanent problem in the traction control
                system. It may be illuminated with the MOD LED or may illuminate by itself.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an intermittent problem exists with the wiring to the engine control module (ECM), this LED
                        will go on. However, it will not latch, it will go out when the problem "corrects" itself.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>MOD (Modulator) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate a permanent or intermittent open or short circuit
                in the solenoids of one of the four M-21 modulators or the wiring connecting them to the system. When
                indicating a problem with an M-21, this LED will be illuminated with two positioning LEDs (RHT/LFT +
                FRT/RER).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The MID positioning LED should not be illuminated with this LED.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This LED is also used to indicate a problem with an ATR-1 or 2, antilock traction relay, and/or
                solenoid. When illuminated for a traction system problem, the TRC LED will also be on.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SEN (Speed Sensor) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate permanent or intermittent failure. The failures
                indicated are open or shorted wheel sensor does not conform to design criteria. The SEN LED will be
                illuminated with two positioning LEDs (RHT/LFT + FRT/MID/ RER).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECU (Electronic Control Unit) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED, when illuminated, indicates that the controller itself has failed. It is latched ON for
                all EC-16 failures except low voltage. Before controller replacement is considered, always check vehicle
                voltage to the controller.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VLT LED</title>
            <para>This Green LED illuminates and remains ON during vehicle operation to indicate that vehicle power is
                reaching the controller. If vehicle power is out of range (below 11 VDC or above 17 VDC), this LED will
                flash until power is brought into range.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RESET</title>
            <para>Beneath the RESET area of the display is a magnetically sensitive switch that is used to reset the
                diagnostic system. The device will respond to a magnet which has strength sufficient to lift a three (3)
                ounce weight. Momentarily holding a magnet against the RESET will cause ALL LEDs to light during the
                time the magnet is against it. Holding a magnet against the RESET longer than 10 to 20 seconds will
                cause the newer version EC-16 to initiate the self-configuration feature.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403204.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
