<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE: AR-1 - MAINTENANCE - EVERY YEAR, 100,000 MILES, OR 3,600 OPERATING HOURS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EVERY YEAR, 100,000 MILES, OR 3,600 OPERATING HOURS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operating Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and release the brakes several times and check for prompt application and release
                    at each wheel. If prompt reaction is not noted at all wheels, test the antilock modulator between
                    the AR-1 and the brake chamber for proper operation. If a "sluggish," or incomplete response is
                    noted at all wheels, inspect for a kinked or obstructed air line leading to or from the AR-1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">During brake release, confirm that a slight puff of air exits at the AR-1's quick
                    exhaust port in the cover. Air exiting at this exhaust port indicates the AR-1 integral quick
                    release is functioning.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build the air system pressure to governor cut-out, then apply a soap solution to the
                    exhaust port in body. The leakage noted should not exceed a one-inch bubble in less than three (3)
                    seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make and hold a full brake application and apply a soap solution to the exhaust ports in
                    the body and cover and around the cover where it joins the body. The leakage noted should not exceed
                    a one-inch bubble in less than three (3) seconds at any exhaust port.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
