<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSING AND LOCATING A SYSTEM FAULT - GENERAL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GENERAL</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The EC-17 contains self test and diagnostic circuitry that continuously checks for proper operation of
                the entire antilock/traction system, including wiring continuity. The EC-17 is programmed at the factory
                to accommodate the needs of the vehicle and the customer's desires. Both the EC-17 controller can be
                reconfigured by the end user to include traction control. A vehicle equipped with traction control can
                generally be identified by noting the presence of a dash mounted condition lamp, a disable switch (for
                the traction control system) and a traction solenoid located above the relay valve.
            </para>
            <para>Separate dash lamps, controlled by the EC-17, advise the driver of the condition of the entire
                antilock/traction system.
            </para>
            <para>When the controller senses an erroneous condition, it stores the condition in memory, illuminates the
                dash-mounted condition lamp and after certain criteria are met, it disables the antilock or traction
                control function.
            </para>
            <para>The fault condition is truly stored and is not cleared by loss of power to the antilock system. After
                the actual issue is corrected, maintenance personnel can clear or reset the EC-17 diagnostics through
                the S.A.E. J1587 diagnostic link or the optional magnetic RESET point in the diagnostics display.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Important Note</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following section of this manual deals with the AlliedSignal Bendix Diagnostic
                        Communication Interface, or DCI, for diagnostics or reconfiguration.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_23.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_25.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
