<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATION - AUTOMATIC TRACTION CONTROL (ATC) MODE (VEHICLES WITH
        OPTIONAL ATC)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="2">
        <title>AUTOMATIC TRACTION CONTROL (ATC) MODE (VEHICLES WITH OPTIONAL ATC)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Automatic Traction Control is not available on four wheel drive (4x4) vehicles.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>The two ATC valves are only present in vehicles equipped with the optional Automatic Traction
                        Control.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Automatic Traction Control uses the ABS components and concepts to improve vehicle traction while
                accelerating. The ATC function is disabled if the ECU senses a brake pedal actuation. As with ABS, the
                ECU uses the information from the wheel speed sensors to determine when the ATC mode is necessary. A
                drive wheel speed higher than the vehicle speed (based on the non-driven wheels) indicates that the
                drive wheel is losing traction. Traction control is provided in two stages. If only one drive wheel is
                losing traction, the ECU will control the valves in the HCU to provide braking to the spinning drive
                wheel, to correct the condition through differential braking. If both drive wheels are losing traction,
                the ECU will also send a J1939 message to the Engine Control Module (ECM) reducing the torque of the
                engine. Differential braking is limited to vehicle speeds of 31 mph and lower.
            </para>
            <para>The dash-mounted MUD/SNOW switch is used to select between two traction control modes (Normal or Mud
                and Snow). When operating in the Mud and Snow mode, the software in the ECU allows more wheel slippage
                to occur. This mode can be desirable when operating in deep snow, mud, or off-road conditions. Since the
                two modes differ in degree only, the basic theory of operation is the same for both. Therefore, unless
                noted otherwise, the following descriptions pertain to both ATC modes.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Inactive (ATC Circuit Operation with No ATC Event Occurring)</title>
            <para>This description and diagram are provided to allow a comparison for the ATC Active mode. When ATC is
                inactive the brake system is operating in the Normal (non-braking) mode (described earlier), and no ATC
                event is being experienced. For the sake of describing the ATC circuit,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405023">FIGURE 23</hotlnk>
                shows the ATC valves, as well as the ABS inlet and outlet valves. As illustrated in the figure, the ATC
                valves provide a second hydraulic input to the relay valves. When the ECU is not sensing an ATC event,
                the ATC valves are in their 'normal' states. The ATC inlet valve is closed and the ATC outlet valve is
                open. In this condition the ATC inlet valve is blocking the pressurized brake fluid (stored in the
                primary accumulator) from reaching the ATC input of the relay valves . Instead, the open ATC outlet
                valve connects that line to the unpressurized reservoir return line.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405023" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405023" filename="../figg04/g0405023a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Brake Fluid Routing - ATC Inactive Mode</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Active (ATC Circuit Operation while Experiencing an ATC Event)</title>
            <para>If the brake pedal is not pressed, and the wheel speed sensors indicate that one or both drive wheels
                are losing traction, the ECU will activate the ATC circuit.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405024">FIGURE 24</hotlnk>
                shows the hydraulic system while operating in the ATC active mode due to a slipping right rear wheel
                (vehicle speed is less than 31 mph).
            </para>
            <para>As the right rear wheel begins to lose traction, the signal generated by its wheel speed sensor
                indicates the slippage to the ECU. When the ATC event is sensed by the ECU, it switches the states of
                the ATC valves and the ABS inlet and outlet valves to correct the traction problem. With the ATC inlet
                valve now in the open state, and the ATC outlet valve in the closed state, the pressurized brake fluid
                is routed from the primary accumulator to the relay valves. The relay valves respond by applying
                pressurized brake fluid from the accumulator to the ABS inlet valves for the wheels. Because the ECU
                recognizes that only the right rear wheel is slipping, the ABS inlet valves for the left rear wheel and
                both front wheels are energized. Meanwhile the ABS inlet and outlet valves for the right rear wheel
                modulate the brake pressure to that wheel. In this condition pressurized brake fluid is blocked from the
                other wheel calipers by their energized (closed) inlet valves. The pressurized brake fluid is routed
                only to the right rear wheel caliper (because of its open inlet valve), where it applies braking force
                to the slipping wheel. Since the differential tends to drive the wheel that presents the least
                resistance, applying a braking force to the right rear wheel causes the differential to shift more of
                the driving force to the left rear wheel. When the ECU no longer senses any wheel slippage, the ATC and
                ABS valves are returned to their normal positions (see ATC Inactive).
            </para>
            <para>If both drive wheels were losing traction, the ECU would send a J1939 message to the Engine Control
                Module (ECM) reducing the torque of the engine until the ATC event had ended.
            </para>
            <para>If the ECU determines that the vehicle speed is
                <emph type="bold">above</emph>
                31 mph when an ATC event is sensed, it will not activate the ATC valves. Above 31 mph, reducing engine
                torque (via a J1939 message to the ECM) is the only form of traction control used. No active braking
                will be done above the 31 mph speed.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405024" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405024" filename="../figg04/g0405024a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Brake Fluid Routing - ATC Active Mode</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050400.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
