<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - Low pressure hose</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04050605" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Low pressure hose</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The design and composition of the low pressure hose is critical. The low pressure hose must be
                        replaced with the same design as installed by the manufacturer. The use of an incompatible hose
                        assembly may cause system damage and loss of braking. Failure to follow this warning could
                        result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses (A3 and A4) that provide
                    power to the brake system motors. The fuses are in the Power Distribution Center (PDC) located near
                    the master cylinder (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050601.xml" xrefid="f0405032">FIGURE 32</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the outside of the Hydraulic Compact Unit (HCU) and the Master Cylinder
                    (MC) reservoir assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area of the crossmember that the low pressure hose passes over, and the clamps
                    that secure the hose to the chassis. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405037">FIGURE 37</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405037" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G0405037" filename="../figG04/G0405004a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Low Pressure Hose from Master Cylinder to HCU</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT (HCU)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MASTER CYLINDER AND RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamp securing the low pressure hose to the MC bracket. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050601.xml" xrefid="f0405033">FIGURE 33</hotlnk>
                    . Retain the clamp, nut, and bolt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405038" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405038" filename="../figg04/g0405038.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Clamping the Low Pressure Hose</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LOCKING CLAMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose at the inlet to the HCU reservoir. Place the
                    clamp midway between the HCU reservoir inlet and the crossmember, being careful not to damage the
                    reservoir inlet. In some vehicle applications the rubber section of the low pressure hose is too
                    short to provide a leakproof clamp at this location. If necessary, clamp the low pressure hose 4 or
                    5 inches below the master cylinder outlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405038">FIGURE 38</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamps (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405037">FIGURE 37</hotlnk>) securing the middle section of the low pressure hose
                    to the chassis. Note the clamp positions to assist installation of new hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before performing the following step, position a container to collect any drained or spilled
                        brake fluid to ensure that no fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint. In the next
                        4 steps up to 3.4 liters (1 gal) of brake fluid will be drained.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the low pressure hose from the HCU reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the low pressure hose and the reservoir inlet to prevent system contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the container is positioned to catch fluid rapidly draining from the hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cap on the MC reservoir and the pinch clamp from the top of the low pressure
                    hose. Remove the plug from the low pressure hose, and carefully open the clamp on the bottom of the
                    hose. The fluid remaining in the MC reservoir and the low pressure hose will drain into the
                    container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the hose from the MC reservoir. Plug the reservoir port. Plug the hose to
                    prevent leakage during removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hose from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent contamination of the system, keep the ends of the replacement hose sealed until you
                        are ready to connect them.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>In the following step, position the hose clamps at the MC reservoir outlet and the HCU
                        reservoir inlet so that the pinch tabs are easily accessible.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the new hose. Make sure hose does not contact sharp edges, moving components or
                    hot components.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the hose to the HCU reservoir and install clamp.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the hose to the MC reservoir and install clamp.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the center clamps at the positions noted during removal.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Secure the low pressure hose to the MC bracket using the clamp, nut, and bolt
                        removed earlier.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container, fill the MC reservoir to
                    the MAX mark. About 3.2 liters (0.9 gallons) are needed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. The HCU pump motors will start and run for approximately 45
                    seconds. This will fill the accumulators and pressurize the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Decrease pressure in the system by applying the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times. This
                    will force fluid from the accumulators back into the HCU reservoir to purge trapped air from the
                    reservoir, through the low pressure hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. The pump motors will start and run for approximately 45 seconds.
                    This will fill the accumulators, pressurizing the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pump the brakes rapidly 4 times to activate both HCU pump motors. After motors stop,
                    fill the MC reservoir up to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed
                    container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of the LOW PRESSURE HOSE REMOVAL procedures to verify that the
                        system is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage,
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check system for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system before making
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050500.xml" xrefid="hl04050500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Further bleeding of the system is not necessary.</emph>
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050604.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050606.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
