<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3000 - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION - M - 21 MODULATOR VALVE (WITH 4
        - CHANNEL SYSTEM 04AZA)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="8">
        <title>M - 21 MODULATOR VALVE (WITH 4 - CHANNEL SYSTEM 04AZA)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The M - 21 antilock system modulator (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402408">Figure 8</hotlnk>
                ) is essentially a high capacity, ON/OFF air valve that incorporates a pair of electrical solenoids for
                control. The solenoids provide the electro-pneumatic link between the antilock controller electronics
                and the air brake system. The M - 21 can be used to control the braking function (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402409">Figure 9</hotlnk>
                ) on an individual wheel or two service actuators (as with 6x4). The M - 21 is the last control valve
                that air passes through on its way to the service brake actuator(s).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402408" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402408" filename="../figg04/G0402408.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. M - 1 Modulator Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402409" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402409" filename="../figg04/G0402409.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. M - 21 Air Flow Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. M - 21 MODULATORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL CONNECTION TO EC - 15 CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. QRV</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CR - 15 RELAY VALVE/ECU</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The M - 21 modulator consists of a die cast aluminum body and a solenoid assembly, which contains one
                normally open (NO) solenoid, one normally closed (NC) solenoid, and two inlet and exhaust diaphragm
                valves. A Packard, three pin, 280 series weather resistant electrical connector is part of the M - 21
                solenoid assembly and carries control commands from the ECU to the M - 21 modulator. The Supply,
                Delivery and Exhaust ports on the M - 21 are identified with raised numerals for positive
                identification. They are:
            </para>
            <table id="t0402403" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>M-21 Valve Port Identification</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" char="." colwidth="3.00in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="1" nameend="2" spanname="s1t2" align="center"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="s1t2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">M - 21 MODULATOR VALVE</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>IDENTIFICATION</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>VALVE PORTING</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">1</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Supply - Incoming air from brake valve through QRV (frt axle) or
                                        relay valve (rear axle).
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">2</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Delivery - Air delivery to service actuators.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">3</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Exhaust - Air exhausted during antilock control.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Non-Antilock Application</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402410">Figure 10.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402410" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402410" filename="../figg04/G0402410.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. M - 21 Application Of Service Brakes</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>During normal non-antilock braking, both solenoids are de-energized (no electrical power). Brake
                application air enters the Supply port of the M - 21 and flows to, and through, the open exhaust
                solenoid then to the exhaust diaphragm. Air pressure, along with spring force, seats the exhaust
                diaphragm on the exhaust passage, thus preventing the escape of service air. Simultaneously, application
                air flows to the supply diaphragm and forces it away from its seat. Air flows past the open supply and
                out the M - 21 delivery port to the service brake chambers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Non - Antilock Hold</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402411">Figure 11.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>When the desired air pressure is attained in the service brake chambers, the brake system is in the
                Holding position. In the Holding position, both solenoids in the M - 21 remain de - energized and the
                balance of the internal components remain in the same position as they assumed during application.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402411" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402411" filename="../figg04/G0402411.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Non - Antilock Holding Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Non-Antilock Exhaust</title>
            <para>The manner in which air exhausts through the M - 21 differs, depending upon how rapidly the brake
                application is released by the driver.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Normal Exhaust</emph>
                - Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402412">Figure 12</hotlnk>
                . During a normal, relatively "slow" brake release, air moves back through the M - 21 in the reverse
                direction as it flowed during application. The internal components of the M - 21 will remain in the same
                position as they assumed during application until air pressure decreases to approximately one half psi,
                at which time the supply diaphragm will seat on the supply passage. Air will generally not be expelled
                from the M - 21 exhaust port during normal brake release.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402412" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402412" filename="../figg04/G0402412.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. M - 21 Non Antilock Exhaust (Normal)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Rapid Exhaust -</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402413">Figure 13</hotlnk>
                . The Rapid Exhaust operation described in the following text
                <emph type="bold">only occurs when the M - 21 is controlling two, type 30 (or larger) service
                    chambers</emph>. During a very rapid brake release, the M - 21 will exhaust air in a different
                manner. An example of this would be if the driver made a severe brake application, then lifted his foot
                from the brake pedal (released foot valve). During a rapid brake release, air from the exhaust diaphragm
                flows back through the open exhaust solenoid and to the application device's exhaust. With pressure
                removed from the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, air, returning to the M - 21 from the service
                chambers, opens the exhaust diaphragm. Returning air flows past the open exhaust and out the the M - 21
                exhaust port. Air will also flow past the open supply diaphragm and back to the application device's
                exhaust.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402413" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402413" filename="../figg04/G0402413.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. M - 21 Non-Antilock Exhaust (Rapid)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Operation - General</title>
            <para>If a service brake application is made and the antilock system finds a beginning wheel lock-up, the
                antilock controller will immediately begin modification of the brake application using the M - 21
                modulator.
            </para>
            <para>In order to modify the brake application, the coils of the two solenoid valves contained in the M - 21
                are energized or de-energized in a pre - programmed sequence by the ECU. When a solenoid coil is
                energized, a shuttle within the solenoid moves, and depending upon the function of the specific
                solenoid, it either opens or closes, thereby causing the exhaust or re-application of air pressure to
                the brake actuator. The solenoids in the M - 21 are controlled independently by the antilock controller.
                By opening and closing the solenoid valves in the M - 21 modulators, the antilock controller is able to
                simulate what the driver does when he "pumps the brakes." The antilock controller is able to "pump" each
                modulator, along with the brakes connected to it, independently and with far greater speed and accuracy.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Exhaust</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402414">Figure 14.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>When wheel lock - up is found, or about to happen, the antilock controller simultaneously energizes
                both the supply and exhaust solenoids in the M - 21. Energizing the supply solenoid causes its exhaust
                to close and inlet to open. With the inlet of the supply solenoid open, application air is permitted to
                flow to the control side of the supply diaphragm. Air pressure acting on the supply diaphragm causes it
                to close the supply and prevent further delivery of air to the brake chamber.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402414" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402414" filename="../figg04/G0402414.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. M - 21 Antilock Exhaust</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Energizing the exhaust solenoid closes its inlet and opens its exhaust. By closing the exhaust
                solenoid inlet, application air is prevented from flowing to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm.
                Air pressure which was present on the control side of the exhaust diaphragm flows out the exhaust port
                of the M - 21. With control air pressure removed from the exhaust diaphragm, brake application air
                forces the exhaust diaphragm to unseat, which allows it to flow out the M - 21 exhaust port. The M - 21
                will remain in the Antilock Exhaust mode until the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has
                increased. The M - 21 can enter the Antilock Hold or Re - apply mode from the Antilock Exhaust mode.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Hold</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402415">Figure 15.</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <para>The antilock controller will place the M - 21 in the Hold position when it senses that the correct
                wheel speed (braking force) has been reached. The antilock controller will also place the M-21 in the
                Hold position, prior to entering the Re - Apply, when it finds recovery from a locked wheel condition.
                In this mode of operation, the M - 21 supply solenoid remains energized, while the exhaust solenoid is
                de-energized.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402415" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402415" filename="../figg04/G0402415.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. M - 21 Antilock Holding Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>De - energizing the exhaust solenoid opens its inlet and closes its exhaust. Opening the exhaust
                solenoid inlet allows application air to flow to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, which then
                seals the exhaust passage. With the exhaust diaphragm seated, further exhaust of brake chamber air
                pressure is prevented. Because the supply solenoid remains energized, the supply diaphragm remains
                seated, thus preventing application air from flowing to the delivery port and out to the brake chamber.
                The M - 21 can enter the Antilock Exhaust or Re - apply mode from the Antilock Hold mode.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Re - Apply</title>
            <para>If the antilock controller senses that wheel speed has increased sufficiently to allow re-application
                of braking pressure, it de - energizes the supply and exhaust solenoids. With both solenoids
                de-energized, the M - 21 re - applies air to the brakes in the same manner it did during a Non -
                Antilock Application.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
