<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - DISASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl0400503">
        <title>DISASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Variations in disassembly procedures may be required as different types of brakes are used on
                International vehicles. Some typical brakes used are single and double anchor pin cam actuated types as
                well as wedge type actuated brakes. For particular service, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS- 5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="2">
            <title>WHEEL, HUB AND DRUM</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position vehicle on floor stands.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used to support vehicle while under chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If servicing a brake assembly with a spring (PARKING) brake, the spring brake must be
                    CAGED. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">It may be necessary to back off the brake adjustment to obtain enough clearance for drum
                    removal. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for procedures.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove brake drum assembly as determined by the type of drum mounting.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inboard mounted drums will be secured to the hub assembly on the brake group side of
                        hub. With this type drum mounting, the wheel, hub and drum are removed as one assembly (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400502">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0400502" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400502" filename="../figg04/G0400502.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Using Wheel Dolly to Remove Wheel, Hub and Drum Assembly</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Outboard mounted drums will be secured between the wheel and hub. When outboard
                        mounted drum brake groups are serviced, the wheels are removed, then the drum can be removed
                        without disturbing the hub assembly. This will eliminate servicing the wheel bearings (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400503">Figure 3</hotlnk>). For more detailed information, refer to GROUP 17 -
                        WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0400503" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400503" filename="../figg04/G0400503.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. Removing Outboard Mounted Drum</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
