<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSTIC LEDS and RESET</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC LEDS and RESET</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The condition of specific components is provided by a series of labeled, light emitting diodes (LEDs)
                on the DCI. No special tools or equipment are needed to read or interpret the diagnostic display. It
                should be noted that the DCI diagnostics display is separate from the antilock and traction condition
                lamps on the dash. With this separation, the driver is aware of any issues that occur but is not
                confused by diagnostic information. The LEDs are software driven and are either ON or OFF depending upon
                their monitor function.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Right and left, front and rear are determined from the driver's seat.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>FRT Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>MID Red LED (See Note below)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>RER Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>RHT Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>LFT Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>TRC Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>MOD Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>SEN Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ECU Red LED</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>VLT Green LED</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The MID LED is used with some but not all vehicles. When six speed sensors are not installed,
                        this LED is not used in the diagnostic process. However, it will light when the RESET switch in
                        the DCI diagnostic display is activated.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>"FRT" (Front) LED</title>
            <para>This Red LED illuminates in order to indicate the location of a faulted component or its wiring. It
                will light in conjunction with either the RIGHT or LEFT LED and the MOD or SENS LED.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_45.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_47.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
