<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048608" graphiccount="3">
        <title>HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact, nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>The HCU contains brake fluid and must be handled with appropriate care when removed from the
                        vehicle. It should not be exposed to impact loads, excessive vibrations or compressed air blown
                        into the hydraulic ports.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>This component has a limited shelf life. When replacing this component, note the expiration
                        date.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECU has programmable parameters that vary by vehicle wheelbase and configuration. The
                        replacement ECU is programmed with the default settings for these parameters. After replacing an
                        ECU, refer to ISIS to modify the programmable parameters to match those assigned to the
                        vehicle's VIN number. This modification requires the use of the EZ-Tech
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        service tool and the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic software.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404843">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404844">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>
                    . Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the area around the HCU, including the outside of the HCU itself.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unlatch and disconnect both electrical connectors from the ECU module. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048606.xml" xrefid="f0404851">FIGURE 56</hotlnk>
                    . Disconnect the electrical connector from the Pressure Supply Valve on the HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404856">FIGURE 61</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404856" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404856" filename="../figg04/G0404807.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 61. Locations of HCU Components and Connectors</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ACCUMULATORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PUMP MOTORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. RELAY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. 2-PIN CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 31-PIN CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT (ECU)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. PRESSURE SUPPLY VALVE WITH CONNECTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose at the inlet to the HCU reservoir. Place the
                    clamp midway between the HCU reservoir inlet and the crossmember, being careful not to damage the
                    reservoir inlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048605.xml" xrefid="f0404850">FIGURE 55</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To provide better access to other components and reduce the weight of the HCU, remove
                    both accumulators from the HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048607.xml" xrefid="hl04048607">ACCUMULATOR</hotlnk>
                    Removal procedures . Retain these accumulators for reinstallation unless they are to be replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, loosen the 2 clamps (see
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048605.xml" xrefid="f0404849">FIGURE 54</hotlnk>) securing the middle
                    section of the low pressure hose to the chassis . Clamps must be loose enough to allow the hose to
                    slide forward in the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before performing the following 3 steps, position a container to collect any drained or
                        spilled brake fluid to ensure that no fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the low pressure hose from the HCU reservoir.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the low pressure hose and the reservoir inlet to prevent system contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing brake lines from the HCU, use a backup wrench to prevent loosening of the
                        adapter fittings from the HCU body.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the 7 brake line fittings from HCU, and protect the tubes and the ports on
                    the HCU from contamination by installing matching plugs. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404857">FIGURE 62</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To allow easy removal of the HCU, LOOSEN the two bolts securing either HCU mounting
                    bracket to the frame rail. The bolts should be left in place, but must be loose enough to allow
                    slight movement of the mounting bracket. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404858">FIGURE 63</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404857" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404857" filename="../figg04/G0404857.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 62. HCU Brake Line Ports</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PORT 1 - SECONDARY MASTER CYLINDER (REAR BRAKE CIRCUIT)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PORT 2 - PRIMARY MASTER CYLINDER (FRONT BRAKE CIRCUIT)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PORT 3 - LEFT REAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PORT 4 - RIGHT REAR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PORT 5 - LEFT FRONT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PORT 6 - RIGHT FRONT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PORT 7 - SAHR PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404858" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404858" filename="../figg04/G0404858b.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 63. Location of HCU Mounting Hardware</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRACKET-TO-FRAME MOUNTING HARDWARE (4)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HCU-TO-BRACKET BOLTS (4) - (REAR BRACKET BOLTS HIDDEN)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Detach the HCU from the HCU mounting brackets by removing the 2 bolts securing the HCU
                    to each bracket. Remove the HCU by sliding it downwards. Retain the mounting hardware (4 bolts and 4
                    bushings) for use with the replacement HCU.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Empty the HCU reservoir (still attached to the HCU) by pouring the brake fluid into a
                    suitable container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove parking brake Pressure Supply Valve and coil for transfer to replacement HCU.
                    Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048610.xml" xrefid="hl04048610">PRESSURE SUPPLY VALVE</hotlnk>
                    procedures . Also, remove brake line fitting from SAHR port (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404857">FIGURE 62</hotlnk>) for transfer to replacement HCU. Other brake line
                    fittings are supplied with the replacement HCU.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Refer to the figures to verify that disconnected brake lines are reconnected to the correct
                        ports. Incorrect installation may result in brake, ABS or ATC malfunction. Inadvertent braking
                        of the front wheels could result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <important>
                    <para>Adjacent brake lines are fitted with difference size fittings so that they cannot be connected
                        incorrectly. However, to prevent thread damage it is advisable to review the figures if there is
                        any question about how the lines are to be connected.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Verify that the HCU being installed contains the same components as the HCU being replaced.
                    </para>
                </important>
                <important>
                    <para>Replacement HCU's are supplied as an assembly containing the following parts: both pump
                        motors, ECU, relay valve assembly, all internal valves, reservoir, both accumulators, and brake
                        line fitting inserts for the master cylinder and wheel end brake lines. The reservoir is shipped
                        unmounted.
                    </para>
                </important>
                <important>
                    <para>The replacement HCU is precharged with brake fluid to ensure successful bleeding and to
                        protect the pumps against dry operation. To prevent fluid loss, do not remove protection caps
                        from HCU until you are ready to connect the brake lines.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, transfer parking brake Pressure Supply Valve and coil to the replacement
                    HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048610.xml" xrefid="hl04048610">PRESSURE SUPPLY VALVE</hotlnk>
                    procedures . Also, transfer the brake line fitting from the SAHR port to the replacement HCU. (Other
                    brake line fittings are supplied with the replacement HCU.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from the HCU reservoir seals. Install the new reservoir onto
                    the new HCU by pressing it carefully and fully into the seals.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the four new mounting screws and a Phillips-head screwdriver, attach the reservoir
                    to the HCU. Tighten the screws to 5 to 6.7 Nm (44 to 60 Lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After verifying that all HCU ports are plugged, fill the HCU reservoir with
                    approximately 2 quarts of new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place 4 bushings into the HCU mounting holes in both HCU brackets (2 bushings per
                    bracket). The stepped bushings are pushed into the holes from the inside surfaces of the brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the HCU between the mounting brackets and secure it using 2 bolts per bracket.
                    Verify that the mounting bushings remained in place. Torque HCU mounting bolts to 43-46 Nm (32-34
                    Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the two bolts (securing the HCU mounting bracket to the frame rail) that were
                    loosened previously. Torque these bolts to 108-135 Nm (79.7-99.6 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the brake lines to the HCU as indicated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404857">FIGURE 62</hotlnk>
                    . Torque these fittings to 12.2 to 19 Nm (9 to 14 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>In the following step, position the hose clamp at the HCU reservoir so that the pinch tabs are
                        easily accessible.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the low pressure hose to the HCU reservoir and secure with hose clamp. Position
                    the hose clamp so that the pinch tabs are easily accessible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the HCU being installed is missing accumulators, install both accumulators at this
                    time. Refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048607.xml" xrefid="hl04048607">ACCUMULATOR</hotlnk>
                    Installation procedures .
                </para>
                <para>If the accumulators are already on the HCU, proceed to the next step.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamp used to pinch the low pressure hose during removal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the center clamps on the low pressure hose were loosened previously, tighten them to
                    secure the low pressure hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>In the following step, insure that the ECU connectors are properly installed and latched to
                        prevent them from becoming disconnected. Failure to securely connect AND LATCH the ECU
                        connectors could result in loss of braking functions during vehicle operation. Failure to follow
                        this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the 2 electrical connectors to the HCU ECU. Secure the electrical connectors by
                    engaging the latches. Connect the 1 electrical connector to the parking brake Pressure Supply Valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the MC circuit. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048401.xml" xrefid="hl04048401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the brake caliper circuits. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048401.xml" xrefid="hl04048401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the SAHR circuit. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048401.xml" xrefid="hl04048401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404843">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system by depressing the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This will force fluid from the accumulators back into the HCU reservoir to purge trapped air
                        from the reservoir, through the low pressure hose.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pump the brakes rapidly 4 times to activate both HCU pump motors. After pumps stop, fill
                    the MC reservoir up to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the MC reservoir cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 2 thru 5 of the HYDRAULIC COMPACT UNIT REMOVAL procedures to verify that
                        the system is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage,
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check system for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system before making
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-Tech
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    service tool and the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic software, refer to ISIS to program the replacement
                    ECU to match the vehicle's VIN number.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048607.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048609.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
