<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - MAINTENANCE - BP-R1
        INSPECTION TEST
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401206" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BP-R1 INSPECTION TEST</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Charge the air brake system to a minimum of 100 psi air pressure.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release the tractor park brake by pushing in the yellow, diamond shaped park brake knob.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Deactivate the trailer brake control system by pulling out the red (octagonal-shaped)
                trailer air supply knob.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply the brakes by partially depressing the brake pedal (treadle) and hold the pedal in
                this partially-depressed position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The observer should note the movement (stroke) of the rear slack adjusters and the position
                of the yoke-pin in the slack adjuster.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the brake pedal in the partially-depressed position, push the red (octagonal-shaped)
                trailer brake control knob in to activate the trailer brake control system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The observer should observe a further movement (increased stroke) of the rear slack
                adjusters and yoke-pin.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>The rear slack adjusters and yoke pins should move away from the chamber as a result of the partial brake
            application in step 4 and then move further away from the chamber (longer stroke) after the trailer brake
            control is applied in step 6. These two reactions confirm that the rear brakes operate at reduced pressure
            when the tractor is operating without a trailer (bobtail mode) and operate at full pressure when the tractor
            is coupled to a trailer.
        </para>
        <para>If the performance of the BP-R1 is not as described, perform the
            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401207.xml" xrefid="hl0401207">OPERATION</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401201.xml" xrefid="hl0401201">LEAKAGE TESTS</hotlnk>
            described in SERVICE CHECKS.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL0401204.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_HL04012LQ.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
