<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DOUBLE DIAPHRAGM ANCHORLOK SPRING BRAKE - ORANGE ALERT STROKE INDICATOR - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>A stroke indicator is not intended to be used as the only indicator of when to adjust the brakes
                    on a vehicle. The stroke indicator may not be accurate on new lining on unburnished brakes. Flex in
                    the system will allow the stroke indicator to show as the brake shoe distorts to fit the drum. The
                    tendency goes away after burnish (wear-in). Refer to GROUP 04 - AIR BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master
                    Service Manual.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>At the point the leading edge of the stroke indicator is level with the mounting face of the service
            housing (
            <hotlnk document="s04019_12.xml" xrefid="f0401917">Figure 17</hotlnk>), the service chamber has only 1/2
            inch of available stroke remaining or 1/2 inch from bottoming out (3/4 inch of stroke remaining for 36 type
            spring brake).
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The diamond knurl can also be used as a reference point to measure actual stroke on a spring
                brake or service chamber. To measure actual stroke, proceed as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With the spring brake or service chamber fully retracted (released), measure from a flat
                    surface on the service housing to the leading edge of the diamond knurl.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply the spring brake or service brake and perform the same measurement. The difference
                    in the length of the two measurements is the actual stroke.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To check if the spring brake or service chamber is fully retracting, the diamond knurl can
                be used as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">With the spring brake fully retracted (released) by air pressure, the trailing edge of
                    the diamond knurl (the edge closest to the service housing) should come to rest flush with, or
                    partially retract into, the service housing (non-pressure housing). Should the trailing edge of the
                    diamond knurl protrude above the mounting face of the service housing by more than .200 inch, check
                    for a malfunction in the braking system; i.e., low air pressure, broken parking spring (compression
                    spring), malfunctioning slack adjuster, worn or broken cam shafts, broken brake shoes, etc.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04019_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04019_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
