<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSING AND LOCATING A SYSTEM FAULT - DIAGNOSTICS USING THE DCI WITH
        ACOM SOFTWARE AND A PC
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTICS USING THE DCI WITH ACOM SOFTWARE AND A PC</title>
        <para>To use the DCI, vehicle must be equipped with a
            <hotlnk document="s04038_26.xml" xrefid="f0403808">J1587 diagnostic link connector</hotlnk>. This connector
            is generally located on the driver's side, in lower portion of the dash or under the dash panel.
        </para>
        <para>Using the DCI in conjunction with the ACom for Windows software requires that the software be installed on
            the computer. If this has not been done, refer to the documentation packaged with the ACom software and
            install ACom. After installing ACom, or verifying it is installed on the computer, use the following
            procedure to connect the DCI and begin troubleshooting.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brake and turn off the ignition.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the
                <hotlnk document="s04038_25.xml" xrefid="f0403807">vehicle diagnostic link connector and connect the DCI
                    cable assembly
                </hotlnk>
                to the vehicle's diagnostic connector.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the male end of a serial cable to the DCI. The serial cable should be long enough to
                accommodate a convenient location for the
                <hotlnk document="s04038_25.xml" xrefid="f0403807">DCI and computer</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the computer turned off, connect the other end of the serial cable to an unused serial
                port on the computer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the vehicle ignition on and note that the 10 diagnostic lamps flash on and off as the
                system goes through a self test.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the computer on then open the ACom for Windows software. Go to the pull down File menu
                and select "Setup." Using online help, fill in the necessary information. Pay particular attention to
                selecting the appropriate "Com Port." Once complete, troubleshooting can begin. Refer to ACom
                documentation packaged with the software.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
