<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 501 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The compressor is driven by the engine and runs continuously while the engine is operating, but the
                actual compression of air is controlled by the governor which, acting in conjunction with the unloading
                mechanism in the compressor, starts or stops the compression of air by loading or unloading the
                compressor when the pressure in the air brake system reaches the minimum or maximum air pressure levels.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
            <title>INTAKE AND COMPRESSION OF AIR (LOADED)</title>
            <para>During the downstroke of each piston, a slight vacuum is created between the top of the piston and the
                head, causing the flat circular inlet valve to move up and off its seat. The flat discharge valve will
                remain on its seat. Air drawn through the intake port on the down stroke enters the cylinder above the
                piston through the inlet valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401002">Figure 2</hotlnk>). As the piston starts the upward stroke, the air is being
                compressed. Air pressure on top of the inlet valve plus the force of its spring returns the inlet valve
                to its seat. The piston continues the upward stroke and compressed air then flows by the open discharge
                valve into the discharge line and on to the reservoirs (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401003">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401002" filename="../figg04/g0401002.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Intake and Compression of Air</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0401003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401003" filename="../figg04/g0401003.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Compressed Air Flows to Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
