<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - SERVICE PROCEDURES - REASSEMBLE CALIPER (ALL CODES EXCEPT CODE 04145)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401608" svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>REASSEMBLE CALIPER (ALL CODES EXCEPT CODE 04145)</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Take a new piston seal and dip the seal in clean brake fluid. Install seal into piston bore
                seal groove by holding seal in groove and gently working seal around into groove. Make sure that the
                seal is not twisted or rolled.
                <emph type="bold">Never use an old seal.</emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a thin film of silicone grease to the inside edge of the caliper bore and to the
                sealing lip edge of the dust boot.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install dust boot onto piston installer tool expanding boot lip only. Insert boot with tool
                into piston bore. Using suitable tool install boot into caliper housing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401630">Figure 30</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401631">Figure 31</hotlnk>). Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04016k_24.xml" xrefid="hl0401610">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401630" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401630" filename="../figg04/g0401630.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 30. Dual Piston Installer Tool</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PISTON INSTALLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DUST BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CALIPER HOUSING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0401631" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401631" filename="../figg04/g0401631.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Dust Boot and Heat Shield Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DUST BOOT LAND</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PISTON SEAL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DUST BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HEAT SHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CALIPER HOUSING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply brake fluid to the outside surface of the piston. Insert piston into piston installer
                tool and piston bore. Start piston past piston seal, then push piston down until bottomed, and remove
                tool.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no piston tool is available, apply clean brake fluid to outside surface of the caliper
                piston. Install piston dust boot over top of piston. Note position of the dust boot steel ring edge,
                facing into caliper bore (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401631">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install piston into caliper bore. Once piston is started past the seal, use your fingers to
                push piston down until bottomed. If piston is difficult to bottom using your fingers, you may use a
                suitable brass punch or piece of wood inserted into the piston opening (hole). Gently tap piston into
                caliper until the piston is bottomed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a suitable tool, install boot into caliper housing.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install piston heat shield over piston with the radius of the heat shield facing outward.
                Press heat shield down on piston against dust boot face using the piston installer tool (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401631">Figure 31</hotlnk>). If tool is not available, use suitable tool to tap heat
                shield onto piston.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Repeat all the above steps 1 through 8 for the remaining piston(s).</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install caliper and pads as outlined in
                <hotlnk document="s04016k_16.xml" xrefid="hl0401611">PADS AND CALIPER INSTALLATION</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
