<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - SERVICE PROCEDURES - CLEANING AND INSPECTION OF CALIPERS AND PADS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="4">
        <title>CLEANING AND INSPECTION OF CALIPERS AND PADS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Visually inspect the caliper housing for leakage. If leakage is evident, overhaul the
                caliper as described in ,
                <hotlnk document="s04016k_17.xml" xrefid="hl0401601">DISASSEMBLE
                    <xref refid="hl0401601"/>
                </hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk document="s04016k_19.xml" xrefid="hl0401608">REASSEMBLE CALIPER
                    <xref refid="hl0401608"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a wire brush to remove any rust or corrosion from machined surfaces of the caliper and
                anchor plate. It is important to clean those areas of the caliper and anchor plate that are in contact
                during the sliding action of the caliper.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the lining thickness. If the minimum thickness is less than 3/16 inch (4.76mm), new
                pad assemblies should be installed on both wheels/brakes of that axle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401617">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401617" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401617" filename="../figg04/g0401617.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Brake Pad Wear Limits</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401618">Figure 18</hotlnk>
                shows pads which require replacement if lining material shows excessive cracking at the edges and poor
                contact surface.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401618" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401618" filename="../figg04/g0401618.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Example Of An Unserviceable Brake Pad</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Brake pads are to be replaced by axle. Never replace brake pads at only one wheel/brake end.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Brake pads with excessive chipping or flaking must be replaced. If an examination of the pads reveals
                20% or more has no contact area with the rotor, the pads must be replaced.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401619">Figure 19</hotlnk>
                illustrates three progressive conditions of pad to rotor contact. The polished contact area is
                represented in the illustration by the white area on the pad surface.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401619" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401619" filename="../figg04/g0401619.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Example of Brake Pad Service Conditions</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The top view in (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401619">Figure 19</hotlnk>) illustrates a new or like new pad that has full contact
                with the rotor while the center view shows a pad that has 70% contact with the rotor. The center pad is
                still serviceable. The bottom pad shows 80% or more has no contact with the rotor and must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>Brake pads contaminated by grease, oil or other materials which cannot be easily cleaned by using
                denatured alcohol and dried by compressed air must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>Examine the pads for flatness of the contact surface. Any pad found with a concave or convex bend more
                than 1/64 inch (0.381mm) should be replaced (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401620">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401620" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401620" filename="../figg04/g0401620.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Acceptable Limits to Brake Pad Warping</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect rotors. Rotors with severe cracks or burn spots (Hot Spots) must be replaced.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>Complete details pertaining to reconditioning rotors can be found in GROUP 04 - BRAKES HYDRAULIC in the
            CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
