<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - PRESSURE PROTECTION VALVE - TEST REPAIRED VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TEST REPAIRED VALVE</title>
        <para>Prior to installing the repaired valve assembly in the vehicle, the valve should be tested for leakage and
            proper adjustment.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery pressures,
                    gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Assemble air gauge and shut-off valve at inlet and outlet of pressure protection valve, then connect to
            shop air source. Open shut-off valve at outlet of pressure protection valve and slowly open shut-off valve
            at air source until air pressure reaches 55 psi.
        </para>
        <para>Check for air leakage with soap solution at outlet. Leakage must not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter soap
            bubble in 5 seconds.
        </para>
        <para>Close the shut-off valve at outlet and increase air pressure at inlet side of pressure protection valve.
            Pressure at outlet air gauge should not be present until pressure at this inlet reaches 65 to 75 psi. Then
            both gauges should equalize.
        </para>
        <para>If pressure protection valve opens prior to 65 psi, add shim to valve and if valve remains closed after 75
            psi is obtained, remove shim.
        </para>
        <para>After valve has been tested and meets requirements, it is ready to be installed on vehicle.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
