<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - DRY ELEMENT - PLEATED PAPER AIR STRAINER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="2">
        <title>DRY ELEMENT - PLEATED PAPER AIR STRAINER</title>
        <para>Every two months, 800 operating hours or 20,000 miles which never occurs first, remove the spring clips
            from either side of mounting baffle and remove the cover (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400409">Figure 9</hotlnk>). Replace the pleated paper filter and remount the cleaned cover
            making sure the filter is in position. Make certain to replace the air strainer gasket if the entire air
            strainer is removed from the compressor intake.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400409" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400409" filename="../figg04/g0400409.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Dry Element - Pleated Paper Strainer</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1.MOUNTING BAFFLE</callout1>
                <callout1>2.FILTER ELEMENT</callout1>
                <callout1>3.COVER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Some compressors are fitted with intake adapters which allow the compressor intake to be connected to the
            engine air cleaner, turbo or supercharger (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400410">Figure 10</hotlnk>). In this case, the compressor receives a supply of clean air
            from the engine air cleaner. When the engine air filter is changed, the compressor intake adapter should be
            checked. lf it is loose, remove the intake adapter, clean the strainer plate, if applicable, and replace the
            intake adapter gasket, and reinstall the adapter securely. Check line connections both at the compressor
            intake adapter and at the engine or engine air cleaner. inspect the connecting line for kinks and ruptures
            and replace it if necessary.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400410" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400410" filename="../figg04/g0400410.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Compressor Intake Adapter</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
