<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - SAFE MAINTENANCE PRACTICES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SAFE MAINTENANCE PRACTICES</title>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT! PLEASE READ</emph>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>When working on or around a vehicle, the following general precautions should be observed:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brakes, and always block the
                            wheels.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with air brakes, make certain to drain the air pressure from
                            all reservoirs before beginning ANY work on the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Following the vehicle manufacturer's recommended procedures, deactivate the electrical
                            system in a manner that removes all electrical power from the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When working in the engine compartment the engine should be shut off. Where circumstances
                            require that the engine be in operation, EXTREME CAUTION should be used to prevent personal
                            injury resulting from contact with moving, rotating, leaking, heated, or electrically
                            charged components.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip. Never remove
                            a component or plug unless you are certain all system pressure has been depleted.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety glasses.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until you have read
                            and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper tools and observe
                            all precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use only genuine Bendix replacement parts, components, and kits. Replacement hardware,
                            tubing, hose, fittings, etc. should be of equivalent size, type, and strength as original
                            equipment and be designed specifically for such applications and systems.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Components with stripped threads or damaged parts should be replaced rather than repaired.
                            Repairs requiring machining or welding should not be attempted unless specifically approved
                            and stated by the vehicle or component manufacturer.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                            restored to their proper operating condition. When working on or around a vehicle, the
                            following general precautions should be observed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The ATC enable/disable switch must be in the disable position (ATC active/warning lamp
                            should be on) prior to performing any vehicle maintenance where the wheels are lifted off of
                            the ground and moving.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
