<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - POWERED Parking Brake</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>POWERED Parking Brake</title>
        <para>The powered parking brake system is a combination of mechanical, hydraulic, and electronic assemblies. The
            drum-style driveline parking brake is cable actuated. The cable tension is controlled by a Spring Applied
            Hydraulic Released (SAHR) canister, which is controlled by brake fluid routed to it by the Hydraulic Compact
            Unit (HCU). Normally the 'apply/release' input signal is provided to the HCU Electronic Control Unit (ECU)
            by the dash mounted park brake switch (similar to an air system park brake switch). However, because the
            hydraulic valves in the HCU are electronically controlled, the software in the ECU can be used to provide
            various parking brake features and interlocks. The following list briefly describes some of the features of
            the powered parking brake system.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Key switch interlock.</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>The parking brake applies automatically when the key is turned off and cannot be released
                            until the key is turned on.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the key is turned off while driving, the park brake is prevented from applying until
                            vehicle speed is less than 2 mph.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Dynamic park brake apply protection.</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>When the parking brake switch is pulled with the vehicle in motion, the HCU is used to
                            apply the rear service brakes. While the rear service brakes are being applied, the ECU
                            signals the ESC/BC to turn on the vehicle's brake lights. After the vehicle has come to a
                            safe stop (less than 2 mph), the driveline park brake is applied. (Since the service brakes
                            are applied initially in lieu of the driveline brake, the stop is under ABS control,
                            preventing rear wheel lock-up.)
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Reduces premature wear and damage to driveline brake caused by applying the parking brake
                            before the vehicle is completely stopped.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Parking brake release interlocks. The parking brake is released when the dash switch is pressed
                    and released, ONLY if the following conditions are met:
                </para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>The foot brake is applied.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The ignition key is in the ON position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The transmission is not in the Park (P or PB) position.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>No major brake system faults have been detected.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Engine control interlock. Engine intervention is used to prevent the operator from 'driving'
                    against the parking brake when it is applied. Engine torque is reduced when the parking brake is
                    applied.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The travel switch on the SAHR canister and circuitry in the ECU identify actuation of the parking
                    brake and malfunctions in the parking brake circuit.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Auto-Apply (AA) feature. This parking brake feature is provided on vehicles equipped with a
                    transmission shifter with a Park (P or PB) position.
                </para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>Automatically applies the driveline park brake when the shifter is placed in the Park
                            position.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Once applied, the parking brake can be released only if the shifter is moved out of the
                            Park position with the foot brake applied
                            <emph type="underscr">and</emph>
                            ignition key in the "On" position.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>In the event of a parking brake system malfunction, the SERVICE PARK BRAKE lamp will flash and an alarm
            will sound for approximately 20 seconds. After 20 seconds the alarm will stop and the lamp will remain
            illuminated (continuous). In addition, diagnostic codes identifying the source of the malfunction will be
            stored in the ECU memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section 5,
            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048207.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
