<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - BRAKE ADJUSTMENT - ADJUSTING MANUAL SLACK ADJUSTERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>ADJUSTING MANUAL SLACK ADJUSTERS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block wheels not being adjusted.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With wheel raised and parking brake released so that the wheel will rotate freely, check
                brake chamber push rod to make certain that it is in a fully released position. To do this, disconnect
                push rod at slack adjuster. If push rod moves toward "released" brake chamber, depress lock sleeve on
                slack adjuster and turn adjusting nut to rotate slack adjuster toward push rod until clevis pin can be
                reinstalled. Install clevis pin and cotter pin (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400531">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400531" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400531" filename="../figg04/g0400531.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Manual Slack Adjuster Locking Sleeve on Adjusting Nut</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOCKING SLEEVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disengage locking sleeve on slack adjuster worm shaft or adjusting screw by depressing
                spring loaded sleeve with a wrench (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400531">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400531">Figure 31</hotlnk>illustrates the locking sleeve in its disengaged
                        position. Be sure sleeve is held in, disengaging the adjust- ing screw when making adjustments.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn vehicle wheel and at the same time rotate adjusting screw until brake shoes are tight
                against drum. Then turn adjusting screw 1/4 turn in opposite direction. Wheel should rotate freely with
                no drag on brake lining.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply brakes and hold full brake application to fully seat brake shoes against drum and note
                the angle between slack adjuster and push rod. This angle should be close to 90 degrees as possible (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400532">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400532" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400532" filename="../figg04/g0400532.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Brake Chamber and Slack Adjuster Adjustment Angles</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_21.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_23.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
