<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR COMPRESSOR GOVERNOR (TYPE D-2) - REASSEMBLE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <para>Prior to assembly, lubricate the lower body bore, the top of the piston, the piston grooves, piston
            grommets, and piston setting spring guide with Fleetrite EP2 Moly grease or equivalent to NLGI #2
            multi-purpose lithium grease. Adjust screw.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the exhaust stem grommet in its groove in the stem bore of the piston.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drop the inlet and exhaust valve into place at the bottom of the piston.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the inlet valve spring with its narrow end against the valve. Press the spring down
                until the large coiled end snaps into the groove inside the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the exhaust stem spring over the exhaust stem. Then carefully press the stem into
                the stem bore of the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the piston in the body.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install in the following order: one lower spring seat, spring guide, the other lower spring
                seat, pressure setting spring and the hex-shaped upper spring seat on the adjusting screw. Screw the
                upper spring seat down until the dimension from the top of the seat to the bottom of the stem head is
                approximately 1-7/8 inches (47.6 mm).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the lock nut.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before placing the adjusting screw and stem assembly in the governor body, check to be sure
                the exhaust stem and its spring are in place in the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the adjusting screw and spring assembly retaining ring. Adjust adjusting screw to
                the measurement that was taken in step 2 in page.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If necessary, install new filters in the reservoir and unloader ports.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_126.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_128.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
