<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - RELAY VALVE (BENDIX R-12 AND R-14) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="2">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400201">
            <title>Application</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400254">Figure 54</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400254" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400254" filename="../figg04/G0400254.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 54. Bendix R-12 and R-14 Operation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SERVICE PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COVER CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. COVER SEALING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PISTON O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. EXHAUST SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. OUTER EXHAUST VALVE O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. INNER EXHAUST VALVE O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. EXHAUST RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Air pressure delivered to the service port (Item 1) enters the small cavity above the piston and moves
                the piston (Item 6) down. The exhaust seat (Item 9) moves down with the piston and seats on the inner or
                exhaust portion of the inlet/exhaust valve (Item 10) sealing off the exhaust passage. At the same time,
                the outer or inlet portion of the inlet/exhaust valve (Item 10) moves off its seat, permitting supply
                air to flow from the reservoir, past the open inlet valve and into the brake chambers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Balance</title>
            <para>The air pressure being delivered by the open inlet valve also is effective on the bottom area of the
                relay piston (Item 6). When air pressure beneath the piston equals the service air pressure above, the
                piston lifts slightly and the inlet spring (Item 8) returns the inlet valve to its seat. The exhaust
                remains closed as the service line pressure balances the delivery pressure. As delivered air pressure is
                changed, the valve reacts instantly to the change, holding the brake application at that level.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust or Release</title>
            <para>When air pressure is released from the service port and air pressure in the cavity above the relay
                piston (Item 6) is exhausted, air pressure beneath the piston lifts the relay piston and the exhaust
                seat (Item 9) moves away from the exhaust valve (Item 10), opening the exhaust passage. With the exhaust
                passage open, the air pressure in the brake chambers is then permitted to exhaust through the exhaust
                port, releasing the brakes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Anti-Compounding (Simultaneous Service and Park Application)</title>
            <para>Where the R-14 relay valve is used to control spring brake chambers, a line is connected from the
                balance/quick exhaust (anti-compound) port in the cover of the valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400255">Figure 55</hotlnk>) to the delivery of the service brake valve or relay valve.
                With no air at the balance/quick exhaust port of the R-14, the parking brakes are applied. If a service
                brake application is made, air from the service brake valve enters the balance/quick exhaust port of the
                R-14 and moves the diaphragm, blocking the service port. Air then enters the cavity above the relay
                piston, forces the piston down, closing the exhaust and opening the inlet to deliver air to the spring
                brake cavity as described under
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400201">
                    <xref refid="hl0400201"/>APPLICATION.
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400255" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400255" filename="../figg04/G0400255.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 55. Simultaneous Service and Park Application</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXHAUST COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BALANCE/QUICK EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. EXHAUST SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_102.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_104.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
