<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - GENERAL INFORMATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>GENERAL INFORMATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Air brake equipment on trucks and truck-tractors provides a means of controlling brakes through the
                medium of compressed air. Air brakes consist of a group of devices: some maintain a supply of compressed
                air, some direct and control the flow of compressed air, and others transfer the energy of compressed
                air into the mechanical force and motion necessary to apply the brakes. Different types and sizes of
                devices are in use on different types of vehicles to meet operating requirements.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 04 - AIR BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for description of the split air
                system used on the particular vehicles covered by Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standard 121 (FMVSS 121).
            </para>
            <para>The components used to make up a typical dual air system on a chassis are listed in this section with
                a brief description, operation, service checks and maintenance procedures. Disassembly and reassembly
                instructions are provided for some components.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Whenever any component is serviced or removed from the air system, be sure to set the parking
                        brake and/or block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving while the service is being
                        performed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
