<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - SYSTEM AND COMPONENT OPERATION - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Axle Brake Operation With 4x2 Chassis</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402201">Figure 1
                    <xref refid="f0402201"/>
                </hotlnk>
                for the following discussion. Also refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04022_14.xml" xrefid="x0402202">COMPONENT LOCATIONS
                    <xref refid="x0402202"/>
                </hotlnk>
                for additional illustrations on system installations.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0402201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Typical Antilock Brake System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXCITER RING (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WARNING LIGHT RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WHEEL SPEED SENSOR (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. C350 CONNECTS REAR HARNESS TO CR-15</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. M-21 MODULATOR VALVE (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CR-15 RELAY VALVE/EC-15 CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. C355 (C288 W/9300) CONNECTS FRONT HARNESS TO CR-15</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. ENGINE BRAKE RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CRANK RELAY (POWER SUPPLY TO CR-15)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. QUICK RELEASE VALVE (QRV) VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The antilock system provides individual wheel control by using a wheel speed sensor and modulator at
                each wheel to measure rotational speed. By monitoring the rate of deceleration during braking, and then
                modifying the service brake application pressure at each wheel, the EC-15 is able to provide improved
                vehicle braking, while maintaining vehicle stability.
            </para>
            <para>The rear axle brakes are controlled completely independent of each other and brake application
                pressure at an individual wheel is adjusted solely on the basis of its behavior on the road surface on
                which it is traveling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Axle Brake Operation With 6x4 Chassis</title>
            <para>With vehicles equipped with tandem rear axles (6x2 or 6x4), the wheel speed sensors are installed at
                the wheels, located on the axle that is most likely to lose traction first. With a 4-spring suspension,
                the rear axle sensors are located on the Forward Rear axle. On an air suspension, sensors are located on
                the Rear Rear axle. A single modulator controls both left side rear axle brakes and another modulator
                controls both right side rear axle brakes. With this arrangement of wheel speed sensors and modulators,
                both brakes on one side of a tandem rear axle will be modulated as one, since they will most likely be
                on the same type of road surface.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front (Steering) Axle Brake Operation</title>
            <para>While each steering axle brake is under the control of an individual modulator valve, the EC-15 does
                not treat these brakes totally independent of each other. The EC-15 utilizes a modified individual
                control method for steering axle brakes. This is done to minimize "steering wheel pull" in the event
                that one front wheel is on dry pavement and the other is on a slippery surface, such as ice or snow. The
                EC-15 controls the braking force differences between the two brakes. The wheel on dry pavement is
                initially given less braking force and is brought up to optimum during the stop, while the wheel on ice
                attempts to maintain optimum braking during the entire stop.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Non-Antilock Brake Application: Rear Axle(s)</title>
            <para>During normal braking, control air pressure from the brake valve (foot valve) enters the service port
                of the service relay valve (part of the CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 assembly). The relay valve also receives
                air from the vehicle's primary air reservoir. The service relay delivers air to, and through, the
                antilock modulators located near the braked wheel(s), and into the brake actuator. The service brakes
                are thus applied. If the wheel sensors do not detect an impending wheel lockup, the EC-15 does not
                initiate any corrective action and the vehicle comes to a stop in a normal fashion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Non-Antilock Brake Application: Front Axle (Steering Axle)</title>
            <para>During normal braking, air pressure from the brake valve (foot valve) is applied to the quick release
                valve (QRV). Air from the QRV is then sent to the right and left front M-21 wheel modulator valves. The
                M-21 antilock modulators then deliver the brake air pressure to the brake actuators. The service brakes
                are thus applied. If the wheel sensors do not detect an impending wheel lockup, the EC-15 does not
                initiate any corrective action and the vehicle comes to a stop in a normal fashion.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Controlled Brake Application - System Fully Operational</title>
            <para>If a service brake application is made and the wheel speed sensors detect an impending wheel lockup,
                the EC-15 will immediately begin modification of brake application using the M-21 antilock modulator(s)
                at the wheel(s) sensing an impending lockup condition.
            </para>
            <para>Solenoid valves contained in the modulator are rapidly energized and de-energized by the EC-15 in
                order to modify the brake application. When a solenoid coil is energized, its shuttle moves, and
                depending upon the function of the specific solenoid, it either opens or closes, thereby causing the
                exhaust or re-application of air pressure to the brake actuator. By opening and closing the solenoid
                valves in the appropriate modulator, the EC-15 is actually simulating what the driver does when he
                "pumps the brakes." Unlike the driver, the EC-15 receives input on which wheel is approaching lockup,
                and is able to pump each brake group on the vehicle independently and with far greater speed and
                accuracy.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock System Operation - Component Failure</title>
            <para>The EC-15 handles equipment failure using a conservative fail-safe philosophy. Any single electrical
                failure of an antilock system component results in three events happening at the same time. The three
                events are:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The yellow antilock warning light on the instrument panel will illuminate to alert the
                    driver that the system has detected a malfunction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The EC-15 will disable all or part of the antilock system.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>When coping with wheel equipment (modulator, wheel sensor/exciter ring or associated wire harness)
                failure, the EC-15 divides and separates the brakes diagonally. For example, if the modulator at the
                right front wheel has a broken wire lead, the EC-15 disables the antilock function for BOTH the right
                front and left rear wheels. The antilock will continue to function on the left front and right wheels
                and will continue to be controlled by the EC-15.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Right and left, and front and rear are determined from the driver's seat position. Left front
                        would be the front corner closest to the driver.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Depending on the type of failure, and location of the failed component, the EC-15 will disable either
                the entire antilock system or only a portion of the antilock system, as previously described. An
                antilock system power failure (less than 9V) or failure of the EC-15 will cause the system to shut down,
                reverting to a standard braking system. Also failure of two or more components will cause the entire
                system to shut down, and again revert to a standard brake system.
            </para>
            <para>With the failed component approach previously described, a partially shutdown antilock brake system
                will still provide improved braking stability over a standard air brake system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>With a partially shutdown antilock brake system, the driver will be alerted by the instrument
                        panel warning light, and the portion of the antilock system disabled by the EC-15 reverts to a
                        standard air brake system controlled by the relay valve (rear axles) or brake valve (front
                        axle).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
