<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Brakes - Hydraulic Brake Actuation - Hydraulic Brake Actuation Description and Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Hydraulic Brake Actuation Description and Operation</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Blistering or swelling of rubber brake components may indicate contamination of the brake
                        fluid by a petroleum-based substance. Contaminated rubber components in the hydraulic brake
                        system must be installed new and the entire hydraulic brake system must be flushed with clean
                        brake fluid to prevent recontamination.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>This vehicle is equipped with a brake pedal-actuated dual brake system. The system consists of the
                following:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Brake booster</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Hydro-Boost&#174;</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake master cylinder</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Front disc brake calipers</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Rear disc brake calipers</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake tubes and hoses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Anti-lock brake system (ABS) components</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The dual brake system is comprised of 2 separate circuits, the front wheel brakes and the rear wheel
                brakes.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Fluid</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Use of any brake fluid other than approved DOT 3 will cause permanent damage to brake
                        components and will render the brakes inoperative.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Brake fluid contains polyglycol ethers and polyglycols. Avoid contact with eyes. Wash hands
                        thoroughly after handling. If brake fluid contacts eyes, flush eyes with running water for 15
                        minutes. Get medical attention if irritation persists. If taken internally, drink water and
                        induce vomiting. Get medical attention immediately.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Brake fluid is harmful to painted or plastic surfaces. If brake fluid is spilled onto a
                        painted or plastic surface, immediately wash it with water.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Use clean, fresh DOT 3 Motor Vehicle Brake Fluid.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Do not reuse brake fluid drained or bled from the system.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Do not use brake fluid that has been stored in an open container.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Do not mix different types of brake fluid.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The brake pedal is connected to the power brake booster, which is connected to the brake master
                cylinder. When the brake pedal is depressed, brake fluid is pushed from the master cylinder through the
                metal tubing and flexible hoses to the rear disc brake calipers and the front disc brake calipers. The
                brake fluid enters the rear disc brake calipers, forcing the rear disc brake caliper pistons outward
                against the brake pads. The brake pads press against the braking surface on the brake discs. The front
                disc brake caliper pistons are forced outward against the brake pads and contact the braking surface of
                the brake discs and hub. When the brake pedal is released, the pressure is relieved, returning the brake
                caliper pistons and the brake shoes and linings to the unapplied position.
            </para>
            <para>The ability of a brake system to stop the vehicle is dependent on the available traction.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Master Cylinder</title>
            <para>The brake master cylinder is a dual-piston type. The brake master cylinder operates as follows:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When the brake pedal is depressed, pressure is applied by mechanical linkage to the primary
                        and secondary piston.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Brake master cylinder pistons apply hydraulic pressure to the 2 hydraulic circuits.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The brake master cylinder consists of:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>brake master cylinder reservoir.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>brake master cylinder body.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Master Cylinder Reservoir</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Whenever the brake master cylinder reservoir is removed from the brake master cylinder, new
                        grommets must be installed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The brake master cylinder reservoir:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>is mounted to the brake master cylinder.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>holds fluid supply for each brake master cylinder hydraulic piston.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>provides visual fluid level markings.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>contains the brake master cylinder fluid level sensor.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Tubes and Hoses</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never use copper tubing. It is subject to fatigue, cracking and corrosion which could result
                        in brake tube failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Steel tubing is used throughout the brake hydraulic system. All brake tube fittings must be properly
                double flared to provide strong leakproof connections. When bending the tubing to fit the underbody or
                rear axle contours, be careful not to kink or crack the tube, allow the tube to contact any other
                component or come within 51 mm (2.0 in) of the exhaust system.
            </para>
            <para>If a section of brake tube is damaged, the entire section must be replaced with a tube of the same
                type, size, shape and length.
            </para>
            <para>When replacing hydraulic brake tubing, hoses or connectors, tighten all connections securely. After
                replacement, bleed the brake system. For additional information, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04049_X2060015.xml" xrefid="x2060015">Brake System</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_X2060657.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
