<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3000 - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl040241a">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The only way the driver knows the Antilock Brake System is not working is when the yellow dash
                        warning light turns on. The driver will not be able to give you any useful information to help
                        you find the problem. It is important that you follow the Troubleshooting Charts step by step
                        and use a copy of the
                        <hotlnk document="s04024_40.xml" xrefid="f0402442">Troubleshooting Record Sheet</hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ANTILOCK WIRING</title>
            <para>The antilock wire harnesses contain wires that are color-coded and have imprinted circuit numbers.
                <hotlnk document="s04024_43.xml" xrefid="f0402451">CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</hotlnk>
                include the circuit numbers, wire colors, wire gauge and connector numbers. The connector numbers
                identify the various connectors by number.
                <hotlnk document="s04024_44.xml" xrefid="x0402403">CONNECTOR END VIEWS</hotlnk>
                display pin configuration and circuits that are attached for the various numbered connectors.
                <emph type="bold">Connectors are always viewed from the mating ends.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>As you diagnose wiring in the antilock system, the following general rules should be followed where
                applicable:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">It is generally advisable to replace a wire harness, rather than repair individual wires
                    in the harness. If a splice repair must be made, it is important that the splice be properly
                    soldered with a rosin flux (not acid-based) and made waterproof.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not pierce wire insulation when checking for continuity. Also, do not probe the ECU
                    harness 12 and 14 pin connectors from the rear to check for continuity. The pins are sealed against
                    moisture.
                    <emph type="bold">Check for power, ground or continuity only by disconnecting the connector(s) and
                        testing the individual pins or sockets in the connector.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Always refer to the Circuit Diagram Book for wire and connector identification.
                    Individual wire identification will differ depending upon the type of connectors in use, the vehicle
                    model, and the system features.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
