<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAMONDLIFE&#8482; (BOSCH PIN SLIDE) DISC BRAKES For Vehicles Built After June 2, 2002 - MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>GENERAL</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface. Block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        Support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle supported only by jacks.
                        Jacks can slip and fall over. Serious personal injury can result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                    <para>Solvent cleaners can be flammable, poisonous and cause burns. Examples of solvent cleaners are
                        carbon tetrachloride, emulsion-type cleaners and petroleum-based cleaners. To avoid serious
                        personal injury when you use solvent cleaners, you must carefully follow the manufacturer's
                        product instructions and these procedures:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Wear safe eye protection.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Wear clothing that protects your skin.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Work in a well-ventilated area.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not use gasoline, or solvents that contain gasoline. Gasoline can explode.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>You must use hot solution tanks or alkaline solutions correctly. Follow the
                                manufacturer's instructions carefully.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>Hydraulic brake fluid is a caustic substance. Contact with hydraulic brake fluid can cause
                        skin irritation. Do not let hydraulic brake fluid touch any painted surfaces, as it will remove
                        the paint. Hydraulic brake fluid may also damage certain non-metal surfaces. Do not let fluid
                        get on brake pads, shoes, rotors or disks.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>It is difficult to determine an exact maintenance schedule (time or mileage) since vehicles will be
                used in wide varieties of operational applications and conditions.
            </para>
            <para>Vehicles operating under severe conditions, such as frequent stop and go driving, mountainous terrain
                or loaded more than 50% of payload, will require more service maintenance checks than a vehicle which is
                used over the road. Therefore, a regular schedule for periodic inspection should be established based on
                past experience and type of operation.
            </para>
            <para>Disc brakes do not require adjustment since the clearance is maintained by the movement of the caliper
                pistons.
            </para>
            <para>Be sure to keep in mind that the Hydro-Max Booster system consists of two completely separate
                hydraulic systems operating on two different incompatible fluids; power steering fluid and hydraulic
                brake fluid. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES and GROUP 05 - STEERING in the Master Service Manual for
                complete details covering the Hydro-Max Booster system and Power Steering.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the Master Service Manual for proper fluids and grease.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
