<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RECONDITIONING ROTORS - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>MACHINING ROTORS</title>
            <para>The terms micrometers and micro-inch describe surface finish or smoothness and are different from
                runout and parallelism. These terms refer to the flatness of the rotor surface.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The rotors are considered acceptable for continued service use without machining when:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lateral runout and thickness variation is within specification.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotor braking surfaces are smooth with even wear. Light grooving or heat checking is
                        acceptable.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Brake pads are being replaced with the SAME brake pad material type.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotor thickness is more than the minimum allowable thickness.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The rotors can be machined to provided a new, smooth braking surface. The rotors should
                    be machined when:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lateral runout or thickness variation exceed the maximum specification.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rotor braking surfaces are worn unevenly, have deep grooves, are scored, heat
                        spotted, heat checked or has excessive brake pad material transfer.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Replacing brake pads with a DIFFERENT brake pad material type.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the rotor will not true up before the minimum allowable thickness, the rotor must be
                    replaced. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04018w_25.xml" xrefid="t0401802">SPECIFICATIONS
                        <xref refid="t0401802"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <para>IMPORTANT - Rotors are identified by the minimum allowable thickness that can be used. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04018w_4.xml" xrefid="f0401810">Figure 10.
                        <xref refid="f0401810"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    Any rotor thinner than the minimum dimension must not be used.
                </para>
            </specpara>
            <para>Be sure to use good sharp cutting tools and proper cutting feed and speed when machining the rotor.
                Avoid dull cutting tools and "tool chatter". After machining, the rotor braking surfaces must be clean
                and smooth with a surface finish of 40 to 120 micro-inch (1.016 to 3.048 micrometers).
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04018w_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04018w_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04018w.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
