<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 550 AND TU-FLO 750 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The compressor is driven by the vehicle engine and is operating continuously while the engine is
                running. Actual compression of air is controlled by the compressor unloading mechanism and the governor.
                The governor, which is generally mounted on the compressor, maintains the brake system air pressure to a
                preset maximum and minimum pressure level.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
            <title>INTAKE AND COMPRESSION OF AIR (LOADED)</title>
            <para>During the down stroke of the piston, a slight vacuum is created between the top of the piston and the
                cylinder head, causing the inlet valve to move off its seat and open. (Note: The discharge valve remains
                on its seat.) Atmospheric air is drawn through the air strainer and the open inlet valve into the
                cylinder (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400305">Figure 5</hotlnk>). As the piston begins its upward stroke, the air that was
                drawn into the cylinder on the down stroke is being compressed. Air pressure on the inlet valve, plus
                the force of the inlet spring, returns the inlet valve to its seat and closes. The piston continues the
                upward stroke and compressed air pushes the discharge valve off its seat. Air flows by the open
                discharge valve into the discharge line and to the reservoirs (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400306">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400305" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0400305.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Operational-Loaded (Intake)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0400306" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0400306.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Operational - Loaded (Compression)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>As the piston reaches the top of its stroke and starts down, the discharge valve spring and air
                pressure in the discharge line return the discharge valve to its seal. This prevents the compressed air
                in the discharge line from returning to the cylinder bore as the intake and compression cycle is
                repeated. With the inlet valves held off their seats by the unloader pistons, air is pumped back and
                forth between the two cylinders, and the discharge valves remain closed after the cutout pressure level
                is reached.
            </para>
            <para>When air pressure from the reservoir drops to the cut-in setting of the governor, the governor closes
                and exhausts the air from above the unloader pistons. The unloader springs force the pistons upward and
                the inlet valves return to their seats. Compression is then resumed.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
