<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RECONDITIONING BRAKE DRUMS AND SHOES - BRAKE DRUMS - INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="13">
        <title>INSPECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>As part of the brake inspection it is important to learn to recognize the various clues offered by a
                brake drum when it is first removed from the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>It is important to take the time to closely read the wear patterns and markings of a worn drum. A
                great deal can be learned about the vehicles braking performance and even help prevent premature wear or
                failure of a new brake job.
            </para>
            <para>It is important to watch for the following conditions. They indicate if the drum needs servicing or
                replacing.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cracked Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400701">Figure 1</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400701" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400701" filename="../figg04/G0400701.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Cracked Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This is caused by excessive heating and cooling. The system should be checked for balance, paying
                particular attention to using brake material with the proper friction rating as recommended by
                International. Replace cracked drums immediately.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heat-Checking (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400702">Figure 2</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400702" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400702" filename="../figg04/G0400702.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Heat Checking</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This condition is indicated when the brake drum braking surface shows fine, hairline cracks.
                Heat-checking is a normal condition of the brake drum caused by constant heating and cooling of the
                braking surface.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Out-Of-Round Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400703">Figure 3</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400703" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400703" filename="../figg04/G0400703.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Out-of Round Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This condition is signified by more wear on one side of the brake lining and variations in drum
                diameter at different points on the braking surface.
            </para>
            <para>The drum should be machined to within allowable limitations, to restore concentricity or be replaced
                with a new drum. Drums should not be machined to exceed maximum rebore limit of .080" and not be worn to
                exceed .120".
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oversized Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400704">Figure 4</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400704" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400704" filename="../figg04/G0400704.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Oversized Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This condition is indicated by uneven lining wear, or braking surface diameter measurements in excess
                of allowable limitations. Corrective action would include the replacement of the brake drum and brake
                lining.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Grease Stained Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400705">Figure 5</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400705" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400705" filename="../figg04/G0400705.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Grease Stained Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Upon inspection, there will be discolored spots on the drum surface, with oil or grease splattered on
                the brake assembly.
            </para>
            <para>The condition may be caused by a faulty seal or improper greasing of the brake cams.</para>
            <para>To correct the condition it is necessary to repair the oil or grease leak, clean the entire assembly
                and replace the lining if it is soaked with oil or grease.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heat Spotted Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400706">Figure 6</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400706" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400706" filename="../figg04/G0400706.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Heat Spotted Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This problem may be indicated by hard, slightly raised, dark colored spots on the braking surface with
                uneven wear. This problem may also be indicated by a pulsating ride upon application of the brakes or
                excessive noise when braking.
            </para>
            <para>Drums should be turned to remove the hard, raised areas. If boring or grinding will not remove the
                spots, the drum should be replaced. Brake linings should also be checked for uneven wear factors and
                replaced to restore maximum braking efficiency.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Scored Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400707">Figure 7</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400707" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400707" filename="../figg04/G0400707.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Scored Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The condition is indicated by a grooved appearance on the braking surface of the drum and excessive
                lining wear.
            </para>
            <para>The scoring can be removed by machining within established limitations. It is also advisable to
                closely inspect the entire brake system to determine if excessive amounts of braking material have
                entered the braking system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blue Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400708">Figure 8</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400708" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400708" filename="../figg04/G0400708.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Blue Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This condition is signified by a bluish color and disfiguration of the brake parts and is caused by
                excessive heat. The system should be checked for broken or weak return springs and possible faulty
                operation of the brake cams.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Polished Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400709">Figure 9</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400709" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400709" filename="../figg04/G0400709.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Polished Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A polished drum can be recognized from a mirror-like finish on the braking surface.</para>
            <para>This condition is easily corrected by removing the gloss with eighty grit emery cloth. If the
                condition reappears, linings should be checked for proper friction rating.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Excessive Wear (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400710">Figure 10</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400710" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400710" filename="../figg04/G0400710.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Excessive Wear</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>If excessive wear occurs along the edges of the lining contact area or in areas coinciding with the
                lining rivet holes, the system should be checked for abrasive material collection.
            </para>
            <para>Brake drums should be checked for scoring and replaced if severely damaged.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Barrel-Shaped Drums (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400711">Figure 11</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400711" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400711" filename="../figg04/G0400711.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Barrel-Shaped Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A barrel-shaped drum results from overheating. If this condition is not corrected, the braking surface
                is reduced and uneven lining wear results.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bellmouthed Drum (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400712">Figure 12</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400712" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400712" filename="../figg04/G0400712.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Bellmouthed Drum</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Extreme pressure over a period of time will create a bellmouthed drum. Brake lining on a bellmouthed
                brake drum will make contact only on the inner surface of the drum. In addition to cutting the braking
                surface to a minimum, it will also cause uneven and rapid lining wear.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Runout (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400713">Figure 13</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400713" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400713" filename="../figg04/G0400713.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Installing New Drum</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.DIAL INDICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.DRUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.POINTER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Any time a new brake drum is to be installed on a vehicle, the runout should be checked as follows.
                Place the new drum with hub and wheel assembled in brake drum lathe making certain drum is centered.
                Mount Dial Indicator on lathe and check runout about 0.5 inch (12.7mm) in from edge of drum (on braking
                surface) as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400713">Figure 13</hotlnk>. Runout must not exceed 0.010 inch (0.25 mm).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_HL0400701.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
