<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 501 - REASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>REASSEMBLE</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>All flange mounted compressors must be assembled without a gasket between the crankcase and flange
                    adapter and some compressors do not require gaskets on the end cover. Install the new crankcase
                    gaskets only where they were removed during disassembly. Failure of the compressor would result if
                    gaskets are used when not required.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On compressors which use a ball type main bearing, press the ball bearing onto the correct
                end of the crankshaft. Position the ball bearing and the crankshaft in the crankcase making sure the
                drive end of the crankshaft is positioned in the crankcase as marked before disassembly. Carefully press
                the crankshaft and ball bearing into the crankcase using an arbor press.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On compressors with a front ball bearing, place two small seal rings in the countersunk
                holes at the front of the crankcase, as well as an end cover gasket. Install the front end cover in
                proper position as marked before disassembly taking care not to damage the new oil seal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On compressors with a rear ball bearing, place two small seal rings in countersunk at the
                rear of the crankcase. In one application a gasket is used and in another a large O-ring is placed in
                the counterbore at the rear of the crankcase. These are in addition to the seal rings. Install the rear
                end cover in the proper position as marked before disassembly. On some compressors the area for the two
                small seal rings has been increased slightly and the seal ring thickness increased. When the thicker
                O-rings are used, a retaining ring will also be used as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401015">Figure 15</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401015" filename="../figg04/g0401015.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Use of Retaining Ring</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On compressors with a sleeve bearing either front or rear, place the two small seal rings in
                the countersunk holes in the crankcase. Where seal rings are used, an end cover gasket MUST NOT be used.
                Place the O-ring seal in the groove around the flange adapter or the end cover, and affix the thrust
                washer.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the flange adapter or end cover in the proper position as marked before disassembly
                taking care not to damage the sleeve bearing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the flange adapter, front or rear cover to the crankcase by tightening the capscrews
                to the following torque values.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">7/16" Capscrews, Cast Iron Flange Adapter, 38 - 45 ft-lbs. (51.5 - 61 N&#8226;m)</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">7/16" Capscrews, Cast Aluminum End Cover, 25 - 30 ft-lbs. (34 - 40.7 N&#8226;m)</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">5/16" Capscrews or Stud and Nut, All End Covers, 15 - 18 ft-lbs. (20.3 - 24.4
                    N&#8226;m)
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">7/16" Capscrews, Through Drive Compressor with Cast Iron End Covers, 25 - 30 ft-lbs. (34
                    - 40.7 N&#8226;m)
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If new wrist pins are being installed, they should be pressed into the connecting rods so
                that the oil hole in the bushing lines up with the one in the rod.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The new bushings should be reamed or honed to provide .0001 - .0006 inch (.00254 - .01524mm)
                clearance on the wrist pin. Position the connecting rod in the piston and press in the wrist pin. Some
                compressors will have the wrist pin secured in the piston by a lock wire extending through matching
                holes in wrist pin and piston boss, anchored in a hole in the side wall of the piston. If the original
                pistons are used, the wrist pin must be pressed in so the hole in the wrist pin aligns with that of the
                piston. Secure same by inserting the new lockwire through the hole in piston and wrist pin and lock the
                wire by snapping the short 90 degree section into the lockwire hole in the bottom of the piston.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Later design compressors will have the wrist pin secured by Teflon buttons in either end of the wrist pin,
            allowing the wrist pin to float. The Teflon buttons may be used with either new or old wrist pins.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The late design pistons have two rings above the wrist pin and one below. Install piston
                rings in the correct location with ring pipmarks up. Stagger the position of ring gaps. Prelubricate
                piston, rings, wrist pin and connecting rod bearings with clean engine oil before installing them in the
                compressor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove connecting rod bearing cap from connecting rod. Turn crankshaft so that one of the
                connecting rod journals is in the downward center position. Install crankshaft journal rod bearing in
                connecting rod and rod cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stagger piston rings so that the ring gaps are 120 degrees apart. Apply engine oil to rings,
                piston and wrist pin. Use ring compressor and compress piston rings.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install piston/rod assembly into correct cylinder (the one it was removed from). Tap ring
                compressor flush with block.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use hammer handle and tap piston into cylinder bore, guiding rod/bearing onto crankshaft
                journal.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach bearing cap to connecting rod making sure that a lock strap is positioned on the cap.
                Tighten the rod bolts to 120 - 150 inch pounds or 10 - 12 ft-lbs. (13.5 - 16.3 N&#8226;m). Bend lock
                strap prongs against hex head of bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install remaining piston and connecting rod in the same manner.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A new unloader kit (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401016">Figure 16</hotlnk>) should be used when reassembling the compressor. The
                pistons in the kit are prelubricated with a special lubricant and require no further lubrication.
                Install unloader pistons in their bores taking care not to cut O-ring. Position unloader plungers in
                their guides and slip them in and over the tops of the pistons. Install unloader spring seat in
                crankcase inlet cavity. A small hole is drilled in crankcase for this purpose. Position the saddle
                between unloader piston guides so its forks are centered on guides. Install unloader spring making sure
                it seats over the spring seats both in crankcase and on saddle. Install inlet valve guides, then
                position valves in their guides. There should be a loose sliding fit between the guides and valves.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401016" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401016" filename="../figg04/g0401016.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Unloader Mechanism</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the inlet valve springs in the cylinder head by applying a turning motion to the
                spring after it is in the head. The turning motion should dig the spring wire into the spring seat in
                the bottom of the spring bore in the head. Should this procedure fail after repeated attempts, use a
                very small quantity of grease to hold them in place, just enough to keep the springs from falling out.
                Place the cylinder head gasket on the cylinder block. Carefully align the cylinder head assembly on the
                block and install the capscrews, tightening them evenly to a torque of 25 - 30 ft-lbs. (34 - 40.7 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the base plate or base adapter gasket on the crankcase and install the base plate
                adapter as marked before disassembly. Tighten the six capscrews securing the cast iron base adapter
                evenly to a torque of 38 - 45 ft-lbs. (51.5 - 61 N&#8226;m) and 12 - 16 ft lbs. (16.26 - 21.69 N&#8226;m)
                for base plate or aluminum cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
