<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DOUBLE DIAPHRAGM MGM SPRING BRAKE - REPLACE SPRING BRAKE ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
        <title>REPLACE SPRING BRAKE ASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>It is mandatory that the service pushrod of the new unit be cut to the proper length. Improper
            installation of the new unit could result in malfunctioning brakes or premature failure of the braking
            system.
        </para>
        <para>If the old double diaphragm spring brake assembly was properly installed, use the old assembly measurement
            to determine proper rod length. If the brake being removed was not properly installed or has been damaged
            too greatly to allow measurement, the following procedure must be followed to determine the proper rod
            length.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure that the old spring brake is fully caged. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_X0402001.xml" xrefid="x0402001">CAGING SPRING</hotlnk>. Be sure the service
                brake piston is fully retracted into brakes "OFF" position. Then measure outward from the bottom face of
                the service brake chamber and record both the X and Y dimensions (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402015">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0402014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Piston Rod Measurement</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>INCHES - X DIMENSION TO END OF THREADED PISTON ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>INCHES - Y DIMENSION TO CENTER LINE OF THE YOKE PIN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On double diaphragm spring brake assemblies that are to be re-attached to standard,
                    manual slack adjusters, the Y dimension (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402015">Figure 15</hotlnk>) is the most critical measurement, and a new service
                    piston rod must be cut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402016">Figure 16</hotlnk>) to exactly duplicate this "rod-plus- yoke" length
                    after the yoke assembly is re-installed on the piston rod.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0402016" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/g0402015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Cut Service Piston Rod</caption>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On double diaphragm spring brake assemblies that are to be re-attached to automatic
                    slack adjusters, the X dimension (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402015">Figure 15</hotlnk>) is the most critical measurement, and a new service
                    piston rod must be cut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402016">Figure 16</hotlnk>) to exactly duplicate this "rod only" length before the
                    yoke assembly is re-installed on the piston rod.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the hex nuts (Item 1,
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml" xrefid="f0402014">Figure 14</hotlnk>) and the flat washers on the
                mounting studs of the new chamber, clean the face of the mounting bracket and install the chamber on the
                bracket with close attention given to positioning the chamber air inlet ports for correct alignment to
                the vehicle air lines. Then install one flat washer and hex nut (Item 1,
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml" xrefid="f0402014">Figure 14</hotlnk>) on each mounting stud and using a
                15/16-inch wrench
                <emph type="bold">(DO NOT USE AN IMPACT-TYPE WRENCH)</emph>, tighten nuts to
                <emph type="bold">100 to 115 ft-lbs. (136 to 156 N&#8226;m) torque.</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When installing any MGM MODEL "TR-T" and "TR-LP3-T"chamber, it is mandatory to position the
                        non-pressure chamber end of the breather tube in upper half of chamber facing away from the road
                        surface (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402008">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Failure to comply will
                        void the warranty on these models.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reconnect yoke to the slack adjuster, being sure that the correct diameter and length of
                yoke pin is installed into the correct hole in the slack adjuster. Secure the yoke pin with a new cotter
                pin.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the piston rod to be sure that it is working free, not binding and is square to the
                service brake chamber bottom within &#177; 3&#176; in any direction at any point in the stroke of the
                chamber. If the piston rod is not square, make corrections by repositioning the assembly on the mounting
                bracket and/or by shimming the slack adjuster to the right or left on the camshaft as required.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Teflon tape or sealing compound to the hose fittings (Item 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml" xrefid="f0402014">Figure 14</hotlnk>) and re-install both of the air
                lines to the chamber being sure each is mated to the correct air inlet port according to markings made
                earlier.
                <emph type="bold">Tighten fittings to 25 ft-lbs. (34 N&#8226;m) torque into the chamber air inlet
                    ports.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using vehicle system air, charge the spring brake with full line pressure (minimum 100 psi).
                Using only soapy water (NEVER ANY TYPE OF OIL!), inspect for air leaks at the air lines and fittings. If
                bubbles appear,
                <emph type="bold">tighten fittings (Item 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml" xrefid="f0402014">Figure 14</hotlnk>) slightly, but not over 30
                    ft-lbs. (41 N&#8226;m) torque.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If the service brake clamp ring was loosened to reposition air inlet ports, apply air to the
                        spring brake and then apply and hold foot brake treadle valve down to charge the service brake
                        chamber. Test for air leaks around the circumference of the service clamp ring. If bubbles
                        appear, firmly tap the circumference of the clamp ring with a hammer (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0402017">Figure 17</hotlnk>) and retighten the clamp nuts until leaks cease.
                        Tighten the clamp nuts to 25 to 30 ft-lbs. (34 to 41 N&#8226;m) torque. Completely exhaust air
                        from service brake chamber when complete.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0402017" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0402016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Tap Clamp Ring</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With air pressure now exhausted from the service brake chamber, but still applied on the
                spring brake, remove release nut, flat washer and release bolt. Replace these parts in their storage
                pocket (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_X0402001.xml" xrefid="f0402010">Figure 10</hotlnk>) on chamber (or in vehicle
                tool box if storage pocket is not present on chamber) and tighten nut (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_X0402001.xml" xrefid="f0402009">Figure 9</hotlnk>) against flat washer to 10
                ft-lbs. (14 N&#8226;m) torque.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the END CAP properly (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402005">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Be sure the "O" ring is installed
                in the plastic end cap (
                <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402006">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Operating units without the END CAP securely in place will cause premature failure of the
                        spring brake assembly and will void any warranty.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If chamber is fitted with an external breather tube, be sure both ends of the connector tube
                        are engaged a minimum of 1/2 inch into each of the flexible elbows (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402007">Figure 7</hotlnk>). The tube must be glued to
                        both of the elbows with a high quality rubber adhesive. These units must be mounted with the
                        BREATHER TUBE in the upper half of the non-pressure chamber facing away from the road surface (
                        <hotlnk document="s04020x_6.xml" xrefid="f0402008">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Failure to comply with
                        these installation instructions will void any warranty.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>After replacement of the service brake diaphragm or the spring brake chamber, the service
                        piston rod stroke and actuating alignment must be checked to assure correct installation and
                        foundation brake adjustment. It is very important to recognize that no foundation brake
                        adjustments can be made at either the spring brake chamber, or at the service brake chamber, and
                        that all "stroke adjustments" must be made at the slack adjuster.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04020x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
