<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - ANTILOCK AND TRACTION WIRING GENERAL NOTES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ANTILOCK AND TRACTION WIRING GENERAL NOTES</title>
        <para>The wires that carry information and power into and out of the EC-17 are generally grouped and terminate
            at a connector. The wire groups or wire harnesses along with the connectors are most often specified and/or
            supplied by the vehicle manufacturer. Refer to Figure 4 for the connectors used on the EC-17. The wiring
            harnesses and connectors are weather resistant and the wires that enter the connector are sealed to the
            connector. The wire gauge used in the wire harnesses is specific to the task performed.
        </para>
        <para>When diagnosing wiring in the antilock system, the following general rules apply and should be followed
            where applicable:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is generally advisable to replace a wire harness rather than repair individual wires in
                the harness. If a splice repair must be made, it is important that the splice be properly soldered with
                a water based or thoroughly cleaned rosin flux (not acid based) and made waterproof.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not pierce wire insulation when checking for continuity. Check for power, ground or
                continuity by disconnecting the connector and testing the individual pins or sockets in the connector.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not spread or enlarge individual pins or sockets during probing.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always check the vehicle handbook for wire and connector identification. Individual wire
                identification will differ depending upon the type of connectors in use, the vehicle manufacturer, and
                the system features in use.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While the retarder disable, serial link, and traction on/off connections are present on all
                EC-17 controllers, they are not always used.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
