<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - TROUBLESHOOTING - 9200, 9300 &#38; 9400 MODELS - TROUBLESHOOTING
        - DIAGNOSTIC LEDS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC LEDS</title>
        <para>There are ten LEDs plus a magnetically actuated reset switch in the controller diagnostic display. The
            first six LEDs locate the defective condition to a specific area of the vehicle, while the next three
            indicate the problem component (or its wiring). The LEDs are software driven and either ON or OFF, depending
            upon their monitor function. The ten LEDs are as follows:
        </para>
        <table id="t0403426">
            <title>Diagnostic LEDs</title>
            <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                <colspec colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <colspec colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                <colspec colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                <spanspec namest="sqcolumn1" nameend="sqcolumn3" spanname="1to3"/>
                <tbody valign="top">
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>FRT</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>MID</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED*</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>RER</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>RHT</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LFT</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>TRC</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>MOD</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>SEN</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ECU</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Red LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>LED &#x25AB;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>VLT</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Green LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>RESET</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>+</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>No LED</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="1to3">
                            <para>*This LED is not used for diagnostic purposes. It will, however, light when a magnet
                                is placed on the RESET switch in the diagnostic display.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <deflist>
            <term>FRT (Front) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will be illuminated at the same time as either the RIGHT or LEFT LEDs and either the MOD or SEN LED.
            </def>
            <term>MID (Mid Axle) LED -</term>
            <def>Only 6x4 vehicles with traction control feature and wheel sensors on all four rear axle wheel ends will
                use this LED. Standard installations will not include wheel sensors on all four rear wheel ends. On 6x4
                vehicles with traction control, the Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a
                problem with a speed sensor or speed sensor wiring. The MID LED should not illuminate at the same time
                as the MOD LED.
            </def>
            <term>RER (Rear) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will be illuminated at the same time as either the RHT or LFT LED and either the MOD or SEN LED.
            </def>
            <term>RHT (Right) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will be illuminated at the same time as either the FRT or RER LED and either the MOD or SEN LED.
            </def>
            <term>LFT (Left) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring.
                It will be illuminated at the same time as either the FRT or RER LED and either the MOD or SEN LED.
            </def>
            <term>TRC (Traction) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON indicating a permanent or intermittent problem in the traction
                control system. It may be illuminated with the MOD LED or by itself.
            </def>
            <term>MOD (Modulator) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON to indicate a permanent or intermittent short or open circuit
                in one of the M-21/M-22 modulator valve solenoids or wiring to the solenoids from the controller. There
                are four M-21/ M-22 modulator valves, each having two solenoids. This LED should be illuminated at the
                same time as either the RHT or LFT LED, and either the FRT or RER LED.
            </def>
            <term>SEN (Speed Sensor) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates and latches ON indicating permanent or intermittent failure. The failures
                indicated are:
            </def>
        </deflist>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open or shorted wheel speed sensor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open or shorted wheel speed sensor circuits.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wheel speed signal not present or is not within expected range (pushed back sensor).</para>
        </step1>
        <para>The SEN LED will be illuminated at the same time as either the RHT or LFT LED and either the FRT, MID or
            RER LED.
        </para>
        <deflist>
            <term>ECU (Electronic Control Unit) LED -</term>
            <def>This Red LED illuminates to indicate that the controller itself has failed. It illuminates and latches
                ON for all controller failures except low voltage. If the controller supply voltage is less than 9 volts
                DC, the LED illuminates to indicate that the controller is inactive. When the supply voltage goes above
                9 volts DC, the LED will turn OFF.
            </def>
            <term>VLT (Voltage) LED -</term>
            <def>This Green LED illuminates and remains ON during vehicle operation to indicate that vehicle power is
                reaching the controller. If the power supply to the controller from the vehicle electrical system is out
                of range (below 11 volts or above 17 volts) the Green VLT LED will
                <emph type="underscr">flash</emph>
                until the power supply returns to the acceptable voltage range.
            </def>
            <term>RESET -</term>
            <def>Under the RESET area of the LED display is a magnetically sensitive switch used to reset the diagnostic
                system. The device will respond to a magnet sufficient to lift a 3 ounce weight. Holding the magnet
                against the RESET causes all the LEDs to light while the magnet is against the reset.
            </def>
        </deflist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04034_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04034_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
