<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - SPRING APPLIED HYDRAULICALLY RELEASED (SAHR)
        CANISTER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048612" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SPRING APPLIED HYDRAULICALLY RELEASED (SAHR) CANISTER</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The full power brake system is a pressurized system that achieves pressures of up to 2320 psi.
                        This pressure
                        <emph type="boldundersc">IS NOT</emph>
                        reduced by switching the ignition off or removing battery power. Prior to servicing this system,
                        the depressurization procedures
                        <emph type="boldundersc">MUST BE PERFORMED EXACTLY AS PRESENTED</emph>. Failure to depressurize
                        the system may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>Any form of contamination entering the system could prevent the system from operating
                        correctly. Thoroughly clean the area around fittings before disconnecting the fittings. Always
                        plug open ports and lines as quickly as possible. Contamination in the system could result in
                        loss of braking functions during vehicle operation. Failure to follow this warning could result
                        in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Individuals without factory training are advised not to work on the Full Power Brakes system
                        to replace or repair items.
                    </para>
                    <para>This is a modern, complex system offering greater braking proficiency and features than
                        previous systems. If the system sustains damage or a component malfunctions and items need to be
                        replaced, users are strongly advised to contact the nearest International dealer for
                        professional assistance and repair. However, if location and circumstances prevent consulting
                        the dealer, and components are to be replaced, the prescribed procedure must be followed
                        accurately.
                    </para>
                    <para>Precharged HCU's and spare parts must be handled with the appropriate care and attention and
                        should not be exposed to excessive vibration or impact, nor air being blown into the hydraulic
                        ports prior to assembly to the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While removing a parking brake cable, only the threaded rod should rotate. If the cable is to
                        be reused, do not allow the cable to twist during removal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the parking brake cable. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404861">FIGURE 68</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the parking brake system is
                            <emph type="bold">inoperable</emph>, disconnect the cable as follows:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Place the transmission in Park (P or PB) if available; otherwise, use neutral (N).
                                    Turn the key to OFF.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using a 15 mm wrench to hold the SAHR canister shaft, loosen the jam nut on
                                    the threaded rod with a 16 mm wrench.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using the 15 mm wrench to hold the canister shaft, unscrew the threaded rod
                                    using an 8 mm wrench. The rod must be unscrewed approximately 2.5 inches before the
                                    cable disconnects. The cable will exhibit some resistance while being unscrewed
                                    because it is under tension.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the parking brake system is
                            <emph type="bold">operable</emph>, disconnect the cable as follows:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Place the transmission in neutral (N),
                                    <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                                    P or PB. Turn the key ON.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While pressing the brake pedal, press the dash mounted PARK BRAKE switch to
                                    release the parking brake. This will extend the SAHR canister shaft and relieve the
                                    tension on the parking brake cable.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using a 15 mm wrench to hold the SAHR canister shaft, loosen the jam nut on
                                    the threaded rod with a 16 mm wrench.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>While using the 15 mm wrench to hold the canister shaft, unscrew the threaded rod
                                    using an 8 mm wrench. The rod must be unscrewed approximately 2.5 inches before the
                                    cable disconnects.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Turn the key to OFF.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404861" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404861" filename="../figg04/g0404837.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 68. Park Brake Cable Adjustment Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 16mm JAM NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SAHR CANISTER SHAFT 15mm</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADJUSTMENT INDICATOR, 'HASH' MARK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. THREADED ROD 8mm</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the transmission in the N, P or PB position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the ignition key is OFF, and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power
                    to the brake system motors. They are in the fuse panel located on the engine side of the cowl. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404843">FIGURE 48</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the center of the instrument panel. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048601.xml" xrefid="f0404844">FIGURE 49</hotlnk>
                    . Set the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a clamp to pinch the low pressure hose at the inlet to the HCU reservoir. Place the
                    clamp midway between the HCU reservoir inlet and the crossmember, being careful not to damage the
                    reservoir inlet. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048605.xml" xrefid="f0404850">FIGURE 55</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the outside of the SAHR canister.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connectors from the cut-off solenoid valve and the travel
                    switch, both located on the SAHR canister. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404862">FIGURE 69</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut or remove any cable ties securing cables to the canister.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position a container to collect the drained brake fluid in the next step. Ensure that no
                    fluid will spill onto the ground or damage the paint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step, use a backup wrench to prevent the threadsaver fitting from being
                        removed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the brake line from the front of the SAHR canister. Plug the line and the
                    port on the canister to prevent contamination.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two 12 mm mounting nuts securing the canister to the frame rail, and remove
                    the canister. Verify that the nylon bushings are removed from the mounting holes in the frame.
                    Retain the bushings and mounting nuts for use during installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0404862" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404862" filename="../figg04/g0404815.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="240px"/>
                <caption>Figure 69. Location of SAHR Canister Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. OUTPUT SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MOUNTING STUDS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BLEED PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BRAKE FLUID PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CUT-OFF SOLENOID VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. TRAVEL SWITCH</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the canister to the frame rail using the two bushings and nuts removed earlier.
                    Torque the nuts to 75 to 81 Nm (55 to 60 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the brake line to the front of the SAHR canister. Torque fitting to 12 to 19 Nm
                    (9 to 14 Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove the clamp used to pinch the low pressure hose during removal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical connectors to the cut-off valve and the travel switch, both
                    located on the SAHR canister. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0404862">FIGURE 69</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the wire harness to the canister using cable ties.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure fluid is at or above the MAX mark in the Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. If
                    not, fill the reservoir up to the MAX mark with new, DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed
                    container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The parking brake circuit must be bled before the parking brake cable can be reconnected. The
                        procedure for connecting the parking brake cable is part of the bleeding procedure referenced in
                        the following step.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed the parking brake circuit, following the service bleeding procedure. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048401.xml" xrefid="hl04048401">PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKE
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                    <emph type="bold">The parking brake bleeding procedures include the procedure for reconnecting the
                        parking brake cable.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If leakage is noted in the following step, the system MUST be depressurized BEFORE making
                        repairs. Perform steps 3 thru 7 of the SAHR CANISTER REMOVAL procedure to verify that the system
                        is depressurized. Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal
                        injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check SAHR connections for leakage. If leakage is present, depressurize the system
                    before making repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key on; and with the brake pedal depressed, apply and release the parking brake
                    several times to verify correct operation. The PARK BRAKE indicator should light when park brake is
                    applied. Also verify that the SERVICE PARK BRAKE warning indicator does not light, and no new fault
                    codes are generated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the key off and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the transmission to the P or PB position (if available), and remove wheel chocks.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048620.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048613.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
