<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - CLEAN AND INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04012_17.xml" xrefid="f0401215">Figure 15</hotlnk>for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using mineral spirits or an equivalent solvent, clean and thoroughly dry all metal
                    parts. Do not damage bores with metal tools.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash all non-metallic components (Items 4, 12, 16, 19, 22, 23, 27, 31) in a soap and
                    water solution, making certain to rinse and dry thoroughly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the interior and exterior of all metal parts that will be reused for severe
                    corrosion, pitting, and cracks. Superficial corrosion and/or pitting on the exterior portion of the
                    body (Item 1) and cover (Item 2) is acceptable.
                    <emph type="bold">Replace the entire valve if the interior of the body or cover exhibits signs of
                        corrosion or pitting.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect each non-metallic component for cracks, wear or distortion. Replace the entire
                    valve if any of these conditions are found.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the bores of the body (Item 1) and cover (Item 2) for deep scuffing or gouges.
                    Replace the entire valve if either defect is found.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain the air channel running between the top surface of the body (Item 1) and
                    its supply port is clear and free of any obstruction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain all air channels and exhaust passages in the valve cover (Item 2) are clear
                    and free of any obstruction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the pipe threads in the body (Item 1) and valve cover (Item 2). Make certain
                    they are clean and free of thread sealant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all air line fittings for corrosion and replace as necessary. Make certain to
                    remove all old thread sealant before reuse.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
