<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DCM AND DDM DRUM TYPE PARKING BRAKE - BENDIX DUO DUTY MECHANICAL BRAKE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl040211a">
        <title>BENDIX DUO DUTY MECHANICAL BRAKE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The Bendix Duo-Duty Mechanical Brake (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402108">Figure 8</hotlnk>) is designed for parking brake usage. In special cases,
                however, this brake may be used to help stop a moving vehicle.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402108" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402108" filename="../figg04/g0402108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Duo-Duty Mechanical Brake</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRAKE SHOES</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. RETURN SPRINGS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SHOE-TO-SHOE SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SUPPORT PLATE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CAM AND LEVER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>An exploded view of the Duo-Duty Mechanical Brake is illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402109">Figure 9</hotlnk>. The brake consists of two brake shoes, two shoe return
                springs, a single shoe-to-shoe spring, a support plate assembly and a cam and lever assembly.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402109" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402109" filename="../figg04/g0402109.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. DDM Brake Exploded View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRAKE SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SUPPORT PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. UPPER ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SHOE RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SHOE GUIDE LUG</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SHOE RAISED BEARING SURFACES</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SHOE-TO-SHOE SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The linings are riveted to the shoes to simplify service through the use of pre-drilled lining sets.
            </para>
            <para>The support plate assembly consists of a support plate and two anchor pins. Large shoulders on the
                pins, together with heavy plate thickness, gives the support plate the strength and rigidity necessary
                to withstand the bending loads imposed on the lower anchor pin.
            </para>
            <para>The ends of the shoe webs are shaved to conform to the curved surfaces of the anchor pins. This allows
                the shoes to rotate on the lower anchor. Since there is no "floating" or vertical movement of the shoes
                on the anchor, the brake is considered to be a "fixed anchor" type.
            </para>
            <para>Two return springs hold the shoes to the top anchor (applying end) and a single shoe-to-shoe spring
                holds the shoes to the lower anchor pin. The two return springs are hooked to a nib formed on the end of
                the anchor pin at the applying end.
            </para>
            <para>The web of each shoe is guided on both surfaces by the support plate. The shoe guiding points consist
                of a guide lug and two raised bearing surfaces on the plate. In addition, the lower ends of the shoe
                webs are held in position by a shoulder formed on the lower anchor pin, and the upper ends of the shoe
                webs are held in place by the ends of the return springs.
            </para>
            <para>The brake is actuated by a cam and lever assembly typical of that shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402110">Figure 10</hotlnk>. The cam and shaft is a forged unit and the cam is hardened
                at the shoe contact surfaces to give high strength and high wear resistance. The lever is pressed on the
                cam shaft and is brazed in place to form an integrated cam and lever unit.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402110" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402110" filename="../figg04/g0402110.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. DDM Brake Cam and Lever View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. UPPER ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ACTUATOR LEVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAMSHAFT BALL</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CAM AND LEVER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the brake assembly is installed, the fork-shaped cam is installed over the upper anchor pin and
                the cams are located between the ends of the webs of the brake shoes. The ball on the opposite side of
                the lever assembly at the cam shaft end is a bearing surface for the shaft. A means must be provided in
                the brake installation for proper support of the shaft.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
