<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s04013" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5172" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>STOPMASTER</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WARNING</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>MATERIAL DUST DURING BRAKE SERVICING</para>
                            <seqlist>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Studies have indicated that exposure to excessive amounts of brake material
                                        dust (whether asbestos or non-asbestos, fiberglass, mineral wool, aramid,
                                        ceramic or carbon) may be a potential cancer-causing health hazard. Even though
                                        the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has not set any limits
                                        on non-asbestos dust exposure, there is some medical opinion that such
                                        non-asbestos fibers can cause cancer as well. Since most automotive friction
                                        materials normally contain a sizeable amount of this material, it is important
                                        that people who handle brake linings be aware of the problem and know the
                                        precautions to be taken.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Areas where brake work is done should be set aside, if possible, and should be
                                        posted with a material dust exposure sign as follows:
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">BRAKE LINING FIBER DUST HAZARD</emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">AVOID BREATHING DUST</emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">WEAR ASSIGNED PROTECTIVE EQUIPMENT</emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">DO NOT REMAIN IN AREA UNLESS YOUR WORK REQUIRES IT</emph>
                                    </para>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">BREATHING BRAKE LINING FIBERS MAY BE HAZARDOUS TO YOUR
                                            HEALTH
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as
                                        well as for suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29,
                                        Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1910.1001.)
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other
                                        operations.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service
                                        procedures. Wear the respirator from removal of the wheels through assembly.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>NEVER use compressed air or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies.
                                        OSHA recommends that you use cylinders that enclose the brake. These cylinders
                                        have vacuums with high efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm sleeves. But,
                                        if such equipment is not available, carefully clean parts and assemblies in the
                                        open air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly,
                                        carefully place all parts on the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use
                                        an industrial vacuum cleaner with a HEPA filter system to clean dust from the
                                        brake drums, backing plates and other brake parts. After using the vacuum,
                                        remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Grinding or machining brake linings. If you must grind or machine brake
                                        linings, take additional precautions because contact with fiber dust is higher
                                        during these operations. In addition to wearing an approved respirator, do such
                                        work in an area with exhaust ventilation.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cleaning the work area. NEVER use compressed air or dry sweeping to clean the
                                        work area. Use an industrial vacuum with a HEPA filter and rags soaked in water
                                        and wrung until nearly dry. Dispose of used rags with care to avoid getting dust
                                        into the air. Use an approved respirator when emptying vacuum cleaners and
                                        handling used rags.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking. Do not
                                        wear your work clothes home. Vacuum your work clothes after use and then launder
                                        them separately, without shaking, to prevent fiber dust from getting into the
                                        air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL</title>
                    <para>The Stopmaster Brake is a wedge actuated brake. It can also be equipped with spring brake
                        units to provide parking and emergency braking. The brake power unit (air chamber) forces a
                        wedge between two rollers and two plungers. This causes the plungers to spread apart and push
                        the brake shoes against the brake drum.
                    </para>
                    <para>There are variations of Stopmaster Brakes in use. Some have two power units per brake and
                        others only one. Where two power units are used, there may be a Fail-Safe unit on one or both.
                        The brake support may be either a cast spider or a stamped backing plate. On the cast spiders,
                        the plunger housings may be either integral or bolted on. Brake shoe adjustment may be either
                        automatic or manual.
                    </para>
                    <para>The various basic Stopmaster Brakes are identified as model RDA (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401301">Figure 1</hotlnk>,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401302">Figure 2</hotlnk>, and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401303">Figure 3</hotlnk>), RDH, RSA (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401304">Figure 4</hotlnk>), or RSH with letters denoting the following: R -
                        Stopmaster Brake, Wedge Actuated; D - Double Actuated; S - Single Actuated; A - Air operated; H
                        - Hydraulic operated.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401301" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401301.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. RDA Bolted on Spider, Integral Plunger Housing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f0401302" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401302.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. RDA Welded on Spider, Bolted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f0401303" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401303.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. RDA Welded on Spider, Bolted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f0401304" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401304.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4. RSA Backing Plate, Bolted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The RDA Brake shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401305">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                        is equipped with integral plunger housings, and employs a cast spider mounting which bolts to a
                        flange on the axle housing. Adjusters may be manual or automatic (automatic shown). Dust shields
                        are the one- or two-piece type.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401305" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401305.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5. RDA Bolted on Spider, Integral Plunger Housings</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. LONG RADIUS</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. BRAKE SHOE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. ADJUSTING BOLT ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. PLUNGER SEAL AND RETAINER</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. ADJUSTING SLEEVE (ACTUATOR)</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. ADJUSTING PLUNGER</callout1>
                            <callout1>7. GUIDE SCREW</callout1>
                            <callout1>8. GASKET</callout1>
                            <callout1>9. ANCHOR PLUNGER (SOLID)</callout1>
                            <callout1>10. CLAMP BOLT</callout1>
                            <callout1>11. NUT</callout1>
                            <callout1>12. IDENTIFICATION TAG</callout1>
                            <callout1>13. AIR CHAMBER CLAMP RING</callout1>
                            <callout1>14. PRESSURE HOUSING</callout1>
                            <callout1>15. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                            <callout1>16. DIAPHRAGM PLATE</callout1>
                            <callout1>17. RUBBER BOOT</callout1>
                            <callout1>18. NON-PRESSURE HOUSING</callout1>
                            <callout1>19. IDENTIFICATION RING</callout1>
                            <callout1>20. WEDGE GUIDE</callout1>
                            <callout1>21. COLLET NUT</callout1>
                            <callout1>22. COLLET KEY</callout1>
                            <callout1>23. WASHER</callout1>
                            <callout1>24. WEDGE SPRING</callout1>
                            <callout1>25. BOOT</callout1>
                            <callout1>26. SPRING RETAINING WASHER</callout1>
                            <callout1>27. ROLLER</callout1>
                            <callout1>28. ROLLER RETAINING CAGE</callout1>
                            <callout1>29. WEDGE</callout1>
                            <callout1>30. BRAKE SPIDER</callout1>
                            <callout1>31. SHOE RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                            <callout1>32. WEDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>33. COLLET NUT</callout1>
                            <callout1>34. AIR CHAMBER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>35. HOLLOW CAPSCREW</callout1>
                            <callout1>36. SPRING</callout1>
                            <callout1>37. PLUNGER GUIDE AND ADJUSTING PAWL</callout1>
                            <callout1>38. HOLD DOWN CLIP</callout1>
                            <callout1>39. HOLD DOWN SPRING BOLT, LOCKWASHER AND NUT</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The RSA Brake shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401306">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                        has a separate plunger housing and a stamped backing plate mount which bolts to a flange on the
                        axle housing. The backing plate also serves as a dust shield. Adjuster may be manual or
                        automatic (automatic shown). The brake shoes may either be the floating type as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401304">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                        or of a pinned anchor type. Pinned type shoes actually have an anchor pin and the shoe is
                        secured to the anchor by means of a retaining ring.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401306" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401306.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 6. RSA Backing Plate Mounted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. SPRING - BRAKE SHOE RETURN</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. SHOE AND LINING ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. SNAP RING - ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. ANCHOR PIN -BRAKE SHOE</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. AUTOMATIC ADJUSTING PLUNGER</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. AUTOMATIC ADJUSTING ACTUATOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>7. DIAPHRAGM SEAL</callout1>
                            <callout1>8. ADJUSTING BOLT ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>9. PLUG - BACKING PLATE</callout1>
                            <callout1>10. WASHER - ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                            <callout1>11. NUT - ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                            <callout1>12. AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                            <callout1>13. COLLET NUT</callout1>
                            <callout1>14. HYDRAULIC CYLINDER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>15. WEDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>16. BOLT - ACTUATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                            <callout1>17. WASHER - ACTUATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                            <callout1>18. BACKING PLATE</callout1>
                            <callout1>19. ACTUATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                            <callout1>20. GASKET</callout1>
                            <callout1>21. PAWL ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>22. ROD - ANTI-RATTLE</callout1>
                            <callout1>23. SPRING - ANTI-RATTLE</callout1>
                            <callout1>24. RETAINER - ANTI-RATTLE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The RDA Brake shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401302">Figure 2</hotlnk>is equipped with separate plunger housings and
                        employs a cast open end spider which is welded to the axle. The actuation system is removed by
                        taking out the four attaching capscrews. This is the 12-1/4" diameter trailer brake and employs
                        the automatic adjuster. Dust shields are of the four-piece type.
                    </para>
                    <para>The RDA Brake shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401303">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                        has separate plunger housings, and employs a cast open end spider which is welded to the axle.
                        The open end spider type permits removal of the complete actuation system at disassembly. This
                        brake employs the automatic adjusters. Dust shields are of the four-piece type to facilitate
                        removal.
                    </para>
                    <para>Since RDA brake groups shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401302">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401303">Figure 3</hotlnk>are not used with truck applications, the exploded
                        views have not been provided.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>AIR CHAMBER SUPPORT BRACKETS</title>
                    <para>Support brackets must be used on all axles with brakes having an air chamber tube standout,
                        dimension "Y," equal to or greater than those listed in Air Chamber Chart under
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401307">Figure 7</hotlnk>. Use listed dimensions as a guide in determining
                        when to use support brackets.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401307" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401307.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7. Air Chamber Support Brackets</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. "U" BOLT</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. SADDLE BRACKET</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The support brackets are welded to the axle beam and attached to the non-pressure housing tube
                        with a "U" bolt and saddle bracket (round beam shown). The brackets are located as close as
                        possible to the air chamber for maximum support.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
