<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - PRESSURE LIMITING VALVE - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0400222" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operating Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                        pressures, governor pressure settings and other tests. Connect an accurate test gauge to the
                        delivery line and observe what pressure the inlet valve opens, which is the delivery pressure.
                        If delivery pressure varies more than 5 psi, adjust the valve to the specified setting. To raise
                        the delivery pressure, the adjusting cap should be turned clockwise. Tighten lock nut after each
                        adjustment and replace locking wire and seal if used.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Test</title>
            <para>No leakage is permitted at the exhaust vent in the slot of the adjusting cap when making the operating
                check. Leakage at this point would indicate a leaking piston O-ring or a leaking exhaust valve seat.
            </para>
            <para>If the pressure limiting valve does not function as described or leakage is excessive, it is
                recommended that it be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_46.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
