<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - CHECK VALVES - DOUBLE CHECK VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DOUBLE CHECK VALVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>Double check valves or two-way check valves (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400213">Figure 13</hotlnk>
                ) are used in an air brake system where it is necessary to automatically direct the flow of air pressure
                into a common line from either of two other lines.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400213" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400213" filename="../figg04/G0400213.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13.
                    <emph type="bold">Double Check Valve</emph>
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DELIVERY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SHUTTLE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SHUTTLE GUIDE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>As air pressure enters either end of the double check valve (inlet port), the movable shuttle responds
                to the air pressure and seals the line on opposite inlet port, but permits air pressure to flow out the
                delivery (outlet) port. The same action takes place if air pressure on one side of shuttle is higher
                than that on the other side. It is not necessary for the cavity of one side of the shuttle to be
                exhausted for the valve to operate. Double check valves are designed so it is impossible for shuttle to
                block outlet port.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Once each year or every 100,000 miles (160,000 km), remove, disassemble, clean and inspect all parts.
                Install new parts if signs of wear or deterioration are apparent.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400223">
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>Due to the various applications of double check valves, it is best to bench test the valve using two
                separately controlled air supplies connected to inlet ports.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install an accurate test gauge in outlet port or in a line from the outlet port.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and release air to one inlet port and note that the gauge registers application
                    and release.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat application and release of air to the other inlet port.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leakage check is performed at inlet ports by:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Disconnecting line from one inlet port.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Applying air to other inlet port. If soap solution is used to check leakage, leakage
                        should not exceed 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 5 seconds.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat step"B"by applying air to other inlet port while checking opposite inlet port
                        for leakage.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If check valve does not meet requirements, it should be repaired or replaced.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve from vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove end cap from valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove O-ring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shuttle (piston) and guide.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all metal parts in cleaning solvent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all parts for signs of wear or deterioration. Replace all parts that are not
                    serviceable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all rubber parts.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install shuttle guide and shuttle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position new O-ring in end cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install end cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400223">
                        <xref refid="hl0400223"/>SERVICE CHECKS
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall on vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
