<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - EC-17 CONTROLLER CONFIGURATION - EC-17 SELF CONFIGURING PROCESS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EC-17 SELF CONFIGURING PROCESS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Important General Information</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Three aspects of the antilock and traction system are influenced by the self configuring
                    feature of the EC-17.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Speed Sensors: The number of speed sensors connected to the EC-17 will be detected
                        during the self configuration process. The EC-17 will check the MID SEN (mid axle speed sensor)
                        locations on its connector to determine if a sensor is connected to it and will default to a six
                        sensor configuration if it detects even one sensor connected. If mid axle speed sensors are not
                        detected, the EC-17 will default to a four sensor configuration (two front and two rear).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Electronic Engine Control: If the EC-17 is connected to the control module of an
                        electronic engine, the torque limiting feature of traction control will be activated during the
                        self configuring process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Antilock Traction Relay Valve: If the solenoid assembly in the ATR valve is
                        connected to the EC-17, the differential braking feature of traction control will be activated
                        during the self configuring process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Traction Disable Switch: The traction disable switch must be in the correct position
                        for the Self Configuration process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No method is available to disable the self configuration feature.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Due to the extended period of time the RESET switch must be held to initiate the self
                    configuration process (20 seconds), it is unlikely that a self configuration would occur
                    accidentally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Basic, four speed sensor, antilock operation cannot be removed during self configuration
                    process. This is a minimum configuration for all EC-17 controllers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a speed sensor is connected to either wheel on the mid axle, the EC-17 will configure
                    for six sensors. If no mid axle speed sensor is detected, the EC-17 will configure for four sensors.
                    Any disconnected speed sensor(s) will register as a failure on the diagnostic display at the end of
                    the EC-17 self test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All or part of traction control can be lost during self configuration by:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Not connecting one of the wire harnesses (engine control module for torque limiting
                        and ATR valve solenoid for differential braking).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A missing or inoperative traction control enable disable switch.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Not toggling traction control enable/ disable switch in "traction enabled" after
                        power up, but prior to the self configuration. The operator can tell that traction features are
                        lost by noting the absence of traction lamp flash upon power up. The operator should note
                        flashing of the antilock condition lamp, and the traction lamp if traction equipped, upon every
                        power up. Observing dash lamps is one method the operator has to verify system operation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The EC-17 can be reprogrammed up to 10,000 times.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When a replacement EC-17 is installed on a vehicle that does not have one or more of the
                    preprogrammed features, a failure will be registered on the dash lamp(s) and on the EC-17 diagnostic
                    display. For this reason it is necessary to perform the self configuring procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Some configuration information is available by observing the reaction of the dash
                    condition lamps on vehicles configured with traction control and equipped with the self configuring
                    EC-17. When the ignition is switched ON, the EC-17 self test is begun. During the self test the dash
                    lamps will flash on and off together as indicated in the Dash Lamp Configuration Table below,
                    depending upon the type and amount of traction control configured into the EC-17.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: For more information on this subject, see the TROUBLESHOOTING section of
                        this document.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0403802">
                <title>Dash Lamp Configuration</title>
                <tgroup cols="7" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" charoff="50" colwidth="1.10in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" charoff="50" colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" charoff="50" colwidth="1.10in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col4" charoff="50" colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col5" charoff="50" colwidth="1.10in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col6" charoff="50" colwidth="0.85in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col7" charoff="50" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col3" nameend="col4" spanname="3to4"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col5" nameend="col6" spanname="5to6"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2" align="center">
                                <para>Torque Limiting &#38; Differential Braking</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="3to4" align="center">
                                <para>Torque Limiting Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="5to6" align="center">
                                <para>Differential Braking Only</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Antilock Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Traction Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Antilock Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Traction Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Antilock Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Traction Dash Lamp</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Both the Antilock and Traction dash lamps are ON during the system self test.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>ON</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>This is the first blink occurrence of the Antilock dash lamp. Compare and note
                                    traction lamp's reaction to Antilock lamp.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ON</para>
                                <para>ON</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>This is the second blink occurrence of the Antilock dash lamp. Compare and note
                                    traction lamp's reaction to Antilock lamp.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>OFF</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Both dash lamps are OFF and remain OFF at the end of the powerup sequence.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Self Configuration Process</title>
            <para>To successfully complete the self configuring process, follow the steps presented.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all antilock and traction control wire harnesses. Refer to the schematic in
                    <hotlnk document="s04038_2.xml" xrefid="f0403804">Figure 4</hotlnk>. Make certain that all the speed
                    sensors present on the vehicle are connected (H2, H3, J1, J2 on the 30 pin connector and E2, E3, F2,
                    F3, B2, B3, C2, C3 on the 18 pin connector). If the vehicle has an electronic engine and traction
                    control torque limiting is desired, the engine control module must be connected (B2 and B3 on the 30
                    pin connector for J1922 or C3, D2, and D3 on the 30 pin connector for J1939). If the vehicle is
                    equipped with either an ATR 1 or ATR 2 valve, the solenoid connection must be made to the EC-17 (D2
                    and D3 on the 18 pin connector) to obtain traction control differential braking.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is to be configured with traction control, it must have a traction
                    control dash lamp and a traction control enable/disable switch. Both the lamp and switch must be
                    functional.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition ON, toggle the traction control enable/disable switch back and forth,
                    then hold a magnet on the RESET position of the EC-17 diagnostic display until the LEDs begin to
                    flash, then remove the magnet. If the magnet is not removed during the LED flashing, a second self
                    configuration may be initiated. The reset switch may have to be held for as long as 20 seconds. When
                    the self configuration process is complete, the EC-17 will automatically go through a self test.
                    During the self test, the diagnostic display will indicate the new configuration as described under
                    the section entitled EC-17 Configuration Display.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the EC-17 is being configured with Traction Control (either torque limiting,
                            differential braking or both), the traction control condition dash lamp will be illuminated
                            as well as the appropriate LEDs on the EC-17 diagnostic display. The traction control dash
                            lamp will be illuminated until the traction control enable/disable switch is placed in the
                            traction control enabled position (traction control operative).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the traction control enable/disable switch in the traction control enabled
                    position (traction control operative), the traction control dash lamp should be off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before placing the vehicle in service, verify the configuration and the system condition
                    by turning the ignition OFF then ON while observing the EC-17 diagnostic display. The diagnostic
                    display should indicate the desired configuration as described under the section entitled EC-17
                    Configuration Display and no red LEDs should be illuminated at the end of the self test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the configuration appears correct but the diagnostic LEDs indicate a failure
                    somewhere in the system, refer to the General Configuration Information section and use the
                    Troubleshooting section of this manual to locate and repair the fault.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the configuration is incorrect, the process can be repeated as required. One common
                    error is performing the self configuration without toggling the traction control enable/disable
                    switch. This will prevent any traction features from being activated.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The traction switch must be toggled to configure traction, but must be placed in the
                            enable position to allow the traction lamp to flash.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_57.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_59.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
