<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>GENERAL</title>
            <para>It is difficult to determine an exact maintenance interval (time or mileage) since vehicles will be
                used in a wide variety of operations, applications and conditions.
            </para>
            <para>Vehicles operating under severe conditions such as frequent stop and go driving will require more
                service maintenance checks than a vehicle used over the road. Therefore, a regular schedule for periodic
                inspection should be established based on past experience and type of operation.
            </para>
            <para>Disc brakes do not require adjustment since the clearance is maintained by the movement of the caliper
                piston.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Keep in mind that the Hydro-Max Brake Booster System consists of two completely separate
                        hydraulic systems that use INCOMPATIBLE FLUIDS: POWER STEERING FLUID for the HYDRO-MAX BOOSTER
                        AND HYDRAULIC BRAKE FLUID for the BRAKE SYSTEM.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Detailed maintenance information pertaining to power booster and hydraulic systems can be found in the
                HYDRO MAX BOOSTER SECTION in GROUP 04 - BRAKES, HYDRAULIC in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>In addition, the following components should be checked when checking the brakes.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
