<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: HOLSET SS 296 AND QE 296/338 - CLEAN AND INSPECT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CLEAN AND INSPECT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Cleaning of parts can be done by most commercial methods used for cleaning ferrous metals and aluminum
                parts. The recommended method below works well.
            </para>
            <para>Inspections of most parts can be accomplished without any special equipment, but the use of some
                measuring equipment, such as micrometers, flat plate and feeler gauges, is required to assure that some
                surfaces and parts meet specifications.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When using solvents, acids, or alkaline materials for cleaning, follow the manufacturer's
                        recommendations for use. Wear goggles and protective clothing.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Soak the parts in a kerosene emulsion based cleaner designed to remove carbon, dirt, oil and grease.
                The cleaner must have a pH of 9.5 or less to avoid turning aluminum parts black. The cleaner
                manufacturer or supplier can be contacted about solution concentration, temperature and soak time. If
                using a hot caustic cleaning process, do not immerse aluminum parts. Use compressed air to dry parts.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use a scraper to remove carbon and scale; the sealing surfaces can be damaged. The
                        parts can be scrubbed with a stiff non-metallic bristle brush (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401448">Figure 48</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0401448" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401448" filename="../figg04/g0401448.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Scrub the Parts</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
