<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: HOLSET SS 296 AND QE 296/338 - LUBRICATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="lubricate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <para>The Holset SS 296 and QE air compressors are lubricated with pressurized engine oil, therefore it is
            recommended that the engine oil be checked regularly and changed at proper intervals.
        </para>
        <para>The oil provides both a lubrication and cooling medium for bearings, piston rings and cylinder walls.
        </para>
        <para>For optimum air compressor performance, the following lubrication system guidelines are provided:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Oil Temperature: Must not exceed 240&#176;F (115&#176;C) to provide proper lubrication
                    capability.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Oil Pressure: Maintain a minimum oil pressure of 10 psi (0.68 kPa).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Oil Supply: Engine oil supply is provided either internally or externally to the compressor.
                    Flange mount models can have both internal or external oil supply sources, while base mount models
                    are provided with external oil supply only. When an external supply is used, a minimum of .125 inch
                    (3.18 mm) inside diameter (ID) line size must be used to provide adequate oil flow.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The supply line must be free of sharp bends or kinks which can cause flow restrictions. The oil
                    supply source must be taken immediately after oil filtration from the engine for best results.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Oil Change Interval: Use the oil drain interval specified by the vehicle or engine manufacturer.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When operating in extreme environments where very high or very low temperatures or airborne dirt
                    or dust is present, consider much shorter oil change intervals consistent with engine manufacturer
                    recommendations.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Oil Drain: Compressor oil drainage is critical to prevention of oil consumption. Flange mount
                    compressor models provide either internal or external oil drainage. Base mount models provide
                    external oil drainage only.
                </para>
                <para>A .50 inch (12.7 mm) ID size is required when using an external oil drain. Using a smaller line
                    size, or less than .50 inch (12.7 mm) fittings, can cause excessive oil build-up in the compressor
                    crank- case. This can result in crankcase pressurization and oil passage into the vehicle's air
                    system.
                </para>
                <para>The oil drain system is gravity based, and therefore, requires installation of the drain line to
                    be free of low spots or traps with a downward flow of 2 to 3 inches (51 to 76 mm) per 1 foot (305
                    mm) minimum fall. The drain line must enter the engine at the point above the engine oil level to
                    prevent a back flow restriction.
                </para>
                <para>Where flange mount compressor drainage is internal to the compressor with engine oil drain or
                    return through the engine block holes, vehicle installation tilt angles greater than 4 degrees from
                    the horizontal, or roll angles exceeding 45 degrees from the vehicle position can cause less than
                    optimum drain back conditions.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_HL0401401.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
