<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - TRACTOR-TRAILER BRAKE ANALYSIS PROCEDURE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TRACTOR-TRAILER BRAKE ANALYSIS PROCEDURE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The air brake system on a tractor-trailer combination must provide balanced braking at all wheels and
                axles of the combination for optimum brake performance and life. This means that the braking effort
                produced at each wheel of the combination must be capable of doing its share of the work in controlling
                the speed of the two units.
            </para>
            <para>There are several factors which can affect brake balance. These are:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Loads must be properly distributed between tractor and trailer</emph>. A
                        balanced condition should not be expected with the combination vehicle if the load is not
                        properly distributed.
                    </para>
                    <para>The brakes on each axle are designed to meet specific performance criteria based on the axle's
                        Gross Axle Weight Rating (GAWR). For example, 34,000 lb. (15,400 kg) GAWR tandem axles used on
                        both the tractor and trailer in combination are designed to meet similar performance standards.
                        Overloading or underloading either the tractor or the trailer tandem axle can cause unbalanced
                        braking in the combination vehicle. A typical symptom would be early lockup of the brakes on an
                        axle loaded to less than the rated capacity.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Tractor and trailer brakes must be compatible.</emph>The foundation brakes
                        used on the tractor and trailer should be of the same type. Operating characteristics, such as
                        fade and speed sensitivity, are different for wedge, cam and disc-type brakes.Consequently,
                        under some operating conditions, the intermixing of brake types can cause or exaggerate an
                        imbalance condition between tractor and trailer(s). Extreme care must be used when operating a
                        combination equipped with brakes of different types.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Tractor and trailer brakes must be maintained in proper adjustment.</emph>
                        The force output of an air brake chamber push rod increases linearly for approximately 75% of
                        its maximum travel. Beyond 75%, the force is reduced. Therefore, if the brake adjustment is not
                        maintained within specification and the push rod travel is allowed to increase beyond 75% of
                        maximum travel, the brake torque output at the wheel will be reduced.
                    </para>
                    <para>For example, when air pressure of 100 psi (689 kPa) is applied to a Type 30 service air brake
                        chamber, approximately 3,000 lbs. of force is produced with a push rod travel of 1-1/2 in.
                        (38mm) or less. When the push rod travel is increased to 2-1/4 in. (57mm) at the same air
                        pressure, the force produced decreases to approximately 2,500 lbs., a reduction of about 17%. A
                        reduction in force at the push rod causes a similar reduction in the brake torque output at the
                        wheel. A reduction in the brake torque output capability at any one or several wheels of a
                        combination vehicle places added work on the brakes at other wheels. The result can be uneven
                        lining and drum or rotor wear (between brake assemblies), trailer surging and increased brake
                        fade.
                    </para>
                    <para>If automatic adjusters are used, they should be used on both
                        <emph type="bold">tractor</emph>and
                        <emph type="bold">trailer</emph>
                        to insure compatibility between the two units. While automatic adjusters do maintain the brakes
                        in reasonable adjustment, it is important that the adjusters be inspected periodically to be
                        sure that they are functioning properly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Tractor and trailer brake assemblies and air systems must be inspected and
                            properly maintained.
                        </emph>
                        Corroded anchor pins, frozen camshafts, worn bushings, weak or broken return springs, or
                        deformed shoes, etc., can reduce the efficiency of the brake assembly at any wheel(s). It is
                        important to inspect the air system - reservoirs, valves, fittings and lines - periodically for
                        damage. This includes draining the reservoirs as required.
                    </para>
                    <para>Whenever complaints of touchy brakes, inadequate braking, short service life of brake linings
                        or drums on either the tractor or the trailer (but not both) are encountered, there may be an
                        imbalance between the tractor and trailer air brake systems.
                    </para>
                    <para>It is suggested that a brake analysis be performed. This analysis includes testing for 1)
                        pressure balance, 2) pressure build-up rate (timing), and 3) torque balance. However, before
                        conducting the tests, the following questions should be considered:
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Are all or a majority of the drivers operating the combination units obtaining the same
                        results or registering the same complaints?
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Are the same results or complaints being registered on similar combination units?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Are the same results or complaints being registered under similar operating conditions?</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Were complaints always received on the combination unit or did complaints originate after some
                        brake service was performed, or vehicle operating conditions changed?
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the vehicle is equipped with Antilock Brakes, is the Antilock Brake system operating
                        properly?
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>The answers to these questions may help in identifying the cause(s). Such problems could be the result
                of incorrect or malfunctioning brake components, or simply the conditions under which the combination
                vehicle is operated.
            </para>
            <para>If the response to these questions seems to indicate that a brake imbalance condition may be present
                in the air brake system, the preliminary checks and test procedures in the following text can be used to
                isolate the cause.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PRELIMINARY CHECKS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before conducting the Pressure Balance, Pressure Build-up Rate, and the Torque Balance Tests,
                        make the following checks of the air brake system on the tractor-trailer combination. These
                        checks are intended to detect and correct conditions which otherwise could produce misleading or
                        inconclusive test results.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the adjustment of all brakes on both the tractor and trailer(s). Adjust the brakes
                    as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually check the slack adjuster movement (if applicable) to determine that all brakes
                    are actuating and releasing freely. If not, inspect and lubricate the brakes thoroughly.
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                    allow any lubricant on the linings, or drums.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the air brake system to be sure that it is free of significant air leaks. Air
                    leakage should not exceed the following values with an air system pressure of 95 psi (655 kPa) or
                    more and the brake pedal released:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">2 psi (13.8 kPa) per minute, on tractor only.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">3 psi (20.7 kPa) per minute, on tractor with trailer combination.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">5 psi (34.5 kPa) per minute, on tractor with two-trailer combination.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repair any leakage points if these values are exceeded.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain the reservoirs of any moisture and contamination.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect for damage or kinked lines and replace any lines found to be
                    defective.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect combination units for loose fifth wheel and king pin condition. A loose fifth
                    wheel to king pin fit can exaggerate an unbalanced brake condition and therefore must be adequately
                    adjusted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If vehicle is equipped with an Anti-Lock Brake System, disconnect the Anti-Lock Brake
                    System by removing the fuse before performing any brake tests. After all tests have been completed,
                    reinstall fuse.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Any deficiencies found in the above areas may be contributing factors to brake complaints. These
                should be considered in the overall analysis of the brake system.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
