<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Meritor/WABCO Hydraulic ABS for Medium-Duty Trucks, Buses and Motor Home Chassis - SERVICE NOTES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SERVICE NOTES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>This publication provides maintenance and service procedures for Meritor WABCO's hydraulic ABS for
                medium-duty trucks, buses and motor home chassis. The information contained in this publication was
                current at time of printing and is subject to revision without notice or liability.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>You must understand all procedures and instructions before you begin maintenance and service
                        procedures.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>You must follow your company's maintenance and service guidelines.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>You must use special tools, when required, to avoid serious personal injury and damage to
                        components.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Meritor uses the following notations to alert the user of possible safety issues and to provide
                information that will help to prevent damage to equipment and components.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>A WARNING indicates a procedure that you must follow exactly to avoid serious personal
                        injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>A CAUTION indicates a procedure that you must follow exactly to avoid damaging equipment or
                        components. Serious personal injury can also occur.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A NOTE indicates an operation, procedure or instruction that is important for proper service.
                        A NOTE an also supply information that will help to make service quicker and easier.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="ftorq" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figtor/torq.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            </figure>
            <para>This
                <hotlnk xrefid="ftorq">symbol</hotlnk>
                indicates that you must tightened fasteners to a specific torque.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04045.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
