<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - RESERVOIR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>RESERVOIR</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The air reservoir (air tank) provides the volume of compressed air required during brake system
                function.
            </para>
            <para>There are at least three reservoirs on trucks with the FMVSS 121 brake system: supply, secondary and
                primary. The primary reservoir is the air source for the rear brakes. The front brakes are supplied by
                the secondary air tank. In some instances, the supply reservoir and secondary reservoir may be the same
                tank with a separation inside (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400201" filename="../figg04/g0400201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Reservoir</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SUPPLY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DRAIN COCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. AUTOMATIC DRAIN VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Another function of a reservoir is to provide a place where the air, heated during compression, may
                cool and cause the oil and water vapors to condense.
            </para>
            <para>The combined volume of all service reservoirs and supply reservoirs is 12 times the combined volume of
                all service brake chambers at maximum travel of the pistons or diaphragms.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not change the size of the air tank(s). Alterations to production air brake systems must be
                        approved by International Engineering prior to alteration or operation.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
