<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - OPERATION - ANTILOCK SYSTEM OPERATION - COMPONENT FAILURE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ANTILOCK SYSTEM OPERATION - COMPONENT FAILURE</title>
        <para>The ECU handles equipment failure using a conservative fail-safe philosophy. Any single electrical failure
            of an antilock system component results in two events happening at the same time. The two events are:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The yellow antilock warning light on the instrument panel will illuminate to alert the
                driver that the system has detected a malfunction.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The ECU will disable all or part of the antilock system.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>When working with wheel equipment (modulator, wheel sensor/exciter ring or associated wire harness)
            failure, the ECU divides and separates the brakes diagonally. For example, if the modulator at the right
            front wheel has a broken wire lead, the ECU disables the antilock function for BOTH the right front and left
            rear wheels. The antilock will continue to function on the left front and right wheels and will continue to
            be controlled by the ECU.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Right and left, and front and rear are determined from the driver's seat position. Left front
                    would be the front corner closest to the driver.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Depending on the type of failure, and location of the failed component, the ECU will disable either the
            entire antilock system or only a portion of the antilock system, as previously described. An antilock system
            power failure (less than 10V) or failure of the ECU will cause the system to shut down, reverting to a
            standard braking system. Failure of two or more components will also cause the ABS system to shut down, and
            operate as a standard air brake system.
        </para>
        <para>With the failed component approach previously described, a partially shutdown antilock brake system will
            still provide improved braking stability over a standard air brake system.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>With a partially shutdown antilock brake system, the driver will be alerted by the instrument
                    panel warning light, and the portion of the antilock system disabled by the ECU reverts to a
                    standard air brake system controlled by the relay valve (rear axles) or brake valve (front axle).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
