<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - MAINTENANCE - BRAKE MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
        <title>BRAKE MAINTENANCE</title>
        <para>Lack of proper brake maintenance can be a contributing factor to brake complaints. Proper brake balance
            between tractor and trailer, and periodic inspection of push rod travel and brake adjustment are essential
            for effective braking.
        </para>
        <para>Inspect the brake lining every 12,000 miles (19,000 km) or every 12 months, whichever occurs first. When
            brake lining or blocks are worn to 1/4 inch (6.35mm) thickness on drive axle brakes or 3/16 inch (4.75mm)
            thickness on steering axle brakes, the brake lining must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>If the brake lining is satisfactory, adjust brakes one wheel at a time, with all drums in place and all
            slack adjusters connected to chambers.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A 15 inch Q Plus is now available in addition to the 15 inch Q brake. The 15 inch Q brake cannot
                    be converted to Q Plus because of the design difference in brake offset, bearing journals and cam
                    head profile. 16 1/2 inch Q brakes can be converted to the Q Plus design by changing the shoe and
                    lining assembly, camshaft and return spring. The differences between the Q Plus design and the Q
                    brake are illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400501">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f0400501" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400501" filename="../figg04/g0400501.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="562px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Identifying Rockwell Q Plus Brake Components</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>It is very important that a standard Q brake camshaft never be used with Q Plus brake shoes. Q
                    Plus brake shoes must be used with Q Plus camshafts. All Q Plus shoes and camshafts are marked with
                    "Q Plus" for easy identification. If Q Plus shoes are used with standard Q camshafts, there is a
                    possibility that the camshaft will "roll over" during brake application under certain operating
                    conditions. This could result in brake failure and possible personal injury. Also, a new brake drum
                    may not fit over the Q Plus brake shoes if the shoes are used with a standard Q brake camshaft.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The tamper resistant spring brake has been factory sealed for your protection. There are no
                    user-serviceable parts inside the spring brake chamber. If you experience any damage or failure to
                    the spring brake chamber, replace the complete assembly. Never attempt to disassemble the spring
                    brake chamber as serious personal injury or death could result from accidental sudden release of the
                    high energy spring.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
