<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - TRACTOR-TRAILER BRAKE ANALYSIS PROCEDURE - TEST PROCEDURES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="10">
        <title>TEST PROCEDURES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Before performing any of the test procedures which follow, record the preliminary data required on the
                Brake Test Data Sheet (Form CTS-1033H,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400816">Figure 16</hotlnk>). This data includes the owner's name, model, serial
                number, and GVWR for both the tractor and trailer. All of this information (except the owner's name) can
                be obtained from the certification labels.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400816" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400816" filename="../figg04/g0400816.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="574px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Brake Test Data Sheet</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Balance and Pressure Build-Up Test</title>
            <para>Conditions: This test is performed on the combination vehicle (tractor-trailer) with wheels blocked,
                parking brake released and air system fully charged.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect two test hoses to a duplex gauge.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the hoses from the duplex gauge to the combination vehicle as follows (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400817">Figure 17</hotlnk>):
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400817" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400817" filename="../figg04/g0400817.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="502px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. Test Connections-Single Trailer</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DUPLEX GAUGE OR SINGLE GAUGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DOUBLE GLADHAND ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. DUPLEX GAUGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. TRAILER SUPPLY CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. PARK BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">One hose to the left service brake chamber on the
                        <emph type="bold">tractor's</emph>
                        rearmost axle. The gauge reading from this connection will be used as a reference for comparing
                        pressure differences with other axles.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">The remaining hose to the left service chamber on the
                        <emph type="bold">trailer's</emph>
                        rearmost axle.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If unused chamber ports do not exist, it will be necessary to disconnect the service
                                brake hose, install a tee fitting between the service brake hose and chamber (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400818">Figure 18</hotlnk>), and then connect the test hose to the
                                remaining opening in the tee fitting.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="f0400818" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400818" filename="../figg04/g0400818.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 18. Test Gauge Hose Connection (At Service Brake Chamber)</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. SERVICE BRAKE HOSE</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. TEE FITTING</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. TEST LINE CONNECTION</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check pressure balance as follows:</emph>While observing the duplex gauge, slowly
                    apply the service brakes in increments of 5 psi from 5 to 30 psi (34 kPa from 34 to 207 kPa) and
                    increments of 20 psi from 30 to 90 psi (138 kPa from 207 to 621 kPa) respectively, as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400819">Figure 19</hotlnk>. As each pressure increment is reached at the
                    <emph type="bold">tractor's</emph>
                    rearmost axle, note and record the pressure reading for the
                    <emph type="bold">trailer's</emph>
                    rearmost axle. Repeat this step three times.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400819" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400819" filename="../figg04/g0400819.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19. Brake Test Application Pressures</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When applying the brakes, air pressure must be increased steadily and maintained at each
                            step. Any slight decrease in pressure will affect the accuracy of the gauge readings and
                            must be avoided. Note and record the pressure only after all gauge recordings are
                            stabilized.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <para>Under normal conditions, the average pressure variance between axles through the pressure range as
                tested should not exceed 4 psi (28 kPa) for optimum performance. The exception will be steering axle
                chambers controlled by automatic limiting valves. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04008_19.xml" xrefid="hl0400804">DATA INTERPRETATION AND CORRECTIVE MEASURES</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Check pressure build-up rate as follows:</emph>
                    While observing the duplex gauge, apply the service brake control moderately to at least 30 psi (207
                    kPa). The moderate rate of application should simulate that used in day-to-day braking under normal
                    operating conditions. Observe and record the pressure difference between the hands on the test gauge
                    dial (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400820">Figure 20</hotlnk>). The dual pressure readings give an indication of the
                    timing difference between the axles. If the pressure build-up in the trailer brakes leads the
                    tractor brakes, the gauge reading should be recorded as a positive (+) number. If the pressure
                    build-up lags, the reading should be recorded as a negative (-) number. Release the service brakes.
                    Repeat this step at least three times and record the average of the total readings.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400820" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400820" filename="../figg04/g0400820.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Gauge Reading-Pressure Balance Check</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Initial pressure difference (lead or lag) between axles should normally be no greater than 10 psi
                    (69 kPa) for single- trailer combinations before the pressures begin to equalize.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Since pressure lead and lag derived from using a duplex test gauge are estimates only,
                        pressure build-up rate tests involving large fleets of vehicles can be performed more easily and
                        accurately using pneumatic timing devices. These instruments are available from PDC. The above
                        check, however, will provide an indication if slow pressure build-up rate is a cause for
                        compatibility complaints.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If
                    <emph type="bold">pressure balance</emph>
                    and/or
                    <emph type="bold">pressure build-up</emph>
                    rate differences between axles exceed the acceptable limit(s), refer to the
                    <hotlnk document="s04008_19.xml" xrefid="hl0400804">DATA INTERPRETATION AND CORRECTIVE MEASURES
                        SECTION
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Multiple Trailers</title>
            <para>The Pressure Balance and Pressure Build-up Rate Test also can be used for checking combination
                vehicles with multiple trailers. One duplex test gauge is installed as described in the test procedure
                to read brake pressures at the rearmost axles of the tractor and the first trailer. A second duplex test
                gauge is installed to read pressure at the dolly axle and the rearmost axle of the second trailer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400821">Figure 21</hotlnk>). Two additional air hoses may be required to make the
                gauge connections at the second trailer in order to keep both duplex gauges at one observation point.
                The test is then conducted as described, noting and recording the pressure differentials and build-up
                times obtained from the four sources - the rearmost axles of the tractor and first trailer, and the
                dolly axle and rearmost axle of the second trailer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400821" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400821" filename="../figg04/g0400821.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Test Connections-Multiple Trailers</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DUPLEX GAUGE OR SINGLE GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DOUBLE GLADHAND ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DOLLY AXLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DUPLEX GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TRAILER EMERGENCY BRAKE SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. TRAILER SERVICE BRAKE SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. TRAILER SUPPLY CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. PARK BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Multiple-trailer combinations and their related complexity make it difficult to establish positive
                criteria. However, meeting the following guidelines should help optimize performance. For the
                <emph type="bold">pressure balance</emph>
                check, the average pressure difference between axles through the pressure range tested should fall
                within 4 psi (28 kPa) for optimum performance.
            </para>
            <para>For the
                <emph type="bold">pressure build-up rate</emph>check, the maximum pressure difference (lead or lag)
                between axles should normally be no greater than 15 psi (103 kPa) before the pressures equalize.
            </para>
            <para>Again, if the pressure balance and/or pressure build-up rate differences exceed the acceptable
                limit(s), refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s04008_19.xml" xrefid="hl0400804">DATA INTERPRETATION AND CORRECTIVE MEASURES
                    SECTION
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Balance Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the pressure difference recorded for the pressure balance check exceeds the acceptable
                        limit, the imbalance must be corrected before a Torque Balance Test is performed. However, if
                        the pressure build-up rate indicates a problem condition, the Torque Balance Test can and should
                        be conducted, especially if the operator's basic concern is that of uneven lining wear between
                        tractor and trailer.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount a decelerometer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400822">Figure 22</hotlnk>) to the inside of windshield as follows:
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400822" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400822" filename="../figg04/g0400822.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Test Instrumentation (In-Cab)</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. DECELEROMETER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. DUPLEX AIR GAUGE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Moisten the vacuum cups and press the decelerometer assembly to the windshield so it
                        can be read by the observer.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the bracket lower clamp nut and adjust the decelerometer so that its sides
                        are parallel to the direction of travel, then tighten the clamp nut.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the side adjusting clamp nut and adjust the vertical position so that the
                        fluid registers zero when the truck is on level ground, then tighten the clamp nut.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the single or duplex air test gauge (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400822">Figure 22</hotlnk>) and connections as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the double gladhand assembly in the tractor to trailer service line (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400823">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0400823" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400823" filename="../figg04/g0400823.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 23. Double Gladhand Assembly Installation</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. DOUBLE GLADHAND ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. TRAILER SERVICE BRAKE CONNECTION</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. TO DUPLEX AIR GAUGE</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. TRACTOR SERVICE BRAKE CONNECTION</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. TRACTOR EMERGENCY BRAKE CONNECTION</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mount the single or duplex test gauge in the cab so it can be seen by both the
                        driver and the observer.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect an air hose between the double gladhand assembly and the gauge.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Secure the air hose to the vehicle so that it will not snag when the vehicle is
                        turned (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400824">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0400824" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400824" filename="../figg04/g0400824.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 24. Gauge Test Hose Routing</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. AIR HOSE BETWEEN DOUBLE GLADHAND ASSEMBLY AND DUPLEX AIR GAUGE</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. NYLON TIE STRAP</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the following Preliminary Data (vehicle information) on the Data Sheet
                    (CTS-1033H) before initiating the test:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Typical Weight (estimated) for normal maximum highway operation.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Test Weight (actual axle weight or best estimate). The vehicle should be loaded to
                        the extent that wheel lockup will not occur with a 40 psi (276 kPa) brake application at a test
                        speed of 40 mph (64 kmh).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Initial Test Speed - if the recommended 40 mph (64 kmh) is not permitted in the area
                        chosen for the test, the test speed for the snubs can be reduced to 30 mph. Whatever speed is
                        used, it should be the same for each of the checks noted below.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the brake torque output of the tractor and trailer in combination and individually
                    as follows:
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>An observer should be used to record all data for these tests. Only the SUSTAINED
                            decelerometer readings should be recorded and not the peak readings at the beginning and end
                            of each step.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tractor-Trailer Combination Torque Output</para>
                    <para>The initial step in evaluating the performance of a tractor-trailer is to determine whether
                        the combination is capable of operating at its designed performance level.
                    </para>
                    <para>While operating the tractor-trailer combination in a suitable test area, make three (3) stops
                        from 40 mph (64 kmh) at 40 psi (276 kPa) brake application pressure. Record the sustained
                        deceleration reading (to the nearest .5 ft./sec.&#178;) for each stop in the appropriate space
                        on the Data Sheet.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Run three tests each at 15 and 40 psi control line pressure to establish average
                        decel at each pressure level. If at 15 psi control pressure, both tractor and trailer run
                        separately fail to produce 1.0 decel, advance to 20 psi. Tests include total combination,
                        tractor only, trailer only. Total of tractor only plus trailer only should be within
                        <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                        1 decel of combination at 40 psi. Tests using pressure of 20 and 30 psi may be conducted as
                        optional steps.
                    </para>
                    <para>Determine the average for the three readings.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Tractor Torque Output</para>
                    <para>With the service brakes released,
                        <emph type="bold">close</emph>
                        the shut-off cock in the double gladhand connection between the tractor and trailer.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Since closing the shut-off cock makes the trailer service brakes inoperative, allow
                                more distance for stopping the combination vehicle. If possible, use a non-public area
                                for conducting the test.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Again, operate the tractor-trailer combination, this time using the tractor brakes only to
                        make three (3) stops from 40 mph (64 kmh) at 40 psi (276 kPa) brake application pressure. Record
                        the decelerometer readings on the Data Sheet; determine and record the average reading.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Trailer Torque Output</para>
                    <para>With the service brakes released, open the shut-off cock in the double gladhand assembly.
                    </para>
                    <para>Again, operate the tractor-trailer combination and, using only the trailer hand control valve
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0400825">Figure 25</hotlnk>), make three stops from 40 mph (64 kmh) at 40 psi
                        (276 kPa) and record the readings and average on the Data Sheet.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0400825" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g0400825" filename="../figg04/g0400825.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 25. Trailer Hand Control Valve</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>NOTE - It may be helpful to preload the trailer air lines for smooth brake application and
                        more accurate test results. This is accomplished by maintaining vehicle speed while lightly
                        applying the hand control valve just prior to the test stop.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add the average deceleration reading for the tractor to the average deceleration reading
                    for the trailer.
                </para>
                <para>The sum should be within
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    .5 ft./sec.&#178; of the average deceleration reading obtained from the
                    <emph type="bold">combination</emph>
                    test. If not, the individual tractor and trailer torque output tests must be rerun.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Evaluating the Performance of Tractor and Trailer</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the test results, compute the Balance Ratio using the following formula:</para>
                <verbatim>
                    <line>Balance Ratio =</line>
                    <line>Typical Tractor Weight/Typical Trailer Weight X</line>
                    <line>Average Trailer Deceleration Rate/Average Tractor Deceleration Rate</line>
                </verbatim>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Typical Weights in the formula are those weights normally being carried by the vehicle. If
                            a realistic estimate cannot be made, it is recommended that the tractor and trailer (with
                            typical load) be weighed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record the Balance Ratio on the Data Sheet</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the balance ratio is 1.00, the tractor-trailer combination is in ideal torque
                        balance.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the balance ratio is below 0.75, the combination unit is out of balance and the
                        tractor is providing more than its share of braking efforts.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If the balance ratio is above 1.25, the trailer is providing more than its share of
                        braking efforts.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
