<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: MIDLAND MODELS EL-1300 AND EL-1600 - DISASSEMBLE - CRANKSHAFT AND BEARINGS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CRANKSHAFT AND BEARINGS</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>On compressors that have sleeve (bushing) type bearings, if visual inspection shows that the
                    crankshaft and/or bearing (bushing) is damaged, replace the compressor.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Do not remove crankshaft and bearings from crankcase unless an inspection reveals the necessity
                    for removal.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>The following procedure is for compressors with ball bearing type crankshaft bearings.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the four crankshaft bearing cap bolts on each bearing cap and remove caps. Discard
                gaskets.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the shaft seal from front bearing cap and discard seal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove seal and bowed washer or spring from rear bearing cap.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place crankcase-crankshaft-bearing assembly in an arbor press, supporting crankcase adjacent
                to rear bearing. Use an adapter as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401112">Figure 12</hotlnk>and press crankshaft rear bearing and crank assembly from
                crankcase.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401112" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401112" filename="../figg04/g0401112.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Crankshaft and Bearings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.ADAPTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.BEARING CRANKSHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.CRANKCASE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4.CRANKSHAFT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With rear bearing free from case, use a bearing puller and pull rear bearing from
                crankshaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove crankshaft with front bearing out through bottom of case.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use bearing puller and remove front bearing.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
