<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - TRACTOR-TRAILER BRAKE ANALYSIS PROCEDURE - DATA INTERPRETATION AND CORRECTIVE
        MEASURES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0400804" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DATA INTERPRETATION AND CORRECTIVE MEASURES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>After the test, the data needs to be interpreted. Guidelines and concepts are provided below but it
                must be recognized that values which are acceptable depend on many factors. These factors include
                terrain, weather, operator and fleet preference, maintenance, and the tractor and trailer foundation
                brake and vehicle characteristics as well as the interrelationship of pressure balance, pressure
                build-up rate and torque balance.
            </para>
            <para>Also, it must be remembered that data taken on one vehicle combination may or may not be
                representative of other units in a fleet.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Balance</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Combination Units</emph>
                - A 4 psi (28 kPa) or less pressure differential is generally acceptable between the tractor rearmost
                axle and the trailer rearmost axle. Some users prefer to have a slightly higher pressure at the trailer
                than at the tractor. This may require special valves on the tractor.
            </para>
            <para>For combinations involving multiple trailers, it is the preference of some operators to have lower
                pressure in the dolly axle brake chambers than at other axle brake chambers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Individual Valves</emph>
                - If the pressure differential between the tractor and trailer brake chambers exceeds the above
                guidelines, the system should be checked for pressure drops across individual valves. This is
                accomplished by connecting air lines from the duplex test gauge to the inlet and outlet ports of the
                individual valves and checking the variation of input to output pressures at 5 psi (34 kPa) increments
                up to 30 psi (207 kPa).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Combination Unit Overview</title>
            <para>The vast majority of brake applications are made at less than 30 psi (207 kPa). Due to this fact,
                minimizing pressure differentials between the tractor and trailer(s) brake chambers becomes very
                important if each axle is to do its share of braking the combination. For example, if on a specific
                brake application the drive axle receives 15 psi (103 kPa) and the trailer axle(s) only 8 psi (55 kPa),
                then the tractor brakes could be doing almost 50% more work in slowing the combination than the trailer
                brakes. Therefore, minimizing the pressure differentials on the trailer axle(s) is very important to
                optimize performance, wear and stability.
            </para>
            <para>It is extremely difficult to obtain exactly the same pressure on all axles due to the additional
                valves used on each of the trailer axles. However, controlling differentials and maintaining them within
                the 4 psi (28 kPa) noted earlier is important.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A point to remember is that the newer vehicles have good aerodynamic design and up-to-date
                        technology on engine design. Also, the new designs and gear ratios on transmissions and
                        differentials, not to mention the different types of lubricants, including synthetic lubricant
                        all affect the vehicle when braking. The braking system has to work a lot harder with all these
                        vehicle advancements than it did in the past. These factors should be considered when doing a
                        brake test.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Build-Up Rate (Timing)</title>
            <para>Tractors and trailers built since 1975 are required to meet FMVSS-121 application and release timing
                requirements. However, meeting these requirements does not insure timing compatibility. Evaluating the
                time it takes to build up pressure in the various axle brake chambers and the time to exhaust this
                pressure from these chambers takes sophisticated equipment normally not available to the user. If such a
                check is desired, the vehicle manufacturer should be contacted.
            </para>
            <para>However, a general comparison of the pressure build-up rates in the tractor and trailer chambers can
                be checked by the procedure noted earlier. This check will give you an indication if the pressure
                build-up differential between the tractor and trailer is reasonable. Usually, there will be a difference
                (the trailer will usually be slower) due to the added piping and valves required to actuate the trailer
                brakes. Minimizing this difference is important in achieving combination compatibility. As noted
                earlier, maintaining this lag to 10 psi (69 kPa) or less should be the objective.
            </para>
            <para>If the Pressure Build-Up Rate Test indicates the lag is not within the 10 psi (69 kPa) guideline, the
                system should be checked for restrictions in the lines and hoses, damaged fittings, or incorrect lines
                or fitting sizes. If no problem is noted, the individual valves should be checked for contamination
                and/or failed components.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Balance</title>
            <para>Normally, acceptable combination unit performance can be achieved with a tractor- trailer balance
                ratio of between .75 and 1.25.
            </para>
            <para>If these guidelines are exceeded, the modifications to consider include:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If ratio is less than .75</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Increase the power of the trailer brakes - or</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Decrease the power of the tractor brakes.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If ratio is greater than 1.25</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Decrease the power of the trailer brakes - or</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Increase the power of the tractor brakes</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>A tractor-trailer combination (with each axle loaded to its GAWR) that meets the
                                performance criteria for pressure balance and timing, and torque balance should also
                                reach a 9-1/2 + 1 ft./sec.&#178; deceleration (minimum) without any wheel lock from 40
                                mph (64 kmh) at 40 psi (276 kPa).
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Common causes of torque imbalance or lack of combination unit performance include:</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use of replacement parts, particularly linings, other than those originally specified.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tractor and/or trailer brake torque output(s) not compatible with the loads being
                    carried.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lining contamination, poorly maintained brakes, and broken or malfunctioning brake
                    components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Brakes out of adjustment.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>The trailer and/or tractor manufacturer should be consulted for any modifications to the respective
                trailer and/or tractor system that would cause deviation from the original specification.
            </para>
            <para>The following test procedure and criteria are intended to supplement the preceding combination vehicle
                brake analysis procedure. The use of electronic test equipment and real world operating conditions have
                been taken into consideration in the scope of the changes and additions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
