<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - SYSTEM AND COMPONENT OPERATION - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock System Operation Overview</title>
            <para>During a brake stop, the maximum point of deceleration occurs just before wheel lockup. When wheel
                lockup occurs, stopping distances increase and loss of directional control may occur.
            </para>
            <para>To reduce wheel lockup, the antilock brake system monitors the rotational speed of the wheels using
                sensors mounted on the axle ends and exciter rings mounted on the wheel assemblies.
            </para>
            <para>When the wheels rotate, an AC voltage pulse is generated by the sensors that is transmitted to the
                electronic control unit (EC-15) which is part of the CR-15 relay valve/ECU assembly. The EC-15 monitors
                the pulse rates. During a brake application, if a wheel(s) is about to lock up, the EC-15 sends a signal
                to the appropriate M-21 modulator valve(s).
            </para>
            <para>Within a fraction of a second, the modulator valve responds by repeatedly exhausting air from the
                brake chamber(s) allowing the wheel(s) to speed up, and then automatically applying air (much like a
                driver pumping the brakes manually). The antilock system only operates when the EC-15 determines that a
                wheel is about to lock up.
            </para>
            <para>A warning light on the instrument panel illuminates when the EC-15 detects a problem with the system.
                If the vehicle includes an engine brake, the EC-15 will dis-engage the engine brake when it senses a
                wheel lockup is about to occur.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Four-Channel System (Code 04AZA)</title>
            <para>The four-channel antilock brake system controls the rear axle brakes (both axles with 6x4) and the
                front (steering) axle. Wheel sensors are installed at each rear wheel (with 4x2), or with a 6x4, on one
                rear axle (one on each wheel end), and one sensor on each front axle wheel end.
            </para>
            <para>The front axle has an M-21 modulator valve for each wheel, so that each front wheel/brake assembly is
                independently controlled by the CR-15 Relay Valve/ECU. The rear axle has separate a M-21 modulator valve
                for the right and left side of the vehicle. With a 6x4, the left modulator valve would control the
                forward rear and rear rear axle brakes on the left side, and the right side modulator valve controls the
                right forward rear and rear rear brakes. The CR-15 Relay Valve/ECU controls both front M-21 modulator
                valves and the two M-21 modulator valves for the rear axle(s).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04022.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
