<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - EC-30 SELF-CONFIGURATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EC-30 SELF-CONFIGURATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The self-configuration feature allows wheel speed sensor and ATC configurations to be altered when
                activated with a magnet or diagnostic tool. This is generally performed shortly after installing or
                replacing an EC-30.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Self-Configuration of Wheel Speed Sensors</title>
            <para>The number of speed sensors connected to the EC-30 will be detected during the self-configuration
                process. The EC-30 will configure for six sensors if it detects one or both Mid sensors. If only one Mid
                sensor is detected, the ABS warning lamp and appropriate diagnostic LEDs will illuminate following the
                self-configure. If no Mid sensors are detected, the EC-30 will configure for four sensors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Self-Configuration of ATC</title>
            <para>In order to self-configure for engine torque limiting ATC, the following must be connected to the
                EC-30 and be operational:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>J1939 or J1922 communication link to the engine</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ATC active/warning lamp</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>ATC enable/disable switch (must be toggled prior to self- configuration)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>In order to self-configure for differential braking ATC, the ATC modulator must also be connected to
                the EC-30 and be operational.
            </para>
            <para>Some EC-30 part numbers will not support six wheel speed sensors or ATC. To insure that the EC-30 you
                are working with has the correct hardware capability, use only the correct replacement part number.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>EC-30 Self-Configuration Procedure</title>
            <para>Verify that all ECU, communication, sensor, ABS modulator and ATC modulator connectors are in place
                and then turn the ignition power on. Toggle the ATC enable/disable switch, if equipped.
            </para>
            <para>Activate an EC-30 self-configuration by one of the following actions:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Hold a magnet on the reset location of the diagnostic display for about 20 seconds (until the
                        LEDs begin to rapidly flash), then remove the magnet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Press the DCI reset switch for about 20 seconds (until the LEDs begin to rapidly flash), then
                        release the switch.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use the self-configuration menu selection on ACom for Windows or the MPSI tool.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When the self-configuration process is complete, the EC-30 will automatically go through the power-up
                sequence and show the new configuration on the diagnostic display. If the EC-30 was properly configured
                for ATC, the ATC active/ warning lamp will also show the ATC configuration. Refer to the EC-30 Power-Up
                Sequence section.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
