<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATIONAL CHECKS OF SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - DETAILED OPERATIONAL CHECK OF
        TRAILER SUPPLY AND PARK BRAKE SYSTEMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DETAILED OPERATIONAL CHECK OF TRAILER SUPPLY AND PARK BRAKE SYSTEMS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Modular (Push-Pull) Control Val ve</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use two air test gauges 0-160 psi (0-1103 kPa) or Duplex gauge with hoses and two
                    additional trailer couplings (service and emergency); attach the gauges to service and emergency
                    couplings on vehicle. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04008_21.xml" xrefid="hl0400803">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the trailer supply knob (red) and parking brake knob (yellow) out, charge primary
                    and secondary air systems to 65 psi (448 kPa). Push red knob in. The red knob should remain in; air
                    pressure at the instrument panel and the test gauge at the trailer emergency port should read
                    approximately the same. The test gauge at the service connection should show no pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push yellow knob in and apply foot valve to deplete air supply. The red knob should pop
                    out when the reservoir with the highest pressure reaches 40
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (276
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa). The red knob could pop immediately if air is depleted quickly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply foot valve to further deplete air pressure. Air should escape the exhaust port of
                    the trailer supply portion of the valve. When air pressure in the reservoir with the higher pressure
                    reaches 30
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (207
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa), the yellow knob may pop out (park brake application).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Deplete the air system even further using foot valve. At 25
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    5 psi (172
                    <emph type="underscr">+</emph>
                    34.5 kPa), the yellow knob must pop out (park brake application).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rebuild air supply to at least 40 psi (276 kPa) and push yellow knob in. It should
                    remain in.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push red knob in and pull yellow knob out. The red knob must pop out almost
                    instantaneously.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rebuild air supply to 100-125 psi (689- 861 kPa) in both primary and secondary
                    reservoirs. Push red and yellow knobs in. Pressure at the trailer emergency connection should equal
                    the pressure in the primary reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reduce air pressure in the primary reservoir. Pressure at the trailer emergency
                    connection should descend to 105-90 psi (724-621 kPa), at which point the double check valve in the
                    modular control valve should switch to the secondary reservoir, and pressure at the emergency
                    connection should adjust (equalize) to the secondary reservoir pressure. Close off leak at the
                    primary reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the red knob in and the hand control valve released, apply brake valve. Pressure at
                    the trailer service should be within 5 psi (34.5 kPa) of the gauge at the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replenish air system to 100-125 psi (689-861 kPa). Slowly vent the secondary reservoir
                    pressure with yellow knob in. As the secondary pressure and trailer emergency pressure descend,
                    between 115-105 psi (793-724 kPa) the double check shuttle in the valve should switch to the primary
                    reservoir and the pressure should adjust to the primary reservoir pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the red knob pushed in, disconnect the trailer emergency coupling from the test
                    gauge. The red knob should pop out instantaneously. If the red knob pops out, reconnect the trailer
                    emergency coupling to gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replenish air in system. With the red knob in, apply the hand control valve. There
                    should be a minimum of 85 psi (586 kPa) at the trailer service gauge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release hand control valve and apply foot valve. Pressure at the service port should be
                    within 5 psi (34.5 kPa) of the pressure indicated at the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all vents or leakage points and charge system to 100-125 psi (689-861 kPa). Apply
                    brake foot valve, pull red knob out (yellow knob in).
                </para>
                <para>The air gauge connected to the service connection should record the same value (100-125 psi or
                    689-861 kPa) as the gauge at the instrument panel. The gauge at the emergency connection should
                    indicate "0."
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With red knob out and yellow knob in, develop a leak in the parking (spring) brake
                    delivery (line) and hold yellow knob in. The primary reservoir pressure must reduce to zero and
                    secondary reservoir pressure to 20-30 psi (138-207 kPa). The double check valve in the modular
                    control should cycle several times during the leak down period.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the foregoing checks perform as described, the chassis is ready for service. Remove air test gauges
                from trailer couplings. If the operational checks revealed malfunctions within the system, a more
                detailed investigation of components will be required. For detailed information regarding service checks
                on various components, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS- 5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
