<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Bosch Parking Brake: Manual or Power Brake - BRAKE SHOE ADJUSTMENT and Inspection</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BRAKE SHOE ADJUSTMENT and Inspection</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, serious personal injury or possibly death, work on a flat, level
                    surface. Use wheel chocks.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, serious personal injury or possibly death, do not work under or around a
                    vehicle supported by a mechanical or hydraulic jack. Vehicle must be supported by suitable floor
                    stands.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other operations. Always wear a
                    respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service procedures. NEVER use compressed air
                    or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies. OSHA recommends that you use cylinders that
                    enclose the brake. These cylinders have vacuums with high efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm
                    sleeves. But, if such equipment is not available, carefully clean parts and assemblies in the open
                    air.
                </para>
                <para>Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly, carefully place all parts on
                    the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use an industrial vacuum cleaner with a HEPA filter
                    system to clean dust from the brake drums, backing plates and other brake parts. After using the
                    vacuum, remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <caution>
                <para>Keep grease and other foreign materials away from the shoe lining and drum surfaces. Contamination
                    of shoe linings or drum may result in degradation of brake linings.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>For complete adjustment and inspection service procedures, go to the Bosch USA website from the ISIS
            Suppliers listing and refer to the 305 x 76 Park Brake Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>
            <exhotlnk document="http://rb-kwin.bosch.com/en-na/pool/en/pdfs/Park_Brake_Service_Manual.pdf"
                      bookname="EXTERNAL">http://rb-kwin.bosch.com/en-na/pool/en/pdfs/Park_Brake_Service_Manual.pdf
            </exhotlnk>
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04044_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04044_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04044.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
