<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - EC-15 CONTROLLER (ECU) - REMOVE AND INSTALL EC-15 CONTROLLER
        (ECU)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVE AND INSTALL EC-15 CONTROLLER (ECU)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before disconnecting ANY electrical circuits in the antilock system, the ignition key must be
                        OFF. If the key is not OFF, the EC-15 will record the open circuit(s) as a fault.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal - ECU Mounted On Antilock Relay Valve</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Identify and remove all air lines connected to the unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Identify and disconnect the electrical connector(s) from the ECU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and mark the mounting position of the Controller/Relay valve assembly on the
                    vehicle. Loosen, remove and save the mounting hardware attaching the CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15
                    Controller assembly bracket to the vehicle. Remove the CR-15 Relay Valve/EC-15 Controller assembly
                    from the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any dirt, grease, etc. from the cover of the ECU assembly.
                    <emph type="bold">Make sure you protect the open ports and connectors.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note and mark the position of the ECU controller relative to the antilock relay valve.
                    Remove and keep the four capscrews that secure the ECU to the antilock relay valve. Carefully
                    separate the ECU from the antilock relay valve making sure you don't damage the gasket between the
                    two components. Peel the gasket from the the ECU or relay valve and keep for reuse (NOTE: Use a new
                    gasket if the old gasket is damaged or if a new gasket is readily available).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation - EC-15 (ECU) Mounted On Relay Valve</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After noting the relationship of the positioning marks made prior to disassembly,
                    position the gasket on the ECU, then secure the ECU to the antilock relay valve using the four
                    capscrews. Torque the capscrews to 50-80 lbs. in. (5.6-9.0 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the assembled ECU and antilock relay valve on the vehicle and orient it in the
                    position marked prior to removal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the air lines (as marked in removal) to the relay valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical connectors (as marked during removal) to the ECU.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the antilock relay valve for operation and leakage prior to placing the vehicle in
                    service.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the "Initial Startup Procedure" in the Troubleshooting Section to assure proper
                    antilock system operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
