<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATION - ANTILOCK (ABS) BRAKING MODE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="3">
        <title>ANTILOCK (ABS) BRAKING MODE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ABS braking mode is entered from the Normal braking mode when the ECU determines that a wheel is
                about to lock up. During braking, in addition to monitoring the MC brake light switch, the ECU monitors
                the wheel speed sensors located at each of the 4 wheel ends. An ABS event occurs when the brake pedal is
                pressed and the ECU determines, from the sensor signals, that a wheel is about to lock up.
            </para>
            <para>During an ABS event the ECU controls the ABS operation by energizing and de-energizing the solenoid
                controlled valves that route the brake fluid to the wheel end calipers. The valve coils are contained in
                the ECU assembly, while the valve cores are part of the HCU assembly. The wheels can enter the ABS mode
                independently. If one wheel is attempting to lock, it will operate in the ABS mode while the other 3
                wheels continue to operate in the Normal braking mode.
            </para>
            <para>While in the ABS mode the ECU adjusts the brakeforce, at the wheel being controlled, by electronically
                cycling through 3 stages several times a second. This essentially prevents the wheel(s) from locking up
                by modulating brake pressure for that wheel. The 3 ABS stages are: Decrease Pressure, Hold, and Increase
                Pressure. Once in the ABS mode, the system remains in that mode until either: the brake pedal is
                released (indicated by MC brake light switch); or, the wheel speed sensors no longer indicate a probable
                lock up condition.
            </para>
            <para>In the event of an ABS system malfunction, the ABS function may remain partially operational. The
                level of ABS functionality during a malfunction depends on the type and location of the malfunction.
                Refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04050_HL04050500.xml" xrefid="hl04050500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                for more information.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Decrease Pressure Stage</title>
            <para>In the first stage of an ABS event, the ECU enters the Decrease Pressure stage. In this stage the ECU
                switches the 'normally open' inlet valve for the affected wheel to the closed state. In addition, the
                'normally closed' outlet valve is switched to the open state. This action decreases the brake fluid
                pressure applied to the wheel caliper, allowing the wheel to recover (continue rotating). The closed
                inlet valve isolates the caliper from the pressurized brake fluid in the accumulator. The open outlet
                valve allows the pressurized brake fluid in the caliper to return to the HCU reservoir.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405020">Figure 20</hotlnk>
                shows the hydraulic system while operating in the ABS Decrease Pressure stage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405020" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405020" filename="../figg04/G0405020a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 20. Brake Fluid Routing - ABS Decrease Pressure Stage</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Hold Stage</title>
            <para>In the second stage the ECU keeps the 'normally open' inlet valve for the affected wheel in the closed
                state. Meanwhile, the outlet valve for that wheel is returned to its 'normally closed' state. This
                action isolates the caliper of the affected wheel to maintain (hold) the brake fluid pressure in that
                caliper at its current level.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405021">Figure 21</hotlnk>
                shows the hydraulic system while operating in the ABS Hold stage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405021" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405021" filename="../figg04/G0405021a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Brake Fluid Routing - ABS Hold Stage</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Increase Pressure Stage</title>
            <para>In the third stage of an ABS event, the ECU enters the Increase Pressure stage. In this stage the ECU
                switches both the inlet and outlet valves, for the affected wheel, back to their 'normal' states. With
                the inlet valve open and the outlet valve closed, the brake fluid pressure applied to the wheel caliper
                will increase according to the pressure placed on the brake pedal. The pressurized brake fluid in the
                accumulator will be routed through the relay valve and inlet valve to the caliper, increasing braking
                force now that lock up has been prevented.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405022">FIGURE 22</hotlnk>
                shows the hydraulic system while operating in the ABS Increase Pressure stage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405022" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405022" filename="../figg04/G0405022a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Brake Fluid Routing - ABS Increase Pressure Stage</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04050.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
