<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROL RELAY VALVE: BENDIX ATR-2 - OPERATION - TRACTION CONTROL - SERVICE APPLICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TRACTION CONTROL - SERVICE APPLICATION</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403109">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403109" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403109" filename="../figg04/g0403109.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Traction Control - Service Application</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>While under the control of an antilock traction controller, the ATR-2 solenoid is able to initiate a brake
            application that allows the traction system to control wheel spin upon acceleration under 25 mph. When wheel
            spin is detected and the vehicle is stopped, or moving at any speed up to 25 mph, the antilock traction
            controller instantly energizes the solenoid in the ATR-2 which then applies air to each of the rear axle
            modulators as shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403110">Figure 10</hotlnk>. The modulators are equipped with solenoid valves also and
            because they are also controlled by the controller, the solenoid valves in the appropriate modulator are
            opened and closed to gently pump the brake on the spinning wheel only. This gentle brake application forces
            the differential to drive the stationary or slowly spinning wheel.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403110" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403110" filename="../figg04/g0403110.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Typical Antilock - Traction System (partial)</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Reservoir air pressure is constantly present at the traction solenoid. When the electronic controller
            detects wheel spin, it energizes the solenoid and in response the solenoid opens momentarily. While the
            solenoid is open, air is delivered through internal passages to the double check valve. The check valve
            diaphragm flexes in response and seals the passage to the open exhaust of the brake valve. Once past the
            double check valve, air from the solenoid flows through the rest of the valve in the same manner as a normal
            service brake application and air is delivered out the delivery ports of the ATR-2.
        </para>
        <para>When the electronic controller de-energizes the solenoid, air between the solenoid and the double check
            valve returns to the solenoid and is exhausted. Air between the relay piston and double check valve is
            exhausted at the brake valve while delivery pressure is exhausted at the main ATR-2 exhaust port.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031_HL0403102.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04031.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
