<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION - ANTILOCK WARNING (INDICATOR)
        LIGHT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ANTILOCK WARNING (INDICATOR) LIGHT</title>
        <para>Refer to Circuit Diagram for this discussion.</para>
        <para>The antilock warning light is located on the instrument panel. When the vehicle is started, the "Initial
            Start-up Self Diagnostic Test" will be run. The test is fully explained in TROUBLESHOOTING. The yellow
            warning light also will turn on if, during operation, the ECU senses a system defect.
        </para>
        <para>The yellow instrument panel warning light and the warning light relay control coil receive ignition power
            from fuse F27. With the relay in the open position (relay de-activated), the ground for the warning light is
            completed and the light is turned on.
        </para>
        <para>The warning light relay control coil ground path is controlled by the ECU, which opens or closes the
            ground (activates or de-activates the relay) to turn the warning light ON or OFF. The warning light is ON
            whenever the relay is de-activated by the ECU.
        </para>
        <para>During the Self Diagnostic Test when starting the vehicle or if a failure occurs in the antilock system,
            the ECU opens the ground path for the warning light relay coil causing it to de-energize, turning on the
            yellow instrument panel warning light.
            <emph type="bold">If the antilock system is operating properly during normal operation, the lamp will not be
                on.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>The yellow antilock warning lamp, located on the instrument panel, receives ignition voltage from an
            in-line 10 amp fuse F27 through the cab harness to circuit 94D of the antilock cab harness. Voltage is
            present whenever the key switch is at IGN. The ground circuit to the warning light is circuit 94E through
            the warning light relay terminals 30 to 87A. The ground goes to circuits 94-G/11-G and ground at J1.
        </para>
        <para>When the warning light relay
            <emph type="bold">is not energized</emph>, the warning light will be on. Ignition voltage (the same source
            as the warning light) is present to the warning light relay control coil whenever the key switch is at IGN.
            The relay control coil ground circuit (94H) is connected through the cab and chassis harness to the ECU
            harness 14-pin connector at pin "K". The ECU opens (light ON) or closes (light OFF) the warning light relay
            in response to antilock system conditions as determined by the ECU.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
