<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - HAND CONTROL VALVE - BENDIX TC-7
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="2">
        <title>BENDIX TC-7</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The hand control valve is used for controlling the brakes on a trailer independently of the brakes on
                the towing vehicle. The valve is usually mounted on the steering column or on the dash and provides the
                operator with a graduated means of applying and releasing the brakes. The distance the brake handle is
                moved in a clockwise direction toward applied position determines the severity of the brake application.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not use the hand control valve to hold the brakes applied when the chassis is parked and
                        unattended. Air may leak from system and vehicle will move.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>When the handle is moved in a clockwise direction from the released position, force is exerted on top
                of the pressure regulating spring through the action of the cam and cam follower. The force on top of
                the spring causes the piston to move down. The exhaust seat in the center of the piston contacts the
                exhaust valve and closes the exhaust passage in the piston. At the same time the exhaust closes, the
                continued downward movement of piston moves the inlet valve off its seat. Air pressure from the
                reservoir then flows by the open inlet and out the delivery port, through the service line and applies
                the brakes (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400258">Figure 58</hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400258" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400258" filename="../figg04/G0400258.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 58. TC 7 Bendix Hand Control Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HANDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hold</title>
            <para>The air pressure that flows by the open inlet valve also becomes effective on the bottom area of the
                piston. As the force of the air pressure beneath the piston balances the force of the depressed
                graduating spring above, the piston lifts slightly and the inlet valve returns to its seat. The exhaust
                valve remains seated so the flow of air through the valve is stopped and air pressure in the service
                line is held.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Release</title>
            <para>When the handle or operating lever is moved in a counterclockwise direction, the force above the
                piston is decreased. The air pressure beneath will then lift the piston, moving it away from the exhaust
                valve. With the exhaust passage open, air pressure in the service line will exhaust out the exhaust port
                of the valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Every three months or 25,000 miles (40,000 km), the hand control valve should be checked for
                graduation and proper operation. The linkage or lever connections to the remote operated type valve
                should be checked and lubricated if required.
            </para>
            <para>Once each year or 100,000 miles (160,000 km), disassemble the hand control valve. Clean and inspect
                all parts. Disassemble and clean parts in mineral spirits. Replace all rubber parts and any part that is
                worn or damaged. Perform the
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400216">
                    <xref refid="hl0400216"/>SERVICE CHECKS
                </hotlnk>
                before placing vehicle in service.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400216">
            <title>Service Checks - Operations Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block the wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                        pressures, gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect an accurate test gauge to the delivery port or connect the gauge to the service
                    hose coupling of the tractor. When the gauge is connected to the service hose coupling, install a
                    dummy hose coupling on the supply (emergency) hose coupling and place tractor protection control in
                    the trailer charging position. When the handle is moved to the fully applied position, the test
                    gauge should register full reservoir pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move the handle between the released and fully applied positions and note that the air
                    pressure registered on the test gauge varies accordingly. Upon release, the test gauge should
                    immediately register zero.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Checks - Leakage Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the exhaust port and exhaust line fitting and apply a soap solution. With the
                    valve in released position, exhaust leakage should not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter soap bubble
                    in 5 seconds. With the valve fully applied, leakage at the exhaust should not exceed a 1 inch (25
                    mm) diameter soap bubble in 3 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repair or replace valve if it does not function as described or leakage is excessive.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply parking brake and block wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain air brake system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air lines at bottom of valve, including exhaust carry-off line if used.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove mounting clamp bolts, clamp and valve.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400259">Figure 59</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400259" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400259" filename="../figg04/G0400259.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 59. Midland-Ross Hand Control Valve - Disassembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. VALVE BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SEALING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FRICTION WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. CAM FOLLOWER</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SPECIAL LOCKWASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. ADJUSTING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. ADJUSTING RING ADAPTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. GRADUATING SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. INLET SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. INLET VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>If the valve is disassembled in a vise, be sure the vise is not over-tightened as the valve and
                internal parts can be distorted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the adjusting ring lockwasher (Item 8).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the adjusting ring (Item 10).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A spanner wrench should be used to rotate the adjusting ring. If a spanner wrench is not
                        available, the adjusting ring can be turned with a small screwdriver inserted in one of the
                        inner notches of the ring.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the retaining ring (Item 9).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove adjusting ring adapter (Item 11), cam follower (Item 7), sealing ring (Item 3),
                    and friction washer (Item 4).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is important to note whether the friction washer is installed with the ribs against or away
                        from the sealing ring, as it must be re-installed the same way.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cam (Item 12) and graduating spring (Item 13), piston (Item 14), and piston
                    return spring (Item 16).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a deep well 11/16 inch socket and remove the inlet and exhaust valve assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash all metal parts in mineral spirits and dry.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not use cleaning solvent.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all rubber parts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all parts for excessive wear or deterioration.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check springs for cracks, corrosion or distortion.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect valve seats and piston bore for nicks and burrs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all unserviceable parts.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <para>Prior to reassembly, lubricate the body cores, cam, cam followers, O-rings and O-ring grooves with a
                lubricant comparable to that listed in Item 3 of
                <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400209.xml" xrefid="hl0400209">
                    <xref refid="hl0400209"/>LUBRICATION SPECIFICATIONS
                </hotlnk>
                . Do not lubricate sealing ring, friction washer or cam follower serrations.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400259">Figure 59</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install O-ring (Item 18) on inlet and exhaust valve assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 11/16 inch deep well socket wrench, install the inlet and exhaust valve
                    assemblies and tighten to 15 in-lbs. (1.7 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install piston return spring (Item 16).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install O-ring (Item 15) on piston (Item 14) and install piston in valve body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install graduating spring (Item 13).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cam (Item 12) in valve body with flat side toward graduating spring (Item 13).
                    Line up cam "ears" to corresponding slots in valve body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rubber sealing ring (Item 3) on cam follower (Item 7).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the friction washer (Item 4) on cam follower in the same direction as noted in
                    Step 4 of Disassemble.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cam follower (Item 7).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Stop "ear" on cam follower (Item 7) will not permit improper assembly of cam follower. Make
                        certain that the positioning "ear" of the friction washer (Item 4) fits in the wide slot in the
                        valve body.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install O-ring (Item 5) in adjusting ring adapter (Item 11) and adjusting ring (Item
                    10).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install adjusting ring (Item 10) in adapter (Item 11) until it is flush with the
                    underside of the adapter.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>There are two indexing lugs on the adapter that fit into slots in the valve body when the
                            adapter is installed. Be sure to install the adjusting ring (Item 10) with its wrench slots
                            accessible (up) after the valve is assembled.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the adapter and adjusting ring assembly (Item 11) over the cam follower (Item
                    7), making certain the adapter lugs fit into the body slots.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push down on cam follower (Item 7) and install snap ring. Be certain the retaining ring
                    (Item 9) is completely seated in its groove.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If lugs on adapter are not in their body slots, the retaining ring (Item 9) cannot be
                        installed completely.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing the lockwasher (Item 8), adjust the valve.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjustment</title>
            <para>Generally, the TC-7 Brake Hand Control Valve should deliver full reservoir pressure.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the delivered pressure is below 125 psi, it can be adjusted by removing the handle,
                    loosening ring lockwasher and rotating the adjusting ring clockwise.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the delivered pressure is above 125 psi, it can be lowered by turning the adjusting
                    ring counterclockwise.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After adjustment is completed, tighten the lockwasher and install the valve handle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Handle position is not adjustable.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the air lines to the TC-7.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the valve to the steering column. Tighten the mounting screws to 30 to 60 in-lbs.
                    (3.39 to 6.78 N&#183; m).
                    <emph type="bold">Do not over-tighten.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform as outlined on page 90.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Chart</title>
            <table id="t0400207" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Torque Chart - Midland-Ross Hand Control Valve</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.62in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.73in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.71in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Location</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">In-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inlet and Exhaust Assemblies</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.7</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Valve Mounting Screws</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to 60</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3.39 to 6.78</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Value handle Screw</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30 to 60</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3.39 to 6.78</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Discharge Value Stem Locknut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5 to 7</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>.6 to .8</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cover Screws</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12 to 14</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.4 to 1.6</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_113.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_115.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
