<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAMONDLIFE&#8482; (BOSCH PIN SLIDE) DISC BRAKES For Vehicles Built After June 2, 2002 - MAINTENANCE - DISC
        BRAKE PADS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="3">
        <title>DISC BRAKE PADS</title>
        <para>There are three types of lining materials available for the hydraulic pin slide brake system. HX-7A1-EE
            brake pads and softer lining brake pads identified by lining code 7610 with smooth backing plates for heavy
            duty braking applications and HX-402-EE brake pads for light duty braking applications.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The HX-7A1-EE lining material of inboard disc brake pad
                    <hotlnk document="s04047_3.xml" xrefid="f0404703">(Item 1, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404703"/>
                    and outboard disc brake pad
                    <hotlnk document="s04047_3.xml" xrefid="f0404703">(Item 2, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404703"/>
                    are chamfered and are marked with an "ARROW" and the word "FORWARD" for proper installation. Brake
                    pads are NOT interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The optional HX-402-EE lining material of inboard and outboard disc brake pads
                    <hotlnk document="s04047_3.xml" xrefid="f0404703">(Item 3, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404703"/>
                    are NOT chamfered and ARE interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The optional SOFTER lining material of inboard and outboard disc brake pads
                    <hotlnk document="s04047_3.xml" xrefid="f0404703">(Item 3, Figure 3)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f0404703"/>
                    are NOT chamfered and ARE interchangeable from inboard to outboard side on the same wheel.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>To inspect disc brake pads for wear, position vehicle on suitable floor stands and remove wheel (tire and
            rim) assemblies.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>A jack must never be used alone to support a vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                    performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support vehicle with
                    suitable floor stands.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>Visually inspect the pad lining by checking each visible end and inspecting through openings of caliper.
            If lining thickness at the thinnest point appears to be 3/16 inch (4.76 mm) or less, the pads must be
            replaced
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404710">(Figure 10)</hotlnk>. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04047_X0404701.xml" xrefid="x0404701">Disc Brake Pads, Remove
                <xref refid="x0404701"/>
            </hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk document="s04047_X0404712.xml" xrefid="x0404712">Disc Brake Pads, Install
                <xref refid="x0404712"/>
            </hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <figure id="f0404710" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404010.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="472px"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Visually Inspect Pad Lining</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>A. 3/16 INCH (4.76 mm) OR LESS</callout1>
                <callout1>1. INBOARD DISC BRAKE PAD</callout1>
                <callout1>2. OUTBOARD DISC BRAKE PAD</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>It is recommended that all disc brake pads be replaced at the same time since this will maintain balanced
            braking of the vehicle. If complete replacement is not desirable or necessary, be sure that all disc brake
            pads on one axle (both sides) are replaced at the same time.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When replacing disc brake pads, be sure to use the same lining material type on both axles. Mixing
                    lining types can result in unbalanced braking and pad wear.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Disc brake pads should not be replaced only because of visual erosion or pitting. This is a normal
            characteristic of semi-metallic pad lining material. Should erosion reduce the polished contact area to less
            then 80% of total surface area, replace pads.
        </para>
        <para>Disc brake pads with lining material that shows excessive erosion at the edges or from the contact area
            with rotor
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404711">(Figure 11)</hotlnk>
            must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Pads must be replaced if an examination of disc brake pads reveals excessive chipping, flaking or severe
            cracks and 80% or less contact area with rotor.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0404711" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 11. Unserviceable Brake Pad</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404712">Figure 12</hotlnk>
            which illustrates two progressive conditions of pad to rotor contact. The polished contact area is
            represented in the illustration by the white area on the pad surface.
        </para>
        <para>The top view illustrates a new or like new pad with full contact with rotor. The bottom view shows a pad
            with 80% or less contact with rotor and must be replaced.
        </para>
        <para>Disc brake pads must be replaced if contaminated by oil, grease or other foreign material which cannot be
            easily removed with a clean rag.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0404712" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="392px"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Progressive Conditions Of Pad To Rotor Contact</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
