<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - ASSEMBLY - FINAL ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FINAL ASSEMBLY</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04004_19.xml" xrefid="f0400411">Figure 11</hotlnk>for numbers in parentheses.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the cylinder head gasket (19) on the crankcase land position the head on the crankcase
                as marked during disassembly. A gasket sealer is neither required or recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the cylinder head to the crankcase using the four cylinder head cap screws (11).
                Tighten the capscrews in an "X" pattern as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a thread sealant install all necessary pipe plugs and tighten as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install all crankshaft keys (30) making certain to support the crankshaft to avoid bearing
                damage. Install the crankshaft nut where applicable. When installing drive couplings, gears or pulleys,
                tighten the crankshaft nut (39) only as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. The self locking crankshaft
                nut used on the BX-2150 requires that it be installed so that the narrow castellation slots are toward
                the end of the crankshaft and not against the pulley, coupling or gear that the nut retains.
            </para>
            <para>Some BX-2150 through drive compressors require the installation of a spline coupling on the rear of
                the crankshaft. The cap screw securing the coupling should be tighten as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use covers, plugs, or masking tape to protect all ports if compressor is not to be installed
                immediately. Protect the ends of the crankshaft against damage by wrapping with masking tape or friction
                tape. The open bottom of a vertical engine lubricated compressors should be protected against the
                entrance of dirt during handling or storage, by installing a temporary cover over the base.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_37.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_39.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
