<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATION - PARK BRAKE OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="7">
        <title>PARK BRAKE OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The parking brake system employs a cable actuated, drum-style, driveline parking brake (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404830">FIGURE 30</hotlnk>). When tension is applied to the brake cable, brake shoes
                are expanded inside of the drum, effectively locking the drive wheels. When tension is removed from the
                brake cable, springs retract the brake shoes, releasing the drum and unlocking the drive wheels. Refer
                to manual
                <exhotlnk document="../s04/s04044.htm">S04044</exhotlnk>
                for more complete information on the driveline parking brake drum assembly.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404830" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404830" filename="../figg04/g0404830.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 30. Driveline Parking Brake</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ADJUSTMENT ACCESS WINDOW (DRUM MOUNTED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE SHOES (DRUM REMOVED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADJUSTING LEVER (DRUM REMOVED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. STAR WHEEL (DRUM REMOVED)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Powered Parking Brake</title>
            <para>The parking brake cable tension is controlled by a Spring Apply Hydraulic Release (SAHR) canister.
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404831">FIGURE 31</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048300.xml" xrefid="f0404821">FIGURE 21</hotlnk>
                , and
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048300.xml" xrefid="f0404822">FIGURE 22</hotlnk>
                . The state of the SAHR canister is hydraulically and electronically controlled by the HCU/ECU. The
                other components of the powered parking brake system are: the dash switch, the Pressure Supply Valve
                (PSV), the Cut-Off Valve, and the Travel Switch. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404832">FIGURE 32</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404831" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404831" filename="../figg04/g0404816.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 31. Location of SAHR Canister and Related Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CONNECTION AT BRAKE CABLE UNION</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SAHR CANISTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CABLE ROUTING WITH ALTERNATE CROSSMEMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DRIVELINE PARKING BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404832" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404832" filename="../figg04/g0404832.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. SAHR Canister Components/Operation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RUBBER BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TRAVEL SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. OUTER SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. INNER SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. OUTPUT SHAFT END PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CYLINDER, PART OF MANIFOLD/CARTRIDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PISTON, PART OF MANIFOLD/CARTRIDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. CUT-OFF VALVE CORE, PART OF MANIFOLD/CARTRIDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CUT-OFF VALVE COIL</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. THREAD SAVER FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. MANIFOLD/CARTRIDGE ASSEMBLY (PISTON/CYLINDER)</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. SAHR MOUNTING STUD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The parking brake dash switch has three switch states (positions): apply (out), neutral (center), and
                release (in). The switch is spring-loaded to return to the neutral (center) position after either of the
                other positions is selected. A resistor network in the switch assembly allows the ECU to detect the
                position of the switch by sensing a change in the resistance value of the switch circuit. The resistor
                network also allows the ECU to detect malfunctions in the switch circuit.
            </para>
            <para>When the ECU detects the switch 'apply' actuation, it sets both the PSV and the cut-off valve to their
                non-energized states. When non-energized, the cut-off valve is normally open, and the PSV connects the
                SAHR brake line to the HCU reservoir (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404876">FIGURE 33</hotlnk>). This condition provides an open brake fluid connection
                between the SAHR canister and the HCU reservoir. With no pressurized fluid at the SAHR canister, the
                internal springs are used to retract the SAHR shaft, applying tension to the brake cable; which, in
                turn, applies the parking brake. The travel switch on the SAHR canister is used to indicate the shaft
                position to the ECU. If the shaft position does not indicate a properly applied parking brake, the ECU
                will generate a fault code and turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404876" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404876" filename="../figg04/g0404876a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Brake Fluid Routing - Park Brake Applied</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When the parking brake is released using the dash switch, the ECU electronically controls the PSV and
                the cut-off valve as follows. First, the PSV is energized to route brake fluid from the pressurized
                primary accumulator circuit to the SAHR canister. The cut-off valve remains non-energized (open) long
                enough for the pressurized brake fluid to overcome the force of the internal springs and extend the SAHR
                shaft (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404877">FIGURE 34</hotlnk>). Once the travel switch indicates that the shaft has
                extended, the ECU energizes (closes) the cut-off valve, preventing the pressurized brake fluid from
                leaving the SAHR canister. After a short delay the ECU returns the PSV to its non-energized state so
                that the parking brake line is again open to the HCU reservoir. This allows the parking brake line to be
                unpressurized even though the SAHR canister is pressurized (park brake released). Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404878">FIGURE 35</hotlnk>. With the SAHR shaft extended, the brake cable is no longer
                under tension and the parking brake is released. The travel switch on the SAHR canister is used to
                indicate the shaft position to the ECU. If the shaft position does not indicate a properly released
                parking brake, the ECU will generate a fault code and turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404877" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404877" filename="../figg04/g0404877a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Brake Fluid Routing - Releasing Park Brake (Step 1)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404878" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404878" filename="../figg04/g0404878a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Brake Fluid Routing - Park Brake Released (Step 2)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When the parking brake is in its released state (SAHR canister pressurized), small reductions of
                pressure may occur over a period of time. To prevent the pressure from dropping far enough to allow a
                partial parking brake application; the ECU commands the PSV and cut-off valve to repressurize the SAHR
                canister whenever the travel switch indicates that the SAHR shaft has moved beyond a preset limit. If
                system leakage requires the SAHR canister to be replenished too frequently, the HCU/ECU will enter the
                'backup mode' and generate a fault code. The 'backup mode' is described in the following paragraph. In
                this condition the HCU/ECU will also turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.
            </para>
            <para>The system has a safety function (backup mode) to ensure that the parking brake will not apply
                unexpectedly if the cut-off valve fails. When the cut-off valve fails it assumes its 'normally open'
                state. When the ECU detects a cut-off valve failure, it uses the PSV as a backup. To provide
                pressurization of the SAHR canister (to keep the park brake released), the ECU energizes the PSV. The
                energized PSV routes pressurized brake fluid from the primary accumulator circuit to the SAHR canister
                continuously to keep the parking brake in its 'released' state (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404879">FIGURE 36</hotlnk>). The parking brake line is pressurized continuously during
                the backup mode. When the ECU detects the cut-off valve malfunction, it will generate a fault code and
                turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator. The parking brake circuit is placed in the backup mode any
                time SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is turned on.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404879" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0404879" filename="../figg04/g0404879a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Brake Fluid Routing - Park Brake Backup Mode</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A travel switch mounted on the SAHR canister monitors the action of the park brake shaft and cable.
                The state of this switch is read by the ECU to determine:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>if the parking brake is applied (ECU will send a signal to the ESC/BC requesting it to turn on
                        the PARK BRAKE indicator.)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>if overtravel of the brake cable is occurring (possible worn brake shoes or stretched/broken
                        cable)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>if undertravel of the brake cable is occurring (possible frozen park brake or cable).</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The ECU also monitors the status of the park brake switch, and the current flow to the cut-off and
                pressure supply solenoid valves used to route brake fluid between the HCU and the SAHR canister. If any
                fault condition is detected, the ECU will send a signal to the ESC/BC requesting it to turn on the
                SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator, and place the park brake circuit in the backup mode. In addition, a
                diagnostic code will be generated by the ECU and stored in memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is
                explained in Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DYNAMIC PARKING BRAKE FUNCTION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>This function is controlled by the ECU. The ECU is constantly monitoring vehicle speed. If it detects
                a parking brake apply signal while vehicle speed is above 2 mph, it uses the ATC and ABS valves to apply
                the rear service brakes. In addition, the ECU signals the ESC/BC to turn on the vehicle's brake lights.
                After the vehicle has come to a safe stop, the driveline parking brake is applied as described above.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PARKING BRAKE SAFETY INTERLOCKS</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The parking brake apply/release input signal to the ECU is normally provided by the dash mounted park
                brake switch as described above. However, because the HCU/ECU is electronically controlled, various
                interlocks can be used to control the parking brake and even override the park brake switch. The
                following interlock functions are used to verify that safe conditions exist before allowing the parking
                brake to be applied or released.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When the park brake is applied, driver cannot "drive" against the park brake. When the parking
                        brake is applied the ECU sends a J1939 message to the engine control module to reduce engine
                        torque.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The parking brake applies automatically when the key is turned off and the vehicle is stopped.
                        If the key is turned off while the vehicle is moving (more than 2 mph), the park brake is
                        prevented from coming on. The ECU electronically monitors the vehicle speed and the position of
                        the ignition key; and will apply the parking brake only when the correct conditions exist.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The parking brake is released when the dash switch is pressed, ONLY when all of the following
                        conditions are met. The ECU detects these conditions electronically and responds to the dash
                        switch only when the correct conditions exist.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>The foot brake must be applied.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The ignition key must be in the "On" position.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>There must be no major brake system faults.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The transmission shifter must be in a position other than P or PB.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048400.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
