<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: HOLSET SS 296 AND QE 296/338 - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>There are two levels of service covered in this manual: the Maintenance Level and the Service Level.
                The Maintenance Level covers service which needs to be done at regular intervals to ensure extended life
                or to correct minor problems, and the Service Level covers service which is necessary due to more
                serious malfunctions.
            </para>
            <para>Compare your air compressor problems to those outlined in
                <hotlnk document="s04014_HL0401401.xml" xrefid="hl0401401">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>. The Troubleshooting
                Chart will direct you to more detailed repair information.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Maintenance and Service Kits are available for field work above the crankcase. For repair work
                        below the valve body gasket, contact your International Dealer Parts Department.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SS 296 COMPRESSOR</title>
            <para>There are two Maintenance Kits and one Service Kit for the single cylinder with 3-leg unloader cap
                compressors as follows:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Unloader Seal Maintenance Kit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401406">Figure 6</hotlnk>). The unloader body bolts, unloader body and
                        unloader cap are not included in this kit; they are to be reused, unless damaged. Apply Teflon
                        grease, supplied in this kit, liberally to the unloader body O-ring and especially to the
                        unloader cap, unloader vee seal and unloader body cavity. The Unloader Seal Kit is also included
                        in both of the following kits (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401407">Figure 7</hotlnk>and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401408">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Conventional Models With 3-Leg Unloader Cap Maintenance Kit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401407">Figure 7</hotlnk>). The unloader body bolts, head bolts, unloader
                        body, unloader cap, intake seat, exhaust seat, cover and head are not included in this kit; they
                        are to be reused, unless damaged. Apply Teflon grease, supplied in this kit, liberally to the
                        unloader body O-ring and especially to the unloader cap and unloader vee seal.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Conventional Models With Direct/Remote Air Governor Mounting Service Kit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401408">Figure 8</hotlnk>). The unloader body bolts, head bolts, cover and
                        head are not included in this kit: they are to be reused, unless damaged. Apply Teflon grease,
                        supplied in this kit, liberally to the unloader body O-ring and especially to the unloader cap
                        and unloader vee seal.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0401406" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401406" filename="../figg04/g0401406.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Unloader Seal Maintenance Kit</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0401407" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401407" filename="../figg04/g0401407.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Conventional Models With 3-Leg Unloader Cap Maintenance Kit</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0401408" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401408" filename="../figg04/g0401408.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Conventional Models With Direct/Remote Air Governor Mounting Service Kit</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
