<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAMONDLIFE&#8482; (BOSCH PIN SLIDE) DISC BRAKES For Vehicles Built After June 2, 2002 - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The caliper attaches to and slides on sealed and lubricated leading and trailing guide pins located
                within an anchor plate, hence the terminology "sliding" or "floating" caliper. The anchor plate is
                mounted on the steering knuckle flange on front axles and on the axle flange at rear axles.
            </para>
            <para>The pin slide caliper disc brake has two disc brake pads. One pad is mounted on each side of the rotor
                and grips the rotor when hydraulic pressure is applied to the two hydraulic pistons.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is not uncommon for disc brakes to have a slight drag. The amount of drag will depend upon
                        the type of brake application made before the inspection is made.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Chassis equipped with these pin slide disc brakes will have a split hydraulic system without ABS brake
                system
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404705">(Figure 5)</hotlnk>
                and with ABS brake system
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404706">(Figure 6)</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f0404706"/>.
            </para>
            <para>The brake power assist is a Hydro-Max Booster system. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the Master Service
                Manual for complete details covering this booster system.
            </para>
            <para>The split hydraulic system has a dual chamber master cylinder. The master cylinder assembly also
                includes an integral pressure differential valve and brake warning light switch which senses a pressure
                loss in either of the hydraulic systems should a failure occur. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the Master
                Service Manual for information pertaining to the pressure differential valve and brake warning light
                switch in the Hydro-Max Booster system.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404705" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404005.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Hydraulic System Without ABS Brake System</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404706" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404006.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Hydraulic System With ABS Brake System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04047.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
