<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPLIT AIR BRAKE SYSTEM - SPLIT AIR SYSTEM VALVES - INVERSION VALVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INVERSION VALVE</title>
        <para>An inversion valve (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400809">Figure 9</hotlnk>) is used on the straight truck and bus split air systems. This
            valve is installed in the air brake system to modulate the parking (spring) brakes on the rear axle along
            with the secondary front axle service brakes if air loss occurs in the primary system.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400809" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400809" filename="../figg04/g0400809.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Inversion Valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. CONTROL PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. RESERVOIR PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>3. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>4. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>During normal brake operation, the inversion valve is simply a path for the signal air from the parking
            brake control valve to the parking brake quick release valve. This system can fully apply or fully release
            the parking brakes.
        </para>
        <para>The split air brake system on most tractors functions in a similar manner as on a straight truck except
            there is no need for an inversion valve to apply the parking brakes. The trailer brakes, which operate off
            the primary or secondary tractor air system, provide braking effort to assist the tractor brake in an
            emergency situation if there is an air loss on one of the systems.
        </para>
        <para>On a straight truck which is equipped with trailer towing provisions, the vehicle will have a split air
            system that includes a tractor protection valve and a hand control valve.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04008.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
