<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DCM AND DDM DRUM TYPE PARKING BRAKE - BENDIX DUO DUTY MECHANICAL BRAKE - CLEANING, INSPECTION AND REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CLEANING, INSPECTION AND REPAIR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cleaning</title>
            <para>Protect the brake lining from solvents, lubricants, or other contaminants that can change the friction
                properties of the lining. Contaminated linings must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>Use an approved brake parts cleaner. OSHA recommends that enclosed cylinders equipped with vacuums and
                high-efficiency (HEPA) filters be used in brake repairs. Under this system, the entire brake assembly is
                placed within the cylinder and the mechanic works through sleeves in the cylinder. Compressed air is
                blown into the cylinder to clean the assembly, and the dirty air is removed from the cylinder by the
                vacuum.
            </para>
            <para>If such an assembly is not available, the mechanic must carefully clean the brake assembly in the open
                air. During disas- sembly, all parts should be carefully placed on the floor to minimize the creation of
                airborne brake dust. Dust should be first cleaned from the brake drum, backing plate, and brake assembly
                using an industrial vacuum cleaner equipped with a (HEPA) filter system. After vacuum cleaning, any
                remaining dust should be removed using a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Compressed air and open dry brushing should NEVER be used for cleaning brake assemblies.
                        Exposure to airborne brake dust can cause serious or fatal diseases.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection and Repair</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the springs for deformed hooks, fatigue cracks, and loss of spring tension. It
                    is recommended that new springs be installed when linings are replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the support plate for distortion or loose anchor pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect shoes for bent webs and rims and worn linings. Lining worn down to or within
                    0.020 inch (.51 mm) of the rivet heads must be replaced. Reline the shoes or replace with factory
                    lined shoes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The brake shoes must be square within 0.004 inch (.10 mm) per inch of lining width.
                    Shoes that are badly out-of-square will drag (rub against the drum) causing heat damage to the
                    lining. Check shoe squareness by placing the brake assembly on a flat surface, as in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402113">Figure 13</hotlnk>, and check shoes with a square as shown. To correct an
                    out-of-square shoe, remove shoes and bend shoe guide lug slightly in vise in direction necessary to
                    correct misalignment. Reassemble and recheck squareness. Shoes must be free to move within the slot
                    provided by the guide lug and the shoe bearing surfaces.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0402113" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0402113" filename="../figg04/G0402113.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="192px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Checking Squareness Of Shoes</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the brake actuating cam and lever assembly. Check cam ears and body for shiny
                    spots which may indicate contact with the drum or return springs. Check lever for retention to cam
                    (it must be tight).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace any damaged, broken, worn or questionable parts.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
