<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s04005" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5060" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9800</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description id="hl0400504">
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>MATERIAL DUST DURING BRAKE SERVICING</para>
                            <seqlist>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Studies have indicated that exposure to excessive amounts of brake material
                                        dust (whether asbestos or non-asbestos, fiberglass, mineral wool, aramid,
                                        ceramic or carbon) may be a potential cancer-causing health hazard. Even though
                                        the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has not set any limits
                                        on non-asbestos dust exposure, there is some medical opinion that such
                                        non-asbestos fibers can cause cancer as well. Since most automotive friction
                                        materials normally contain a sizeable amount of this material, it is important
                                        that people who handle brake linings be aware of the problem and know the
                                        precautions to be taken.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Areas where brake work is done should be set aside, if possible, and should be
                                        posted with a material dust exposure sign as follows:
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>BRAKE LINING FIBER DUST HAZARD</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>AVOID BREATHING DUST</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>WEAR ASSIGNED PROTECTIVE EQUIPMENT</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>DO NOT REMAIN IN AREA UNLESS YOUR WORK REQUIRES IT</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>BREATHING BRAKE LINING FIBERS MAY BE HAZARDOUS TO YOUR HEALTH</para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as
                                        well as for suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29,
                                        Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1910.1001.)
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other
                                        operations.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service
                                        procedures. Wear the respirator from removal of the wheels through assembly.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>NEVER use compressed air or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies.
                                        OSHA recommends that you use cylinders that enclose the brake. These cylinders
                                        have vacuums with high efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm sleeves. But,
                                        if such equipment is not available, carefully clean parts and assemblies in the
                                        open air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly,
                                        carefully place all parts on the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use
                                        an industrial vacuum cleaner with a HEPA filter system to clean dust from the
                                        brake drums, backing plates and other brake parts. After using the vacuum,
                                        remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Grinding or machining brake linings. If you must grind or machine brake
                                        linings, take additional precautions because contact with fiber dust is higher
                                        during these operations. In addition to wearing an approved respirator, do such
                                        work in an area with exhaust ventilation.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cleaning the work area. NEVER use compressed air or dry sweeping to clean the
                                        work area. Use an industrial vacuum with a HEPA filter and rags soaked in water
                                        and wrung until nearly dry. Dispose of used rags with care to avoid getting dust
                                        into the air. Use an approved respirator when emptying vacuum cleaners and
                                        handling used rags.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking. Do not
                                        wear your work clothes home. Vacuum your work clothes after use and then launder
                                        them separately, without shaking, to prevent fiber dust from getting into the
                                        air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>The term "Foundation" brake is given to those components at wheels which actually do the
                        braking. This includes such items as brake shoes, linings, anchors, drums, spiders and/or
                        backing plates. Although the slack adjusters, cam, cam rollers and spring brake chambers are not
                        considered components of the foundation brakes, they will be covered in this section.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
