<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK MODULATOR ASSEMBLY: BENDIX M-21 AND M-22 - OPERATION, LEAKAGE AND ELECTRICAL TESTS - LEAKAGE
        TESTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>LEAKAGE TESTING</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block or chock the wheels. Release the parking
                brakes and build the air system to full pressure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the engine OFF and make 4 or 5 brake applications and note that the service brakes
                apply and release promptly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Build system pressure to governor cut-out and turn the engine OFF.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make and hold a full service brake application.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap solution to the exhaust port of the modulator. Leakage should not exceed a
                    one inch bubble in less than 3 (three) seconds. If leakage exceeds the specified maximum, replace
                    the modulator.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap solution around the solenoid assembly (top and bottom). Leakage should not
                    exceed a one inch bubble in less than 3 (three) seconds. If leakage exceeds the specified maximum,
                    tighten the solenoid capscrews and re-test. If the leakage remains excessive after re-testing,
                    replace the modulator.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap solution around each diaphragm cover. Leakage should not exceed a one inch
                    bubble in less than 3 (three) seconds. If leakage exceeds the specified maximum, tighten the
                    diaphragm capscrews and re-test. If the leakage remains excessive after re-testing, replace the
                    modulator.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_HL0403003.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
