<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DCM AND DDM DRUM TYPE PARKING BRAKE - ROCKWELL DUPLEX CAM MECHANICAL BRAKE - CLEANING, INSPECTION AND
        REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLEANING, INSPECTION AND REPAIR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cleaning</title>
            <para>Protect the brake lining from solvents, lubricants, or other contaminants that can change the friction
                properties of the lining. Contaminated linings must be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>Use an approved brake parts cleaner. OSHA recommends that enclosed cylinders equipped with vacuums and
                high-efficiency (HEPA) filters be used in brake repairs. Under this system, the entire brake assem- bly
                is placed within the cylinder and the mechanic works through sleeves in the cylinder. Compressed air is
                blown into the cylinder to clean the assembly, and dirty air is removed from the cylinder by the vacuum.
            </para>
            <para>If such an assembly is not available, you must carefully clean the brake assembly in the open air.
                During disassembly, all parts should be carefully placed on the floor to minimize the creation of
                airborne brake dust. Dust should be first cleaned from the brake drum, backing plate, and brake assembly
                using an industrial vacuum cleaner equipped with a (HEPA) filter system. After vacuum cleaning, any
                remaining dust should be removed using a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Compressed air and open dry brushing should NEVER be used for cleaning brake assemblies.
                        Exposure to airborne brake dust can cause serious or fatal diseases.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection and Repair</title>
            <para>It is important that you carefully inspect all parts before assembly starts. Check all parts for wear
                or damage and repair or replace any damaged, broken, worn or questionable parts. Some key things to
                check for are:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check backing plate for distortion or loose anchor pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the hole that the cam rotates in for elongation and wear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check actuator strut for wear at the cam slot and pressure points at both shoes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check both shoes for rust, expanded rivet holes, broken welds and correct alignment.
                    Check for shoe square to the backing plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check brake drums for cracks, severe heat checking, heat spotting, scoring, pitting,
                    distortion, and excessive inside diameter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If lining material is worn to .100 inch (2.5 mm) or within 0.020 inch (.51 mm) of rivet
                    head at thinnest point, replace lining, or shoe and lining assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
