<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - PRINCIPLES, OPERATION AND SERVICE - COMPONENT FAILURE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>COMPONENT FAILURE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The controller handles equipment failure. Any single electrical failure of an antilock system
                component results in three events happening at the same time.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The appropriate warning light on the instrument panel (ABS warning light or Traction Active
                        light) will illuminate to alert the driver that the system has detected a malfunction.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The controller will disable all or part of the antilock/traction control system.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The system reverts to standard braking on wheels no longer controlled by the ABS controller.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Depending upon the the type of failure and its position of occurrence, the controller disables all or
                only a portion of the ABS and traction control system. A power or controller failure, for instance, will
                result in complete disabling of the ABS and traction control systems and the vehicle would revert to
                standard brakes. The failure of two or more system components will also disable the entire system.
            </para>
            <para>The instrument panel warning light will react as it normally would during a single component failure,
                and the controller LEDs will show one failure at a time. When the first failure is corrected and the
                system is reset, the next problem area will be displayed by the LEDs. This is done so that the service
                technician does not lose track of problem areas, and the system is not restored until all errors are
                corrected and the controller is reset.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>References to right and left or front and rear are determined from the driver's seat. Left
                        front is therefore the corner closest to the driver.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>FRONT MODULATOR VALVE</title>
            <para>If either the right front or left front modulator fails, antilock on that wheel is disabled. Antilock
                and traction control on all the other wheels remain active.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
