<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - OPERATION - OPERATION PHILOSOPHY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION PHILOSOPHY</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Axle Brake Operation With 4x2 Chassis</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402301">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                for the following discussion. Also refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04023_52.xml" xrefid="x0402301">COMPONENT LOCATIONS
                    <xref refid="x0402301"/>
                </hotlnk>
                for additional illustrations on system installations.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402301" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402301" filename="../figg04/G0402301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Typical Antilock Brake System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EXCITER RING (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WARNING LIGHT RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WHEEL SPEED SENSOR (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. C350 CONNECTS REAR HARNESS TO ITEM 6</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. M-21 MODULATOR VALVE (4 PLACES)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CR-15 RELAY VALVE/ECU CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. C288 CONNECTS FRONT HARNESS TO ITEM 6</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. ENGINE BRAKE RELAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CRANK RELAY (POWER SUPPLY TO CR-15)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. QUICK RELEASE VALVE (QRV)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The antilock system provides individual wheel control by using a wheel speed sensor and modulator at
                each wheel to measure rotational speed. By monitoring the rate of deceleration during braking, and then
                modifying the service brake application pressure at each wheel, the ECU is able to provide improved
                vehicle braking, while maintaining vehicle stability.
            </para>
            <para>The rear axle brakes are controlled completely independent of each other and brake application
                pressure at an individual wheel is adjusted solely on the basis of its behavior on the road surface on
                which it is traveling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Axle Brake Operation With 6x4 Chassis</title>
            <para>With vehicles equipped with tandem rear axles (6x2 or 6x4), the wheel speed sensors are installed at
                the wheels, located on the axle that is most likely to lose traction first. With a 4-spring suspension,
                the rear axle sensors are located on the Forward Rear axle. On an air suspension, sensors are located on
                the Rear Rear axle. A single modulator controls both left side rear axle brakes and another modulator
                controls both right side rear axle brakes. With this arrangement of wheel speed sensors and modulators,
                both brakes on one side of a tandem rear axle will be modulated as one, since they will most likely be
                on the same type of road surface.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front (Steering) Axle Brake Operation</title>
            <para>While each steering axle brake is under the control of an individual modulator valve, the ECU does not
                treat these brakes totally independent of each other. The ECU utilizes a modified individual control
                method for steering axle brakes. This is done to minimize "steering wheel pull" in the event that one
                front wheel is on dry pavement and the other is on a slippery surface, such as ice or snow. The ECU
                controls the braking force differences between the two brakes. The wheel on dry pavement is initially
                given less braking force and is brought up to optimum during the stop, while the wheel on ice attempts
                to maintain optimum braking during the entire stop.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
