<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - HOSES, TUBING AND CONNECTIONS - FLEXIBLE HOSE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="5">
        <title>FLEXIBLE HOSE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>Any air system hose can be made locally. Hose is stocked bulk by size.</para>
            <para>The hose is constructed of a seamless synthetic rubber lining or tube reinforced with one fabric braid
                of high tensile steel wire which is covered with a synthetic rubber-impregnated, oil-resistant fabric
                braid.
            </para>
            <para>These hoses can be used for air systems and air brake systems, except the air line from air compressor
                to air reservoir, where the temperature will exceed 300&#176;F (149&#176;C.
            </para>
            <para>The fittings used at the ends of the flexible hose are of the swivel type, such as that shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400293">Figure 93</hotlnk>
                . The swivel end permits one end of the hose to be disconnected without disturbing the complete hose.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400293" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400293" filename="../figg04/G0400293.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 93. Flexible Hose Fittings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HOSE SOCKET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Do not try to mix different type hoses and hose fittings. In some cases the hose and hose fittings may
                seem to fit, but the ends may not hold up under pressure which could result in loss of air while vehicle
                is being operated. If in doubt as to the identification of the hose, and/or fittings which are being
                repaired, use new components to make up a new hose assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hose Assembly Instructions</title>
            <para>When making up a length of hose, each step should be finished carefully to assure proper connections
                at the hose ends (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400293">Figure 93</hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hose fitting and nut from socket and hose.
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400293">Figure 93</hotlnk>
                    illustrates the swivel hose fitting. So that the swivel nut and fitting can be removed from the hose
                    and socket assembly, install a male fitting in the swivel nut and tighten it. That locks the swivel
                    joint assembly (nut and fitting). The swivel nut and fitting can now be turned out of the hose using
                    a wrench.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the hose from the socket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 1 and 2 for the removal of second end.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lightly clamp the hose in a vise.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a fine-tooth hacksaw to cut hose to desired length (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400294">Figure 94</hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0400294" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400294" filename="../figg04/G0400294.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 94. Hacksaw to Cut Hose</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lightly clamp the hose socket in a vise with the hose end facing out (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400295">Figure 95</hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0400295" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400295" filename="../figg04/G0400295.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 95. Hose Bottoms in Fitting</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Screw end of new hose into socket (turn counterclockwise) until hose bottoms in fitting,
                    then back off 1/4 turn
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400295">(Figure 95)</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reposition hose and socket in the vise as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400296">Figure 96</hotlnk>
                    . Lubricate hose socket and fitting threads. Use light weight engine oil sparingly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0400296" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400296" filename="../figg04/G0400296.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 96. Lubricate Socket and Fitting Threads</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position hose socket in swivel nut and reassemble male fitting (if removed) to lock
                    swivel nut on the fitting. Thread the fitting and swivel nut (with male adapter) assembly into the
                    hose as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400297">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                    , leaving 1/32 inch to 1/16 inch (.793-1.59 mm) clearance between nut and socket so that the nut can
                    swivel freely.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0400297" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400297" filename="../figg04/G0400297.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Thread Fitting</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 5, 6, 7 and 8 on opposite end of hose to install the remaining nut and
                    fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the threads of the hose assembly when connecting the lines (use light engine
                    oil sparingly).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing the new hose assembly on the vehicle, be sure to check for leakage and
                    correct any leaks if leaks are present.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hose Assembly Special Instructions</title>
            <para>Installation and routing of these hoses is just as important as special attention given to the
                installation of the ends. Common problems encountered with installation and routing which will result in
                short service life of these hoses are:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">High external temperatures will shorten the life of a hose. Route hoses away from hot
                    manifolds and exhaust systems.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Abrasion of hoses will cause outer surfaces to wear and weaken the hose. When installing
                    these flexible hoses, avoid contact or crisscrossing sharp surfaces and with interference of moving
                    parts (shift levers and pedals). Clamp or plastic/tie hoses in place to prevent vibration, chaffing;
                    route hoses together and parallel. If the hose cannot be clamped adequately, the hose must be
                    equipped with a protective conduit (cover). If the hose being replaced has a protective conduit, be
                    sure to use a cover on the new hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flexing of short hoses should not be allowed, since this will tend to wear the hoses at
                    the fittings. If the hose must move, do not permit the hose to twist; keep the bend in the hose in
                    the same plane as the movement where the hose is connected. Provide enough hose to permit any
                    movement which may be required. Avoid sharp bends or turns in the hoses.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_144.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_146.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
