<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - BENDIX E6-TREADLE AND E7-SUSPENDED PEDAL TYPE (FOOT) BRAKE VALVES - SERVICING TREADLE TYPE VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SERVICING TREADLE TYPE VALVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply parking brake and block wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from all reservoirs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all supply and delivery lines at (foot) brake valve. Mark all air lines in
                    relation to valve to assist when reconnecting lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fittings from valve. Mark these fittings also in relation to location and
                    position on the valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove (foot) brake valve and treadle assembly by removing three capscrews on outer bolt
                    circle of mounting plate. Basic valve alone may be removed by removing three capscrews on inner bolt
                    circle.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400207">
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400225">Figure 25</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the entire brake valve and treadle assembly was removed from the vehicle, remove the
                    capscrews securing treadle assembly to the basic brake valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove screw (Item 19) securing the exhaust diaphragm (Item 17) and washer (Item 20) to
                    exhaust cover (Item 16).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove four screws that secure exhaust cover (Item 16) to lower valve body (Item 23).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0400225" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic id="g0400225" filename="../figg04/G0400225.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Treadle Type Valve - Disassemble</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PLUNGER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SPRING GUIDE SCREW (NOT USED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. STEM SPRING GUIDE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. STEM SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING SEAT NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SPRING SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. MOUNTING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. RUBBER SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. PRIMARY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. PRIMARY INLET AND EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. RELAY PISTON SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. SEAL RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. SECONDARY INLET AND EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. EXHAUST COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. DIAPHRAGM WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>20. WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>21. O-RING RETAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>22. RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. LOWER VALVE BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>24. UPPER VALVE BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>25. PRIMARY PISTON RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. PRIMARY PISTON RETAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>27. STEM</callout1>
                    <callout1>28. BOOT</callout1>
                    <callout1>29. TREADLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove secondary inlet and exhaust valve assembly (Item 14) from lower valve body (Item
                    23). Disassembly of secondary inlet and exhaust valve assembly is not required since it is only
                    serviced as an assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove four hex head capscrews securing the lower valve body (Item 23) to upper valve
                    body (Item 24) and separate the bodies.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rubber seal ring (Item 13) from the lower body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply thumb pressure to primary piston (Item 9), lift out and up on the three lock tabs
                    of primary piston retainer (Item 26).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a 3/8 inch (10 mm) wrench to hold the nut on threaded end of stem on top of primary
                    piston. Insert a screwdriver in exhaust passage through center of valve and engage slotted head of
                    the stem (Item 27).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before proceeding, note the nut and stem are used to contain primary piston return spring
                        (Item 25), stem spring (Item 4) and relay piston spring (Item 11). Combined force of these
                        springs is approximately 50 ft-lbs. (68 Nm). Care must be taken to prevent personal injury when
                        removing the nut as the spring forces will be released. It is recommended that primary piston
                        and relay piston be contained while nut and stem are being removed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate the screwdriver counterclockwise and remove stem (Item 27), stem spring (Item 4),
                    spring guide (Item 3) and nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove relay piston (Item 12), relay piston spring (Item 11), primary piston (Item 9)
                    and primary piston return spring (Item 25) from the upper body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disassemble primary piston (Item 9) by separating spring seat nut, spring seat (Item 6),
                    rubber spring (Item 8) and removing piston O-ring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove large and small O-rings from relay piston.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove retaining ring securing primary inlet and exhaust valve assembly (Item 10) in
                    upper body and remove valve assembly. Do not disassemble primary inlet as it is only serviced as an
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <para>Wash all metal parts in cleaning solvent. Use compressed air to dry parts. Inspect all parts for
                excessive wear or deterioration. Inspect valve seats for nicks or burrs. Check springs for cracks or
                corrosion. Replace all rubber parts and any part not found to be serviceable during inspection.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400225">Figure 25</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>Prior to reassembling brake valve, lubricate all O-rings, O-ring grooves, piston bores and
                metal-to-metal moving surfaces. Lubricate with Fleetrite EP2 Moly grease or equivalent to NLGI #2
                multi-purpose lithium grease.
            </para>
            <para>All torques specified are assembly torques and can be expected to differ after assembly is
                accomplished. Do not re-tighten nuts after initial torque is applied.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position primary inlet and exhaust assembly in the upper body; then install retaining
                    ring to secure it. Be sure the retaining ring is seated completely in its groove.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install large and small O-rings on relay piston.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace primary piston O-ring in piston O-ring groove.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position rubber spring (Item 8), concave side down, in primary piston (Item 9) and place
                    spring seat (Item 6), flat side up, over rubber spring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install primary piston spring seat nut (Item 5) with its hex closest to spring seat and
                    rotate clockwise until top surface of spring seat is even with top surface of piston (Item 9).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position primary piston return spring (Item 25) in the upper body piston bore.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install primary piston, spring seat out, over return spring and press piston into body
                    bore.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place relay piston return spring (Item 11) in the upper body and position relay piston
                    (Item 12) over spring so that the concave side of the piston is against the spring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compress both primary piston and relay piston into the upper body and hold them
                    compressed, either manually or mechanically (see
                    <emph type="bold">WARNING</emph>
                    under step 8 in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400207">
                        <xref refid="hl0400207"/>Disassemble,
                    </hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place stem (Item 27) through exhaust passage of the lower body so that threaded portion
                    is visible at primary piston.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a screwdriver to engage and hold the slotted head of stem; then position stem spring
                    (Item 4) and spring guide (Item 3) over primary piston (Item 9).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install nut on stem and rotate clockwise. Tighten to 20 to 30 in-lbs. (2.3 to 3.4 N&#183;
                    m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install primary piston retainer (Item 26) over piston making certain all three lock tabs
                    have engaged the outer lip of body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install secondary inlet and exhaust valve assembly in lower body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place exhaust cover (Item 16) on lower body and install four machine screws with
                    lockwashers; tighten to 70 to 100 in-lbs. (7.9 to 11.3 N &#8226; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install exhaust diaphragm (Item 17) and diaphragm washer (Item 18) to exhaust cover
                    (Item 16) using Phillips head screw and lockwasher.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install seal ring (Item 13) in lower body and secure lower body to upper body using four
                    hex head capscrews and lockwashers; tighten capscrews to 70 to 100 in-lbs. (7.9 to 11.3 N &#8226;
                    m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install treadle valve assembly to basic brake valve. Secure with capscrews and
                    lockwashers and tighten to 80 to 100 in-lbs. (9 to 11.3 N &#8226; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the rebuilt brake valve by performing
                    <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400206.xml" xrefid="hl0400206">
                        <xref refid="hl0400206"/>SERVICE CHECKS
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400206.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_53.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
