<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ANTILOCK SYSTEM OPERATION OVERVIEW</title>
            <para>During a brake stop, the maximum point of deceleration occurs just before wheel lock-up. When wheels
                lock up, stopping distances increase and loss of directional control may occur.
            </para>
            <para>To reduce wheel lock-up, the antilock brake system monitors the rotational speed of the wheels using
                sensors mounted on the axle ends and exciter rings mounted on the wheel assemblies.
            </para>
            <para>When the wheels rotate, an AC voltage pulse is generated by the sensors that is transmitted to the
                Electronic Control Unit (EC-15) (
                <hotlnk document="s04025_3.xml" xrefid="t0402501">Component Identification Table</hotlnk>) which is part
                of the CR-15 relay valve/ECU assembly. The ECU monitors the pulse rates. During a brake application, if
                a wheel(s) is about to lock up, the ECU sends a signal to the appropriate M-21 modulator valve(s).
            </para>
            <para>Within a fraction of a second, the modulator valve responds by repeatedly exhausting air from the
                brake chamber(s) allowing the wheel(s) to speed up, and then automatically applying air (much like a
                driver pumping the brakes manually). The antilock system only operates when the ECU determines that a
                wheel is about to lock up.
            </para>
            <para>A warning light on the instrument panel illuminates when the ECU detects a problem with the system. If
                the vehicle includes an engine brake, the ECU will dis-engage the engine brake when it senses a wheel
                lock-up is about to occur.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
