<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DCM AND DDM DRUM TYPE PARKING BRAKE - BENDIX DUO DUTY MECHANICAL BRAKE - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>A simplified schematic of the Duo-Duty Mechanical Brake is shown in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402111">Figure 11</hotlnk>. The return springs and the shoe-to-shoe spring have been
            omitted. The Duo-Duty Brake is a non-servo type brake and the shoes operate independently of each other. One
            shoe is energizing (leading shoe) and the other shoe is a non-energizing shoe (trailing shoe). Whether a
            shoe becomes "leading" or "trailing" depends upon the direction of drum rotation.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0402111" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0402111" filename="../figg04/g0402111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. DDM Brake Operation</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. LEADING SHOE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. TRAILING SHOE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. UPPER ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                <callout1>4. ACTUATOR LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>5. CAM</callout1>
                <callout1>6. BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
                <callout1>7. LOWER ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>With the drum rotation counterclockwise, as indicated by the arrow, an applying force as indicated is
            applied to the lever and the cam rotates counterclockwise around the upper anchor pin. Forces A and B are
            applied to the brake shoes and the upper ends of the shoes move out toward the drum.
        </para>
        <para>When the linings contact the drum braking surface, the friction force between the leading shoe and the
            drum forms a counterclockwise moment around the lower anchor pin. Since this moment is in the same direction
            as the moment due to applying Force A, the shoe-to-drum friction force aids the applying force in holding
            the shoe against the drum.
        </para>
        <para>The leading shoe, therefore, becomes an "energized" shoe. On the other hand, in the case of the trailing
            shoe, the friction force opposes the applying Force B and the trailing shoe, therefore, becomes a
            "non-energized" shoe. During braking, the leading shoe does the greater portion of the work. If the drum
            rotation of
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402111">Figure 11</hotlnk>is reversed (e.g., clockwise), the right-hand shoe becomes the
            leading shoe and the left-hand shoe becomes the trailing shoe. The lever can be applied in either direction;
            however, the brake is usually more effective when the lever is applied in the forward direction, which
            corresponds to cam rotation in the same direction as the drum rotation.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_HL040211A.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
