<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: ROCKWELL WABCO 4 CHANNEL - TROUBLESHOOTING - BLINK CODE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0403602" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BLINK CODE</title>
        <para>The ABS includes a quick and easy way of checking for system failures using a pattern of light flashes
            called
            <emph type="bold">blink codes.</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The blink code is used to determine failures in the ABS. These failures are called
            <emph type="bold">faults</emph>
            when stored in the ECU memory. When the ABS warning light stays on, the blink code identifies the specific
            system fault causing the failure.
        </para>
        <para>When the blink code is activated, the most current ECU fault is displayed. If more than one fault exists,
            the first fault displayed must be corrected and erased from the ECU memory before the next fault is
            displayed.
        </para>
        <para>Two types of faults can be in the ECU. They are:</para>
        <para>
            <title>Existing -</title>
        </para>
        <para>If the ABS warning light does not go off when the ignition is turned off and on and the vehicle exceeds 4
            mph, then there is an existing fault. This is a failure that must be repaired. You cannot erase this fault
            from the ECU memory until it is repaired.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>An existing fault must be erased from the ECU after you have repaired the failure.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <title>Intermittent -</title>
        </para>
        <para>If the ABS light goes on after the vehicle exceeds 4 mph, but does not stay on after the ignition is
            turned off and on and the vehicle exceeds 4 mph again, then there is an intermittent failure in the ABS. A
            fault will appear in the ECU memory, but it can be erased from the ECU memory without doing any repair.
            Examples of an intermittent failure would be loose connectors or partially broken wires. These are failures
            that only register as faults under certain conditions. Write these faults down before you erase them to help
            isolate the problem over a period of time.
        </para>
        <para>When all faults have been corrected and erased from the ECU memory, the blink code 2-0-0 (No-Faults -
            System O.K.) will be displayed when you activate the blink code switch.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04036_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04036_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
