<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - INVERSION VALVE (BENDIX SR-1) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="4">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Initial Air Charge</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400232">Figure 32</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400232" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400232" filename="../figg04/g0400232.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Initial Air Charge - Inversion Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INLET AND EXHAUST A</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PISTON A</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PISTON B</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INLET AND EXHAUST B</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SPRING BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DOUBLE CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Initial air charge (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400232">Figure 32</hotlnk>
                ) from the primary and secondary reservoirs flows through the spring brake control valve and enters the
                supply port of the inversion valve. Air entering the support port flows past inlet and exhaust valve "B"
                (Item 8), to the underside of piston "B" (Item 5) and out the delivery port to the emergency air
                connection on the spring brake chamber. Note that the springs above piston "B" (Item 5) force it into
                contact with inlet and exhaust valve "B"(Item 8). In the position shown, the exhaust is closed and the
                inlet is open.
            </para>
            <para>Only air flowing from the primary reservoir enters the reservoir port on the inversion valve. This air
                remains under piston "A" (Item 4) as system pressure builds up. With primary reservoir pressure below
                approximately 55 psi, the spring above piston "A" (Item 4) forces it into contact with inlet exhaust
                valve "A" (Item 3), causing the exhaust to seal and inlet to open.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Fully Charged</title>
            <para>When the air pressure builds up past the approximate 55 psi in both the primary and secondary
                reservoirs, piston "A" (Item 4) has moved against the force of the spring above it permitting the inlet
                of valve "A" (Item 3) to close and open the hollow exhaust passage through piston "A" (Item 4).
            </para>
            <para>When air pressure under piston "B" (Item 5) is about 95 psi, piston "B" (Item 5) rises slightly
                against the force of springs above it, allowing the inlet of valve "B" (Item 8) to close. The exhaust
                through valve "B" (Item 8) remains closed.
            </para>
            <para>The closing of inlet portion of valve "B" traps about 95 psi in the hold-off cavity of the spring
                brake actuators while allowing full air system pressure to build elsewhere.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Normal Brake Application With Primary and Secondary Reservoirs Charged</title>
            </para>
            <para>When the service brakes are applied by actuating the dual brake valve, air from the secondary system
                is delivered from the brake valve to the control port where it is stopped at the closed inlet valve "A"
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400233">Figure 33, Item 3</hotlnk>
                ). No further movement of internal components of the inversion valve takes place. Air from the primary
                delivery system of the brake valve actuates the service brakes of the spring brake chambers.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400233" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400233" filename="../figg04/g0400233.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Normal Brake Application - Primary and Secondary Reservoirs</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INLET AND EXHAUST A</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PISTON A</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PISTON B</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INLET AND EXHAUST B</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SPRING BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DOUBLE CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Brake Application With Loss of Air in Secondary System</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400233">Figure 33</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>If air pressure is lost in the secondary reservoir (Item 2), the primary reservoir (Item 1) as well as
                the spring brake control valve (Item 9) is protected against air loss through action of single check
                valve (air source to primary reservoir) and double check valve (Item 10). A brake application at brake
                valve in this situation results in little or no air being delivered from the secondary system to the
                control port of inversion valve. No movement of the internal components of the valve takes place.
                Braking is assured since the primary reservoir is protected and the primary delivery system of the brake
                valve will apply the service brake portion of the spring brake chambers.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Brake Application With Loss of Air in Primary System</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400234">Figure 34</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400234" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400234" filename="../figg04/g0400234.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Brake Application With Loss of Air in Primary System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INLET AND EXHAUST A</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PISTON A</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PISTON B</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INLET AND EXHAUST B</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SPRING BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DOUBLE CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>If air pressure in the primary reservoir (Item 1) should fall below approximately 55 psi, the pressure
                below piston "A" (Item 4) is insufficient to resist spring force above and piston "A" moves into contact
                with valve "A" (Item 3). Initial contact between piston "A" (Item 4) and valve "A" (Item 3) closes the
                hollow exhaust passage of piston "A". Continued movement of piston opens the inlet valve "A" (Item 3).
            </para>
            <para>The secondary reservoir and spring brake control valve are protected from air pressure loss by action
                of the check valve.
            </para>
            <para>When brake application is made through the brake valve, air delivered from the secondary system of the
                brake valve enters the inversion valve control port. Air enters control port, moves past the inlet of
                valve "A" (Item 3) and is conducted through a passage in the body to the underside of piston "B" (Item
                5). The added force of air pressure below piston "B" (Item 5) moves up, opening the exhaust valve "B"
                (Item 8). When exhaust of valve "B" (Item 8) opens, air pressure trapped in the emergency section of the
                spring brake chamber is allowed to escape, resulting in a brake application by emergency section. The
                amount of air pressure released from the spring brake is proportional to the amount of air pressure
                delivered to the control port of the inversion valve by delivery of brake valve secondary system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Parking (Spring) Brake Application</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400235">Figure 35</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400235" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400235" filename="../figg04/g0400235.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Parking (Spring) Brake Application</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INLET AND EXHAUST A</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PISTON A</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PISTON B</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INLET AND EXHAUST B</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SPRING BRAKE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DOUBLE CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When both primary and secondary systems are charged with air and the spring brake control valve (Item
                9) is placed in "apply" or exhaust position, the inversion valve air supply and air pressure in the
                spring brake chambers will be exhausted. The single check valve in the inversion valve assists the
                exhaust of air from the spring brake by allowing air below piston "B" (Item 5) to flow back out the open
                exhaust of the spring brake control valve (Item 9). When air pressure below piston "B" (Item 5) has
                dropped enough, piston "B" (Item 5) moves down, opening the inlet of valve "B" (Item 8), thus providing
                an additional exhaust passage for air exhausting through the inversion valve from spring brakes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_62.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_64.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
