<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - SERVICE PROCEDURES - DISASSEMBLE CALIPER (BOTH SINGLE AND DUAL PISTON) TYPE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401601" svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DISASSEMBLE CALIPER (BOTH SINGLE AND DUAL PISTON) TYPE</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove caliper. Refer to ,
                <hotlnk document="s04016k_14.xml" xrefid="hl0401609">CALIPER AND PADS REMOVAL
                    <xref refid="hl0401609"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean caliper with solvent.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a suitable screwdriver, pry off the heat shields from the caliper pistons.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove piston(s) from caliper using pliers designed for disc brake caliper piston removal.
                If pliers are not available or pliers cannot remove piston(s), remove pistons using compressed air.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not insert any part of your hand between the caliper and block of wood or between the
                        piston and caliper housing when injecting compressed air into the caliper to remove caliper
                        pistons. Personal injury may occur.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For dual and single piston caliper, place a block of wood between the caliper housing and
                the caliper piston(s). Leave approximately 1.0 to 1 1/2 inch clearance between the caliper piston(s) and
                the block of wood. Using compressed air and an air blow (gun), insert gun into inlet port of caliper.
                Inject air into caliper housing forcing piston(s) out of caliper. Remove block of wood and finish
                removing piston(s) from caliper using caliper piston pliers. If no pliers are available, place a
                suitable cover (such as a piece of cardboard or a thin book) over caliper piston opening). Hold cover
                firmly onto caliper and apply compressed air into the caliper again. The piston(s) will pop out of the
                caliper and the cover will contain the piston(s) from flying out and causing possible personal injury (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401624">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401624" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401624" filename="../figg04/G0401624.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Removing Piston From Caliper</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AIR BLOW GUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 1.0" TO 1 1/2" CLEARANCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WOOD BLOCK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove piston dust boot(s) and seal(s) from caliper housing.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
