<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CALIPER DISC BRAKES - BLEEDING INSTRUCTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BLEEDING INSTRUCTIONS</title>
        <para>The bleeder screw is located on the inboard side of the caliper housing. It is not necessary to remove the
            wheel assembly to bleed the brakes.
        </para>
        <para>The fluid distribution passage between the two pistons is cast into the caliper housing, allowing brake
            fluid to pass from cylinder to cylinder. This requires only one bleeder screw.
        </para>
        <para>Bleed brakes in the following order: Right Rear, Left Rear, Right Front and Left Front.</para>
        <para>Use the brake bleeding procedure as directed in GROUP 04 - BRAKES, HYDRAULIC in the CTS-5000 Master
            Service Manual.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>All INTERNATIONAL vehicles equipped with hydraulic disc brakes are equipped with a HYDRO-MAX BRAKE
                    BOOSTER SYSTEM. This system has two sections and each section is separate from the other. Each
                    section uses different types of fluid. The two fluids are NOT COMPATIBLE and if mixed severe damage
                    will occur to the contaminated component.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <para>The HYDRO-MAX BOOSTER is operated by the Power Steering System and uses POWER STEERING FLUID ONLY.</para>
        <para>The BRAKING SYSTEM (MASTER CYLINDER) uses HYDRAULIC BRAKE FLUID ONLY.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>DO NOT PUT POWER STEERING FLUID OR ANY OTHER KIND OF FLUID EXCEPT BRAKE FLUID IN THE MASTER
                    CYLINDER RESERVOIR.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>CONTAMINATED BRAKE FLUID IS A MAINTENANCE ERROR AND IS NOT COVERED BY WARRANTY.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04016k.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
