<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - EC-17 INFORMATIONAL INPUTS AND COMMAND OUTPUTS - INPUTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INPUTS</title>
        <para>Wheel speed information is provided to the EC-17 via a wiring harness from
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403805">individual wheel speed sensors at the vehicle wheels</hotlnk>. Working with an
            exciter or tone ring, wheel speed sensors provide information to the EC-17 in the form of an AC signal which
            varies in voltage and frequency as the speed of the wheel increases or decreases. The EC-17 is designed to
            receive wheel speed information, from various wheel speed sensor models, at the rate of 100 pulses (86
            pulses if so configured) per wheel revolution. The EC-17 is able to simultaneously receive, and individually
            interpret, speed signals from up to six wheel speed sensors. Vehicle drive configuration and whether the
            traction control feature is in use determines the number of speed sensors that must be used. A vehicle with
            a single rear axle drive (4 x 2, 4 x 4, or 6 x 2) requires 4 speed sensors for both antilock and traction
            operation. A vehicle with two rear drive axles(6 x 4) requires 4 speed sensors for antilock only operation,
            but have the option to use 6 speed sensors for enhanced performance of both antilock and traction operation.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403805" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403805.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 5. WS-20 Speed Sensors</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Vehicle power is supplied to the EC-17 from the ignition switch through a 30 amp fuse. The electrical
            ground for the EC-17 is the vehicle chassis.
        </para>
        <para>A connection for a traction enable switch is provided, and used when the optional traction feature is
            installed. The switch allows traction to be turned on or off manually.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
