<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RECONDITIONING BRAKE DRUMS AND SHOES - BRAKE DRUMS - REFINISHING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REFINISHING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>On brake drums manufactured after January 1, 1971, the maximum diameter to which drum can be worn is
                stamped or cast into the drum. Drum should be discarded if worn to this limit.
            </para>
            <para>Most brake drum manufacturers do not recommend machining (turning) brake drums. Remember that each
                time brake drums are turned, less metal remains to absorb the heat developed by braking action. Brake
                drums containing less metal will operate at a higher temperature. As a result, brake fade, slow recovery
                and erratic wear will be more noticeable.
            </para>
            <para>Also, extremely high temperatures shorten lining life and cause heat checks and cracks to form on
                inner surface of drums. These conditions will become progressively worse until drums fail.
            </para>
            <para>Minor scores on brake drum can be removed with fine emery cloth or steel wool, but always clean emery
                or steel wool particles from the drum after this operation. More heavily damaged or out-of-round drums
                should be ground or turned on brake drum lathe to within allowable limitations.
            </para>
            <para>Measure with micrometer across brake surface. If depth of scoring exceeds 0.005 inch (0.13 mm), drum
                should be refinished. Reboring limits must not be exceeded and no heat checks, cracks or bluing should
                be evident.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Machining</title>
            <para>Brake drums that are otherwise in good condition can be turned in a lathe. However it must be
                remembered that the recommended re-machining or rebore limit for brake drums with a diameter over 14
                inches (355 mm) may not be increased more than 0.080 inch (2.03 mm) diameter (total cut) and discard at
                0.120 inch (3.05 mm) over normal diameter.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the brake lathe manufacturer's operating manual for instructions to operate the brake
                lathe.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The dimension located on the drum is discard dimension. Never re-machine drums to maximum wear
                        or discard diameter.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_HL0400701.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
