<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - BRAKE ADJUSTMENT - BENDIX AUTOMATIC SLACK ADJUSTERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>BENDIX AUTOMATIC SLACK ADJUSTERS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the slack adjuster is equipped with the easy-on yoke, position the actuator jam nut
                approximately 2 inches from the end. Thread the easy-on yoke adapter on the push rod until it is about
                3/4 inch from the end of the push rod. Turn the manual adjustment hex clockwise until the end of the
                actuator push rod protrudes beyond the threaded bore of the yoke approxi- mately 1/8 inch (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400529">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Thread the adapter into the yoke and tighten to 10
                ft-lbs. (13.6 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400529" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400529" filename="../figg04/G0400529.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 29. Bendix Easy-On Yoke Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 3/4" OUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. YOKE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADAPTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. JAM NUT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the slack adjuster is equipped with the quick connect yoke (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400530">Figure 30</hotlnk>), position the actuator jam nut approximately 1-1/2 inches
                from the end. Thread the quick connect adapter bushing on the push rod until approximately 1/8 inch of
                the push rod protrudes from the end of the adapter bushing. Install the retaining ring on the adapter
                bushing making certain it is in the adapter bushing groove. Turn the manual adjustment hex clockwise
                until the adapter bushing begins to enter the yoke. Fully compress the "legs" of the retaining ring and
                continue turning the manual adjustment hex until the adapter is completely in the yoke. Allow the
                retaining ring to expand into the corresponding groove in the yoke. Make certain the retaining ring is
                seated in both the yoke and adapter bushing groove by manually pulling on the arm, attempting to
                separate the adapter bushing and yoke.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400530" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400530" filename="../figg04/G0400530.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 30. Bendix Quick Connect Yoke Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 1/8" OUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. YOKE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ADAPTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. JAM NUT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Run the actuator push rod jam nut down against the adapter. Hold the adapter bushing hex
                with a wrench and tighten the jam nut to 25 - 33 ft-lbs. (33.9 - 44.7 N&#8226;m) for the 1/2" x 20
                thread and 33 - 50 ft-lbs. (44.7 - 67.8 N&#8226;m) for the 5/8" x 18 thread.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Manually adjust the brakes. The wheel to be adjusted should turn freely. Turn the manual
                adjustment hex clockwise until the brakes begin to drag. Back off the adjustment, counterclockwise,
                until the wheel turns freely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Uncage the spring parking brake(s). Refer to GROUP 04 - AIR BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove floor stands. Test vehicle for correct brake operation before putting vehicle back
                into service.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
