<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - EC-17 INFORMATIONAL INPUTS AND COMMAND OUTPUTS - OUTPUTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OUTPUTS</title>
        <para>The
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403806">Bendix M 22</hotlnk>
            is the means by which the EC-17 controller modifies driver applied air pressure to the service brakes. The
            modulator is an electrically controlled air valve located near the service actuator(s) it controls. It is
            the last valve that air passes through on its way to the brake actuator. A wiring harness connects the
            modulator to the EC-17 antilock controller. Solenoid valves contained in the modulator provide the
            electrical interface between the EC-17 controller electronics and the air brake system. The EC-17 is able to
            simultaneously and independently control four individual modulator assemblies. When vehicle power is
            supplied to the EC-17, a modulator "chuff" test is performed. When the brake pedal is depressed while the
            ECU is powered up, the modulator "chuff" test can be heard. This test will verify if the modulator is
            connected correctly and functional. The modulators will exhaust air in the sequence of rightfront, left
            front, right rear, and left rear. If they do not follow this sequence, proceed with modulator
            troubleshooting. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04038_2.xml" xrefid="f0403804">correct pin to pin wiring</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403806" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403806.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 6. Modulators</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>An antilock dash light through an electrical relay is connected to, and controlled by, the EC-17 and
            serves as a means of advising the driver of the condition of the antilock system.
        </para>
        <para>Two control link connections to the engine or transmission retarder and its relay are provided on the
            EC-17. One control link or the other can be utilized, but not both on the same vehicle. The hardware for one
            control link conforms to S.A.E. standard 1708 and the protocol, or coded language used, conforms to S.A.E.
            standard J1922.
        </para>
        <para>The other control link conforms to S.A.E. standard J1939. Use of a control link allows the EC-17 to
            temporarily disable the retarder during certain modes of operation. While the EC-17 is capable of this
            function, and connections are provided, it is not always used. Use of the retarder disable function is not
            essential but highly recommended for vehicles equipped with a retarder.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The EC-17 can also disable the retarder using the same S.A.E. J1922 or S.A.E. J1939 protocol it
                    uses to control the traction control, engine torque limiting feature. For this redundant retarder
                    disable to function, the EC-17 must be connected to the engine control module (as would be the case
                    if the EC-17 is programmed for the traction control, torque limiting feature).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The diagnostic link enables the EC-17 to "report" its operating condition to an external computer using
            the Bendix diagnostic communications interface hardware in response to certain commands it receives from
            software like Bendix ACom for Windows. The EC-17 diagnostic link hardware conforms to S.A.E. standard J1708.
            The protocol, or coded language used, conforms to S.A.E. standard J1587. While connections are provided for
            this function, it is not always used. The use of the diagnostic link is essential for the servicing and
            reconfiguration of the EC-17.
        </para>
        <para>If the EC-17 is programmed for traction control, it contains the following outputs:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>A connection to the engine's electronic control module allows the EC-17 to reduce engine torque
                    under certain circumstances.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A traction dash light is connected to and controlled by the EC-17 and serves as a means of
                    advising the driver of the condition of the traction control system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A connection to the traction solenoid (located in the upper portion of the antilock traction relay
                    valve is provided via a
                    <hotlnk document="s04038_1.xml" xrefid="f0403803">2 pin Deutsch connector</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
