<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - COMPONENT DESCRIPTION/OPERATION - ANTILOCK HOLD</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ANTILOCK HOLD</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402314">Figure 14</hotlnk>
            .
        </para>
        <figure id="f0402314" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0402314" filename="../figg04/g0402314.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. M-21 Antilock Holding Position</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                <callout1>3. EXHAUST SOLENOID</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BRAKE VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>5. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. SUPPLY SOLENOID</callout1>
                <callout1>7. SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>8. SUPPLY DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                <callout1>9. BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>11. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The antilock controller will place the M-21 in the Hold position when it senses that the correct wheel
            speed (braking force) has been reached. The antilock controller will also place the M-21 in the Hold
            position, prior to entering the Re-Apply, when it finds recovery from a locked wheel condition. In this mode
            of operation, the M-21 supply solenoid remains energized, while the exhaust solenoid is de-energized.
        </para>
        <para>De-energizing the exhaust solenoid opens its inlet and closes its exhaust. Opening the exhaust solenoid
            inlet allows application air to flow to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, which then seals the
            exhaust passage. With the exhaust diaphragm seated, further exhaust of brake chamber air pressure is
            prevented. Because the supply solenoid remains energized, the supply diaphragm remains seated, thus
            preventing application air from flowing to the delivery port and out to the brake chamber. The M-21 can
            enter the Antilock Exhaust or Re-apply mode from the Antilock Hold mode.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
