<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 550 AND TU-FLO 750 - REMOVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVE</title>
        <para>These instructions are general and are intended to be a guide; in some cases additional preparations and
            precautions are necessary.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Block the wheels of the vehicle and drain the air pressure from all the reservoirs in the
                system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain the engine cooling system and the cylinder head of the compressor. Identify and
                disconnect all air, water and oil lines leading to the compressor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the governor and any supporting bracketry attached to the compressor and note their
                positions on the compressor to aid in reassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the discharge and inlet fittings, if applicable, and note their position on the
                compressor to aid in reassembly.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If compressor is equipped with rear mounted fuel pump, note location of fuel lines.
                Disconnect fuel lines. After air compressor has been removed from engine, scribe fuel pump in relation
                to compressor and remove fuel pump.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the flange or base mounting bolts and remove the compressor from the vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the drive gear(s) or pulley from the compressor crankshaft using a gear puller.
                Inspect the pulley or gear and associated parts for visible wear or damage. Since these parts are
                precision fitted, they must be replaced if they are worn or damaged.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
