<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: MIDLAND MODELS EL-1300 AND EL-1600 - DIAGNOSIS AND TESTING (COMPRESSOR ON ENGINE)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSIS AND TESTING (COMPRESSOR ON ENGINE)</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If the compressor is belt-driven, and the drive pulley is removed or replaced during service, it
                    must be replaced with the same size pulley. A different size pulley will affect compressor output,
                    and would also require a different size drive belt.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Run the compressor at 1250 rpm pumping against 100 psi pressure for five minutes. This time should be used
            to adjust and test the governor. During this test, check for oil and air leakage, overheating and excessive
            noise. Open reservoir drain valve and decrease the pressure in the air tank to zero. Close the drain valve
            and check the build-up time from zero to 100 psi in the air tank.
        </para>
        <para>The build-up time must not exceed 30 seconds per 1000 cubic inches of tank volume for the EL-1300 air
            compressor and 24 seconds for the EL-1600. To determine the allowable build-up time, use the following
            formula:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">EL-1300 allowable build-up time (seconds) = air tank volume in cubic inches x .030.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">EL-1600 allowable build-up time (seconds) = air tank volume in cubic inches x .024.</para>
        </step1>
        <para>After completing testing, set governor to recommended air pressure 120 psi (&#177; 5 psi).</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
