<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - DIAGNOSTICS - PRELIMINARY INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PRELIMINARY INSPECTION</title>
        <para>When servicing the ABS, the following steps should be followed in order. Failure to follow these steps may
            result in the loss of important diagnostic data and may lead to difficult and time consuming diagnostic
            procedures:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform a preliminary diagnostic inspection. This should include:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection of the master cylinder fluid reservoir for proper fluid levels and signs of
                        leaks.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection of the EHCU for any leaks or wiring damage.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection for loose or damaged wheel bearings that may allow a wheel to wobble.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection of the wheel speed sensor and speed sensor wiring.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verification that tires meet legal tread depth requirements.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform the preliminary system check found in this section. If any diagnostic trouble codes
                (DTCs) are displayed, note the last malfunction that occurred. Diagnose and repair this malfunction
                first.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no DTCs or mechanical component malfunctions are present, or if the failure is
                intermittent and not reproducible, test drive the vehicle while using the automatic snapshot feature of
                the EZ-Tech. Perform normal acceleration, stopping and turning maneuvers. If this does not reproduce the
                malfunction, perform an ABS stop, on a low coefficient surface such as gravel, from approximately 48-50
                km/h (30-50 mph) while triggering the snapshot mode on any ABS DTC.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Once all system malfunctions have been corrected, clear the ABS DTCs and test drive the
                vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
