<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ABS BLEEDING</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This special procedure is normally only required when replacing the HCU or the ABS has been
                        activated when air is suspected in the brake lines.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following steps outline the two person procedure:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Gain access to the system bleed screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin by bleeding the system at the right rear wheel, then left rear, then front
                    wheels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a clear hose on the bleed screw. Immerse the opposite end of the hose into a
                    container partially filled with clean DOT 3 Brake fluid. Install a clear hose on the bleed screw.
                    Immerse the opposite end of the hose into a container partially filled with clean DOT 3 Brake fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Have an assistant pump the brakes and then slowly press the brake pedal until it reaches
                    full travel and hold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the bleed screw 1/2 to 1 full turn to let air out of system. Close bleed screw
                    before all pressure is released.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Have your assistant release the brake pedal and wait 10-15 seconds for the master
                    cylinder pistons to return to home position.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 4 through 6 until clean, air free, brake fluid is present at each of the
                    wheel bleed screws. (This procedure may use more than a pint of fluid per wheel. Check the master
                    cylinder fluid level every 4 to 6 strokes of the brake pedal to avoid running the system dry).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-bleed all four wheels using steps 4 through 7 to remove the remaining air from the
                    brake system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the EZ-Tech or PRO-LINK 9000 to run the "Zero-Speed System Test" or "Dealer's Bleed
                    Test" four times consecutively while applying the brake pedal firmly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-bleed all four wheels using steps 4 through 7 to remove the remaining air from the
                    brake system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evaluate the brake pedal feel before attempting to drive the vehicle and re-bleed as
                    many times as necessary to obtain appropriate pedal feel.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_57.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_59.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
