<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - EC-30 OUTPUTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EC-30 OUTPUTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Modulators</title>
            <para>Bendix ABS modulators (M-21, M-22 or M-30) are controlled by the EC-30 to modify driver applied air
                pressure to the service brakes during ABS or ATC activation. See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404306">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                for illustration. The ABS modulator, an electro-pneumatic control valve, is the last valve that air
                passes through on its way to the brake chamber. The modulator hold and exhaust solenoids are activated
                to precisely modify the brake pressure during ABS. The hold solenoid is normally open and the exhaust
                solenoid is normally closed. The EC-30 is able to control four individual modulator assemblies. For ABS
                modulator connector pin locations see the EC-30 system schematic,
                <hotlnk document="s04043_25.xml" xrefid="f0404313">Figure 13</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404306" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. M-30 Modulator</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Modulator</title>
            <para>Premium EC-30 models configured for differential braking ATC will activate the ATC modulator during
                ATC situations. The ATC modulator is an electrically controlled air valve integral to the ATR valve.
                Pins D2 and D3, of the 18-pin connector, control the ATC modulator. A connection to the ATC modulator is
                provided via a two-pin Deutsch connector from the ATR valve. See
                <hotlnk document="s04043_4.xml" xrefid="f0404302">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>The EC-30 controls an ABS warning lamp to indicate the ABS unit status. The EC-30 provides a ground
                signal to activate an ABS warning lamp relay and turn the ABS lamp off. The actual ABS warning lamp is
                connected to the normally-closed contacts of the relay in order to illuminate in a fail-safe manner
                during an ABS ECU failure. Pin E3, of the 30-pin connector, is the ABS warning lamp output.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939 ABS Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to broadcast the ABS status over the SAE J1939 serial communications link.
                A vehicle dash controller directly controls the ABS warning lamp. When configured in this manner, there
                is no wire installed in pin E3 of the 30-pin connector. If J1939 communications is lost between the
                EC-30 and the vehicle dash controller, the dash controller will activate the ABS warning lamp.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Retarder Disable Relay</title>
            <para>The EC-30 controls an engine or transmission retarder disable relay. The retarder activation wire is
                routed through the normally-closed contacts of the relay. The EC-30 provides a ground path to activate
                the relay and interrupt power to the retarder during ABS operation. This output may also connect
                directly to a transmission ECU. Pin K1, of the 30-pin connector, is the retarder disable relay output.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/J1922 Retarder Disable</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to interrupt the engine or transmission retarder over the SAE J1939 serial
                communications link (J1922 for some service replacement models). The retarder will be disabled during
                ABS via the serial communications. When configured in this manner, there is no wire installed in pin K1
                of the 30-pin connector. Use of the retarder disable function via the serial link may be essential to
                ABS performance and is highly recommended for vehicles equipped with a capable retarder.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/J1922 Torque Converter Lock Disable</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to interrupt the automatic transmission torque converter lock function,
                over the SAE J1939 serial communications link (J1922 for some service replacement models). The converter
                lock will be disabled during ABS via the serial communications. Use of the torque converter lock disable
                function may be essential to ABS performance and is highly recommended for vehicles equipped with a
                capable transmission.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Trailer ABS Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>EC-30 models with PLC can be configured to control a trailer ABS warning lamp (located in the dash)
                that indicates the status of the trailer ABS unit of one or more trailers or dollies. The EC-30 directly
                controls the trailer ABS warning lamp by providing a ground path when the lamp is to be activated. Pin
                E2, of the 30-pin connector, is the trailer ABS warning lamp output.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/J1587 Trailer ABS Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to broadcast the trailer ABS status over the SAE J1939 or the SAE J1587
                serial communications links. In this case, a vehicle controller will directly operate the trailer ABS
                warning lamp. When configured in this manner, there is no wire installed in pin E2 of the 30-pin
                connector. In the event that communications is lost between the EC-30 and the vehicle controller, the
                dash controller will activate the trailer ABS warning lamp.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/J1587 Diagnostic Link (J1939)</title>
            <para>The EC-30 provides a J1708/J1587 diagnostic link to communicate with the vehicle and various
                diagnostic tools. Diagnostics, system configuration, data uploading and downloading and other functions
                can be performed using this link. The EC-30 is supported by tools such as Bendix ACom for Windows*
                (*Windows is a registered trademark of Microsoft Corporation), the Bendix DCI hand held tool and the
                MPSI ProLink. The EC-30 may also provide diagnostics using the SAE J1939 serial communications link.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/1922 Engine Torque Reduction - ATC</title>
            <para>The EC-30 can be configured to reduce engine torque over the SAE J1939 (J1922 for some service
                replacement models) serial communications link. The EC-30 will send a J1939 message to reduce engine
                torque during ATC operation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Active/Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>Premium EC-30 models configured for ATC can control an ATC active/warning lamp to indicate the status
                of the ATC system. The ATC active/warning lamp flashes when ATC is active and stays on if an ATC system
                fault is detected or ATC is disabled by the ATC enable/disable switch. The EC-30 directly controls the
                ATC active/warning lamp by providing a ground path when the lamp is to be activated. Pin C2, of the
                30-pin connector, is the ATC active/warning lamp output.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939 ATC Active/Warning Lamp</title>
            <para>Premium EC-30 models configured for ATC can be configured to broadcast the status of the ATC
                active/warning lamp over the SAE J1939 serial communications link. In this case a vehicle dash
                controller directly operates the ATC active/ warning lamp. When configured in this manner, there is no
                wire installed in pin C2 of the 30-pin connector. In the event that J1939 communications are lost
                between the EC-30 and the vehicle dash controller, the dash controller will activate the ATC
                active/warning lamp.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
