<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - ASSEMBLY</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CYLINDER HEAD</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04004_19.xml" xrefid="f0400411">Figure 11</hotlnk>for numbers in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">lf the discharge valve stop (15) was removed and must be replaced, a sealant such as
                    <emph type="bold">Locktite Retaining Compound #75</emph>, must be applied to the stop and its
                    corresponding bore in the cylinder head. Before applying the sealant, make certain that the press
                    fit between the discharge valve stop outside diameter and the valve stop bore in the cylinder head
                    is a minimum of .0013 inches (.033 mm) and a maximum of .0028 inches (.07112 mm). lf this fit cannot
                    be maintained, a new cylinder head body must be used. Be sure to completely support the outside top
                    of the cylinder head casting, while pressing in the replacement stops.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The cylinder head must be supported in a fashion that allows the machined head surface to
                            be.parallel to the arbor press bed and perpendicular to the press ram. This is necessary to
                            permit the discharge valve stop to be installed squarely in its bore and to minimize the
                            possibility of "cocking".
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the discharge valve spring (16), discharge valve (17) and valve seat (18). Using
                    a 9/16" Allen wrench tighten the discharge valve seat as specified in the Torque Chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test for leakage by the discharge valve. Apply 100 psi (690 kPa) of air pressure through
                    the cylinder head discharge port and apply a soap solution to the discharge valve and seat. A slight
                    leakage in the form of soap bubbles is permissible. lf excessive leakage is found, leave the air
                    pressure applied and with the use of a fiber or hardwood dowel and a hammer, tap the discharge valve
                    off its seat several times. This will help the valve to seat and should reduce the leakage. With the
                    air pressure still applied at the discharge port of the cylinder head, check for leakage around the
                    discharge valve stop exposed on the top of the cylinder head casting. No leakage is permitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">lf the unloader piston bushing (2) was removed, press in a new bushing following the
                    same pressing procedures given in Step 1. The inside diameter of the unloader piston bushing must be
                    between .7497 inches (19.0mm) and .7460 inches (18.9mm) after pressing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a 3/8" Allen wrench install the unloader stop (11) and 0-ring (13) in the head.
                    Tighten as specified in the Torque Chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the unloader piston (4) and 0-ring in the head so that the short stem of the
                    piston rests on the unloader stop.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the unloader piston spring (5), small end first, on the stem of the unloader
                    piston. Install the metal (copper) unloader gasket (6) so that it rests on the shoulder of the
                    unloader cavity. Install the inlet valve seat on top of the unloader gasket with its beveled side
                    visible. Make certain the large coils of the piston spring rest within the recess of the inlet valve
                    seat on the side opposite the bevel. Install the inlet valve so that it rests on the beveled side of
                    the valve seat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the inlet valve spring (9) on the inlet valve stop (10) and install the stop in
                    the head. Using a spanner wrench, tighten the inlet valve stop as specified in the
                    <hotlnk document="s04004_42.xml" xrefid="hl0400405">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 100 psi (689.5 kPa) air pressure to the unloader port of the governor mounting pad
                    and note Inlet valve is driven away from its seat. Using a soap solution, test for air leakage at
                    the valve stop. No leakage is permitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
