<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - TROUBLESHOOTING - DIAGNOSTIC LEDS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DIAGNOSTIC LEDS</title>
        <para>There are nine LEDs, plus a magnetically actuated reset switch in the EC-15 diagnostic window (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0402315">Figure 15</hotlnk>
            ). The first five LEDs locate a problem to a specific area of the vehicle, while the last four indicate the
            problem component or its wiring. The LEDs are software driven and are either ON or OFF depending upon their
            monitor function.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0402315" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0402315" filename="../figg04/g0402315.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 15. EC-15 LED Window</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. LED WINDOW</callout1>
                <callout1>2. EC-15 CONTROLLER</callout1>
                <callout1>3. LEDs</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Right and left, front and rear are determined from the driver's seat. Left front is therefore the
                    corner closest to the driver.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'FRONT' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring. This LED
            (when ON) indicates a defect in either the right or left front modulator or sensor circuits. The defect may
            be either the wiring or components. The FRONT LED lights at the same time
            <emph type="underscr">as either</emph>
            the RIGHT or LEFT LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the MOD or SENS LED.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'MID' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED is not used in troubleshooting the ECU and should only turn on when a magnet is held on the
            RESET switch.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'REAR' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring. This LED
            (when ON) indicates a defect in either the right or left rear modulator or sensor circuits. The defect may
            be either the wiring or components. The REAR LED illuminates at the same time
            <emph type="underscr">as either</emph>
            the RIGHT or LEFT LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the MOD or SENS LED.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'RIGHT' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring. This LED
            (when ON) indicates a defect on the right side (passenger) of the vehicle. The defect is in either the
            modulator or sensor circuits. The defect may be either wiring or the components. The RIGHT LED turns on at
            the same time
            <emph type="underscr">as either</emph>
            the FRONT or REAR LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the MOD or SENS LED.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'LEFT' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate the location of a problem component or its wiring. This LED
            (when ON) indicates a defect on the left side (driver side) of the vehicle. The defect is in either the
            modulator or sensor circuits. The defect may be either wiring or the components. The LEFT LED illuminates at
            the same time
            <emph type="underscr">as either</emph>
            the FRONT or REAR LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the MOD or SENS LED.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'MOD' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate a permanent or intermittent open or short circuit in the
            solenoids of one of the four modulators or the wiring connecting a modulator to the system. When this LED is
            on,
            <emph type="underscr">either the</emph>
            RIGHT OR LEFT LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the FRONT OR REAR LED will also turn on to identify the defect location.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'SENS' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED turns ON and stays ON to indicate permanent or intermittent failure. The failures indicated
            are: open or shorted wheel speed sensor, open or shorted wheel speed sensor wiring, wheel speed signal not
            present or is not proper. When this LED is ON,
            <emph type="underscr">either the</emph>
            RIGHT OR LEFT LED
            <emph type="underscr">and either</emph>
            the FRONT OR REAR LED will also be ON to identify the defect location.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'ECU' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Red LED, when ON, indicates that the controller itself has failed. It stays ON for all ECU failures,
            except low voltage. For voltages less than 9V DC, this LED turns on to indicate the controller is
            inoperative; however, when the voltage again exceeds 9V DC, the LED will TURN ITSELF OFF.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'VOLT' LED</emph>
        </para>
        <para>This Green LED turns ON and stays ON during vehicle operation to indicate that vehicle power is reaching
            the controller. If vehicle power is out of range for proper operation (below 11 vdc or above 17 vdc) this
            LED will flash until power returns to the proper operating range.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">'RESET'</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Beneath the RESET area of the window display is a magnetically sensitive switch that is used to reset the
            diagnostic system. The device will respond to a magnet (magnet strength must be capable of picking up 3
            ounces). With the vehicle key at IGN, holding a magnet against the RESET will cause all LEDs to turn on as
            long as the magnet is held against it. Resetting can only be done with the key at IGN.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_35.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023_37.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
