<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX 2150 - OPERATION - INLET CHECK VALVE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INLET CHECK VALVE</title>
        <para>An inlet check valve is used on some naturally aspirated BX-2150 compressors (never with pressurized
            induction, see number 3 above) to prevent inlet oil misting during the unloaded cycle. The inlet check valve
            is mounted directly at the inlet cavity of the compressor. lt consists of three parts, the inlet gasket, the
            inlet check valve reed, and the inlet check valve seat (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400408">Figure 8</hotlnk>). During the compression cycle, the inlet check valve reed is
            drawn away from its seat uncovering three inlet holes which allows air to flow into the compressor inlet
            cavity. A machined stop in the cylinder head inlet cavity limits the travel of the inlet check valve reed.
            in the unloaded cycle the inlet check valve reed rests on its seat covering the three inlet holes. Air from
            within the compressor is prevented from exiting the inlet cavity.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400408" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400408" filename="../figg04/G0400408.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Inlet Check Valve</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1.CYLINDER HEAD</callout1>
                <callout1>2.GASKET</callout1>
                <callout1>3.CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>4.GASKET</callout1>
                <callout1>5.CHECK VALVE SEAT</callout1>
                <callout1>6.HALF MOON INDENT FACES CHECK VALVE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The inlet check valve may only be used in conjunction with cylinder heads incorporating the machined inlet
            check valve stop in the inlet cavity. Inlet gasket (Bendix 243430) is required since its thickness
            contributes to the minimum reed travel required. Either side of the inlet check valve reed may be installed
            next to the gasket; however, the free end (tip) of the inlet check valve reed must coincide with the
            machined inlet cavity stop in the cylinder head. The inlet check valve seat must be installed, so that the
            two "half moon" indentations are on the side facing the inlet check valve as illustrated in
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400408">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04004.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
