<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>RECONDITIONING BRAKE DRUMS AND SHOES - BRAKE LINING - INSPECTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="2">
        <title>INSPECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Vehicle brake systems require the correct lining material to perform as originally designed. The type
                of lining material that is specified is based on several technical considerations and DOT braking
                performance regulations. Always use the lining specified by International.
            </para>
            <para>Check brake lining for possible out-of-square condition which would indicate a distorted shoe and/or
                bent backing plate (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400722">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400722" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400722" filename="../figg04/G0400722.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Brake Lining Inspection</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Eaton</title>
            <para>Standard production (EB) brakes use different lining assemblies than Extended Service (ES) brakes.
                Because of the parts differences, normal wear of each type creates its own unique wear pattern.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400723">Figure 23</hotlnk>shows the difference between (EB) and (ES) lining when new
                and after normal worn.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400723" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400723" filename="../figg04/G0400723.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. EB and ES Lining - Eaton</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rockwell</title>
            <para>Combination lining sets with different friction ratings on the primary and secondary shoes are
                sometimes used. When combination friction lining sets are used, the lining blocks must be installed in
                the correct location on the brake shoes.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always follow the instructions supplied with the replacement combination linings for correct
                        installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04007.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
