<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - OPERATION - WARNING INDICATORS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048301" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WARNING INDICATORS</title>
        <para>Six indicators located in the Electronic Gauge Cluster (EGC), are used to display the status of the brake
            system. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s04048_12.xml" xrefid="f0404820">FIGURE 20</hotlnk>
            . Four of the indicators identify conditions that may require service. In addition, a warning buzzer is
            sounded for certain conditions. The following table includes brief descriptions of how each of the
            indicators is energized. In the event that a lit indicator is the result of a malfunction, diagnostic codes
            identifying the source of the malfunction will be stored in the ECU memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic
            codes is explained in Section 5,
            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
            . Although the following table lists possible malfunctions for each indicator, some malfunctions such as
            loss of data link communications, will result in more than one indicator being lit. When the IGN key is
            turned on a bulb check is performed. The indicators in the gauge cluster will light for about 3 seconds,
            then turn off. (NOTE: The PARK BRAKE indicator will remain lit until the park brake is released.)
        </para>
        <table id="t0404802" tblwidth="pg-wide">
            <title>Warning Indicators</title>
            <tgroup cols="4">
                <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.31*"/>
                <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="0.39*"/>
                <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.31*"/>
                <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.55*"/>
                <spanspec namest="COLSPEC0" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN3"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="COLSPEC0" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1" valign="bottom" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">INDICATOR</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry valign="bottom" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">SYSTEM CONDITION BEING INDICATED</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">BRAKE /</emph>
                            </para>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">BRAKE PRESSURE</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Indicator differs by model year.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Half system failure. A sensor in the HCU has detected low pressure (&#60;1550 psi) in
                                the accumulator for either the front or rear brake circuit.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data
                                link signal to the EGC commanding it to turn on the indicator and sound the warning
                                buzzer.
                            </para>
                            <para>If the fault is detected in the front brake circuit, once the parking brake has been
                                set, it will not release until this fault is repaired and the ignition is cycled.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- FLASHING</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Full system failure. Sensors in the HCU have detected low pressure (&#60;1550 psi) in
                                the accumulators for both the front and rear brake circuits.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data
                                link signal to the EGC commanding it to turn on the indicator and sound the warning
                                buzzer.
                            </para>
                            <para>The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal to the ECM. Once vehicle speed drops below 25
                                mph, engine limiting will limit the vehicle speed to 25 mph or less. In addition, once
                                the parking brake has been set, it will not release until this fault is repaired and the
                                ignition is cycled.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>System pressures are in normal range.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">BRAKE FLUID</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Low brake fluid level detected in the Master Cylinder reservoir.</para>
                            <para>The fluid level sensor on the MC reservoir sends a signal to the ECU. The ECU sends a
                                J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data link signal to the
                                EGC commanding it to turn on the indicator.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Brake fluid level detected in the Master Cylinder reservoir is at or above MIN.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">ABS</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>An ABS related fault has been detected by the ECU.</para>
                            <para>-OR-</para>
                            <para>Communications between the ECU and the ESC/BC have been lost.</para>
                            <para>-OR-</para>
                            <para>The ECU is not receiving power.</para>
                            <para>When the ECU detects an ABS related fault, it sends a J1939 data link signal to the
                                ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data link signal to the EGC commanding it to turn on
                                the indicator.
                            </para>
                            <para>When the ESC/BC does not receive a communication from the ECU within a predetermined
                                period of time, it sends a J1939 data link signal to the EGC commanding it to turn on
                                the indicator.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The ECU is receiving power and is communicating with the ESC/BC, and no ABS related
                                faults have been detected by the ECU.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">PARK BRAKE</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Park brake is applied. Travel switch on SAHR canister detects that park brake is
                                applied.
                            </para>
                            <para>Switch sends signal to ECU. The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The
                                ESC/BC sends a J1939 data link signal to the EGC commanding it to turn on the indicator
                                and sound the chime once.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Park brake is not applied.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">SERVICE PARK BRAKE</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- FLASHING/SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>A Park brake related fault has been detected by the ECU.</para>
                            <para>The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data
                                link signal to the EGC commanding it to flash the indicator and sound the alarm for
                                approximately 20 seconds. After 20 seconds the signal sent by the ESC/BC will command
                                the EGC to turn the indicator on continuously, and turn the alarm off.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>No park brake faults detected by the ECU.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN2">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">TRAC CTRL</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry></entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- SOLID ON</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The TRAC CTRL indicator will be continuously lit whenever:</para>
                            <para>A traction control related fault has been detected.</para>
                            <para>- OR -</para>
                            <para>The ATC system is operating correctly, and an ATC event is occurring.</para>
                            <para>When the ECU experiences an ATC event or detects an ATC related fault, it sends a
                                J1939 data link signal to the ESC/BC. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data link signal to the
                                EGC commanding it to turn on the indicator.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- FLASHING</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The TRAC CTRL indicator will be flashing whenever the Mud and Snow mode has been
                                selected using the traction control switch (switch indicator lit).
                            </para>
                            <para>The ESC/BC senses the position of the dash switch via the switch data link. The ESC/BC
                                sends a J1939 data link signal to the ECU. The ECU sends a J1939 data link signal back
                                to the ESC/BC indicating that the Mud and Snow mode is selected, and that no ATC related
                                faults have been detected. The ESC/BC sends a J1939 data link signal to the EGC
                                commanding it to flash the indicator.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry></entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3">
                            <para>- OFF</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The ATC system is operating correctly, the Mud and Snow mode has not been selected,
                                and the vehicle is not experiencing an ATC event.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048300.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
