<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - HOSES, TUBING AND CONNECTIONS - TRAILER BRAKE HOSE ASSEMBLIES AND CONNECTORS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TRAILER BRAKE HOSE ASSEMBLIES AND CONNECTORS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Trailer brake hose assemblies are used for making flexible connections between components which change
                position in relation to each other, or for making flexible connections between the tractor and trailer.
                Hose lines or couplings at the rear of tractor are marked by tags identifying them as "SERVICE" or
                "EMERGENCY."
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Every six months, all air connections should be checked and tightened if leaking (refer to on this
                page). Once each year, all tubing and hoses should be inspected for cuts, dents, kinks, swelling,
                chafing or crimping. Replace tubing if these conditions are found.
            </para>
            <para>Be sure to inspect trailer brake hoses and hose coupling packing rings and replace if necessary.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>If any evidence is found that an air line is restricted, remove and blow through it in both directions
                to be sure the passage is not obstructed. Inspect piping restrictions caused by dents or kinks. Damaged
                pipes should be replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Test</title>
            <para>With the air system fully charged, the governor cut out and brakes applied, use a soap solution at air
                lines, hoses and fittings to check for leakage. There should be no leakage. Leakage at a tubing fitting
                is sometimes corrected by tightening the fitting nut. If this fails to correct the leakage, replace the
                tubing, sleeve or fitting, the tubing or hose. Leakage at hose connections is sometimes corrected by
                tightening the connector nut. If this fails, replace the connector, hose or both.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_148.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400209.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
