<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - MODULAR CONTROL VALVE (MV-3) - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0400217" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation Test</title>
            <para>Perform the Operation Test after rebuilding valve assembly.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                        pressures, gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>When the Operation Test on the modular control valve is performed on the vehicle, both the Leakage and
                Operation checks will be accomplished simultaneously.
            </para>
            <para>In some instances it will be necessary to remove the instrument panel bezel and the access panel on
                the instrument panel to gain access to the valve. Block wheels of vehicle while performing the Operation
                Test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With both control knobs out, charge the air brake system to 65 psi and check for
                    leakage. No leakage is permitted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With supply pressure still at 65 psi, push the red knob in. The knob must stay in.
                    Leakage at the exhaust port must not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 5 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the yellow knob in. With the engine off, actuate the foot valve several times to
                    deplete the air supply. The red knob must pop out when the reservoir with the highest pressure
                    reaches 40 &#177; 5 psi. If air is depleted quickly, the red knob could pop immediately. Leakage at
                    exhaust port must not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 5 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">.With the engine off, actuate foot valve, depleting additional air. Air must start to
                    escape from the exhaust port when the air pressure in the reservoir with the higher pressure reaches
                    30 &#177; 5 psi. The yellow knob must pop out at this time.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine off, deplete the air system further by activating the foot valve. At 25
                    &#177; 5 psi, the yellow knob must pop out and maintain supply pressure. Leakage at exhaust port
                    should not exceed 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 5 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rebuild the supply pressure to at least 40 psi. Push in the yellow knob; the yellow knob
                    must remain in. Leakage at the exhaust port should not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) bubble in 5 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge the system to 120 psi and push both knobs in. Pull the red knob out. The yellow
                    knob must remain in.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the red knob in and pull the yellow knob out. The red knob must pop out almost
                    instantaneously.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a gauge to monitor tractor spring brake delivery pressure. Apply 120 psi to both
                    primary and secondary reservoirs. Push in the yellow knob. Delivery pressure should equal the
                    pressure in the primary reservoir. Reduce the pressure in the primary reservoir. Delivery pressure
                    and primary reservoir pressure should descend together to 105 to 90 psi, at which point the dual
                    circuit supply (double check) valve shuttle should switch to the secondary reservoir and delivery
                    pressure should increase to the secondary reservoir pressure. After the primary reservoir pressure
                    is reduced to zero, a leakage of a 1/2 inch (12.7 mm) diameter bubble in 5 seconds is permitted at
                    the primary reservoir opening. Close the leak which had been created at the primary reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leaving the yellow knob in, recharge the secondary reservoir to 120 psi. The delivery
                    pressure should also read 120 psi. Recharge the primary reservoir to 100 psi. Slowly vent the
                    secondary reservoir. As the secondary reservoir pressure and the delivery line pressure descend
                    between 115 and 105 psi, the dual circuit supply (double check) valve shuttle should switch to the
                    primary reservoir, causing the delivery line pressure to adjust to the primary reservoir pressure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all vents or leakage points and charge both reservoirs to 120 psi. Position the
                    red knob out and the yellow knob in. Develop a leak in the spring brake delivery line and hold the
                    yellow knob in. The primary reservoir pressure must reduce to zero and the secondary reservoir
                    pressure to 20 to 30 psi. The dual circuit supply valve shuttle should cycle several times during
                    this leak-down period.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_92.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_94.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
