<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - OPERATION - BP-R1 Bobtail
        Brake Proportioning Relay Valve
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="6">
        <title>BP-R1 Bobtail Brake Proportioning Relay Valve</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The following topics refer to the bobtail brake proportioning valve.</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Initial Charging</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401209">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401209" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401209" filename="../figg04/g0401209.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Initial Charging</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CONTROL PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SERVICE PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SERVICE PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>During the initial build up of tractor system air pressure, supply air flows through internal body and
                cover passages in the BP-R1 to the blend back piston.
            </para>
            <para>Activating the trailer air supply valve (dash control with red octagonal button) simultaneously
                charges the trailer and the BP-R1 control port. Air entering the BP-R1 control port causes the
                proportioning piston to move toward its stop in the cover. The integral inlet and exhaust valve is
                carried along with the piston until it seats and seals the exhaust passage. Continued movement of the
                proportioning piston opens the inlet valve. With the tractor and trailer air system fully charged, the
                vehicle may be operated.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brakes Applying (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401210">Figure 10</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401210" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401210" filename="../figg04/g0401210.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Service Brakes Applying</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REAR AXLE AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. AIR RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Brake application air enters the BP-R1 service port and is conducted through the service piston to the
                exhaust diaphragm which flexes in response to the incoming air and seals the exhaust passage in the
                exhaust piston. Air flows around the exhaust diaphragm then through the center of both the blend back
                and proportioning pistons to the inlet and exhaust valve. Flowing around the inlet valve, application
                air moves through a passage in the cover to the top of the service relay piston. In response to air
                pressure, the relay piston moves into contact with the exhaust portion of the inlet and exhaust valve.
                With the exhaust passage sealed, continued movement of the piston unseats the inlet portion of the inlet
                and exhaust valve, allowing supply air from the reservoir to flow out the BP-R1 delivery ports to the
                brake chambers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brakes Holding (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401211">Figure 11</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401211" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401211" filename="../figg04/g0401211.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Service Brakes Holding</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REAR AXLE AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. AIR RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The air pressure being delivered to the brake chambers is also present beneath the relay piston.
            </para>
            <para>When the air pressure above and below the relay piston is equal, the piston moves slightly allowing
                the inlet valve to return to its seat. The exhaust valve remains closed. With both the inlet and exhaust
                valves closed, air pressure in the brake chambers is held stable and neither increases nor decreases.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brakes Releasing (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401212">Figure 12</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401212" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401212" filename="../figg04/g0401212.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Service Brakes Releasing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REAR AXLE AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. AIR RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the brake application is released, air pressure in the service port of the BP-R1 returns to the
                brake control valve (foot valve) and is exhausted. Air from above the relay piston flows back through
                the proportioning, blend back and service pistons to the exhaust diaphragm. If the service brakes are
                rapidly released, the diaphragm flexes in response to the returning air and opens the exhaust. If the
                brakes are slowly released, service air pressure will flow through the slot behind the diaphragm and
                back to the brake control valve (foot valve). As air pressure is reduced above the relay piston,
                pressure beneath it lifts the piston away from the exhaust valve and opens the exhaust passage. Air from
                the service brake chambers returns to the BP-R1 and flows out the open exhaust.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Application (Bobtail Tractor Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401213">Figure 13</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401213" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401213" filename="../figg04/g0401213.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Service Application</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REAR AXLE AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. AIR RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the trailer air supply valve (dash control with red octagonal button) is pulled out to disconnect
                the trailer, air in the BP-R1 control port and trailer supply line is exhausted to atmosphere. During
                bobtail tractor operation, service application air enters the BP-R1 service port causing the exhaust
                diaphragm to seal the exhaust port. Service application air passing through the blend back piston exerts
                a force on the full effective diameter of the piston. The blend back piston remains stationary at
                application pressures below approximately 80 psi because of opposing reservoir air acting on the large
                diameter. Application air flowing through the blend back piston also exerts force on the small diameter
                of the proportioning piston while simultaneously flowing through the center of it on its way to the
                inlet and exhaust valve. Service air pressure exerts a force on the larger diameter end of the
                proportioning piston, which opposes the air pressure and spring force exerted on the other end. The
                proportioning piston inlet valve remains open until a preset, initial application pressure has reached
                the relay piston assuring that the foundation brake shoes are brought into contact with the drum. As
                service pressure begins to exceed the preset initial application, the proportioning piston will move
                sufficiently to close its inlet valve without opening the exhaust.
            </para>
            <para>As service air pressure continues to increase, the inlet valve opens as necessary to deliver
                additional, but reduced air pressure to the relay piston, thus to the rear axle brakes. Proportioning
                occurs due to the difference in effective area on each end of the proportioning piston.
            </para>
            <para>Service applications of more than 80 psi cause the blend back piston to begin to move. Service air
                pressure acting on the full diameter of the blend back piston overcomes the resistance of reservoir
                pressure acting on the large diameter of the other side. Above 80 psi, the difference between control
                and delivered air pressure is reduced and "blends back" from a proportioned delivery to a full 1:1
                delivery. Complete "blend back" to a 1:1 delivery is achieved when a full brake application is made, and
                it will occur regardless of reservoir pressure level.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Brakes Releasing (Bobtail Tractor Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401214">Figure 14</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401214" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401214" filename="../figg04/g0401214.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Service Brakes Releasing - Bobtail Tractor Mode</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RELAY PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. REAR AXLE AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. AIR RESERVOIR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the brake application is released, air pressure in the service port of the BP-R1 returns to the
                brake control valve (foot valve) and is exhausted. Air between the closed proportioning piston inlet
                valve and the service piston returns to the exhaust diaphragm. If the release is rapid, the diaphragm
                flexes in response to the returning air and opens the exhaust.
            </para>
            <para>Air from above the relay piston flows back to the proportioning piston, causing it to move. As the
                proportioning piston moves, it unseats the exhaust valve allowing air from above the relay piston to
                escape to the atmosphere. Reducing the air pressure above the relay piston causes pressure beneath it to
                lift the piston away from the exhaust valve. Air from the service brake chambers returns to the BP-R1
                and flows out the open exhaust.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
