<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - DISASSEMBLY - BRAKE GROUPS WITH BACKING PLATE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>BRAKE GROUPS WITH BACKING PLATE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rockwell "T" Series (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400504">Figure 4</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400504" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400504" filename="../figg04/g0400504.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Rockwell "T" Series Brake with Backing Plate</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BACKING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LINING AND SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ANCHOR PINS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ANCHOR PIN RETAINERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ROLLERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. GUIDE PIN ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shoe return spring by using brake pliers, or by using a pry bar or large
                    screwdriver and lifting shoe off the cam. Then remove rollers and retainers (if equipped) from cam
                    end of shoes. Removing rollers first will relieve most of the tension from the return spring,
                    permitting the spring to be disconnected from the shoes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove "C" washers (retainers) from guide pins. Then remove flat washers, cupped washers
                    or coil spring from guide pin. Note position of the spring assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove retainer lock rings from anchor pins. Then remove washers, felt retainers and
                    felts from anchor pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift brake shoes from guide and anchor pins.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The brake shoe anchor pin may now be removed if so desired, by removing the nut and lock
                    washer from the anchor pin, then forcing the anchor pin from the backing plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing the automatic slack adjuster, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master
                        Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With manual slack adjusters, mark the position of slack adjuster in relation to the
                    camshaft and remove clevis pin connecting the brake chamber push rod to the slack adjuster.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the lock ring retaining the slack adjuster to the camshaft, then remove the slack
                    adjuster from the camshaft. Note location of spacers and washers for reassembly purposes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove camshaft from support bracket.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Eaton Brake (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400505">Figure 5</hotlnk>)
            </title>
            <figure id="f0400505" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400505" filename="../figg04/g0400505.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Eaton Brake with Backing Plate</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BACKING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LINING AND SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ROLLERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. RETURN SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SHOE RETAINER CLAMPS</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RETAINER SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. ANCHOR PIN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a large screwdriver or suitable pry bar, lift upper shoe and remove cam roller and
                    retainer (if equipped).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove lower cam roller using the same procedure used for the upper roller.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shoe return spring using a suitable tool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate lower shoe downward and turn to allow disengagement of shoe from shoe retainer
                    clamp. Remove lower shoe and retainer spring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift upper shoe, rotate, and remove from shoe retainer clamp.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cotter pin and clevis pin from air chamber push rod clevis.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing the automatic slack adjuster, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master
                        Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With manual slack adjusters, mark position of slack adjuster in relation to camshaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With manual slack adjusters, if slack adjuster does not clear chamber push rod clevis,
                    depress locking sleeve and turn adjuster nut until slack adjuster is clear of air chamber push rod
                    clevis.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove snap ring, spacer, and washers retaining the slack adjuster to camshaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove slack adjuster from camshaft. If the slack adjuster is difficult to remove, use a
                    suitable puller.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not use a hammer to remove the slack adjuster or camshaft.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove camshaft from air chamber bracket.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_HL0400503.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
