<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - DESCRIPTION - OUTPUTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OUTPUTS</title>
        <para>The M-22
            <emph type="bold">modulator</emph>
            is the means by which the EC-16 controller modifies driver- applied air pressure to the service brakes. The
            modulator is an electrically controlled air valve located near the service actuator(s) it controls. It is
            the last valve that air passes through on its way to the brake actuator. A wiring harness connects the
            modulator to the EC-16 antilock controller. Solenoid valves contained in the modulator provide the
            electrical interface between the EC-16 controller electronics and the air brake system. The EC-16 is able to
            simultaneously and independently control four individual modulator assemblies.
        </para>
        <para>An
            <emph type="bold">antilock dash light</emph>
            and its electrical relay are connected to, and controlled by, the EC-16 and serve as a means of advising the
            driver of the condition of the antilock system (
            <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <para>A connection to the engine or transmission
            <emph type="bold">retarder</emph>
            and its relay is provided on the EC-16, which allows the EC-16 to temporarily disable the retarder during
            certain modes of operation (
            <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>). While the EC-16 is capable of this
            function, and connections are provided, it is not always used.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The EC-16 can also disable the retarder using the same J1922 protocol it uses to control the
                    traction control, engine torque limiting feature. For this redundant retarder disable to function,
                    the EC-16 must be connected to the engine control module (as would be the case if the EC-16 is
                    programmed for the traction control, torque limiting feature).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The
            <emph type="bold">data link</emph>
            enables the EC-16 to "report" its operating condition to a specialized, external computer in response to
            certain commands it receives (
            <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>). The EC-16 diagnostic data link
            hardware conforms to SAE standard J1708. The protocol, or coded language used, conforms to SAE standard
            J1587. There are two connections to the EC-16 devoted to the data link. While connections are provided for
            this function, it is not always used. The data link is not essential for the EC-16 to be functional.
        </para>
        <para>If the EC-16 is programmed for traction control, it contains the following outputs:</para>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>A connection to the
                    <emph type="bold">engine's electronic control module</emph>allows the EC-16 to reduce engine torque
                    under certain circumstances (
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A
                    <emph type="bold">traction dash light</emph>
                    is connected to and controlled by the EC-16 and serves as a means of advising the driver of the
                    condition of the traction control system (
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>A connection to the traction solenoid [located in the upper portion of the antilock traction relay
                    valve (
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403204">Figure 4</hotlnk>) is provided via a 2 pin Deutsch
                    connector.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
