<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE - SERVICE - WEDGE ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="12">
        <title>WEDGE ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wedge assembly from plunger housing by pulling it straight out of the housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401323">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401323" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401323.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Pulling Wedge From Housing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cotter pin from wedge shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401324">Figure 24</hotlnk>) while holding spring compressed by hand.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401324" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401324.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24. 1-1/2 Inch (38.1 mm) Stroke Wedge Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wedge spring washer, wedge spring rubber boot and wedge spring retainer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401325">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401325" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401325.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 25. 1-3/4 Inch (44.45 mm) Stroke Wedge Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a thin-bladed screwdriver between one flat of the wedge head and roller retainer
                    cage. Spread the cage open just far enough to remove the rollers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401326">Figure 26</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401326" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401326.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Removing Rollers</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not attempt to drive the wedge through the rollers and cage or force the rollers
                            through the slightly closed slots of the cage. This will permanently damage the cage.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the roller retainer cage by sliding it off the wedge shaft. Do not mix components
                    from 1-1/2 and 1-3/4 inch (38.1 and 44.45 mm) stroke wedge assemblies.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dust Shields and Backing Plates</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Welded on spider brakes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401327">Figure 27</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401328">Figure 28</hotlnk>) have four-piece dust shields attached to the spider
                    with capscrews and lockwashers. Either one or all of the sections can be removed directly from the
                    brake by removing the capscrews and lockwashers.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401327" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401327.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. RDA Welded on Spider, Bolted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0401328" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401328.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 28. RDA Welded on Spider, Bolted on Plunger Housing</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Most bolted-on spider brakes with two-piece dust shields can be serviced as described in
                    Step 1 after removing wheels, drums and brake shoes. Refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual for brake service.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bolted-on spider brakes with one-piece dust shields will have to be taken off the
                    vehicle for servicing. To remove dust shield from brake, first cage and remove power units, then
                    remove shield-to-spider capscrews and lockwashers. The shields can be replaced with a one- or
                    two-piece dust shield. To cage power unit, refer to ,
                    <hotlnk document="s04013_11.xml" xrefid="x0401304">CAGING AND UNCAGING SPRING BRAKE</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On backing plate-mounted brakes, the backing plate serves as a support for the plunger
                    housing and anchor block as well as a dust shield. For servicing remove complete brake assembly. The
                    complete backing plate will have to be taken off the vehicle by removing the plate-to-spindle flange
                    bolts, nuts and lockwashers. To remove brake assembly refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000
                    Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Plunger Housing Components Service - Disassembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With brake shoes removed, remove guide screws and gaskets from the plunger housing. If
                    brake is automatic adjusting, remove pawl assembly or hollow capscrew, gasket, spring, and adjusting
                    pawl (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401329">Figure 29</hotlnk>). Use a small magnet to remove pawl if necessary.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401329" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401329.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 29. Cross Section of Plunger Housing</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. HOLLOW CAPSCREW</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. GASKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SPRING</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. ADJUSTING PAWL</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. PLUNGER SEAL</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pry plunger seals loose and remove anchor (solid) plungers, adjusting plungers,
                    adjusting sleeves (actuator) and adjusting bolt.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="x0401306">
            <title>Plunger Housing Components Service - Assembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly inspect and clean all parts including the housing plunger, seal bores and
                    shoe rest pads. DO NOT use solvent to clean any rubber parts (plunger seals or gaskets). Wire brush
                    plunger parts and adjusting bolt threads to remove caked on dirt and corrosion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully inspect plunger seals and gaskets for tears, cuts or deterioration, and
                    replace if necessary. Also check the angled plunger roller faces for pits, grooves or nicks and
                    replace if necessary.
                </para>
                <para>RD spider-mounted brakes have one adjusting plunger and one anchor (solid) plunger per plunger
                    housing. The anchor plungers are marked on the shoe slot end, "R" for right hand brakes and "L" for
                    left hand brakes.
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                    mix at reassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble seals on plungers and not in plunger housing first. To assemble seal into
                    housing first will result in lack of sealing of internal plunger housing components.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply a film of grease to inside surface of seals. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s04013_25.xml" xrefid="x0401302">LUBRICATE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Inspect anchor (solid) plungers for burrs. To protect seal, apply masking tape to
                        slotted end of plunger nose (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401330">Figure 30</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1"></para>
                    <figure id="f0401330" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401330.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 30. Masking Tape Applied to Plunger Nose</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Carefully push the double lip seal onto the plunger (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401331">Figure 31</hotlnk>), stretching the outer seal lip over the plunger
                        nose end until the inner seal lip is completely in the second plunger groove and the outer seal
                        lip is in the first plunger groove. Remove masking tape. (Brakes employing single grooved
                        plungers and single lip seals should be assembled in the same manner except masking tape is not
                        used.)
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401331" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401331.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 31. Positioning Seal on Plunger</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install plunger in plunger housing.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Coat all plunger bores with grease. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s04013_25.xml" xrefid="x0401302">LUBRICATE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Anchor (solid) plungers - make sure anchor plungers marked "L" are installed in left
                        hand brake and anchor plungers marked "R" are installed in the right hand brake. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s04013_5.xml" xrefid="f0401315">Figure 15</hotlnk>and
                        <hotlnk document="s04013_5.xml" xrefid="f0401316">Figure 16</hotlnk>
                        for correct location of anchor plungers in the plunger housings.
                    </para>
                    <para>(1) Coat entire anchor plunger with grease, packing cavity behind seal, and insert plunger and
                        seal into housing with plunger keyway slot aligned with guide screw hole. Make certain the
                        plunger goes all the way into the plunger bore and seats on bosses at the bottom.
                    </para>
                    <para>(2) Seat plunger seal in plunger housing using a 1-3/4" wrench socket on spider-mounted brakes
                        or a 1-3/8" socket on backing plate- mounted brakes. Be certain that the socket is centered over
                        the seal retainer to prevent damage to the seal.
                    </para>
                    <para>(3) Assemble gasket and guide screw into plunger housing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401332">Figure 32</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401332" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401332.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 32. Guide Screw Installation</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. PLUNGER SEAL</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. GASKET</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. GUIDE SCREW</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Make certain guide screw end enters the plunger keyway slot so plunger can slide freely in
                        housing bore. Tighten guide screws to 15 to 25 ft-lbs. (20.3 to 33.9 N&#8226;m) torque.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Automatic Adjusting Plungers.</para>
                    <para>(1) Lubricate outside and inside surfaces of both the adjusting plunger and adjusting sleeve.
                        Position plunger in the plunger keyway slot with guide hole.
                    </para>
                    <para>Lubricate the seal and adjusting bolt threads and carefully assemble the seal on the bolt,
                        making sure the seal is not damaged. Grease the adjusting sleeve and thread it into the bolt.
                    </para>
                    <para>Insert sleeve, bolt, and seal (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401333">Figure 33</hotlnk>) into plunger already in housing.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401333" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401333.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 33. Adjusting Bolt and Sleeve Assembly</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. ADJUSTING SLEEVE</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. SEAL</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. ADJUSTING BOLT</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Adjusting sleeve must bottom on shoulder inside of plunger. If bolt is threaded too
                                far into sleeve, bolt will bottom in plunger and automatic adjuster will not function.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Coat pawl with grease and insert into housing.</para>
                    <para>The original design adjusting pawl has teeth and flats on one end and a chamfered edge on the
                        other end. Newly designed adjusting pawl has a key with a corresponding keyway in the spider (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0401334">Figure 34</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0401334" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401334.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 34. Adjusting Pawl</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>(2) Tighten pawl capscrew to 15 to 25 ft-lbs. (20.3 to 33.9 N&#8226;m) torque.</para>
                    <para>(3) Using proper size wrench socket, seat seal into plunger housing.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
