<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - EC-15 DIAGNOSTIC STEPS - EXCITER RING/WHEEL SENSOR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="4">
        <title>EXCITER RING/WHEEL SENSOR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Adjustment</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To adjust the wheel sensors, push the sensor into the bushing (on front axle) or into
                    the mounting block (rear axle) as far as it will go. The sensor will bottom out against the exciter
                    ring, then as the exciter ring rotates, the sensor will self-adjust. To adjust or check adjustment
                    of the rear wheel sensor, the brake drum must be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The
                    <emph type="bold">front axle sensor</emph>can be removed from the axle side of the steering knuckle
                    by pulling the sensor out. Inspect the sensor lead, the connector and the sensor for damage. Replace
                    if damaged. To install, push the sensor into the bushing as far as it will go.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The
                    <emph type="bold">rear axle sensor</emph>removal requires removal of the wheels and brake drum.
                    Inspect the sensor lead, the connector and the sensor for damage. Replace if damaged. To install,
                    push the sensor into the bushing as far as it will go.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the
                    <emph type="bold">exciter rings</emph>for damage by removing the brake drum from the wheel hub. If
                    damaged, the exciter ring should be replaced. Observe the exciter ring, noting that it is properly
                    seated on the wheel hub. To inspect for exciter ring runout with respect to the installed sensor,
                    (with drum removed) push the sensor in against the exciter ring. Using a feeler gauge, slowly rotate
                    the wheel hub observing the clearance between the exciter ring and the sensor. The gap must be
                    between 0 and 0.025 inch for proper signal output.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove And Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Exciter Ring</emph>- To remove the exciter ring, first remove the brake drum from
                    the wheel hub. Then remove the hub from the vehicle. Using a suitable puller,
                    <emph type="bold">lightly heat</emph>the exciter ring to expand it and remove from wheel assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To install the exciter ring on the wheel, uniformly heat soak the exciter ring to a
                    temperature of approximately 200&#176;F. It is recommended that the exciter ring be heated by
                    placing it in a 200&#176;F (approximate) bath (water or oil) until the desired temperature is
                    achieved. Then install the exciter ring onto the wheel hub, taking care to fully seat the exciter
                    ring, then allow the exciter ring to cool and "shrink fit" on the wheel hub.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not heat with a torch as the exciter ring may develop hot spots, causing the
                        exciter ring to distort.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the hub to the axle (less the brake drum) and adjust the wheel bearings (refer
                    to SERVICE MANUAL, Group 17). The bearing end play should not exceed .005 inch. Install the sensor
                    and then inspect for runout as described in step 3 of "Inspection". Install the brake drum after the
                    inspection is complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Sensor Retainers</emph>- To replace the sensor retainer, remove old retainer and
                    insert new retainer from axle side. Push into sensor bushing (front axle) or into sensor mounting
                    block (rear axle) until retainer tongues are against the sensor bushing or mounting block.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Front Sensor</emph>- Install the sensor into the retainer and sensor bushing from
                    the backside of the steering knuckle. Push the sensor as far as possible through the sensor bushing.
                    Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402538">Figure 38</hotlnk>
                    . No further adjustment is necessary.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0402538" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0402538" filename="../figg04/G0402538.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 38. Typical Front Axle, Wheel Sensor Installation</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. SENSOR BUSHING (PART OF KNUCKLE ASSY)</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SENSOR RETAINER</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER OUTSIDE - TONGUES</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES - LEAD (CONNECTS TO CHASSIS ANTILOCK HARNESS) STEERING
                            KNUCKLE
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Rear Sensor</emph>- Install the sensor into retainer and sensor mounting block
                    from the axle side in a horizontal position with the "cable end" of the sensor positioned as shown
                    in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402539">Figure 39</hotlnk>
                    or
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402540">Figure 40</hotlnk>
                    , depending on suspension type. Push the sensor in as far as possible through the mounting block. No
                    further adjustment is necessary.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0402539" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0402539" filename="../figg04/G0402539.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 39. Typical Rear Sensor Installation With Air Suspension</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. REF - REAR AXLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SENSOR MOUNTING BLOCK (PART OF AXLE)</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER (USE ONLY INTERNATIONAL RETAINER)</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SENSOR SHOWN REMOVED</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. REF - AXLE FLANGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES - REF</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0402540" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0402540" filename="../figg04/G0402540.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0"/>
                    <caption>Figure 40. Typical Sensor Installation With 4-Spring Suspension</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. REF - REAR AXLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SENSOR MOUNTING BLOCK (PART OF AXLE)</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. SENSOR RETAINER (USE ONLY INTERNATIONAL RETAINER)</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SENSOR SHOWN REMOVED</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. REF - AXLE FLANGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. SENSOR ASSEMBLY INCLUDES LEAD</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. RETAINER OUTSIDE TONGUES - REF</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0402541">Figure 41</hotlnk>
                    for TROUBLESHOOTING RECORD SHEET.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0402541" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0402541" filename="../figg04/G0402541.webp" type="webp" scalefit="0" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 41. TROUBLESHOOTING RECORD SHEET</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
