<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE - SERVICE - AIR CHAMBER ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0401301" svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="4">
        <title>AIR CHAMBER ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels to prevent vehicle from moving. Then cage the spring and disconnect brake
                    lines. Be sure air is exhausted from parking brake system. Air chambers used are of the bottoming
                    type. Bottoming air chambers have an identification tag fastened to the clamp ring bolt. Refer to ,
                    <hotlnk document="s04013_11.xml" xrefid="x0401304">CAGING AND UNCAGING SPRING BRAKE</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If an adjusting type unit is used, carefully mark the position of the assembly on the
                    first exposed thread of the housing tube with a scribe or punch to aid reassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a drift or other blunt tool and hammer, loosen the collet (lock) nut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401319">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401319" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/g0401319.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19. Loosening Collet (Lock) Nut</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>With welded-on spiders and mounted open end brakes, the complete actuation system can be removed
                    at this time by removing four (4) spider to plunger housing capscrews. The hub and drum assembly as
                    well as the dust shield must be removed before the actuation system is removed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401320">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401320" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/g0401320.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Complete Actuator Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unscrew the air chamber from the plunger housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401321">Figure 21</hotlnk>). At this time, remove and inspect the wedge assembly.
                    Service if necessary.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401321" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/g0401321.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21. Removing Air Chamber Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spread the clamp ring. Hold the diaphragm on the non-pressure half and remove the
                    pressure half or spring brake chamber (
                    <hotlnk document="s04013_3.xml" xrefid="f0401310">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove the diaphragm (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401322">Figure 22</hotlnk>) while holding diaphragm plate against the wedge rod.
                    This will prevent the wedge assembly from coming out of engagement with the plungers.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0401322" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg04/g0401322.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Exploded View of Brake Chamber Assembly</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. BOLT AND NUT</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CLAMP RING</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. PRESSURE HOUSING</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. PLATE AND PUSH ROD</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. WEDGE GUIDE</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. NON-PRESSURE GUIDE</callout1>
                        <callout1>8. BOOT (SEAL)</callout1>
                        <callout1>9. RETAINER</callout1>
                        <callout1>10. RIVET</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>If wedge assembly backs out of plunger anytime during this entire procedure, remove non-pressure
                    housing from brake to replace diaphragm.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue to hold plate and inspect boot (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0401322">Figure 22</hotlnk>). If boot is torn or not attached to housing, strip old
                    boot free from housing and carefully remove plate assembly off wedge rod and out of non-pressure
                    housing tube. (Boot and wedge guide will remain on plate push rod.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wedge guide and old boot from push rod. Inspect guide for wear and replace if
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new boot on diaphragm plate push rod and press wedge guide all the way onto end
                    of push rod.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean non-pressure housing with cement thinner or similar material in area where boot is
                    to be cemented.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply cement to housing around tube end. Position the plate push rod assembly into tube.
                    Carefully engage wedge rod so as to not pull it out of plungers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While holding plate against wedge, press boot into position for cementing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new diaphragm over plate and onto non-pressure housing while pushing plate
                    against wedge. Assemble pressure half and clamp ring in reverse manner of disassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect air lines to proper chamber and spring brake ports. Make a full pressure brake
                    application and check for air leaks. Road test for brake performance.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
