<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSTICS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The EC-16 contains self-test and diagnostic circuitry that continuously checks for proper operation of
                the entire antilock/ traction system, including wiring continuity. The EC-16 is programmed at the
                factory to accommodate the needs of the vehicle and the customer's desires. All EC-16 controllers are
                not factory programmed with the traction control feature, in which case antilock only will be active.
                The newer, self-configuring EC-16 controller can be reconfigured by the end user to include Traction
                Control. A vehicle equipped with traction control can generally be identified by noting the presence of
                a dash-mounted condition lamp, a disable switch (for the traction control system) and a traction
                solenoid located above the relay valve.
            </para>
            <para>Separate dash lamps, controlled by the EC-16, advise the driver of the condition of the entire
                antilock/traction system. The condition of specific components is provided by a series of labeled, light
                emitting diodes (LEDs) in the EC-16 housing. No special tools or equipment are needed to read or
                interpret the EC-16 diagnostic display. It should be noted that the EC-16 diagnostics display is
                separate from the antilock and traction condition lamps on the dash. With this separation, the driver is
                aware of any problems that occur but is not confused by diagnostic information.
            </para>
            <para>When the controller senses an erroneous condition, it stores the condition in memory, disables the
                antilock or traction function, and illuminates the dash-mounted condition lamp and the appropriate
                diagnostic LEDs on the EC-16. The failure condition is truly stored and is not cleared by loss of power
                to the EC-16. The LEDs will re-light when power is restored and remain illuminated until the failure is
                corrected. After the actual condition is corrected, maintenance personnel can clear or reset the EC-16
                diagnostics by holding a small magnet over the RESET point in the diagnostics display.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
