<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - DIAGNOSING AND LOCATING A SYSTEM FAULT - INTRODUCTION TO DCI</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INTRODUCTION TO DCI</title>
        <para>The AlliedSignal Diagnostic Communication Interface, or DCI, is an electronic, diagnostic tool for
            locating faults in the EC-17-based antilock system. The DCI can either be used as a "stand alone" diagnostic
            tool or with AlliedSignal's ACom for Windows software.
        </para>
        <para>When used by itself the DCI is capable of locating individual antilock system faults using a series of
            lamps that indicate the faulted device or its wiring and the location on the vehicle.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403807">The DCI has 12 LED lamps and a reset switch</hotlnk>. The row of 10 lamps is
            similar to the diagnostic LED display found on some Bendix antilock Controllers. The two other lamps
            indicate that the DCI has a power source and that a communications link is established with the controller.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403807" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403807.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 7. Diagnostic Communications Interface</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When used in conjunction with a personal computer (PC) and AlliedSignal's "ACom For Windows" software
            installed, the DCI becomes a communications arbitrator between the vehicle's numerous onboard controllers
            and the personal computer (PC). In this case all testing and diagnostics are performed by the computer and
            ACom for Windows.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
