<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Please Read</para>
                <para>When you are working on, or near a vehicle, the following general precautions should be
                    observed.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brakes, and always block the
                wheels.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain the air pressure from all reservoirs before beginning ANY work on the vehicle.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When working in the engine compartment, the engine should be shut off. Where circumstances
                require running the engine, EXTREME CAUTION must be used to prevent personal injury resulting from
                contact with moving, rotating, leaking, heated, or electrically charged components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip. Never remove a
                component or plug, unless you are certain all system pressure has been released.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety glasses.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until you have read
                and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper tools and observe all
                precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use only International approved parts, components, and kits. Replacement hardware, tubing,
                hose, fittings, etc. must be designed specifically for such applications and systems.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Components with stripped threads or damaged parts should be replaced, rather than repaired.
                Repairs requiring machining or welding should not be attempted unless specifically approved and stated
                by the International Engineering.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                restored to their proper operating condition.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always turn the ignition key to OFF before disconnecting any of the antilock wiring or
                connectors. If the key is not OFF, the ECU controller will record the power interruption as a static
                fault.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Before you weld on a vehicle with an electronic control module for the engine, antilock brake
                    system or other electronically controlled components, it is mandatory to remove all connectors going
                    to the Electronic Control Unit (ECU). It is also mandatory to disconnect the positive (+) and
                    negative ( ) battery cables before connecting the welder. Attach the welder ground cables as close
                    as possible to the part being welded. Never connect the welder ground cables to an ECU or mounting
                    bracket for the ECU.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
