<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BRAKE BOOSTER AND MASTER CYLINDER - INSTALL - BLEEDING HYDRAULIC BRAKE SYSTEM</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0401703" svcproctype="fill" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BLEEDING HYDRAULIC BRAKE SYSTEM</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>When adding fluids, take care to identify fluids (power steering fluid or brake fluid) and use
                    only in the proper system. Discard all fluid bled or drained from either system. Do not use for
                    refill, cleaning or any other purpose. Failure to observe these precautions could result in failure
                    of the brake system, with resultant personal injury and/or property damage.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If both the brake fluid system and Hydro-Max&#8482; booster system require bleeding, bleed the
                    booster system first. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04017y_X0401704.xml" xrefid="x0401704">BLEEDING HYDRO-MAX&#8482; BOOSTER AND
                        BACKUP PUMP ASSEMBLY
                    </hotlnk>
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The hydraulic brake system must be free of air to function properly. If air becomes mixed with brake
            fluid, excess pedal travel will result since air in the hydraulic system compresses. A bleeder screw is
            provided at each caliper assembly for removal of any air in the hydraulic brake system.
        </para>
        <para>Bleeding the hydraulic brake system expels brake fluid and any air from the hydraulic system at one or
            more bleed points. Since the brake master cylinder reservoir is at the highest point in the brake system and
            there are no residual check valves in the system, the weight of the brake fluid will create fluid flow when
            a bleeder screw is opened. Thus, "gravity flow bleeding" of the hydraulic system can be accomplished. It is
            important that the master cylinder reservoir fluid level be maintained while bleeding the brakes.
        </para>
        <para>For bleeding, a supply of clean DOT 3 brake fluid is necessary. DO NOT reuse brake fluid that has been
            drained from the hydraulic brake system as the fluid may be contaminated.
        </para>
        <para>It is recommended that the hydraulic brake system be thoroughly flushed with new brake fluid whenever
            repairs are performed to be assured that hydraulic brake system is filled with clean fluid.
        </para>
        <para>To flush the system, use bleeding procedures outlined herein and flush new brake fluid through system
            until it appears clean.
        </para>
        <para>The following bleeding sequence is recommended, to reduce the possibility of missing a caliper assembly:
            right rear, left rear, right front, left front.
        </para>
        <para>Brake fluid level in the master cylinder reservoir should be touching the bottom of the half cylindrical
            portion of either of the port openings.
        </para>
        <para>Gravity flow bleeding of the hydraulic brake system requires only one person and NO pressure bleeder.
        </para>
        <para>Install a clear plastic tube over the bleeder screw where bleeding operation is being performed and insert
            the opposite end of the tube into a container to catch the fluid. Open bleeder screw at caliper furthest
            away from master cylinder (right rear). Observe flow of fluid through the tube. When air bubbles no longer
            appear and a steady flow of clean fluid is present, that brake group is free of air. Close bleeder screw.
            Tighten to 8 to 15 lbf-ft (10 to 20 N&#8226;m).
        </para>
        <para>Frequently check brake fluid level as air will be reintroduced into the system if the reservoir is allowed
            to empty.
        </para>
        <para>When the bleeding procedure is complete. Fill master cylinder reservoir with brake fluid. When brake fluid
            touches the bottom of the half cylindrical portion of either of the fill port openings, the master cylinder
            is full. Loosen each brake line hex fitting (Item 5) enough to allow brake fluid to seep out past the
            fittings. When seepage starts, tighten fittings. Tighten to 16 to 17 lbf-ft (22 to 23 N&#8226;m).
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If entire system has been drained, it may be necessary to slightly depress the brake pedal to
                    initially start the fluid flow when bleeding the brake system.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If pressure bleeding the system, do not exceed 35 psi.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y_X0401704.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04017y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
