<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - EC-30 WITH PLC</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>EC-30 WITH PLC</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Effective March 1, 2001, all towing vehicles must control an in-cab trailer ABS warning lamp. Trailers
                built after this date will transmit the status of the trailer ABS unit over the power line (blue wire of
                the J560 connector) to the tractor using PLC communications.
            </para>
            <para>The PLC signal is usually broadcasted by the trailer ABS ECU. The application of PLC technology for
                the heavy vehicle industry is known as PLC4Trucks. The Bendix EC-30 premium with PLC, and basic with
                PLC, will support PLC communication in accordance with SAE J2497.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Identifying an EC-30 with PLC</title>
            <para>An EC-30 with or without PLC can be identified by the individual part number label on the ECU. Also,
                an EC-30 that does not support the PLC feature should have the following label applied:
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">ECU does not control a trailer ABS warning lamp. Do not install on a towing vehicle
                    manufactured after March 1, 2001.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Measuring /Identifying the PLC Signal</title>
            <para>An oscilloscope can be used to verify the presence of a PLC signal on the power line. The PLC signal
                is an amplitude and frequency modulated signal. Depending on the filtering and load on the power line,
                the PLC signal amplitude can range from 0.5 mvp-p to 7.0 Vp-p. Suggested oscilloscope settings are (AC
                coupling, 1 volt/div, 100 &#181;sec/div). The signal should be measured at the power leads of the EC-30.
                See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404303">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0404304">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The EC-30 will not broadcast PLC messages unless it is specially programmed to do so. With this
                standard configuration, an ABS trailer equipped with PLC or a PLC diagnostic tool will need to be
                attached to the vehicle in order to generate a PLC signal on the power line.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404303" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404303.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Power Line Without PLC Signal</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0404304" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/g0404304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Power Line With PLC Signal</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
