<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR DRYER - AD-9 AIR DRYER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="7">
        <title>AD-9 AIR DRYER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The function of the AD-9 Air Dryer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400264">Figure 64</hotlnk>
                ) is to collect and remove air system contaminants in solid, liquid and vapor form before they enter the
                brake system. It provides clean, dry air to the components of the brake system, which increases the life
                of the system and reduces maintenance costs.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400264" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400264" filename="../figg04/g0400264.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 64. AD-9 Air Dryer</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. UPPER MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CHECK VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. DISCHARGE PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PURGE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. TURBO CUTOFF PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. PURGE VALVE HOUSING ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. CONTROL PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. OIL SEPARATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. DESICCANT BED</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. DESICCANT CARTRIDGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. UPPER BRACKET STRAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. END COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The AD-9 Air Dryer consists of the desiccant cartridge and a die cast aluminum end cover secured to a
                cylindrical steel outer shell with eight capscrews and nuts. The end cover contains a check valve
                assembly, a safety valve, three threaded air connections and the purge valve housing assembly. The
                removable purge valve housing assembly incorporates a purge valve mechanism and a turbocharger cutoff
                feature that is designed to prevent loss of engine "turbo" boost pressure during the purge cycle of the
                air dryer. The desiccant cartridge and discharger check valve assembly are screw-in type. The purge
                valve housing assembly, which includes the heater and thermostat assembly, and the discharge check valve
                assembly, are serviceable from the exterior of the air dryer. The screw-in desiccant cartridge requires
                removal of the air dryer assembly from the vehicle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>The AD-9 Air Dryer alternates between two operational "cycles" during operation: the CHARGE CYCLE and
                the PURGE CYCLE. The following description of operation is separated into these "cycles" of operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Charge Cycle</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400265">Figure 65</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400265" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400265" filename="../figg04/g0400265.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 65. AD-9 Air Dryer - Charge Cycle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ORIFICE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PURGE VOLUME</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CHECK VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. HEATER ELEMENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. PURGE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. GOVERNOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. CONTROL PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. OIL SEPARATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. DESICCANT BED</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. DESICCANT CARTRIDGE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When the compressor is loaded (compressing air), compressed air, along with oil, oil vapor, water and
                water vapor flows through the compressor discharge line to the supply port (Item 10) of the air dryer
                end cover. As air travels through the end cover assembly, its direction of flow changes several times,
                reducing the temperature, causing contaminants to condense and drop to the bottom or sump of the air
                dryer end cover.
            </para>
            <para>After exiting the end cover, the air flows into the desiccant cartridge (Item 17). Once in the
                desiccant cartridge, air first flows through an oil separator (Item 15), which removes water in liquid
                form as well as oil, oil vapor and solid contaminants.
            </para>
            <para>Air exits the oil separator and enters the desiccant drying bed (Item 16). Air flowing through the
                column of desiccant becomes progressively dryer as water vapor adheres to the desiccant material in a
                process known as ADSORPTION. The desiccant cartridge using the adsorption process removes water vapor
                from the pressurized air.
            </para>
            <para>Dry air flows out of the purge volume through the single check valve assembly (Item 4) and out the
                delivery port (Item 5) to the first (supply) reservoir (Item 11) of the air system.
            </para>
            <para>The air dryer will remain in the charge cycle until air brake system pressure builds to the governor
                cutout setting.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Purge Cycle</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400266">Figure 66</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400266" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400266" filename="../figg04/g0400266.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 66. AD-9 Air Dryer - Purge Cycle</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ORIFICE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PURGE VOLUME</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CHECK VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. DELIVERY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. HEATER ELEMENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. PURGE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. GOVERNOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. CONTROL PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. OIL SEPARATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. DESICCANT BED</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. DESICCANT CARTRIDGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. PURGE PISTON</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When air brake system pressure reaches the cutout setting of the governor (Item 13), the compressor
                unloads (air compression stopped) and the purge cycle of the air dryer begins. When the governor unloads
                the compressor, it pressurizes the compressor unloader mechanism line connecting the governor unloader
                port to the dryer end cover control port (Item 14). The purge piston (Item 18) moves in response to air
                pressure, causing the purge valve (Item 9) to open to atmosphere and (partially) closing off the supply
                of air from the compressor. Contaminants in the end cover sump (Item 6) are expelled immediately when
                the purge valve (Item 9) opens. Also, air which was flowing through the desiccant cartridge (Item 17)
                changes direction and begins to flow toward the open purge valve (Item 9). Oil and solid contaminants
                collected by the oil separator (Item 15) are removed by air flowing from the desiccant drying bed (Item
                16) to the open purge valve (Item 9).
            </para>
            <para>The initial purge and desiccant cartridge decompression lasts only a few seconds and is evidenced by
                an audible burst of air at the exhaust (Item 8). The reactivation of the desiccant drying bed begins as
                dry air flows from purge volume (Item 3) through the desiccant cartridge purge orifice (Item 2); its
                pressure is lowered and its volume increased. The flow of dry air through the drying bed (Item 16)
                reactivates desiccant material by removing the water vapor adhering to it. Fifteen to 30 seconds are
                required for the entire purge volume to flow through the desiccant drying bed (Item 16).
            </para>
            <para>The end cover single check valve assembly (Item 4) prevents air pressure in the brake system from
                returning to the air dryer during the purge cycle. After the 30 second purge cycle is complete, the air
                dryer is ready for the next charge cycle to begin.
            </para>
            <para>The purge valve will remain open after the purge cycle is complete and will not close until air brake
                system pressure is reduced and the governor signals the compressor to charge.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Turbo Cutoff (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400267">Figure 67</hotlnk>
                    )
                </title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400267" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400267" filename="../figg04/g0400267.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 67. AD-9 Air Dryer - Turbo Cutoff</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHECK VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PURGE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TURBO CUTOFF PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. DISCHARGE LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SUPPLY PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The function of the turbo cutoff valve is to prevent loss of engine turbocharger air pressure through
                the air dryer in systems where the compressor intake is connected to the engine turbocharger. The turbo
                cutoff valve also reduces the "puffing" of air out the open exhaust when a naturally aspirated, single
                cylinder compressor equipped with an inlet check valve is used on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>At the beginning of the purge cycle, the downward travel of the purge piston is stopped when the turbo
                cutoff valve (tapered portion of purge piston) contacts its mating metal seat in the purge valve
                housing. With the turbo cutoff valve seated (closed position), air in the discharge line and inlet port
                is restricted from entering the air dryer. While the turbo cutoff effectively prevents loss of
                turbocharger boost pressure to the engine, some "seepage" of air may be detected under certain
                conditions of compressor engine and turbocharger operation, even though there will be low pressure air
                trapped in the discharge line.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Every 900 operating hours or 25,000 miles (40,000 km) or every three (3) months:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for moisture in the air brake system by opening reservoirs, drain cocks, or valves
                    and check for presence of water. If moisture is present, the desiccant may require replacement;
                    however, the following conditions can also cause water accumulation and should be considered before
                    replacing the desiccant:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">An outside air source has been used to charge the system. This air did not pass
                        through the drying bed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Air usage is exceptionally high and not normal for a highway vehicle. This may be
                        due to accessory air demands or some unusual air requirement that does not allow the compressor
                        to load and unload (compressing and non-compressing cycle) in a normal fashion. Check for high
                        air system leakage.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">In areas where more than a 30 degree range of temperature occurs in one day, small
                        amounts of water can accumulate in the air brake system due to condensation. Under these
                        conditions, the presence of small amounts of moisture is normal and should not be considered as
                        an indication that the dryer is not performing properly.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>A small amount of oil in the system may be normal and should not, in itself, be
                                considered a reason to replace the desiccant; oil stained desiccant can function
                                adequately.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check mounting bolts for tightness. Tighten to 80 to 120 in-lbs. (9.03 to 13.55 N&#183;
                    m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the on this page.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Every 10,800 hours, 300,000 miles (480,000 km) or 36 months:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rebuild the air dryer including the desiccant cartridge.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The desiccant change interval may vary from vehicle to vehicle. Although typical desiccant
                            cartridge life is three years, many will perform adequately for a longer period of time. To
                            take maximum advantage of desiccant life and assure that replacement occurs only when
                            necessary, it is important that the following
                            <emph type="bold">Service Checks</emph>
                            be performed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400215">
            <title>Service Checks - Operation and Leakage Tests</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                        pressures, gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the outlet port check valve assembly by building the air system to governor cut-out
                    and observing a test air gauge installed in the #1 reservoir. Check all lines and fittings leading
                    to and from the air dryer for leakage and integrity. A rapid loss of pressure could indicate a
                    failed outlet port check valve. This can be confirmed by bleeding the system down, removing the
                    check valve assembly from the end cover, subjecting air pressure to the unit and applying a soap
                    solution to the check valve side. Leakage should not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 1
                    second.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for excessive leakage around the purge valve. With the compressor in loaded mode
                    (compressing air), apply a soap solution to the purge valve housing assembly exhaust port and
                    observe that leakage does not exceed a 1 inch (25 mm) diameter bubble in 1 second. If the leakage
                    exceeds the maximum specified, service the purge valve housing assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close all reservoir drain cocks. Build up system pressure to governor cut-out and note
                    that the AD-9 purges with an audible escape of air. The system once again builds to full pressure
                    and is followed by a purge.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the operation of the safety valve by pulling the exposed stem while the compressor
                    is loaded (compressing air). There must be an exhaust of air while the stem is held and the valve
                    should reseat when the stem is released.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the operation of the end cover heater and thermostat assembly during cold weather
                    operation as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Electric Power to the Dryer - With the ignition or engine kill switch in the ON
                        position, check for voltage to the heater and thermostat assembly using a voltmeter or test
                        light. Unplug the electrical connector at the air dryer and place the test leads on each of the
                        pins of the male connector. If there is no voltage, look for a blown fuse, broken wires, or
                        corrosion in the vehicle wiring harness. Check to see if a good ground path exists.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Thermostat and Heater Operation - Turn off the ignition switch and cool the end
                        cover assembly to below 40&#176; F (4&#176;C). Using an ohmmeter, check the resistance between
                        the electrical pins in the female connector. The resistance should be 1.5 to 3.0 ohms for the 12
                        volt heater assembly and 6.8 to 9.0 ohms for the 24 volt heater assembly.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Some early models of the AD-9 will have resistance readings of 1.0 to 2.5 ohms for the
                                12 volt heater assembly and 4.8 to 7.2 ohms for the 24 volt heater assembly. If the
                                resistance is higher than the maximum stated, replace the purge valve housing assembly,
                                which includes the heater and thermostat assembly.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Warm the end cover assembly to over 90&#176;F (32&#176;C) and again check the resistance. The
                        resistance should exceed 1000 ohms. If the resistance values obtained are within the stated
                        limits, the thermostat and heater assembly is operating properly. If the resistance values
                        obtained are outside the stated limits, replace the purge valve housing assembly, which includes
                        the heater and thermostat assembly.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle on a level surface and block the wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Completely drain
                    <emph type="bold">all</emph>
                    reservoirs.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Compressor discharge line may still contain residual pressure.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Identify and disconnect the three air lines from the end cover and note the position of
                    end cover ports relative to the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug the vehicle wiring harness from the heater and thermostat assembly connector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400268">Figure 68</hotlnk>
                    ) on the purge valve housing assembly.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400268" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400268" filename="../figg04/g0400268.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 68. AD-9 Air Dryer - Thermostat and Heater Assembly</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. LOWER MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. FEMALE ELECTRICAL CONNECTOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. MALE ELECTRICAL CONNECTOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. MALE CONNECTOR END VIEW</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. MALE CONNECTOR SIDE VIEW</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. END COVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. AIR DRYER LATCH MUST BE INSERTED UNTIL IT SNAPS OVER TAB ON MATING CONNECTOR
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the bolt securing the upper mounting strap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove, retain and
                    <emph type="underscr">mark</emph>
                    the two end cover capscrews, lock nuts and four special washers that retain the lower mounting
                    bracket to the end cover; also mark these two holes of the end cover. (These bolts are longer than
                    the other 6 bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air dryer from its mounting brackets on the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While performing service on AD-9 air dryer, it is not recommended that a clamping device
                        (vise, C-clamp, etc.) be used to hold any die cast aluminum component as damage may result. To
                        hold the end cover, install a pipe nipple in the supply port and clamp the nipple into a vise.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400269">Figure 69</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400269" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic id="g0400269" filename="../figg04/g0400269.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="562px"/>
                <caption>Figure 69. Ad-9 Air Dryer - Disassembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. COMPLETE DESICCANT CARTRIDGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SAFETY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. LOWER MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 3/8 I SPECIAL WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. 3/8 I CAPSCREW (LONG)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CHECK VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. PURGE VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. PURGE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. PURGE VALVE LOCK NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. EXHAUST DIAPHRAGM WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. 1/4 I TAPPING SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. EXHAUST COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. PURGE PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>20. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>21. TORX HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>22. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>24. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>25. 3/8 I CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. END COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>27. LOCK NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>28. HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>29. UPPER MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>30. 5/16 I LOCK NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>31. 5/16 I LOCKWASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>32. UPPER BRACKET STRAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>33. 5/16 X 4-1/2 I UPPER BRACKET CAPSCREW</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the delivery, check valve assembly (Item 9) and O-ring (Item 8). Remove the
                    O-ring from the check valve assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the three self tapping screws (Item 15) that secure the purge valve housing
                    assembly to the end cover assembly. Pull the purge valve housing assembly out of the end cover
                    assembly. Remove the three O-rings (Items 22, 23 and 24) from the exterior of the purge valve
                    housing assembly.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>O-rings (Items 22 and 23) may be lodged in the end cover bores; if so, they must be
                            removed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of the piston from the purge valve housing assembly requires a special Torx head
                    socket or a twelve point 1/4 in. socket to hold the head of the purge valve bolt (Item 21).
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the nut (Item 13) from the bottom of the purge valve housing assembly using a
                        9/16 inch socket wrench and a Torx head socket to hold the head of the bolt (Item 21). Remove
                        the diaphragm washer (Item 14) (if present), and the diaphragm (Item 12) (if present), and the
                        purge valve (Item 11) from the purge valve housing.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the Torx head bolt (Item 21) from the opposite end, then the purge piston
                        (Item 18), the return spring (Item 17) and two O-rings (19 and 20); one on the O.D. and the
                        other in the inside of the purge piston.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Do not attempt to remove the heater and thermostat assembly, as it will be damaged
                                during the removal process. If the heater and thermostat are defective, replace the en
                                tire purge valve housing assembly which includes these items.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the remaining six capscrews (Item 25), lock nuts (Item 27) and twelve special
                    washers (Item 6) that secure the end cover to the housing. Separate the end cover and desiccant
                    cartridge (Item 1) from the housing (Item 28).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the end cover to outer housing O-ring (Item 3).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not remove the safety valve from the end cover unless it has been proven defective.
                    If replacement is required, apply thread sealant or Teflon tape on the threads of the replacement
                    valve and tighten to 120 to 400 in-lbs. (13.50 to 45.19 N&#183; m), making sure the drain hole
                    (slot) is facing down.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a strap or chain wrench around the desiccant cartridge (Item 1) so that it is
                    approximately 2 to 3 inches (51 to 76 mm) away from the end cover. Rotate the cartridge
                    counterclockwise until it completely separates from the end cover.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>A substantial torque [up to 50 ft-lbs. (68 N&#183; m)] may be required to perform this
                            disassembly.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the desiccant cartridge O-ring (Item 2) from the end cover.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using mineral spirits or an equivalent solvent, clean and
                    <emph type="bold">thoroughly dry</emph>
                    all metal parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the interior and exterior of all metal parts that will be reused for severe
                    corrosion, pitting and cracks. Superficial corrosion and/or pitting on the exterior portion of the
                    upper and lower body halves is acceptable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the bores of both the end cover and the purge valve housing for deep scuffing or
                    gouges.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain that all purge valve housing and end cover passages are open and free of
                    obstructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the pipe threads in the end cover. Make certain they are clean and free of
                    thread sealant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the purge valve housing bore and seats for excessive wear and scuffing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the purge valve piston seat for excessive wear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all air line fittings for corrosion. Clean all old thread sealant from the pipe
                    threads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All O-rings removed should be discarded and replaced with new O-rings.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assemble</title>
            <para>Prior to assembly, coat all O-rings, O-ring grooves and bores with a generous amount of barium base
                lubricant.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400269">Figure 69</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Purge Valve Housing Assembly</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the O-ring (Item 19) in its groove on the O.D. of the purge piston. Place
                        the return spring (Item 17) in the bore of the purge valve housing. Place the O-ring (Item 20)
                        into its recess in the bore of the purge piston. Install the Torx head bolt (Item 21) into the
                        I.D. of the purge piston. Insert the purge piston (Item 18) into the I.D. of the spring (Item
                        17). Using a Torx head wrench engaged on head of Torx head bolt, push the piston into the purge
                        valve housing until it bottoms.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">While depressing the purge piston with the Torx head wrench, install the following
                        parts over the purge valve bolt (Item 21) from the opposite end of the purge valve housing; the
                        purge valve (Item 11) with its rubber side first, followed by the diaphragm (Item 12) (if
                        present) or the flat washer and finally the hex nut (Item 13). Tighten the purge valve nut and
                        bolt to 60 to 80 in-lbs. (6.77 to 9.03 N&#183; m).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the three O-rings (Items 22, 23 and 24) on the purge valve housing, placing
                        each in its appropriate location. If the exhaust cover (Item 16) was removed during disassembly,
                        install it on the purge valve housing assembly, making certain the "bubble" portion is
                        positioned over the thermostat. Install the assembled purge valve housing in the end cover,
                        making certain to orient both parts so that the connector is approximately 10 degrees clockwise
                        from the supply port, while also making certain the purge valve housing is fully seated against
                        the end cover. Secure the purge valve housing to the end cover using the three self-tapping
                        screws (Item 15). Start all three screws by hand, then tighten to 85 to 125 in-lbs. (9.6 to
                        14.12 N&#183; m).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the O-ring (Item 8) on the check valve assembly (Item 9), and install the
                    assembly in the end cover using a 1-3/4 inch socket. Tighten to 200 to 250 in-lbs. (22.39 to 28.24 N&#183;
                    m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the desiccant O-ring (Item 2) in its groove in the end cover. Using a light coat
                    of barium grease, lubricate the bottom of the desiccant cartridge in the area that will contact the
                    O-ring (Item 2) and end cover. Screw the desiccant cartridge into the end cover until contact is
                    made between it and the O-ring. Using a strap or chain wrench positioned 2 to 3 inches (51 to 76 mm)
                    from the bottom of the cartridge, turn the desiccant cartridge clockwise 180 to 225 degrees beyond
                    the position where initial contact was made between the cartridge and end cover O-ring. Torque
                    should not exceed 50 ft-lbs. (68 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the end cover outer housing O-ring (Item 3) on the shoulder in the end cover.
                </para>
                <para>Place the housing (Item 28) over the desiccant cartridge and align the holes. Install the six
                    capscrews (Item 25), lock nuts (Item 27) and twelve special washers (Item 6), making certain they
                    are in the proper position as marked during disassembly. The two long capscrews (Item 7) will be
                    used to secure the dryer to its mounting bracket. Tighten the six capscrews and nuts in a star
                    pattern as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400270">Figure 70</hotlnk>
                    depending on lower bracket location. Tighten to 270 to 385 in-lbs. (30.7 to 43.5 N&#183; m).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400270" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400270" filename="../figg04/g0400270.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 70. AD-9 Air Dryer - Tightening Capscrews</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The two remaining bolt holes in end cover and two 3/8" capscrews MUST be the ones marked
                            during disassembly to assure proper orientation of the ports and adequate length of the
                            capscrews.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the assembled air dryer back onto the vehicle by slipping it into the upper
                    mounting bracket. Align the two unused holes in the end cover with the bottom mounting bracket so
                    that the bottom bracket supports the air dryer. The end cover should rest on the bracket. Using the
                    remaining two capscrews (Item 7), four special washers (Item 6), and two lock nuts (Item 27), fasten
                    the air dryer to the lower bracket. Tighten to 270 to 385 in-lbs. (30.7 to 43.5 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the bolt and nut on the upper mounting bracket. Tighten to 80 to 120 in-lbs.
                    (9.03 to 13.55 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the three air lines to the proper ports on the end cover (identified during
                    disassembly).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect vehicle wiring harness to heater and thermostat assembly connector by plugging
                    it into the air dryer connector until its lock tab snaps in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <table id="t0400210" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Troubleshooting Chart - AD-9 Air Dryer</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="2.34in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="2.65in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Cause</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remedy</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Dryer is</para>
                                <para>constantly "cycling" or purging.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Excessive system leakage.</para>
                                <para>2. Excessive leakage in fittings, hoses and tubing connected to the compressor,
                                    air dryer and first reservoir.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. Defective check valve assembly in air dryer end cover.</para>
                                <para>4. Defective governor.</para>
                                <para>5. Leaking purge valve housing assembly and/or O-rings in end cover.</para>
                                <para>6. Compressor unloader mechanism leaking excessively.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Test for excessive system</para>
                                <para>leakage.</para>
                                <para>Allowable leakage:</para>
                                <para>Truck - 2 psi/minute.</para>
                                <para>Tractor trailer - 3 psi/minute.</para>
                                <para>Truck - 1 psi/minute per service reservoir.</para>
                                <para>Tractor trailer - 3 psi/minute per service reservoir.</para>
                                <para>2. Using soap solution, test for leakage at fittings, drain valve (if any) and
                                    safety valve in first reservoir. Repair or replace as necessary.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. Remove check valve assembly from end cover. Subject air pressure to delivery
                                    side of valve. Apply soap solution at opposite end and check for leakage.
                                    (Permissible leakage: 1" bubble in five seconds). If excessive leakage, replace
                                    check valve assembly.
                                </para>
                                <para>4. Test governor for proper cut-in and cut-out pressures and excessive leakage in
                                    both positions.
                                </para>
                                <para>5. With the supply port open to atmosphere, apply 120 psi at the control port.
                                    Apply a soap solution to the supply port and exhaust port (purge valve seat area).
                                    Permissible leakage: 1" bubble in five seconds.
                                </para>
                                <para>6. Remove air strainer or fitting from compressor inlet cavity. With compressor
                                    unloaded, check for unloader piston leakage. Slight leakage permissible.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2. Water in</para>
                                <para>vehicle.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Desiccant requires replacement, excessive contaminants in desiccant cartridge
                                    assembly.
                                </para>
                                <para>2. Improper discharge line length or improper line material. Maximum air dryer
                                    inlet temperature is exceeded.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. Air dryer not purging (see Condition #5).</para>
                                <para>4. Purge (air exhaust) time</para>
                                <para>insufficient due to excessive system leakage (see causes for Condition #1).</para>
                                <para>5. Air bypasses desiccant</para>
                                <para>cartridge assembly.</para>
                                <para>6. Purge time is significantly less than minimum allowable.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Replace desiccant cartridge.</para>
                                <para>2. Minimum of six feet of discharge line must be used between the port of the
                                    compressor and the supply port.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. See Cause and Remedy for</para>
                                <para>Condition #5.</para>
                                <para>4. Check Cause and Remedy for Condition #1.</para>
                                <para>5. Replace desiccant cartridge/end cover O-ring.</para>
                                <para>Check to make sure desiccant cartridge assembly is properly</para>
                                <para>installed.</para>
                                <para>6. Replace desiccant cartridge/end cover O-ring.</para>
                                <para>Check to make sure desiccant cartridge assembly is properly</para>
                                <para>installed.</para>
                                <para>Replace desiccant cartridge</para>
                                <para>assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. Safety valve on air dryer "popping off" or exhausting air.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Desiccant cartridge plugged.</para>
                                <para>2. Defective discharge check valve in end cover.</para>
                                <para>3. Defective fittings, hose or</para>
                                <para>tubing between air dryer and first reservoir.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Check compressor for excessive oil passing. Repair or replace compressor as
                                    necessary.
                                </para>
                                <para>Rebuild or replace</para>
                                <para>cartridge.</para>
                                <para>2. Test to determine if air is passing through check valve. Repair or</para>
                                <para>replace.</para>
                                <para>3. Check to determine if air is reaching first reservoir. Inspect for kinked
                                    tubing or hose. Check for undrilled or restricted hose or
                                </para>
                                <para>tubing fittings.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4. Constant exhaust of air at air dryer purge valve exhaust or unable to build
                                    system pressure. (Charge mode.)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Air dryer purge valve leaking excessively.</para>
                                <para>2. Defective governor.</para>
                                <para>3. Purge control line connected to reservoir or exhaust port of governor.</para>
                                <para>4. Purge valve frozen open - faulty heater and thermostat, wiring, blown fuse.
                                </para>
                                <para>5. Inlet and outlet air connections reversed.</para>
                                <para>6. Kinked or blocked (plugged) discharge line.</para>
                                <para>7. Excessive bends in discharge line (water collects and freezes).</para>
                                <para>8. Excessive system leakage.</para>
                                <para>9. Purge valve stays open - supply air leaks to control side.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. With compressor loaded, apply soap solution on purge valve</para>
                                <para>exhaust to test for excessive</para>
                                <para>leakage. Repair purge valve as necessary.</para>
                                <para>2. Check governor for proper "cut-in," "cut-out" pressure and excessive leakage in
                                    both positions. Repair or replace as necessary.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. Purge control line must be</para>
                                <para>connected to unloader port of governor.</para>
                                <para>4. Test heater and thermostat as</para>
                                <para>described in
                                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400215">
                                        <xref refid="hl0400215"/>SERVICE CHECKS
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    .
                                </para>
                                <para>5. Compressor discharge to inlet port. Reconnect lines properly.</para>
                                <para>6. Check to determine if air passes through discharge line. Check for kinks,
                                    bends, excessive carbon deposits.
                                </para>
                                <para>7. Discharge line should be constantly sloping from compressor to air dryer with
                                    as few bends as possible.
                                </para>
                                <para>8. See Cause and Remedy for</para>
                                <para>Condition #1.</para>
                                <para>9. Replace purge valve housing</para>
                                <para>assembly O-rings.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5. Air dryer does not purge or exhaust air.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Broken, kinked, frozen, plugged or disconnected purge control line.</para>
                                <para>2. See Causes, 2, 5, 7 of</para>
                                <para>Condition #4.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Test to determine air flows through purge control line when compressor
                                    unloaded. Check for undrilled fittings (See Condition #4, Remedy 3.)
                                </para>
                                <para>2. Refer to Remedies 2, 5, 7 of</para>
                                <para>Condition #4.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6. Desiccant material being expelled from air dryer purge valve exhaust (Many look
                                    like whitish liquid or paste or small beads).
                                </para>
                                <para>OR</para>
                                <para>Unsatisfactory desiccant life.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Defective cloth covered perforated plate in air dryer.</para>
                                <para>2. Compressor passing excessive oil.</para>
                                <para>3. Desiccant cartridge not assembled properly to end cover (loose attachment).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Replace desiccant cartridge</para>
                                <para>assembly.</para>
                                <para>2. Check for proper compressor installation; if symptoms persist, replace
                                    compressor.
                                </para>
                                <para>3. Check the torque on the desiccant cartridge to end cover</para>
                                <para>attachment.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7."Pinging" noise excessive during compressor loaded cycle.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Single cylinder compressor with high pulse cycles.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A slight "pinging" sound may be heard during system build up when a single
                                    cylinder compressor is used.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>8. Constant seepage of air at air dryer purge valve exhaust (non-charging mode).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Inlet of air compressor pressurized by turbocharger from engine.</para>
                                <para>2. Defective check valve assembly in air dryer end cover.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Some leakage of pressure past the metal seat of the turbo feature of the AD-9
                                    is to be expected, also may be audible. This slight loss of air will not affect the
                                    engine or turbo performance.
                                </para>
                                <para>2. Refer to Remedy 3, Condition #1.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para></para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Chart</title>
            <table id="t0400212" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Torque Chart - AD-9 Air Dryer</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.49in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.49in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">In-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Purge Valve Nut &#38; Bolt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>60 to 80</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6.77 to 9.03</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1/4 Inch Self Tapping Screw</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>85 to 125</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>9.6 to 14.12</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Check Valve to End Cover</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>200 to 250</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>22.39 to 28.24</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>End Cap Capscrews</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>270 to 385</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30.7 to 43.5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3/8 Inch Capscrews</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>270 to 385</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30.7 to 43.5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Upper Mounting Bolt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>80 to 120</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>9.03 to 13.55</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Safety Valve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>120 to 400</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>13.50 to 45.19</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_116.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_118.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
