<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Brakes - Anti-Lock Control - 4-Wheel - Anti-Lock Control Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>Anti-Lock Control Description and Operation</title>
        <para>The vehicle is equipped with a 3-channel anti-lock brake system (ABS) that prevents wheel lockup by
            automatically modulating the brake pressure during an emergency stop.
        </para>
        <para>The ABS controls the front and rear brakes separately. The brake pedal force required to engage the ABS
            function may vary with the road surface condition. A dry surface requires greater force than a slippery
            surface.
        </para>
        <para>During ABS operation, the driver may feel a pulsation in the brake pedal, accompanied by a slight up and
            down movement in the pedal height. In addition, a mechanical noise from the engine compartment may be heard.
            The pedal effort and pedal feel during normal braking are similar to that of a conventional power brake
            system.
        </para>
        <para>When the brakes are applied, brake fluid is forced from the brake master cylinder outlet ports to the
            hydraulic control unit (HCU) inlet ports. The fluid pressure is transmitted through 3 normally open solenoid
            valves inside the HCU, through the outlet ports of the HCU to the brakes. One circuit of the brake master
            cylinder feeds the front brakes, while the other circuit feeds the rear brakes. If the anti-lock brake
            control module senses that a wheel is about to lock, based on wheel speed sensor data, the solenoid valve
            will pulse closed, preventing more fluid from entering that circuit. The anti-lock brake control module then
            reads the sensor signal from the affected wheel again. If the wheel is still decelerating, the normally
            closed solenoid valve for that circuit is opened. A controlled amount of hydraulic pressure between the
            normally open valve and the brake is relieved into the HCU accumulator. Once the affected wheel returns to
            vehicle speed, the anti-lock brake control module returns the solenoid valves to their normal condition,
            allowing fluid flow to the affected brake.
        </para>
        <para>The anti-lock brake control module monitors the electromechanical components of the system. Malfunction of
            the anti-lock brake system will cause the anti-lock brake control module to shut off or inhibit the system,
            however, normal power-assisted braking remains. Malfunctions are indicated by the yellow ABS warning
            indicator in the instrument cluster.
        </para>
        <para>The ABS system is self-monitoring. When the ignition switch is placed in the RUN position, the anti-lock
            brake control module performs a preliminary self-check on the anti-lock electrical system indicated by a
            3-second illumination of the yellow ABS warning indicator in the instrument cluster.
        </para>
        <para>A self-test of the solenoid valve coils and the pump motor is carried out when the vehicle is started.
            During start up, the brake pedal must be released to run the self-test. If the brake pedal is depressed or a
            failed brake switch occurs, the self-test is run at 6 km/h (4 mph) regardless of brake pedal position.
        </para>
        <para>The anti-lock brake control module and the hydraulic control unit can be serviced separately.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_X2060945.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_FC.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
