<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 501 - DISASSEMBLE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401001" svcproctype="disassemble" graphiccount="3">
        <title>DISASSEMBLE</title>
        <para>Before disassembling the compressor, the following parts should be marked for correct alignment at
            reassembly. Scribe mark front and rear end covers in relation to crankcase. Mark drive end of crankshaft.
            Mark cylinder head in relation to crankcase and mark base plate or base adapter (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0401008">Figure 8</hotlnk>and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0401009">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0401008" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0401008" filename="../figg04/G0401008.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Alignment Marks</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. ALIGNMENT MARKS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0401009" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0401009" filename="../figg04/G0401009.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. Exploded View</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. CRANKSHAFT NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. ADAPTER COVER FLANGE WITH BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>3. END COVER O-RING</callout1>
                <callout1>4. CRANKSHAFT BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>5. CONNECTING ROD BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1>6. CONNECTING ROD BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>7. CONNECTING ROD WITH CAP</callout1>
                <callout1>8. PISTON WITH PIN</callout1>
                <callout1>9. PISTON RING SET</callout1>
                <callout1>10. LOCK WRIST PIN WIRE</callout1>
                <callout1>11. PISTON WRIST PIN</callout1>
                <callout1>12. CYLINDER HEAD</callout1>
                <callout1>13. DISCHARGE VALVE SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>14. DISCHARGE VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>15. DISCHARGE VALVE SEAT</callout1>
                <callout1>16. CYLINDER HEAD GASKET</callout1>
                <callout1>17. INLET VALVE BUSHING</callout1>
                <callout1>18. INLET VALVE SEAT</callout1>
                <callout1>19. INLET VALVE SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>20. INLET VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>21. INLET VALVE STOP</callout1>
                <callout1>22. INLET VALVE GUIDE</callout1>
                <callout1>23. BACK-UP RING</callout1>
                <callout1>24. O-RING</callout1>
                <callout1>25. REAR COVER WITH BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>26. THRUST WASHER</callout1>
                <callout1>27. AIR COMPRESSOR CRANKSHAFT</callout1>
                <callout1>28. AIR COMPRESSOR CRANKCASE</callout1>
                <callout1>29. CRANKCASE GASKET</callout1>
                <callout1>30. CRANKCASE COVER</callout1>
                <callout1>31. CRANKCASE COVER O-RING</callout1>
                <callout1>32. CRANKSHAFT BUSHING</callout1>
                <callout1>33. CRANKSHAFT KEY</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove all attachments such as governor, air strainer inlet fittings, discharge fittings and
                pipe plugs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove six cylinder head capscrews and tap the head with a soft mallet to break the gasket
                seal. Remove head and gasket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove inlet valve springs from the head, and inlet valves from their guides in the
                crankcase. Remove inlet valve guides from the valve seats on crankcase taking care not to damage seats.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Scrape off gasket material from cylinder head and crankcase.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unscrew discharge valve seats from cylinder head and remove discharge valve and springs.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the discharge valve stops, support the machined surface of the cylinder head on an
                arbor press bed and carefully press the stops from the top of the head and out the bottom. Be sure to
                allow sufficient clearance for the stops between the press bed and bottom of cylinder head. Discard
                inlet valve and springs. If the discharge valves, springs, and valve seats are defective, replace them.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove base plate or adapter mounting capscrews. Use a soft hammer or mallet to break seal.
                Clean seal material from surfaces.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before removing the connecting rods, mark each rod and its cap. Connecting rods are matched
                to their own cap for proper bearing fit and parts should not be interchanged. Straighten the lock tabs
                on connecting rod locks and remove bolts and bearing caps. Push the piston with connecting rod out top
                of cylinders of the crankcase (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401010">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401010" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401010" filename="../figg04/G0401010.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Connecting Rod Out Top of Cylinders</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reassemble bearing caps on their respective connecting rods.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove piston rings from piston.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove pistons from connecting rods by removing wrist pin lock wires or teflon plugs and
                press the wrist pins from pistons and connecting rods. If wrist pin bushing is excessively worn, press
                out worn bushing and press in new bushing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove key from crankshaft. Through drive type compressors may have a crankshaft key at each
                end. Remove drive end cover. Remove end cover.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove both small seal rings from crankcase and O-ring from the front end cover.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove capscrews from rear end cover and remove rear end cover. Use care in removing end
                cover so as not to damage main bearing if bearing is used.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove both small seal rings from crankcase and O-ring from end cover.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If compressor is equipped with ball type main bearings, press crankshaft and ball bearings
                from crankcase. Then press bearings from crankshaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove unloader spring, spring saddle and spring seat from the inlet cavity of crankcase
                using a long nose pliers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove unloader plunger and guides.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position a shop cloth over the inlet cavity and apply air pressure to governor mounting pad
                unloader port to blow the unloader pistons out of their bores and into the inlet cavity.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
