<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE: AR-1 - MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>If the AR-1 fails to function as described, or leakage is excessive, it should be repaired or replaced
                with a new or re-manufactured unit, available at authorized International Dealers.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>When working on or near electrical components, follow the vehicle manufacturer's
                                recommended procedures, and deactivate the electrical system in a manner that removes
                                all electrical power from the vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>When working in the engine compartment, the engine should be shut off. Where
                                circumstances require that the engine be in operation, EXTREME CAUTION should be used to
                                prevent personal injury resulting from contact with moving, rotating, leaking, heated,
                                or electrically charged components.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip. Never
                                remove a component or plug unless you are certain all system pressure has been depleted.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety glasses.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until you have
                                read and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper tools and
                                observe all precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Use only genuine INTERNATIONAL&#174; replacement parts, components, and kits.
                                Replacement hardware, tubing, hose, fittings, etc. should be of equivalent size, type,
                                and strength as original equipment and be designed specifically for such applications
                                and systems.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Components with stripped threads or damaged parts should be replaced rather than
                                repaired. Repairs requiring machining or welding should not be attempted unless
                                specifically approved and stated by the vehicle or component manufacturer.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                                restored to their proper operating condition.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
            <title>EVERY 3 MONTHS, 25,000 MILES OR 900 OPERATING HOURS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any accumulated contaminants and visually inspect the exterior for excessive
                    corrosion and physical damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all air lines connected to the AR-1 for signs of wear or physical damage.
                    Replace as necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test air line fittings for excessive leakage and tighten or replace as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the Leakage Test.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04026.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
