<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - SYSTEM COMPONENTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="11">
        <title>SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Full Power Brake system is comprised of the following components. Each is described, in greater
                detail, in the following paragraphs.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Master Cylinder and Reservoir</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Hydraulic Compact Unit (HCU)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Foundation Brakes (Rotors and Calipers)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Wheel Speed Sensors</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Body Controller (BC)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Traction Control (Mud and Snow) Switch (Optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Electronic Gauge Cluster (EGC)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Master Cylinder and Reservoir</title>
            <para>The master cylinder is mounted to the engine side of the cowl directly in front of the driver (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405105">FIGURE 5</hotlnk>). It consists of a dual channel (primary and secondary)
                piston assembly, providing separate circuits for the front and rear brakes. The master cylinder also
                contains the spring pack that returns the brake pedal to its up position, and provides the correct pedal
                'feel' to the driver. The purpose of the master cylinder is to translate the pedal force applied by the
                driver into the hydraulic pilot signals that are routed to the relay valve, attached to the hydraulic
                compact unit. The switch that detects a brake actuation (brake light switch) is mounted to the master
                cylinder and is replaceable without draining any brake fluid.
            </para>
            <para>The reservoir mounted to the top of the master cylinder provides the fill port for the entire brake
                system. This is accomplished by a low pressure hose that connects the master cylinder reservoir to the
                reservoir on top of the HCU. Internal baffles in the reservoir provide a protected volume of brake fluid
                for the master cylinder circuit, in the event of a leak in the remainder of the system. An external
                sensor mounted to the bottom of the reservoir detects when the brake fluid level is low. This sensor is
                replaceable without draining any brake fluid.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405105" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G0405105" filename="../figg04/G0405105.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Master Cylinder and Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RESERVOIR MOUNTING NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FLUID LEVEL SENSOR CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. MASTER CYLINDER BRAKE TUBE CONNECTIONS</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. MASTER CYLINDER MOUNTING NUT (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. BRAKE LIGHT SWITCH CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. CLAMP FOR LOW PRESSURE HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CLAMP FOR BRAKE TUBES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Compact Unit (HCU)</title>
            <para>The HCU is mounted to the inside of the left frame rail, behind the cab, and is the heart of the Full
                Power Brakes system (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405106">FIGURE 6</hotlnk>). The HCU responds to hydraulic inputs from the master
                cylinder. The ECU is mounted to the HCU, but will be described in more detail separately. Like the
                master cylinder, the HCU is divided into front and rear hydraulic channels. However, the electronically
                controlled ABS valves of the HCU allow independent control of the braking force at each of the four
                wheel ends during an ABS event.
            </para>
            <para>It is worth noting that the accumulator, pump motor, and relay valve connection located to the rear of
                the HCU are part of the front axle brake circuit (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405107">FIGURE 7</hotlnk>). Likewise, the rear half of the reservoir is also part of
                the front axle circuit. The components located to the front of the HCU are part of the rear axle
                circuit. However, the brake tubes feeding the front axle circuits are connected to the front of the HCU;
                and the rear axle circuits are fed by tubes connected to the rear of the HCU.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405106" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405106" filename="../figg04/G0405106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Hydraulic Compact Unit</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ACCUMULATORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PUMP MOTORS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. RELAY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. 2-PIN CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 31-PIN CONNECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT (ECU)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0405107" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G0405107" filename="../figg04/G0405107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Brake Circuits in the HCU</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>F - PART OF FRONT AXLE (PRIMARY) BRAKE CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>R - PART OF REAR AXLE (SECONDARY) BRAKE CIRCUIT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0405108" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405108" filename="../figg04/G0405108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Hydraulic Compact Unit Exploded View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RELAY VALVE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT (ECU)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HCU RESERVOIR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HCU BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ACCUMULATOR (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PUMP MOTOR (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PUMP (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SOLENOID VALVES AND PRESSURE SENSORS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405108">FIGURE 8</hotlnk>
                for an exploded view of the HCU. The HCU is comprised of:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>the dual circuit relay valve (Figure 8, item 1)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>routes brake fluid from the pressurized accumulator circuits to the wheel ends in
                                proportion to the pilot signals received from the master cylinder during braking
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>connects the wheel ends to the reservoir when not braking</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>actuated by the ATC valves during an ATC event (vehicles with optional ATC)</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the Electronic Control Unit (ECU) (Figure 8, item 2)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>may be replaced separately from the HCU</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The ECU is described separately in the following paragraph.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the HCU reservoir (Figure 8, item 3)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>supplied brake fluid by a low pressure hose from the master cylinder reservoir</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>contains an internal baffle to separate the fluid supply for the front and rear
                                hydraulic channels
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>contains two supply ports for the front and rear axle circuits (pump assemblies)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>contains two return ports from the front and rear axle circuits (calipers)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>may be replaced separately from the HCU</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the HCU body (Figure 8, item 4)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>provides brake fluid routing passages for the primary and secondary circuits</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>houses two pressure relief valves for safety against overpressure</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>components (except pumps) are not replaceable separately, repair requires replacement
                                of the HCU assembly
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>two precharged accumulators pre-charged to 1087 psi (Figure 8, item 5; also refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0405109">FIGURE 9</hotlnk>)
                        <emph type="bold">(NOTE: The accumulators are physically mounted to the HCU, but may be replaced
                            separately.)
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>provide independent front and rear brake channel pump/motor accumulator circuits
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>act as storage devices for the pressurized brake fluid that provides the braking
                                force
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>are pressurized by the pump/motor circuits to between 1770 psi and 2320 psi during
                                normal operation
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>may be replaced separately from HCU, and must be replaced in pairs (the accumulators
                                are not rechargeable)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>two hydraulic pumps driven by electric motors (E-motors) (Figure 8, items 6 and 7)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>provide independent front and rear brake channel pump/motor circuits</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>are controlled by the ECU, based on readings of the fluid pressure transducers (in the
                                HCU)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>pressurizes the accumulators as directed by the ECU</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>pumps may be replaced separately from HCU</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>E-motors are not replaceable separately, repair requires replacement of the HCU</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the ABS/ATC solenoid control valves (Figure 8, item 8)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>eight ABS solenoid valves that control the brake fluid pressure applied to each wheel
                                caliper during ABS and ATC events (one inlet valve and one outlet valve per wheel)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>two ATC solenoid valves that work in conjunction with the ABS valves to control the
                                brake fluid pressure to each wheel during an ATC event (only on vehicles equipped with
                                optional ATC)
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>all solenoid valves are controlled by the ECU and the TOOLBOX diagnostic program while
                                performing certain maintenance procedures
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>cannot be replaced separately, repair requires replacement of the HCU assembly</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the two pressure transducers (Figure 8, item 8)</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>monitor the brake fluid pressure stored in the accumulators</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>cannot be replaced separately, repair requires replacement of the HCU assembly</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0405109" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G0405109" filename="../figg04/G0405109.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Cutaway View of Accumulator</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRESSURIZED GAS PRECHARGE AREA</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREADED PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PRESSURIZED FLUID AREA</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</title>
            <para>The ECU is mounted to the side of the HCU, and is the brains of the brake system (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405110">FIGURE 10</hotlnk>). It provides all of the electronic control required for
                normal braking, ABS operation, and ATC operation (on vehicles equipped with optional ATC). The ECU
                interfaces with the other brake system components, as well as the vehicle electrical system, through
                waterproof connectors. The 2-pin and 31-pin connectors are part of the ECU housing.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not open the ECU. Opening the ECU to gain access to the internal components will void the
                        warranty.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0405110" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405110" filename="../figg04/G0405110.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The ECU has various programmable parameters that can vary according to vehicle configuration. The
                default parameter settings are programmed at the factory. To ensure that a replacement ECU has the
                correct settings, use only the correct replacement part number. Then, refer to ISIS to complete the
                programming of the replacement ECU, based on the VIN number of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">During ALL operational modes, the ECU:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>monitors status of the fluid level sensor, and outputs a signal if fluid is low</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>maintains the correct accumulator pressure by monitoring the pressure transducers, and cycling
                        the motor/pumps as necessary
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>provides fault detection, stores fault codes, and signals the Body Controller (BC) to turn on
                        warning indicators
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>stores a set of counters in memory for reference during diagnostics, or to plan preventive
                        maintenance
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>(with optional ATC) monitors status of the dash-mounted MUD/SNOW switch, and selects the ATC
                        mode indicated by the switch position. Selects between ATC Normal mode and ATC Mud and Snow
                        mode.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>(with optional ATC) monitors signals from wheel speed sensors to determine if ATC operation is
                        necessary
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>(with optional ATC) provides ATC fault detection, stores fault codes, and turns on TRAC CTRL
                        warning indicator if necessary
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">During normal braking operation, the ECU:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>monitors status of master cylinder brake switch (actuated by brake pedal), and outputs a
                        signal indicating brake actuation
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>monitors signals from wheel speed sensors to determine if ABS operation is necessary</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">During ABS operation, the ECU:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>monitors status of master cylinder brake switch (to verify that the brake pedal is
                        depressed)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>monitors signals from wheel end sensors to determine which wheels require ABS operation</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>controls the ABS solenoid valves for the wheels requiring ABS operation</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">(with optional ATC) During ATC operation, the ECU:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>monitors status of master cylinder brake switch (to verify that the brake pedal is not
                        depressed)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>processes sensor signals and generates solenoid valve commands to apply differential braking
                        of slipping drive wheel(s) during an ATC event (if vehicle speed is 31 mph or less)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>sends a signal to the engine controller (ECM), to limit engine torque, during an ATC event, if
                        both drive wheels begin to lose traction
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>outputs a signal to the vehicle Body Controller (BC), during an ATC event. The BC sends a
                        signal to the gauge cluster to continuously light the TRAC CTRL indicator.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Foundation Brakes (Rotors and Calipers)</title>
            <para>Service information covering the rotors and calipers can be found in existing service manual
                <exhotlnk document="../s04/s04047.htm">s04047</exhotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Speed Sensors</title>
            <para>The wheel speed sensors are magnetic coil/pickup type sensors located at each wheel end (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405111">FIGURE 11</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405112">FIGURE 12</hotlnk>). Each sensor is positioned near a tooth ring (also known
                as a tone ring or exciter ring) which is attached to the wheel hub (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405113">FIGURE 13</hotlnk>). As the wheel spins, the teeth (and the spaces between
                them) pass through the magnetic field of the sensor, causing the sensor to produce voltage pulses. The
                voltage pulses (signal) from each wheel speed sensor are routed to the ECU to indicate the relative
                speed of each wheel. The frequency of the wheel speed signal is directly proportional to the speed of
                the wheel. Broken or missing teeth, or corrosion between the teeth, can cause an inaccurate wheel speed
                signal.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405111" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405111" filename="../figg04/G0405111.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Typical Wheel Speed Sensor</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BUSHING (SPRING CLIP)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WHEEL SPEED SENSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0405112" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405112" filename="../figg04/G0405112.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Typical Speed Sensor Locations</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT SENSOR BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FRONT SENSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. REAR SENSOR CABLE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0405113" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405113" filename="../figG04/G0405113.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Rotor with Tooth Ring</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Controller (BC)</title>
            <para>The Body Controller (BC) is located on the driver's side kick panel, behind the trim panel. While the
                Electronic Control Unit (ECU) is the brains of the brake system, the BC is the brains of the vehicle
                electrical system. Some electrical signals used by the ECU are communicated through the BC. Also, to
                turn on warning and status indicators, the ECU must communicate with the gauge cluster through the BC.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Driveline Parking Brake Drum</title>
            <para>The parking brake systems currently used with the Full Power Brakes system, on medium duty vehicles,
                are the manual (Orscheln) lever and the air powered parking brake. Both systems apply the parking brake
                by providing tension to the cable that actuates the drum type parking brake. The parking brake drum is
                located where the driveshaft is connected to the rear axle yoke. Refer to manual
                <exhotlnk document="../s04/s04044.htm">S04044</exhotlnk>
                for more complete service information on the driveline parking brake drum assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Traction Control (Mud and Snow) Switch (with Optional ATC)</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>While servicing an ATC equipped vehicle, the ATC system
                        <emph type="underscr">MUST BE DISABLED</emph>
                        before operating the vehicle with only one drive wheel lifted off of the ground. Performing this
                        operation on a vehicle with an active ATC system may result in the vehicle moving and falling
                        from the jacks as power will be transferred to the wheel that is still on the ground.
                    </para>
                    <para>The ATC system cannot be disabled using the dash mounted MUD/SNOW switch. This switch selects
                        between two levels of traction control.
                    </para>
                    <para>The ATC system can be TEMPORARILY disabled using the EZ-Tech service tool, running the TOOLBOX
                        diagnostic program. Use extreme caution. When the ATC system is disabled using the EZ-Tech, it
                        will remain disabled only until the next ignition cycle. The TOOLBOX screen will indicate when
                        the ATC function is disabled.
                    </para>
                    <para>Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The dash mounted MUD/SNOW switch (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405114">FIGURE 14</hotlnk>) is used to select the Mud and Snow mode when the driving
                conditions require it. The following paragraphs describe the difference between the Mud and Snow mode
                and normal ATC operation.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Normal Traction Control (Normal Driving Conditions)</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>When the MUD/SNOW switch is off (switch indicator NOT lit) the ATC system operates in its
                        normal traction control mode. The indicator on the switch and the TRAC CTRL indicator in the
                        gauge cluster will both be unlit. (NOTE: the TRAC CTRL indicator will be on solid during an ATC
                        event, or if an active ATC fault is detected.) In this mode differential braking is used to
                        control traction when one drive wheel loses traction and vehicle speed is 31 mph or less. Engine
                        torque limiting is used to control traction when both drive wheels lose traction. This is the
                        normal operating mode and should be used for most driving conditions.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Mud and Snow Mode (Off-Road Driving Conditions)</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>The driver should set the MUD/SNOW switch to the on position when driving in deep snow or
                        off-road conditions. This signals the ECU to allow more wheel spin than normal. When the Mud and
                        Snow mode is enabled the indicator on the switch will be lit and the TRAC CTRL indicator in the
                        gauge cluster will be flashing. (NOTE: the TRAC CTRL indicator will be on solid during an ATC
                        event, or if an active ATC fault is detected.) The MUD/SNOW switch should be returned to the off
                        position when the vehicle is no longer operating in deep snow or mud.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>For complete system electrical diagrams, refer to the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS manual
                listed in ISIS. For information concerning troubleshooting the electrical circuits in the full power
                brakes system, refer to the applicable ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405114" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405114" filename="../figg04/G0405114.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="112px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Mud/Snow (Traction Control) Switch</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Gauge Cluster (EGC)</title>
            <para>The EGC contains all of the indicators used to display the status of the Full Power Brakes system (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>). The warning buzzer that activates under certain
                conditions, is also located in the EGC.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0405115" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405115" filename="../figg04/G0405101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Indicators Used for the Full Power Brakes System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Pressure Indicator</title>
            <para>The BRAKE pressure indicator is located in the instrument panel gauge cluster (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>). The indicator lights to indicate that the pressure in all
                or part of the system has dropped below a minimum level (approximately 1550 psi). Low pressure detected
                in half of the system (front or rear circuit only) will be indicated by a solid on indicator. Low
                pressure detected in the full system (both front and rear circuits) will be indicated by a flashing
                indicator. Every time the indicator is lit, the warning buzzer sounds, and a diagnostic code is
                generated by the ECU and stored in memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                . A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch is turned to the RUN position. The indicator should
                turn on for about three seconds then turn off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Fluid Indicator</title>
            <para>The BRAKE FLUID indicator (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>) lights to indicate that the brake fluid level in the
                master cylinder reservoir is below the minimum level. A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch
                is turned to the RUN position. The indicator should turn on for about three seconds then turn off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Indicator</title>
            <para>The ABS indicator (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>) lights when a malfunction has been detected in the ABS
                system. Every time the indicator is lit, a diagnostic code is generated by the ECU and stored in memory.
                Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                . A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch is turned to the RUN position. The indicator should
                turn on for about three seconds then turn off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TRAC CTRL Indicator</title>
            <para>On vehicles equipped with the optional ATC the traction control indicator (TRAC CTRL) is located in
                the electronic gauge cluster (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>). A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch is
                turned to the RUN position. The indicator should turn on for about three seconds then turn off. This
                indicator indicates the following three conditions.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The TRAC CTRL lamp will be flashing whenever the Mud and Snow mode is selected using the
                        MUD/SNOW switch (switch indicator lit).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The TRAC CTRL indicator will be lit continuously whenever a traction control related fault has
                        been detected. Every time a fault is detected, a diagnostic code is generated by the ECU and
                        stored in memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section 5,
                        <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If no ATC related faults have been detected, the TRAC CTRL indicator will be continuously lit
                        only during an ATC event.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Indicator</title>
            <para>Some vehicles have an additional BRAKE indicator located in one of the indicator quadrants below the
                speedometer and tach (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0405115">FIGURE 15</hotlnk>). The specific location of this indicator may vary.
            </para>
            <para>When the indicator is on solid it indicates that either:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>the brake fluid level in the Master Cylinder reservoir is low, or</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>a sensor in the HCU has detected low pressure (&#60;1550 psi) in the accumulator for
                        <emph type="bold">either</emph>
                        the front or rear brake circuit.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When the indicator is flashing it indicates that a sensor in the HCU has detected low pressure (&#60;1550
                psi) in the accumulators for
                <emph type="bold">both</emph>
                the front and rear brake circuits. In this situation, once vehicle speed drops below 25 mph, engine
                limiting will limit the vehicle speed to 25 mph or less.
            </para>
            <para>Every time the indicator is lit (solid or flashing), the warning buzzer sounds, and a diagnostic code
                is generated by the ECU and stored in memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section
                5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                . A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch is turned to the RUN position. The indicator should
                turn on for about three seconds then turn off.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051206.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051300.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
