<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 550 AND TU-FLO 750 - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <table id="hl0400303">
            <title>Troubleshooting Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="0">
                <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.99in"/>
                <colspec colname="2" colwidth="1.99in"/>
                <colspec colname="3" colwidth="2.99in"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry valign="bottom">
                            <para>CONDITION</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry valign="bottom">
                            <para>POSSIBLE CAUSE</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry valign="bottom">
                            <para>REMEDY</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor passes excessive oil as evidenced by presence of oil at exhaust ports of
                                valving or seeping inlet from air strainer.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Restricted air intake.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check engine or compressor air cleaner and replace if necessary. Check compressor air
                                inlet line for kinks, excessive bends and be certain inlet lines have the minimum
                                specified inside diameter. Recommended minimum inlet line inside diameter is 5/8" (15.9
                                mm). Recommended maximum air inlet restriction is 25" of water.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Restricted oil return line to engine.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Oil return to the engine should not be in any way restricted. Check for excessive
                                bends, kinks, and restrictions in the oil return line. Minimum recommended oil return
                                line size is 5/8" O.D. (15.9 mm) tubing or equivalent l.D. (1/2" (12.7 mm) minimum).
                                Return line must CONSTANTLY DESCEND from the compressor to the engine crankcase. Make
                                certain oil drain passages in the compressor and mating engine surfaces are unobstructed
                                and aligned. Special care must be taken when sealants are used with or instead of
                                gaskets.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Poorly filtered inlet air.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for damaged, defective or dirty air filter on engine or compressor. Check for
                                leaking, damaged or defective compressor air intake components (i.e., induction line,
                                fittings, gaskets, filter bodies, etc.).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Insufficient compressor cooling.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For air-cooled portions of the compressor:</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1. Remove accumulated grease, grime, or dirt from the cooling fins. Replace components
                                found damaged.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2. Check for damaged cooling fins. Replace components found damaged</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>For water-cooled compressor or water-cooled portions of the compressor:</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>1. Check for proper coolant line sizes. Minimum recommended size is 1/2" l.D.
                                tubing.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2. Check the coolant flow through the compressor. Minimum allowable flow is 2.5
                                gallons (9.5L) per minute at engine governed speed. If low coolant flow is detected,
                                inspect the coolant lines and fittings for accumulated rust scale, kinks and
                                restrictions.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>3. Water temperature should not exceed 200 degrees F (93&#176;C).</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>4. Optimum cooling is achieved when engine coolant flows as shown in
                                <hotlnk document="s04003r_5.xml" xrefid="f0400309">Figure 9</hotlnk>of this manual.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Contaminants not being regularly drained from system reservoirs.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check reservoir drain valves to insure that they are functioning properly. It is
                                recommended that the vehicle should be equipped with functioning automatic drain valves,
                                or have all reservoirs drained to zero (0) psi daily optimally to be equipped with a
                                desiccant-type air dryer prior to the reservoir system.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor runs loaded for an excessive amount of time.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle system leakage should not exceed industry standards of 1 psi pressure drop per
                                minute without brakes applied, and 3 psi pressure drop per minute with brakes applied.
                                If leakage is excessive, check for system leaks and repair.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive engine crankcase pressure.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test for excessive engine crankcase pressure and replace or repair crankcase
                                ventilation components as necessary. (An indication of crankcase pressure is a loose or
                                partially lifted dipstick.).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive engine oil pressure.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the engine oil pressure with a test gauge and compare the reading to the engine
                                specifications. Bendix does not recommend restricting the compressor oil supply line
                                because of the possibility of plugging the restriction with oil contaminants. Minimum
                                oil supply line size is 3/16" l.D. tubing.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace or repair the compressor only after making certain none of the preceding
                                installation defects exist.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Noisy compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Loose drive gear or pulley.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect the fit of the drive gear or pulley on compressor crankshaft. The pulley or
                                gear must be completely seated and the crankshaft nut must be tight. If the compressor
                                crankshaft surface or its keyway is damaged, it is an indication of loose drive
                                components. If damage to the compressor crankshaft is detected, replace the compressor
                                or the crankshaft. When installing the drive gear or pulley, torque the crankshaft nut
                                to 100 ft-lbs. (135 N&#8226;m).
                                <emph type="bold">Do not back off the crankshaft nut to align the cotter pin and
                                    castellated nut.</emph>(Some compressors do not use castellated nuts.)
                                <emph type="bold">Do not use impact wrenches.</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessively worn drive couplings or gears.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect drive gear, couplings and engine for excessive wear. Replace as necessary.
                                (Non-metallic gears should be replaced when the compressor is changed.)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor cylinder head or discharge line restrictions.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect the compressor discharge port and discharge line for carbon build-up. If
                                carbon is detected, check for proper cooling to the compressor (see first condition,
                                fourth remedy).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect the discharge line for kinks and restrictions. Replace discharge line as
                                necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Worn or burned out bearings.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for proper oil pressure in the compressor. Minimum required oil pressure: 5 psi
                                engine idling, 15 psi maximum governed engine rpm. Check for excessive oil temperature.
                                The temperature should not exceed 240&#176;F (115.5&#176;C).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace or repair the compressor after determining none of the preceding installation
                                defects exist.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive build-up and recovery time. Compressor should be capable of building air
                                system from 85 to 100 psi in 40 seconds with engine at full governed rps. Minimum
                                compressor performance is certified to meet Federal requirements by the vehicle
                                manufacturer. Do not downsize the original equipment compressor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dirty induction air filter.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect engine or compressor air filter and replace if necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Restricted induction line.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect the compressor air induction line for kinks and restrictions and replace as
                                necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Restricted discharge line or compressor discharge cavity.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect the compressor discharge port and line for restrictions and carbon build-up.
                                If a carbon build-up is found, check for proper compressor cooling. Replace faulty
                                sections of the discharge line.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Slipping drive components.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for faulty drive gears and couplings and replace as necessary. Check the
                                condition of drive belts and replace or tighten, whichever is appropriate.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive air system leakage.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test for excessive system leakage and repair as necessary. Use the following as a
                                guide: build system pressure to governor cutout and allow the pressure to stabilize for
                                one minute. Using the dash gauge, note the system pressure and the pressure drop after
                                two minutes.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The pressure drop should not exceed:</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>2 psi in each reservoir for a single vehicle.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>6 psi in each reservoir for a tractor and trailer.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>8 psi in each reservoir for a tractor and 2 trailers.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Sticking unloader pistons.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the operation of the unloading mechanism. Check the proper operation of the
                                compressor air governor. If the governor is operating properly, replace the unloader
                                mechanism. Inspect for bent, kinked or blocked tubing leading to or from the governor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace or repair the compressor after determining none of the preceding installation
                                defects exist.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor fails to unload.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty governor or governor installation.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test the governor for proper operation and inspect air lines to and from the governor
                                for kinks or restrictions. Replace or repair the governor or its connecting air lines.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty or worn unloader pistons or bores.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inspect for worn, dirty or corroded unloader piston and bore. Replace as necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor leaks oil.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Damaged mounting gasket.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the compressor mounting bolt torque. If the mounting bolt torque is low, replace
                                the compressor mounting gasket before retorquing the mounting bolts.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cracked crankcase or end cover.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Visually inspect the compressor exterior for cracked or broken components. Cracked or
                                broken crankcases or mounting flanges can be caused by loose mounting bolts. The end
                                cover can be cracked by overtorquing fitting or plugs installed in the end cover.
                                Replace or repair the compressor as necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Loose end cover cap cover.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the capscrew torques and tighten as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Loose oil supply or return line fittings.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the torque of external oil line fittings and tighten as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Porous compressor casting.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace the compressor if porosity is found.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Mounting flange or end cover O-ring or gasket missing, cut or damaged</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor constantly cycles (compressor remains unloaded for a very short time).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaking compressor unloader piston.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remove the compressor inlet air strainer or fitting. With the compressor unloaded (not
                                compressing air), check for air leakage. Replace as necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty governor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test the governor for proper operation and repair or replace as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive system leakage.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test for excessive system leakage as instructed under the condition of "Excessive
                                build-up and recovery time". Reduce leakage wherever possible.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive reservoir contaminants.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Drain reservoirs.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor leaks coolant.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Improperly installed plugs and coolant line fittings.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check torque of fittings and plugs and tighten as specified in the Torque Chart.
                                Overtightened fittings and plugs can crack the head casting.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Freeze cracks due to improper anti-freeze strength.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Test antifreeze and strengthen as necessary. Check coolant flow through compressor to
                                assure the proper antifreeze mixture reaches the compressor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty compressor (faulty castings).</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If casting porosity is detected, replace the compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor head failure.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Restricted discharge line.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clear restriction or replace line.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Loose head bolts.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tighten evenly as specified in the Torque Chart.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry>
                            <para></para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Faulty compressor or head gasket.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for rough or poorly machined head or block surfaces. Replace necessary
                                components.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
