<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR COMPRESSOR GOVERNOR (TYPE D-2) - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0400214" svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operating Test</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                        pressures, gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Start the vehicle engine, build up air pressure in the air brake system, and check the pressure
                registered by a dash or test gauge at the time the governor cuts out, stopping the compression of air by
                the compressor. The cut-out pressure should be in accordance with the piece number of the governor. The
                more common cut-out pressure is 125 5 psi.
            </para>
            <para>With the engine still running, make a series of brake applications to reduce the air pressure and
                observe at which pressure the governor cuts in the compressor. As in the case of the cut-out pressure,
                the cut-in pressure should be in accordance with the specifications of the governor part number. Common
                cut-in pressure is 100 to 105 psi. Governor pressure settings should be checked with an accurate test or
                dash gauge. If the pressure settings of the governor are inaccurate or it is necessary that they be
                changed, procedure is as follows.
            </para>
            <para>To adjust the governor, first unscrew the cover at the top of the governor. Next, loosen the adjusting
                screw lock nut. Turn the adjusting screw counterclockwise to raise the pressure setting, and turn the
                screw clockwise to lower the pressure setting. After the adjustment is completed, the adjusting screw
                lock nut should be tightened to lock this adjustment. Screw cover securely onto governor.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>1/4 turn will change the setting approximately 4 psi. Any governor requiring more than a full
                        turn adjustment should be cleaned and inspected.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Test</title>
            <para>Leakage checks on the governor are made at its exhaust port in both cut-in and cut-out positions.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">In the cut-in position, check exhaust port for inlet valve leakage by applying a soap
                    solution at the port.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leakage could also be going past the bottom piston grommet. In the cut-out position,
                    check the exhaust port to determine leakage at the exhaust valve seat or stem grommet. In this
                    position, leakage could also be going past the upper piston grommet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Leakage in excess of 1 inch (25 mm) diameter soap bubble in 3 seconds is not permissible in either of
                the foregoing tests. If excess leakage is found, the governor must be repaired or replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_122.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_124.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
