<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - ABS PARTIAL SHUTDOWN</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ABS PARTIAL SHUTDOWN</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Depending which component the fault is detected on, the ABS and ATC functions may be fully or
                partially disabled. Even with the ABS warning lamp on, the EC-30 may still provide ABS function on
                wheels that are not affected by the fault. The EC-30 should be serviced as soon as possible.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front ABS Modulator Fault</title>
            <para>ABS on the affected wheel is disabled. ABS and ATC on all other wheels remains active.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear ABS Modulator Fault</title>
            <para>ATC is disabled. ABS on the affected wheel is disabled. ABS on all other wheels remains active.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Front Wheel Speed Sensor Fault</title>
            <para>The faulted wheel is still controlled by using input from the remaining wheel speed sensor on the
                front axle. ABS remains active on the rear wheels. ATC is disabled.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mid or Rear Wheel Speed Sensor Fault</title>
            <para>ATC is disabled. In a four sensor system, ABS on the affected wheel is disabled, but ABS on all other
                wheels remains active.
            </para>
            <para>In a six sensor system, ABS remains active by using input from the remaining rear wheel speed sensor
                on the same side.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ATC Modulator Fault</title>
            <para>ATC is disabled. ABS remains active.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>J1939/J1922 Communication Fault</title>
            <para>ATC is disabled. ABS remains active.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ECU Fault</title>
            <para>ABS and ATC are disabled. The system reverts to normal braking.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Voltage Fault</title>
            <para>While voltage is out of range, ABS and ATC are disabled. The system reverts to normal braking. When
                the correct voltage level is restored, full ABS and ATC function is available. Operating voltage range
                is 9.0 to 16.0 VDC.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
