<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: BENDIX TU-FLO 550 AND TU-FLO 750 - REPAIR - DISCHARGE VALVES, VALVE STOPS AND SEATS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DISCHARGE VALVES, VALVE STOPS AND SEATS</title>
        <para>If the discharge valve seats merely show signs of slight wear, they can be dressed by using a lapping
            stone, grinding compound and grinding tool; however, it is recommended that a cylinder head maintenance kit
            be used.
        </para>
        <para>Install new discharge valve springs and valves. Screw in the discharge valve seats, and tighten to 70 to
            90 ft-lbs. (94.906 to 122.022 N&#8226;m). Discharge valve travel should be between .030 inch to .046 inch
            (.762 to 1.168 mm). To test for leakage of the discharge valves, apply 100 psi to the cylinder head
            discharge port and apply a soap solution to the discharge valve and seats. Leakage in the form of soap
            bubbles is not permissible.
        </para>
        <para>If excessive leakage is found, leave the air pressure applied and with the use of a fiber or hardwood
            dowel and a hammer, tap the discharge valves off their seats several times. This will help the valves to
            seat and should reduce the leakage. With the air pressure still applied at the discharge port of the
            cylinder head, check for leakage around the discharge valve stop on the top of the cylinder head casting. No
            leakage is permitted.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_32.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r_34.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04003r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
