<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - ANTILOCK AND TRACTION SYSTEM OPERATION DURING COMPONENT FAILURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ANTILOCK AND TRACTION SYSTEM OPERATION DURING COMPONENT FAILURE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The Bendix EC-17 handles equipment failure using a conservative fail safe philosophy. Any single
                electrical failure of a component devoted to antilock or traction control results in simultaneous
                illumination of the appropriate condition lamp on the dash, a disabling of part or all of the antilock
                or traction system, and reversion to standard braking on wheels no longer under EC-17 control.
            </para>
            <para>Depending upon the type of failure and its position of occurrence, the EC-17 disables all or only a
                portion of the antilock and traction system. A power or controller failure, however, will result in
                complete disabling of both systems and reversion to standard (non-antilock) braking is still available
                on all wheels.
            </para>
            <para>There are a variety of ways to clear faults detected by the system. In most cases, the system will
                reset the fault condition when the source of the original fault has returned to a normal state for a
                period of time. Isolated faults are able to be reset by the system, but repeated occurrence (and
                self-clearing) of some faults will require a manual reset. This is done to aid in the troubleshooting of
                intermittent faults. The PC interface (or optional magnetic reset) is used to manually clear faults.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
