<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - OPERATION - ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use the electrical circuit diagram book for your truck model as a reference for the following
                        explanations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403908">EHCU Power Circuits</hotlnk>
            </title>
            <figure id="f0403908" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403908" filename="../figg04/G0403908.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Electrical Connections</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. 2-WAY CONNECTOR (258)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 24-WAY CONNECTOR (279)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Ignition power to the ECU is supplied to pin 14 of 24-way connector (279) on circuit 94K with 1000
                series models, 94 with the IC bus and circuit 94F with all other models.
            </para>
            <para>Power to the pump motor is supplied on pin B of 2-way connector (258) from a 60 amp maxi fuse on
                circuit 94A with 3000RE models, circuit 94K or 94K with all other models.
            </para>
            <para>Ground for the entire EHCU is supplied on pin A of 2-way connector (258) from ground on circuit
                94-G.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Data Link Circuit</title>
            <para>The ECU data link information is supplied on circuit 98J(+) or 98P(+) from connector (279) pin 5 to
                diagnostic connector (384)/(419), pin D on
                <emph type="bold">6 pin</emph>
                diagnostic connectors and pin H on
                <emph type="bold">9 pin</emph>
                connectors.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Switch Circuit</title>
            <para>On models other than the 3000FE/RE and IC bus, when the brakes are applied, 12 volts are supplied from
                stop light switch (51) on circuit 94C to ECU connector (279) pin 15.
            </para>
            <para>On 3000RE models, 12 volts are supplied from brake relay (R3) on circuit 97Y through dash connector
                (2), on circuit 94C to ECU connector (279) pin 15.
            </para>
            <para>On 3000FE models, 12 volts are supplied from brake switch (209) on circuit 90F to circuit 94C, through
                dash connector (2) to ECU connector (279) pin 15.
            </para>
            <para>On the IC bus, when the brakes are applied, 12 volts are supplied from hydraulic brake switch (50) on
                circuit 94C to ECU connector (279) pin 15.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Warning Light Circuit</title>
            <para>The ABS indicator is illuminated for a five second bulb check when the ignition is turned on. The lamp
                also illuminates when ABS is initialized or a fault is detected.
            </para>
            <para>Ignition power for the lamp is supplied on circuit 94F on the IC bus or 94B on all other models.
            </para>
            <para>The ABS indicator is normally on with ground supplied by a ground on circuit 94-GC through the
                normally closed contacts of the ABS warning light relay (4F) on the 1000 models, (R5) on the 4000
                models, (R1) on the 3800 and 4000FBC models or (R4) on the IC bus. The ABS lamp is switched off when the
                relay is energized by a ground originating from the ECU on pin 7 of connector (279) on circuit 94K on
                3000RE models, 94-GA on the IC bus and circuit 94H on all other models. This insures the warning light
                will always come on if there is an open in any of the circuits feeding the relay coil or a faulty ECU.
            </para>
            <para>When there is a fault, the ECU will light the indicator by applying a ground from pin 1 of connector
                (279) on circuit 94H with the IC bus and circuit 94A on all other models, to circuit 94E and the ABS
                warning light.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Left Rear Wheel Speed Sensor Circuit</title>
            <para>The AC signal from the left rear wheel speed sensor travels through 2-way connector (293) or (430) on
                circuits 94LR(H) and 94LR(L) and through 6-way connector (323) pins 1 and 3 to ECU connector (279) pins
                9 and 21.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Right Rear Wheel Speed Sensor Circuit</title>
            <para>The AC signal from the right rear wheel speed sensor travels through 2-way connector (295) or (432) on
                circuits 94RR(H) and 94RR(L) to ECU connector (279) pins 8 and 20.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Left Front Wheel Speed Sensor Circuit</title>
            <para>The AC signal from the left front wheel speed sensor travels through 2-way connector (289) or (426A)
                on circuits 94LF(H) and 94LF(L) to ECU connector (279) pins 11 and 23.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Right Front Wheel Speed Sensor Circuit</title>
            <para>The AC signal from the right front wheel speed sensor travels through 2-way connector (1004), on the
                1000 series trucks, on circuits 94RF(H) and 94RF (L) to ECU connector (279) pins 10 and 22. The signal
                travels through 2-way connector (292) or (428), on models other than the 1000 series, through connector
                (1004) on circuits 94RF(H) and 94RF (L) to ECU connector (279) pins 10 and 22.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Retarder Circuits</title>
            <para>On 1000 Series models, a 1K ohm resistor is wired from circuit 94F to ECU connector (279) pin 2 on
                circuit 24H. This resistor simulates the coil of the retarder interrupt relay to prevent the fault code
                which would result from an open relay coil. It is located in the wire harness, approximately 150mm (6
                inches) from the EHCU.
            </para>
            <para>3000 FE/RE models not equipped with an Allison electronic transmission have a 1K ohm resistor jumper
                on connector (377)/(168) from circuit 24H or 94J to circuit 13J. This resistor simulates the ABS/MD
                signal ground relay (569).
            </para>
            <para>On 3000FE/RE models equipped with an Allison electronic transmission, during normal operation, the
                ABS/MD signal ground relay (569) is de-energized and the transmission retarder is not disabled. When the
                ABS is activated, a ground from the ECU on pin 2 of connector (279) will energize the relay and disable
                the transmission retarder. This prevents these features from interfering with ABS function.
            </para>
            <para>3400, 3800, 4000 and 4000FBC models not equipped with retarder(s) have a 1K ohm resistor jumper on
                connector (377) from circuit 24H to circuit 13J. This resistor simulates the coil of the retarder
                interrupt relay to prevent the fault code which would result from an open relay coil.
            </para>
            <para>On 3400, 3800, 4000 and 4000FBC models equipped with retarder(s), during normal operation, the
                retarder interrupt relay (286) is de-energized and there is no break in the signal path of the retarder
                circuits. When the ABS is activated a ground from the ECU on pin 2 of connector (279) will energize the
                relay and break the signal path of the retarder circuits. This will disable the exhaust brake,
                transmission retarder or engine brake, if equipped. This prevents these features from interfering with
                ABS function.
            </para>
            <para>IC bus models not equipped with an Allison electronic transmission have a 1K ohm resistor jumper on
                connector (377) from circuit 94J to circuit 92. This resistor simulates the ABS/MD signal ground relay
                (569).
            </para>
            <para>On IC bus models equipped with an Allison electronic transmission, during normal operation, the ABS/MD
                signal ground relay (569) is de-energized and the transmission retarder is not disabled. When the ABS is
                activated, a ground from the ECU on pin 2 of connector (279) will energize the relay and disable the
                transmission retarder. This prevents these features from interfering with ABS function.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_S0403901.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
