<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - PRINCIPLES, OPERATION AND SERVICE - OPERATION - MODULATOR VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
        <title>MODULATOR VALVE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The antilock system modulator (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402905">Figure 5</hotlnk>) is essentially a high capacity, ON/OFF air valve that
                incorporates a pair of electrical solenoids for control. The solenoids provide the electro-pneumatic
                link between the antilock controller electronics and the air brake system. The modulator valve can be
                used to control the braking function (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402906">Figure 6</hotlnk>) on an individual wheel or two service actuators (as with
                6x4). The modulator valve is the last control valve that air passes through on its way to the service
                brake actuator(s).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402905" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402905" filename="../figg04/G0402905.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Antilock System Modulator</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0402906" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402906" filename="../figg04/G0402906.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Modulator Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.MODULATOR VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.ELECTRICAL CONNECTION TO ABS CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.QRV</callout1>
                    <callout1>4.CONTROLLER/RELAY VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The modulator valve consists of a die cast aluminum body and a solenoid assembly, which contains one
                normally open (NO) solenoid, one normally closed (NC) solenoid, and two inlet and exhaust diaphragm
                valves. A Packard, three pin, 280 series weather resistant electrical connector is an integral part of
                the modulator valve solenoid assembly and serves to carry control commands from the antilock controller
                to the modulator valve. The Supply, Delivery and Exhaust ports on the modulator valve are identified
                with a cast, embossed numeral for positive identification. They are as follows:
            </para>
            <para>IDENTIFICATION VALVE PORTING</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Supply: Incoming air from brake valve through QRV (front axle) or relay valve (rear axle).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Delivery: Air delivery to service actuators.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Exhaust: Air exhausted during antilock control.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Antilock Operation - General</title>
            <para>If a service brake application is made and the antilock system detects an impending wheel lockup, the
                antilock controller will immediately begin modification of the brake application using the modulator
                valve.
            </para>
            <para>In order to modify the brake application, the coils of the two solenoid valves contained in the
                modulator valve are energized or de-energized in a pre-programmed sequence by the antilock controller.
                When a solenoid coil is energized, a shuttle within the solenoid moves, and depending upon the function
                of the specific solenoid, it either opens or closes, thereby causing the exhaust or re-application of
                air pressure to the brake actuator. The solenoids in the modulator valve are controlled independently by
                the antilock controller. By opening and closing the solenoid valves in the modulator valves, the
                antilock controller is able to simulate what the driver does when he "pumps the brakes." The antilock
                controller is able to "pump" each modulator, along with the brakes connected to it, independently and
                with far greater speed and accuracy.
            </para>
            <para>For more detailed information on the modulator valve, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04029.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
