<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3900 - AR-1 ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE - OPERATION AND LEAK TESTS - AR-1
        ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION AND LEAK TESTS - AR-1 ANTILOCK RELAY VALVE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following test requires 2 technicians.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation Test</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply and release the brakes several times while a helper checks for prompt application
                    and release at each wheel. If prompt reaction is noted at some,
                    <emph type="bold">but not all wheels</emph>, test the antilock modulator between the AR-1 and the
                    brake actuator for proper operation. If a "sluggish" response is noted at all wheels, inspect for a
                    kinked or obstructed air line leading to or from the AR-1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If some,
                    <emph type="bold">but not all,</emph>brakes release completely, test the antilock modulator between
                    the AR-1 and the brake actuator. If an incomplete release is noted at all wheels, inspect for a
                    kinked or clogged air line leading to or from the AR-1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">During brake release, confirm that a slight "puff" of air exits at the AR-1's quick
                    exhaust port in the cover. Air exiting at this exhaust port indicates the AR-1 integral quick
                    release is functioning.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Leakage Tests</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build the air system pressure to governor cut-out, and apply a soap solution to the
                    exhaust port in body. The leakage noted should not exceed a one-inch bubble in less than three (3)
                    seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make and hold a full brake application and apply a soap solution to the exhaust ports in
                    the body, cover, and around the cover where it joins the body. The leakage noted should not exceed a
                    one-inch bubble in less than three (3) seconds at any exhaust port.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
