<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - CONTROLLER CONFIGURATION - SELF-CONFIGURING PROCESS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SELF-CONFIGURING PROCESS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Three aspects of the antilock and traction system are influenced by the self-
                    configuring feature of the EC-16.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Speed Sensors - The number of speed sensors connected to the EC-16 will be detected
                        during the self-configuration process. The EC-16 will check the MID SEN (mid axle speed sensor)
                        locations on its connector to determine if a sensor is connected to it and will default to a six
                        sensor configuration if it detects even one sensor connected. If no mid axle speed sensor is
                        detected, the EC-16 will default to a four sensor configuration.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Electronic Engine Control - If the EC-16 is connected to the control module of an
                        electronic engine, the torque limiting feature of traction control will be activated during the
                        self-configuring process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Antilock Traction Relay Valve - If the solenoid assembly in the ATR valve is
                        connected to the EC-16, the differential braking feature of traction control will be activated
                        during the self-configuring process.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No method is available to disable the self-configuration method.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Due to the extended period of time the magnet must be held on the RESET to initiate the
                    self-configuration process (between 10 and 20 seconds), it is unlikely that a self-configuration
                    would occur accidentally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Basic, four speed sensor, antilock operation cannot be removed during the
                    self-configuration process. This is a minimum configuration for all EC-16 controllers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a speed sensor is connected to either wheel on the mid axle, the EC-16 will configure
                    for six sensors. If no mid axle speed sensor is detected, the EC-16 will configure for four sensors.
                    Any disconnected speed sensor(s) will register as a failure on the diagnostic display at the end of
                    the EC-16 self test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All or part of traction control can be lost during self-configuration by:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Not connecting one of the wire harnesses (engine control module for torque limiting
                        and ATR valve solenoid for differential braking).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A missing or inoperative traction dash lamp (bulb missing or burned out).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A missing or inoperative traction control enable/disable switch.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Not placing the traction control enable/disable switch in the disabled position. The
                        operator can tell that the traction features are lost by noting the absence of the traction lamp
                        flash upon power up. The operator should note the flashing of the antilock condition lamp, and
                        the traction lamp if traction equipped, upon every power-up. Observing the dash lamps is the
                        only method the operator has to verify the system operation.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The EC-16 can be reprogrammed up to 10,000 times.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When a replacement EC-16 is installed on a vehicle that does not have one or more of the
                    pre-programmed features, a failure will be registered on the dash lamp(s) and on the EC-16
                    diagnostic display. For this reason, it is necessary to perform the self-configuring procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Some configuration information is available by observing the reaction of the dash
                    condition lamps on vehicles configured with traction control and equipped with the self-configuring
                    EC-16. When the ignition is switched ON, the EC-16 self test is begun. During the self test, the
                    dash lamps will flash on and off together as indicated in Table 8.01, depending upon the type and
                    amount of traction control configured into the EC-16.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For more information on this subject, refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403205.xml" xrefid="hl0403205">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Controller Configuration</title>
            <table id="hl0403206">
                <title>Antilock Lamp Signals</title>
                <tgroup cols="6">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.95in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="1.00in"/>
                    <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.96in"/>
                    <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.95in"/>
                    <colspec colname="6" colwidth="0.97in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Antilock Lamp</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Lamp On 1st Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Lamp Off 1st Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Lamp On 2nd Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Lamp Off 2nd Time</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Lamp On Stays On</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Traction Lamp (EC-16 w/torque limiting and differential braking)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>On</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>On</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para>Stays Off</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Traction Lamp (EC-16 w/torque limiting only)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>On</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para>Stays Off</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1">
                                <para>Traction Lamp (EC-16 w/differential braking only)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2">
                                <para>On</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="4">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="5">
                                <para>Off</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="6">
                                <para>Stays Off</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Self-Configuration Process</title>
            <para>To successfully complete the self-configuring process, follow the steps below.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all antilock and traction control wire harnesses. Refer to the schematic in
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_2.xml" xrefid="f0403203">Figure 3</hotlnk>. Make certain that all the speed
                    sensors present on the vehicle are connected (H2, H3, J1, J2 on the 30 pin connector and E2, E3, F2,
                    F3, B2, B3, C2, C3 on the 18 pin connector). If the vehicle has an electronic engine and traction
                    control torque limiting is desired, the engine control module must be connected (B2 and B3 on the 30
                    pin connector). If the vehicle is equipped with either an ATR-1 or ATR-2 valve, the solenoid
                    connection must be made to the EC-16 (D2 and D3 on the 18 pin connector) to obtain traction control
                    differential braking.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is configured with traction control, it has a traction control dash lamp
                    and a traction control enable/disable switch. Both the lamp and switch must be functional. Place the
                    traction control enable/disable switch in the traction control disabled position (traction control
                    inoperative).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the ignition ON and hold a magnet on the RESET position of the EC-16 diagnostic
                    display until the LEDs begin to randomly flash, then remove the magnet. If the magnet is not removed
                    during the random LED flashing, a second self-configuration may be initiated. The magnet may have to
                    be held on the RESET for as long as 20 seconds. When the self-configuration process is complete, the
                    EC-16 will automatically go through a self-test. During the self-test, the diagnostic display will
                    indicate the new configuration as described under the section entitled
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403207.xml" xrefid="hl0403207">CONFIGURATION DISPLAY</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the EC-16 is being configured with Traction Control (either torque limiting,
                            differential braking or both), the traction control condition dash lamp will be illuminated
                            as well as the appropriate LEDs on the EC-16 diagnostic display. The traction control dash
                            lamp will be illuminated until the traction control enable/disable switch is placed in the
                            traction control enabled position (traction control operative).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the traction control enable/disable switch in the traction control enabled
                    position (traction control operative); the traction control dash lamp should be off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before placing the vehicle in service, verify the configuration and the system condition
                    by turning the ignition OFF then ON while observing the EC-16 diagnostic display. The diagnostic
                    display should indicate the desired configuration as described under the section entitled
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403207.xml" xrefid="hl0403207">CONFIGURATION DISPLAY</hotlnk>, and no
                    red LEDs should be illuminated at the end of the self-test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the configuration appears correct but the diagnostic LEDs indicate a failure
                    somewhere in the system, refer to the general configuration information below and use the
                    <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403205.xml" xrefid="hl0403205">TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                    section to locate and repair the problem.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the configuration is incorrect, the process can be repeated as required. One common
                    error is performing the self-configuration with the traction enable/disable switch in the wrong
                    position. This will prevent any traction features from being activated.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The traction switch must be in the disable position to configure traction, but must be
                            placed in the enable position to allow the traction lamp to flash.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403207.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_HL0403205.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
