<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAM AIR FOUNDATION BRAKES - REASSEMBLY - SERVICE INFORMATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="assemble" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SERVICE INFORMATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>After various components of the brake assemblies have been serviced, brakes are reassembled by
                reversing the disassembly procedure.
            </para>
            <para>It is recommended that newly installed brake linings be circle/cam ground before installing brake
                drums. Circle/cam grinding of linings to fit drum assures full contact between lining and drum. For more
                detailed information, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>When reassembling various components which are secured with bolts and/or nuts such as backing plates,
                spiders, camshaft brackets or anchor pins, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s04005_HL0400505.xml" xrefid="hl0400505">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>, for torque
                specifications.
            </para>
            <para>Brake shoes must be properly located to provide the designed efficiency of the brake group. The
                primary (forward) shoe is the first shoe just past the cam in forward direction of wheel rotation.
            </para>
            <para>Brake shoes with combination brake block sets of semi-metallic and organic lining must be installed as
                shown in (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400517">Figure 17</hotlnk>and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400518">Figure 18</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400517" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400517" filename="../figg04/G0400517.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Right Wheel Rotation (Arrow)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY (FORWARD) SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY (REVERSE) SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SEMI-METALLIC BRAKE BLOCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ORGANIC BRAKE BLOCK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0400518" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400518" filename="../figg04/G0400518.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Left Wheel Rotation (Arrow)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRIMARY (FORWARD) SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SECONDARY (REVERSE) SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CAM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SEMI-METALLIC BRAKE BLOCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. ORGANIC BRAKE BLOCK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The brake blocks on each shoe consist of one semi-metallic material (shaded area) and one organic
                material (unshaded area).
            </para>
            <para>The semi-metallic is identified by the metal particles embedded in the brake block. The organic
                material will not have the visible metal particles.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drums and Shoes</title>
            <para>For complete details covering the servicing of drums and shoes, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Anchor Pins</title>
            <para>Anchor pins provide a point where shoes can be secured to the backing plate or spider and also permit
                positioning the shoe in respect to the drum.
            </para>
            <para>Anchor pins are designed to withstand all braking force of slowing or stopping vehicle.</para>
            <para>Anchor pins which are secured to the backing plate with a lock washer and nut are tightened by using
                two wrenches: one wrench is positioned on the nut while the second wrench is positioned over the flats
                on threaded area on anchor pin. For torque value, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04005_HL0400505.xml" xrefid="hl0400505">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>, .
            </para>
            <para>If staked anchor pins become worn, the complete spider will have to be replaced.</para>
            <para>Anchor pins in spiders which are removable will be equipped with bushings which are serviceable.
                Replacement bushings are to have a clearance of .003 - .005 inch (.076 - .127mm) between bushing and
                pin.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04005.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
