<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR PRESSURE GAUGES - SERVICE CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE CHECKS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect connections to assure no air leakage at gauge or in the system.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is not compulsory but it is advisable that vehicles be inspected to be sure that the air
                gauges are properly installed. The primary system should be the gauge with number 1 on the gauge face.
                The secondary system is the gauge with number 2 on the gauge face.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To check for correct gauge installation, charge the air system (full), bleeding off the
                primary system (rear brake reservoir). Gauge number 1 should drop.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the air gauge for accuracy. The simplest way to do this is to compare the pressures
                registered by the gauge over its normal pressure range with the pressure registered by a test gauge
                known to be accurate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery pressures,
                    governor pressure settings and other tests.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">A gauge which loses its accuracy must be replaced. The continued use of a dash gauge showing
                an error of more than 5 psi is not recommended.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
