<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: MERITOR WABCO WITH "D" VERSION ECU</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s04037" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5289" date="08/11/1998">
        <title>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: MERITOR WABCO WITH "D" VERSION ECU</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/02/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WARNING</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>MATERIAL DUST DURING BRAKE SERVICING</para>
                            <seqlist>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Studies have indicated that exposure to excessive amounts of brake material
                                        dust (whether asbestos or non-asbestos, fiberglass, mineral wool, aramid,
                                        ceramic or carbon) may be a potential cancer-causing health hazard. Even though
                                        the Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has not set any limits
                                        on non-asbestos dust exposure, there is some medical opinion that such
                                        non-asbestos fibers can cause cancer as well. Since most automotive friction
                                        materials normally contain a sizeable amount of this material, it is important
                                        that people who handle brake linings be aware of the problem and know the
                                        precautions to be taken.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Areas where brake work is done should be set aside, if possible, and should be
                                        posted with a material dust exposure sign as follows:
                                    </para>
                                    <randlist type="bullet">
                                        <item>
                                            <para>BRAKE LINING FIBER DUST HAZARD</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>AVOID BREATHING DUST</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>WEAR ASSIGNED PROTECTIVE EQUIPMENT</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>DO NOT REMAIN IN AREA UNLESS YOUR WORK REQUIRES IT</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>BREATHING BRAKE LINING FIBERS MAY BE HAZARDOUS TO YOUR HEALTH</para>
                                        </item>
                                    </randlist>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as
                                        well as for suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29,
                                        Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1910.1001.)
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Whenever possible, work on brakes in a separate area away from other
                                        operations.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all brake service
                                        procedures. Wear the respirator from removal of the wheels through assembly.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>NEVER use compressed air or dry brushing to clean brake parts or assemblies.
                                        OSHA recommends that you use cylinders that enclose the brake. These cylinders
                                        have vacuums with high efficiency (HEPA) filters and worker's arm sleeves. But,
                                        if such equipment is not available, carefully clean parts and assemblies in the
                                        open air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Clean brake parts and assemblies in the open air. During disassembly,
                                        carefully place all parts on the floor to avoid getting dust into the air. Use
                                        an industrial vacuum cleaner with a HEPA filter system to clean dust from the
                                        brake drums, backing plates and other brake parts. After using the vacuum,
                                        remove any remaining dust with a rag soaked in water and wrung until nearly dry.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Grinding or machining brake linings. If you must grind or machine brake
                                        linings, take additional precautions because contact with fiber dust is higher
                                        during these operations. In addition to wearing an approved respirator, do such
                                        work in an area with exhaust ventilation.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cleaning the work area. NEVER use compressed air or dry sweeping to clean the
                                        work area. Use an industrial vacuum with a HEPA filter and rags soaked in water
                                        and wrung until nearly dry. Dispose of used rags with care to avoid getting dust
                                        into the air. Use an approved respirator when emptying vacuum cleaners and
                                        handling used rags.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking. Do not
                                        wear your work clothes home. Vacuum your work clothes after use and then launder
                                        them separately, without shaking, to prevent fiber dust from getting into the
                                        air.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL</title>
                    <para>The Meritor WABCO Antilock Braking System (ABS) is an electronic system that monitors and
                        controls wheel speed during braking. The system works with standard air brake systems.
                    </para>
                    <para>ABS monitors wheel speeds at all times and controls braking during wheel lock situations. The
                        system improves vehicle stability and control by reducing wheel lock during braking.
                    </para>
                    <para>The ECU receives and processes signals from the wheel speed sensors. When the ECU detects a
                        wheel lockup, the unit activates the appropriate modulator valve, and air pressure is
                        controlled.
                    </para>
                    <para>In the event of a malfunction in the system, the ABS in the affected wheel(s) is disabled;
                        that wheel still has normal brakes. The other wheels keep the ABS function.
                    </para>
                    <para>An ABS warning lamp lets drivers know the status of the system. This lamp is also used to
                        display blink code diagnostics (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403701">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403701" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="312px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. ABS Warning Lamp</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The location of the ABS warning lamp varies, depending on the make and model of the
                                vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ECU IDENTIFICATION</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not open the ECU. Opening the ECU to gain access to the internal components will
                                void the warranty.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>C and D version ECUs are easy to distinguish (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403702">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403702" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="352px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. C and D Version ECUs</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The ECU version, C or D, appears on the part number identification tag (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403703">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403703" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403703.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                                 scalefitheight="352px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3. Part Number Identification Tag</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If you cannot identify the ECU version installed on your vehicle, contact Meritor
                                Customer Service, 1-800-535-5560.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ABS CONFIGURATION</title>
                    <para>The ABS configuration is defined by the number of wheel end sensors and modulator valves.
                        There are three common ABS configurations used with D version ECUs:
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>4S/4M (4 wheel speed sensors, 4 modulator valves)
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403704">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>6S/4M (6 wheel speed sensors, 4 modulator valves).</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>6S/6M (6 wheel speed sensors, 6 modulator valves).</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                    <figure id="f0403704" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403704.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                                 scalefitheight="472px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4. 4S/4M ABS Configuration</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ABS WARNING LAMP</title>
                    <para>The ABS warning lamp works as follows:</para>
                    <table id="t0403701" frame="all">
                        <title>ABS Warning Lamp Operation</title>
                        <tgroup cols="4" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                            <colspec colwidth="1.38in"/>
                            <colspec colwidth="1.38in"/>
                            <colspec colwidth="1.99in"/>
                            <colspec colwidth="1.99in"/>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry morerows="2">
                                        <para>Ignition
                                            <emph type="bold">ON</emph>
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Normal Operation</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>ABS lamp comes on at ignition momentarily for a bulb check, then goes
                                            out.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>System is OK.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>-</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>After Servicing ABS System</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>ABS lamp does not go out at ignition.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>When vehicle is driven at speeds above 4 mph (6 km/h), lamp goes out.
                                            System is OK.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>-</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Existing Fault</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>ABS lamp does not go out at ignition.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>Lamp does not go out at speeds above 4 mph (6 km/h) - a fault exists in
                                            the ABS system.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If the ECU senses a fault during normal vehicle operation, the ABS warning lamp will
                                come on and stay on.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ABS Modulator Valves</title>
                    <para>Modulator valves control the air pressure to each affected brake during an ABS function.
                    </para>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403705">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403705" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403705.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="472px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 5. Easy Listening Tip for ABS Valve Operation</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Valve Arrangement Option</title>
                        <para>In
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403704">Figure 4</hotlnk>, the modulator valves on the rear axle are
                            mounted separately and a relay valve is used to deliver air pressure to the modulator
                            valves. There is also an optional valve package available from Meritor WABCO, the ABS Valve
                            Package, which may be found on certain vehicle models. The ABS valve package may be used on
                            all D version units, including D Basic.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>ABS Valve Package</title>
                        <para>The ABS valve package combines a service brake relay valve with two ABS modulator valves.
                            It is mounted in the rear of the vehicle, near the brake chambers it serves, on vehicles
                            equipped with Meritor WABCO ABS (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403706">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f0403706" figsize="pg-wide">
                            <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403706.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                                     scalefitheight="472px"/>
                            <caption>Figure 6. ABS Valve Package</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>ABS SENSORS</title>
                    <para>ABS sensor systems consist of a tooth wheel mounted on the hub of each monitored wheel and a
                        sensor installed so that its end is against the tooth wheel. The sensor continuously sends wheel
                        speed information to the ECU. A sensor clip holds the sensor in place at the tooth wheel.
                    </para>
                    <para>The type of axle determines sensor mounting location:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Steering axle sensors are installed in the steering knuckle or in a bolted-on
                                bracket.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Drive axle sensors are mounted in a block attached to the axle housing or in a
                                bolted-on bracket.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>AUTOMATIC TRACTION CONTROL</title>
                    <para>Automatic Traction Control (ATC) is available as an option on all ABS truck, tractor, and bus
                        applications. ATC can be used with individual valves, or with an integrated ABS/ATC valve
                        package.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
                    <para>The ECU is the brain of the ABS system. It receives information from the sensors and sends
                        signals to the ABS valves (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403707">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403707" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403707.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                                 scalefitheight="192px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 7. ECU</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403708">Figure 8</hotlnk>
                        for the following references in parentheses. A tooth wheel (A) is mounted at, or cast in, the
                        hub of each sensed wheel, with a sensor (B) installed so that its end is against the tooth
                        wheel. A sensor clip (C) holds the sensor in place at the tooth wheel.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403708" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403708.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                                 scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 8. Sensor Operation</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The sensor and clip must be greased with Meritor WABCO-recommended lubricant (D) (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403708">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Lube must be mineral oil-based and contain
                        molydisulfide. It should have excellent anti-corrosion and adhesion characteristics, and be
                        capable of continuous function in a temperature range of -40&#176; to 300&#176;F (-40&#176; to
                        150&#176;C).
                    </para>
                    <para>An ABS modulator valve controls air pressure to each affected brake during an ABS event (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403709">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403709" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403709.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                                 scalefitheight="272px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 9. ABS Modulator Valve</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The modulator valve is usually located on a frame rail or crossmember near the brake
                        chamber.
                    </para>
                    <para>Sensor cables connect the sensor to the ECU (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403710">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403710" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403710.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                                 scalefitheight="192px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 10. Sensor Cables</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>ABS modulator valve cables connect the modulator valve to the ECU (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0403711">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f0403711" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../figg04/g0403711.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                                 scalefitheight="192px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 11. ABS Modulator Valve Cables</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04037_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04037.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
