<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR DRYER - CR BRAKEMASTER MODEL 62
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="4">
        <title>CR BRAKEMASTER MODEL 62</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The CR Brakemaster (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400260">Figure 60</hotlnk>
                ) functions as a heat exchanger, cooling air from the compressor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400260" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400260" filename="../figg04/g0400260.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 60. CR Brakemaster Model 62</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When the compressed air leaves the air compressor, it is approximately 300&#176;F (149&#176;C), and by
                the time it reaches the Brakemaster unit, it has cooled to 140&#176;F (60&#176;C).
            </para>
            <para>The hot, compressed air enters the expansion chamber where the sudden drop in pressure provides
                additional cooling. Heat is dissipated through the external fins on the one-piece aluminum body.
            </para>
            <para>As the air cools in the expansion chamber, both water and oil vapors are condensed. This condensation
                collects on the walls of the expansion chamber and runs down into the collection area where it is
                automatically discharged through an unloader valve.
            </para>
            <para>The heat exchanger has a permanent air filter element which traps carbon particles harmful to other
                components in the air system. Each time the unloader operates (each time the compressor completes a
                cycle), there is a back-rush of air through the filter, so that any carbon trapped in the filter element
                is flushed out and ejected through the unloader valve.
            </para>
            <para>If the air compressor is working properly, the filter will require little or no maintenance. If the
                filter should require servicing, flush it with cleaning solvent and air dry.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400225">
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Periodic or scheduled maintenance is not required. However, for trouble-free operation, the following
                items should be checked.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cooling fins should be free of dirt build-up or paint.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check air lines to be sure they have not become kinked, cracked, broken or chafed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build up pressure in air system, then bleed off air to cause the compressor to cycle.
                    Repeat several times.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compare heat level inlet and outlet ports by holding your hands on each of the ports.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>The inlet port may be hot; a burn could result if touched.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>The inlet port should be warmer than the outlet port; the outlet port should be at or slightly above
                ambient temperature. Since the vehicle is stationary, the unit will become warmer than normally
                experienced during over the road operation. If both inlet and outlet temperatures seem high (too hot to
                touch), the deflector will need servicing.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold a clean shop towel under the unloader (exhaust) port and make the air compressor go
                    through several "unload" cycles. Catch water from the unloader port. If water is oily, the
                    compressor should be checked. If water is "brownish" or if brown particles are expelled, the
                    deflector requires servicing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the heat exchanger has "exhausted" and while air compressor is in "stand-by" mode,
                    hold your hand under the unloader port. If air flows out the port, the check valve at the top
                    (outlet port) of the heat exchanger is stuck open and requires service, or the compressor inlet is
                    connected to the outlet side of the turbocharger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air leaks past the exhaust port while the compressor is building up pressure, the
                    unloader valve is stuck open and requires attention.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">While the air compressor is building up pressure, it is normal for the check valve to
                    produce a rattling sound through rapid opening and closing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the air compressor is rebuilt or replaced or if the heat exchanger is moved from
                    one vehicle to another, it is recommended that the heat exchanger unit be completely disassembled
                    and cleaned.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the unloader valve should stick in the open position while the vehicle is on the road, the air
                system can be restored by threading a 1/2 inch pipe plug into the exhaust port. By doing this, the air
                system pressure can be restored but moisture cannot be exhausted from the air dryer. The unit should be
                serviced as soon as possible by repairing the unloader valve.
            </para>
            <para>Before any work is accomplished, it is important to check the following:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The area surrounding the unit, and the unit itself, should be thoroughly cleaned to
                    remove dirt, oil and other road grime.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake and block wheels.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from vehicle's air system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Relieve pressure in line from "UNL" port of compressor governor to unloader port in the
                    center of the large nut on the bottom of the air dryer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Each part of the heat exchanger can be serviced by means of using the various service and replacement
                kits available.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Unloader Valve Service</title>
            <para>There are several indications which may mean that the unloader valve of your heat exchanger unit needs
                servicing:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The compressor goes into "stand-by" mode but cycles rapidly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Air flows from the exhaust port when the compressor is attempting to build up pressure
                    in the air system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The unit does not "unload" when the compressor goes into stand-by mode.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>These situations can be caused by several conditions. Check the
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0400208">
                    <xref refid="t0400208"/>TROUBLESHOOTING CHART
                </hotlnk>
                , to make sure that the probable cause is a malfunctioning unloader valve on the CR BRAKEMASTER unit. If
                the probable cause is the unloader valve, it could mean that a piece of debris is clogging this valve,
                and it only needs to be cleaned, or that the valve assembly itself has been worn and needs to be
                replaced. In either case, the following steps should be taken:
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400261" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic id="g0400261" filename="../figg04/g0400261.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 61. Air Dryer - CR Brakemaster Model 62</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. OUTLET PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. V-SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TOP CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. FILTER CUP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. STRAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. LOCKWASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. SUPPORT ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. LOCKWASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. CAPSCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. SPINDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. RING SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. HEATER</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. THERMOSTAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>20. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>21. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>22. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. U-CUP</callout1>
                    <callout1>24. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>25. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. UNLOADER PORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>27. UNLOADER NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>28. SLEEVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>29. BOTTOM CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>30. GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>31. GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>32. SUPPORT PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>33. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>34. DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>35. WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>36. PACKING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>37. V-SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>38. FILTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>39. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>40. GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>41. SAFETY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>42. SPINDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>43. GASKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>44. NUT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect electrical wire to heater.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect inlet air line from bottom cap (Item 29).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove governor control line from UNL port (Item 26).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove large unloader nut (Item 27) from UNL port (Item 26).</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Use care in removing the nut to prevent bodily injury since nut is spring loaded.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400262">Figure 62</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400262" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400262" filename="../figg04/g0400262.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 62. Air Dryer - Reassembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. RING SEAT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. LARGE SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. U-CUP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SLEEVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. RETAINING RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. SMALL SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. UNLOADER SPINDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. COPPER GASKET (2)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete unloader valve assembly, including copper gaskets (Item 10).</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Excessive accumulation of oil in the unloader assembly indicates that the air compressor requires
                attention.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Examine unloader valve assembly. If the unloader sleeve (Item 5) is nicked, wrinkled or
                    has axial scratches, the unloader valve assembly should be replaced. If clogged, the unloader valve
                    assembly should be cleaned with a good cleansing solvent.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not remove retaining ring (Item 7) from unloader spindle (Item 9) since they are
                    serviced as an assembly with spring (Item 8) and ring seat (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400262">Figure 62</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new "U" cup (Item 3) in groove of unloader piston (Item 6). Lips of "U" cup
                    should face away from spring seat. Do not use sharp tools that may mar or score parts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a light film of Fleetrite EP2 Moly grease or equivalent to NLGI#2 multi-purpose
                    lithium grease to O-ring (Item 4) and position on unloader nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the two copper gaskets (Item 10) together and lightly coat exposed surfaces
                    with Fleetrite EP2 Moly grease or equivalent to NLGI#2 multi-purpose lithium grease. Then position
                    lubricated gaskets on shoulder of ring seat (Item 1). Gaskets should be on face opposite the spring
                    (Item 8).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place gaskets (Item 10) followed by ring seat assembly into bottom cap (Item 29,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install unloader sleeve (Item 5) in unloader port against the ring seat. Be sure the 1/2
                    inch (12.7 mm) diameter cross hole is next to the ring seat (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position large spring (Item 2) in the sleeve (Item 5) with large diameter coil against
                    ring seat (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert unloader piston (Item 6) into unloader sleeve. Lips of U-cup (Item 3) must face
                    out with spring seat toward spring. The unloader spindle (Item 9) and ring seat (Item 1) is a mated
                    assembly and should not be disassembled. If either the ring seat or spindle is nicked, the entire
                    mated assembly must be replaced as an assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a 1/2 inch (12.7 mm) diameter rod or equivalent through the exhaust port in the
                    bottom cap (Item 29,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ) and into the cross hole of sleeve (Item 28,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ) to maintain alignment. If the cross holes are not aligned, the unit will not operate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a non-hardening sealing compound to threads in the unloader valve nut (Item 27,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ) and install nut. Tighten nut to 60 ft-lbs. (81 N&#183; m) -
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT OVER-TIGHTEN</emph>- maintaining the alignment of the cross holes of sleeve
                    (Item 28,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Over-tightening of the unloader nut will result in damage to the unloader assembly.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the alignment rod inserted in Step 8.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the governor control line to UNL port (Item 26,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                    ) in center of unloader nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall air inlet line from the compressor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electrical lead for the heater.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test unit using the instructions listed in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400225">
                        <xref refid="hl0400225"/>MAINTENANCE
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Deflector Assembly Service</title>
            <para>There are several indications which may mean that the deflector assembly needs servicing:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compressed air is not sufficiently cooled.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Water exhausted by the CR BRAKEMASTER is brownish or brown particles are exhausted.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">A piece of the deflector is caught in the unloader valve assembly, causing it not to
                    operate properly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>These situations can be caused by several conditions. Check the
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0400208">
                    <xref refid="t0400208"/>TROUBLESHOOTING CHART
                </hotlnk>
                , to make sure that the probable cause is a malfunctioning deflector assembly. If it is a malfunctioning
                deflector assembly, the following are the instructions for replacing this deflector assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air compressor inlet line at UNL port (Item 26).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wire from heater assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the eight capscrews (Item 13) retaining bottom cap (Item 29) to body (Item 33).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bottom cap (Item 29) and deflector assembly (Item 34).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all traces of old gasket(s) material from gasket surfaces of bottom cap (Item 29)
                    and body. Discard old gaskets. Be careful not to scratch or mar new gasket surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash bottom cap (Item 29) and inside of unit with cleaning solvent.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position new gasket (Item 31) on top of the surface of the deflector support plate (Item
                    32).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position second new gasket (Item 30) on gasket surface of bottom cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align bolt holes and position assembly against bottom gasket surface of body (Item 33).
                    Use of gasket sealant is NOT recommended.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert eight capscrews (Item 13) to attach bottom cap to body and deflector assembly
                    (Item 34). Tighten alternately to 15 ft-lbs. (20.3 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the air line to the inlet port (this line leads from the compressor service
                    port).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the wire to the heater.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Check Valve Assembly Service</title>
            <para>There are several indications which may mean that the check valve needs servicing:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Air is exhausted from the exhaust port when compressor is in stand-by mode.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">System air pressure bleeds off rapidly when air-using equipment is not being operated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compressor goes into stand-by mode but cycles rapidly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compressor attempts to build pressure but system pressure will not build up.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Safety valve opens.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>These situations can be caused by several conditions. Check the
                <hotlnk xrefid="t0400208">
                    <xref refid="t0400208"/>TROUBLESHOOTING CHART
                </hotlnk>
                , to make sure that the probable cause is a defective assembly. The following is the procedure for
                servicing and replacing the check valve assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400263">Figure 63</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400263" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400263" filename="../figg04/g0400263.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 63. Air Dryer CR Brakemaster Model 62 - Disconnect Air Line</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SPINDLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. GASKETS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TOP NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. NUTS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air line at outlet port at top of unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove top nut (Item 4). This nut is spring loaded.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove copper gaskets (Item 3), spring (Item 1), and check valve spindle (Item 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean and dry entire check valve area and top nut (Item 4).</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400263">Figure 63</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position new check valve spindle (Item 2) in top cap with tapered end down.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install spring (Item 1) in check valve spindle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position new copper gaskets (Item 3) in nut (Item 4) and rub a small quantity of grease
                    on the gaskets to help them keep their position in the top nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thread nut (Item 5) onto top cap studs and tighten to 15 ft-lbs. (20.3 N&#183; m). Top
                    nut (Item 4) is not included in check valve replacement kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the air line to the outlet port. The safety valve cannot be serviced and it is
                    recommended that it not be removed from the top cap. If the safety valve has been removed, apply
                    non-hardening sealant to threads of top cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Filter Assembly Service</title>
            <para>Although the filter assembly of the unit is designed to require little or no servicing, it is a good
                practice to service the filter assembly when performing service on other filters located on the vehicle.
                This servicing can be accomplished in one of two ways, either replacing entire filter assembly, or by
                servicing filter assembly. In most cases, only servicing will be necessary. The following are the steps
                for servicing the filter assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400261">Figure 61</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air line at outlet port (Item 1).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove eight capscrews holding top cap (Item 3) in body.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>The top cap is spring loaded to approximately 40 ft-lbs. (54 N S m). Use care in removing
                            the top cap bolts to prevent possible bodily injury.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove spring (Item 39).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all traces of gasket material from top cap and body gasket surfaces (Items 40 and
                    43). Discard gasket. Be careful not to scratch or score gasket surfaces. Wash top cap in cleaning
                    solvent.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove complete filter assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove rubber packing ring (Item 36) and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discard old stainless steel filter (Item 38). If you are replacing the entire filter
                    assembly, discard the entire filter assembly including filter cup (Item 5), strainer (Item 6) and
                    V-spring (Item 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash strainer (Item 6) and filter cup (Item 5) in cleaning solvent.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Reassemble</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble stainless steel filter (Item 38) in filter cup (Item 5). Filter should be
                    stretched slightly to fill the space in filter cup.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall strainer (Item 6) with flat face of strainer towards stainless steel filter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install V-spring (Item 2) holding the filter assembly together.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new packing ring (Item 36) on ledge of body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position filter assembly into body with large end down. The filter must set on packing
                    ring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install heavy spring (Item 39) with larger diameter coil against top of filter
                    assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position new gasket (Item 40) on body. Do not use gasket cement.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position top cap (Item 3) and V-spring (Item 2) so that the small diameter coil on
                    spring fits groove in top cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compress spring and install four 3/8 capscrews (Item 4) into body. Each of these four
                    screws should be engaged at least three full turns before load on cap is removed. Capscrews should
                    be equally spaced. Then thread remaining screws into place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Alternately tighten top cap bolts to 15 ft-lbs. (20.3 N&#183; m).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect air line to outlet port.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostatically Controlled Cartridge Type Heater Service</title>
            <para>The current heat exchanger units contain a 15 volt 50 watt heater as standard equipment. This heater
                requires a newly designed bottom cap which is completely interchangeable with those in use previously.
                Use of this new cap may, however, necessitate a change of the deflector assembly if your present bottom
                cap has the deflector attached by screws.
            </para>
            <para>There are two kits used in servicing the thermostatically controlled cartridge type heater assembly.
                Both heaters are 50 watt; however, one is 12 volt and the other is a 24 volt.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical line from the heater.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove old cartridge type heater by loosening set screw for heater on bottom cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove old thermostat from bottom cap by removing the two small screws which retain the
                    thermostat to the bottom cap. Discard entire heater/thermostat assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new heater by inserting it into hole from which old heater was removed and
                    tighten set screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new thermostat by inserting it into the hole from which old thermostat was
                    removed and attach by means of the two screws provided.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach the lead from the thermostat to the electrical system. Even though the heater is
                    thermostatically controlled, it is recommended that the heater be hooked up through a control
                    switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the unit is grounded to the chassis.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting Chart</title>
            <table id="t0400208" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Troubleshooting Chart - CR Brakemaster Model 62</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.68in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="2.49in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="2.38in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Possible Cause</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Remedy</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Air is exhausted from exhaust port when compressor is in the stand-by mode.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inlet side of compressor</para>
                                <para>connected to outlet side of turbocharger.</para>
                                <para>2. Check valve at outlet port stuck open.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Change compressor inlet connection.</para>
                                <para>2. Clean or replace check valve assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>System air pressure bleeds off rapidly when air-using equipment is not
                                    operating.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Leak in air line connection(s).</para>
                                <para>2. Leak in air line or reservoir.</para>
                                <para>3. Check valve at outlet port stuck open.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Tighten or replace fittings.</para>
                                <para>2. Repair or replace faulty item(s).</para>
                                <para>3. Clean or replace check valve assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressor runs continuously (will not go into stand-by mode).</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Leak in air line connections.</para>
                                <para>2. Leak in air line or reservoir.</para>
                                <para>3. Compressor defective.</para>
                                <para>4. Unloader valve stuck open.</para>
                                <para>5. Compressor capacity too low for vehicle.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Tighten or replace fittings.</para>
                                <para>2. Repair or replace faulty item(s).</para>
                                <para>3. Rebuild or replace</para>
                                <para>compressor.</para>
                                <para>4. Clean or replace unloader valve assembly.</para>
                                <para>5. Install larger compressor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressor goes into stand-by mode but cycles rapidly.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Leak in air system.</para>
                                <para>2. Check valve in CR Brakemaster outlet port stuck open.</para>
                                <para>3. Defective seal in unloader.</para>
                                <para>4. Unloader sleeve defective.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Correct leak.</para>
                                <para>2. Clean or replace check valve assembly.</para>
                                <para>3. Repair unloader valve.</para>
                                <para>4. Replace sleeve.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Air flows from exhaust port when compressor builds up pressure in air system.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Unloader valve stuck open.</para>
                                <para>2. Seat of unloader valve chipped or nicked.</para>
                                <para>3. Piece of dirt or foreign material stuck in unloader valve.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Rebuild unloader valve.</para>
                                <para>2. Replace seat assembly.</para>
                                <para>3. Replace seat assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressor attempts to build pressure but system pressure will not build up.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Line between compressor and exchanger blocked.</para>
                                <para>2. Check valve in outlet port stuck closed.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Replace line or remove blockage.</para>
                                <para>2. Clean outlet and replace check.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressor attempts to build pressure but system pressure will not build up
                                    (Cont.).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. Pressure sensing device</para>
                                <para>defective.</para>
                                <para>4. Blockage in air line between compressor and sensing device (Note: If safety
                                    valve of exchanger opens, blockage is after unit).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3. Replace.</para>
                                <para>4. Remove blockage.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Does not cool air (initial installation).</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Mounted in location where it cannot be cooled by ambient air.</para>
                                <para>2. Mounted too near heat</para>
                                <para>producing equipment or too near other heat dissipating equipment.</para>
                                <para>3. Copper tubing from compressor to inlet too short.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Relocate unit.</para>
                                <para>2. Relocate unit.</para>
                                <para>3. Increase length of copper tubing.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Does not "unload" when compressor goes into stand-by mode.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. UNL port of governor not</para>
                                <para>connected to unloader port or line broken.</para>
                                <para>2. Components of unloader valve worn.</para>
                                <para>3. Ice formed in area of unloader valve.</para>
                                <para>4. Heater inoperative.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Connect or repair valve.</para>
                                <para>2. Rebuild unloader valve.</para>
                                <para>3. Shorten line (24" minimum allowable length) and/or install heater.</para>
                                <para>4. Replace heater or check electrical connections.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Safety valve opens.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Check valve in outlet stuck closed.</para>
                                <para>2. Obstruction in air line beyond heat exchanger.</para>
                                <para>3. Compressor governor valve defective.</para>
                                <para>4. Safety valve defective.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Clean outlet and replace check valve assembly.</para>
                                <para>2. Remove obstruction.</para>
                                <para>3. Replace.</para>
                                <para>4. Replace.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Water exhausted by unit contains excessive oil and/or soot.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressor rings defective.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Rebuild or replace compressor.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No water exhausted during unloading cycle.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Insufficient water in ambient (inlet) air.</para>
                                <para>2. Not cooling air sufficiently to condense water.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1,2. Lengthen copper line from compressor to heat exchanger (36" max. length
                                    allowable). Relocate heat exchanger to area of greater ambient air flow.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Compressed air was cooled by unit but no longer is cooled</para>
                                <para>properly.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Covered with dirt or paint.</para>
                                <para>2. Deflector damaged or broken.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1. Steam clean and/or remove paint.</para>
                                <para>2. Replace deflector assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Water exhausted is brownish or brown particles are exhausted.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Broken or damaged deflector.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace deflector assembly.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Chart</title>
            <table id="t0400209" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Torque Chart - CR Brakemaster Model 62</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.03in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.08in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="0.96in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Location</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Ft-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Unloader Value Nut Cap</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>60</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>81</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Capscrews</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>20.3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Top Cap Bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>20.3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_115.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_117.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
