<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR COMPRESSOR GOVERNOR (TYPE D-2) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400288">Figure 88</hotlnk>
            for all items in parentheses.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400288" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400288" filename="../figg04/g0400288.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="352px"/>
            <caption>Figure 88. D-2 Governor Operation</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. COVER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. ADJUSTING SCREW</callout1>
                <callout1>3. LOCK NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                <callout1>5. EXHAUST STEM SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. EXHAUST STEM</callout1>
                <callout1>7. FILTERS</callout1>
                <callout1>8. PISTON</callout1>
                <callout1>9. INLET-EXHAUST VALVE SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>10. INLET AND EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>11. GROMMETS</callout1>
                <callout1>12. LOWER SPRING SEATS</callout1>
                <callout1>13. SPRING GUIDE</callout1>
                <callout1>14. PRESSURE SETTING SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>15. UPPER SPRING SEAT</callout1>
                <callout1>16. RETAINING RING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Reservoir air pressure enters the governor at one of its reservoir ports and acts on the area of the
            piston and beneath the inlet and exhaust valve. As the air pressure builds up, the piston moves against the
            resistance of the pressure setting spring (Item 14) and the inlet and exhaust valve (Item 10) moves up when
            the reservoir air pressure reaches the cut-out setting of the governor (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400288">Figure 88</hotlnk>
            ).
        </para>
        <para>The exhaust stem (Item 6) seats on the inlet and exhaust valve (Item 10) and then the inlet passage opens.
            Reservoir air pressure then flows by the open inlet valve, through the passage in the piston and out the
            unloader port to the compressor unloader mechanism. The air, besides flowing to the compressor unloader
            mechanism, also flows around the piston (Item 8) and acts on the additional area of the piston, assuring
            positive action and fully opening the inlet valve.
        </para>
        <para>As the system reservoir air pressure drops to the cut-in setting of the governor, the force exerted by the
            air pressure on the piston (Item 8) will be reduced so that the pressure setting spring (Item 14) will move
            the piston down. The inlet valve will close and the exhaust will open. With the exhaust open, the air in the
            unloader line will escape back through the piston, through the exhaust stem (Item 6) and out the exhaust
            port.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_120.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_122.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
