<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl04048500">
        <title>DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When working around or under the vehicle, block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving.
                        When raising the vehicle, support the vehicle with safety stands. Do not work under a vehicle
                        supported only by jacks. Jacks can slip and fall over. Failure to follow this warning could
                        result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The diagnostic system in the ECU is sensitive to over and under voltage conditions that could
                        be experienced during some service procedures (replacement of battery, jump starting). Fault
                        codes may be set due to these conditions, and may not indicate a true fault. Codes generated
                        during service must be cleared before placing the system back into service.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To display operational information: the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        service tool must be connected to the vehicle; the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic program must be
                        running; and the vehicle ignition must be ON.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For complete instructions for using the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic program, refer to the User's
                        Manual, TP-99102. Contact Meritor WABCO at 800-535-5560 (or www.meritorwabco.com) for
                        information about TOOLBOX&#8482; software.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The vehicles covered in this manual have used two different electrical controllers. Both
                        controllers are mounted in the same location. The original controller was known as the
                        Electrical System Controller (ESC). The current controller is known as the Body Controller (BC).
                        In this manual the controller will be identified as the Body Controller or the ESC/BC.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Malfunctions in the brake system could be attributed to either hydraulic, mechanical, or electrical
                failures in the system. Hydraulic and mechanical malfunctions are covered in this manual. When an
                electrical malfunction is indicated, the procedures located in the ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING
                manual will be referenced. Use the troubleshooting procedures and table(s) in those manuals to isolate
                and repair any electrical malfunctions.
            </para>
            <para>Diagnosis and troubleshooting of the brake system consists of the following steps:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnosis - identifying the general area of the system malfunction by observing the
                        warning/status indicators and the recorded faults.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Troubleshooting - following the repair instructions (presented in TOOLBOX&#8482;) to isolate
                        the fault to a specific component.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048405.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048501.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
