<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - USING ACOM FOR WINDOWS SOFTWARE - ACOM FILE MENU</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="4">
        <title>ACOM FILE MENU</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The ACom File menu contains two selections and allows the technician to alter the Setup of Acom that
                was selected during the installation of ACom on the computer. The Setup selection is used primarily to
                set the communications port (only the EC-17 controller is currently supported). The Exit selection is
                used to close ACom (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403821">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403821" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403821.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Exit Selection to Close ACom</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Setup Selection</title>
            <para>Click Setup and note that the Setup box has 3 file tabs at the bottom entitled:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Communications</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tool Bar/Status Bar</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Dialog Preferences.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Communications Tab</title>
            <para>Under "Communications" there are 4 list boxes (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403822">Figure 22</hotlnk>). The left two deal with the controller and the right 2
                with communication between ACom and the communications adapter, DCI or RS232 to J1708 converter.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403822" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403822.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. Four List Boxes</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Begin by choosing the correct ABS Controller Type. Refer to the DCI instructions and compare to the
                controller on the vehicle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Initially, only the EC-17 is supported.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>It is recommended that the ACom default ABS Controller Interface of J1587 remain unchanged unless you
                are sure that a different interface is in use.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Initially, only J1587 is supported.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Com1 is the default setting for the PC Communications Port and should be changed to the port that the
                DCI is connected to.
            </para>
            <para>Under PC Communications Adapter, select the "AlliedSignal DCI" v 1.0.</para>
            <para>After the selections have been made on the "Communications" tab, click Save on the actions menu along
                right side, then click the "Tool Bar/Status Bar" tab along the bottom.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The default setting can be reestablished by clicking the Default button above the Save
                        button.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tool Bar/Status Bar Tab</title>
            <para>The "Tool Bar/Status Bar" tab allows the user to customize the look of the main window of ACom screen.
                The Tool Bar along the top of the screen displays icons for the most common activities. The Tool Bar can
                be disabled so that only the menus across the top of the screen show.
            </para>
            <para>The Tool Bar may also be customized by adding or deleting various functions. This is accomplished by
                referring to the "Available Tool Bar Buttons" and the "Selected Tool Bar Buttons" and using the arrows
                to add or delete various buttons to the tool bar.
            </para>
            <para>In addition to the Tool Bar there is a Status Bar at the bottom of the screen that provides various
                handy pieces of information. The Status Bar can also be disabled (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403823">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403823" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403823.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Status Bar Can Be Disabled</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>After making the desired changes to the Tool and Status Bars, click Save on the actions menu along the
                right side then click the "Dialog Preferences" tab along the bottom.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The default setting can be reestablished by clicking the Default button above the Save
                        button.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dialog Preferences Tab</title>
            <para>The "Dialog Preferences" tab allows the user to modify the way in which ACom responds to the user's
                inputted information. Various notes and reminders are displayed. For example, ACom requests a
                confirmation to either save or not save a file before moving to a different function. It is recommended
                that the default settings not be changed until the user becomes familiar with the various functions of
                ACom (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403824">Figure 24</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403824" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0403824.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 24. Default Settings</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_39.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_41.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
