<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - HOSES, TUBING AND CONNECTIONS - TRAILER BRAKE HOSE COUPLING AND DUMMY COUPLING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TRAILER BRAKE HOSE COUPLING AND DUMMY COUPLING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Hose couplings provide a convenient means for connecting and disconnecting air lines between tractors
                and trailers. When two couplings are joined, their packing rings are forced together under pressure to
                form an air tight seal.
            </para>
            <para>Dummy coupling is the term given to those couplings which are used to keep dirt or foreign matter out
                of the air lines when they are not being used. Dummy couplings are either rigidly mounted to the truck
                or fastened by a chain.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>With hose couplings connected and brakes applied, coat hose couplings with soap suds to check for
                leaks. There should be no leakage. Leakage results from worn, dam- aged, or improperly installed packing
                rings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At least once a year or when leakage is detected, the hose coupling should be
                    disassembled, cleaned and serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove old packing ring with a screwdriver. Be sure packing ring groove is thoroughly
                    cleaned.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new packing ring by partially collapsing it with the fingers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f04002b6">Figure 116</hotlnk>
                    ) and entering one side of flange in groove in coupling.
                </para>
                <figure id="f04002b6" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g04002b6" filename="../figg04/G04002B6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 116. Install New Packing Ring</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. PACKING RING</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. HOSE COUPLING</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Work the remaining part of the packing ring into place with a blunt nosed (not sharp)
                    screwdriver or similar tool (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f04002b7">Figure 117</hotlnk>
                    ). Exposed face of packing ring will be flat and free of any bulges when properly installed.
                </para>
                <figure id="f04002b7" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g04002b7" filename="../figg04/G04002B7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 117. Packing Ring Properly Installed</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. BLUNT NOSED SCREWDRIVER</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. PACKING RING</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. HOSE COUPLING</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_HL0400226.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_149.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
