<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - DESCRIPTION - COMPONENTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="3">
        <title>COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electro-Hydraulic Control Unit</title>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403901">Electro-Hydraulic Control Unit (EHCU)</hotlnk>
                performs all electronic and hydraulic functions of the ABS. The Electronic Control Unit (ECU) and the
                Hydraulic Control Unit (HCU) are joined together to form the EHCU. The EHCU is shock mounted to the left
                side frame rail, behind the rear cab crossmember. It regulates hydraulic pressure in the brake system
                during an antilock stop.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Electronic Control Unit</title>
            <para>The Electronic Control Unit (ECU) is the upper module of the EHCU. It provides all of the electronic
                control for the EHCU including wheel speed and vehicle speed comparison, fault detection and valve
                activation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Control Unit</title>
            <para>The Hydraulic Control Unit (HCU) is the lower module of the EHCU. The HCU includes two hydraulic
                inputs and four outputs. It houses eight solenoid valves, four low pressure sumps, two pump elements and
                one motor. The HCU responds to instructions from the ECU, controlling the braking at each of the four
                locations independently.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403901" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403901" filename="../figg04/g0403901.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Electro-Hydraulic Control Unit</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wheel Speed Sensors</title>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403902">wheel speed sensors</hotlnk>
                are a magnetic coil/pickup type sensor. Each wheel speed sensor produces an AC voltage signal which is
                transmitted to the ECU to indicate how fast the wheel is turning. The speed of the wheel is directly
                proportional to the frequency of the wheel speed signal. Misadjusted or damaged wheel speed sensor(s)
                and damaged sensor wiring can cause inaccurate wheel speed signals.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403902" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403902" filename="../figg04/g0403902.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Rear Wheel Speed Sensor</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WHEEL SPEED SENSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disc Brake Rotor Teeth</title>
            <para>The wheel speed sensors work with teeth on the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0403903">disc brake rotor</hotlnk>
                to produce an AC voltage signal which is used to determine wheel speed. The AC voltage is produced as
                the teeth pass through the magnetic field of the wheel speed sensor. Broken, missing, or severely
                corroded teeth can cause an inaccurate wheel speed signal.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0403903" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0403903" filename="../figg04/g0403903.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Brake Rotor With Tone Teeth</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Indicator Lamp Relay</title>
            <para>The ABS lamp relay insures the ABS warning light will come on if there is an open in any circuit
                feeding the ABS system or if there is a problem with the ABS.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>ABS Indicator Lamp</title>
            <para>The system uses an amber ABS warning light in the instrument cluster to show system operation and
                malfunctions. A bulb check occurs each time the ignition switch is turned to the RUN position. The brake
                warning light and antilock brake light lamps should turn on for about three seconds then turn off. The
                ABS indicator also indicates system malfunctions. When the ECU detects a malfunction in the system, it
                turns ABS off and the ABS warning light lamp on.
            </para>
            <para>The lamp may remain on or turn off after the fault is repaired or corrected, depending on the
                malfunction. To determine the specific cause of the malfunction, refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s040393_X0403900.xml" xrefid="x0403900">preliminary system check
                    <xref refid="x0403900"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>Retrieval of the malfunction codes is explained in the diagnostic section of this manual.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Exhaust Brake and Transmission Disabling Circuit</title>
            <para>Where applicable, the exhaust brake retarder, transmission retarder and transmission convertor lock-up
                are disabled when wheel slip occurs. This prevents these features from affecting rear wheel slippage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
