<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR DRYER - CYCLO-GARD
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="4">
        <title>CYCLO-GARD</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The Cyclo-Gard air dryer is a heat transfer type air dryer that cools compressed air pumped from the
                compressor to ambient temperature before it enters the supply reservoir. It is also designed to prevent
                water, oil, carbon and sludge from entering the braking system air supply.
            </para>
            <para>A thermostatically controlled heater is provided to keep moisture from freezing inside the dryer or
                drain valve during cold weather operation.
            </para>
            <para>A check valve is provided in the discharge port of the dryer to permit depressurizing the dryer
                without draining the air system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>
                <title>Air Flow - Pressure Cycle (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400283">Figure 83</hotlnk>
                    )
                </title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400283" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400283" filename="../figg04/g0400283.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 83. Cyclo-Gard Air Dryer - Air Flow</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CHECK VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WIRE MESH FILTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TUBE WALL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. COOLING FINS</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. BAFFLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. EXIT TUBE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SUMP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Hot air from the compressor enters the dryer at the inlet and is diverted at a right angle around the
                sump (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400283">Figure 83</hotlnk>
                ), creating a spinning action. Centrifugal force removes oil and other contaminants.
            </para>
            <para>Air leaves the sump through the exit tube and is directed by the baffle to flow against the tube wall.
                The heat of compression is dissipated through the tube and the cooling fins, and the air temperature
                drops rapidly from as high as 500 degrees F to about 10 degrees above ambient temperature.
            </para>
            <para>Condensed moisture runs down the tube wall and settles at the bottom of the dryer.</para>
            <para>The cooled air then passes through a wire mesh filter which collects any minute droplets of moisture
                that may remain. Clean, dry air then leaves the dryer through the check valve to the supply reservoir.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Air Flow - Unload Cycle (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 84</hotlnk>
                    )
                </title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400284" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400284" filename="../figg04/g0400284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 84. Cyclo-Gard Air Dryer - Unload Cycle</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>When system air pressure builds to governed pressure, the air compressor governor will unload the
                compressor and, at the same time, the governor directs system air pressure to the air dryer unloading
                valve which causes the valve to open. When the unloading valve opens, the check valve in the dryer
                discharge port will close, and air in the dryer will escape out the unloader valve (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400284">Figure 84</hotlnk>
                ). Moisture and other contaminants will be carried out the exhaust port of the unloader valve by the
                escaping air.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>The dryer should be inspected and cleaned every 200,000 miles. Wipe out the inside and check for any
                damage to the baffle or other parts. Remove the mesh filter and soak in solvent to remove accumulated
                oil. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400204">
                    <xref refid="hl0400204"/>DISASSEMBLE - AIR DRYER
                </hotlnk>
                for the procedure to remove the filter from the air dryer.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Be sure the filter is completely dry before it is reinstalled in the dryer.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The only moving parts in the air dryer are the check valve and the unloader valve. No maintenance is
                required other than the 200,000 mile cleaning as long as the unloader valve and check valve operate
                properly when the compressor is running in the unload cycle.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>
                <title>Heater</title>
            </para>
            <para>The heater keeps the sump from freezing in cold weather operation. The heater will automatically turn
                ON when the thermostatic temperature falls below 35 degrees F and automatically turn OFF when the
                thermostatic temperature rises above 75 degrees F. To test the heater, disconnect the unit and place it
                in a cup of ice water for five minutes. Reconnect the heater. The heater should heat up and continue
                heating until the thermostat reaches 75 degrees F. At 75 degrees F, the heater should turn itself OFF. A
                heater unit that fails to perform as described above should be replaced.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Unloader Valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>With the engine running, pump the brakes until the compressor cuts in (starts pumping). Verify that
                the unloader valve discharge port does not leak any air while the compressor is cut in (pumping).
            </para>
            <para>When the compressor cuts out (stops pumping), listen for a 2 second high pressure discharge at the
                unloader valve discharge port. This is normal. The unloader valve will remain in the open position until
                the compressor cuts in again.
            </para>
            <para>If the unloader valve leaks air while the compressor is cut in, or does not open (discharge air) when
                the compressor cuts out, then the valve is not working properly. A non-functioning valve should be
                cleaned, rebuilt or replaced.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Unloader Valve Test (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 85</hotlnk>
                    )
                </title>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400285" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400285" filename="../figg04/g0400285.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 85. Cyclo-Gard Air Dryer - Unloader Valve Test</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SNAP RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WASHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. LOCK NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. PLUNGER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. QUAD RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BODY OPEN SIDE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Turn the engine off and perform the following test. It is not necessary to remove the unloader valve
                for this test.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from the air system.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not attempt to remove any component from the air dryer or disassemble any component on
                            the air dryer while the air system is under pressure. High pressure air can cause personal
                            injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the sensing line from the air compressor to the unloader valve and drain any
                    water in the line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the unloader valve lock nut and unscrew the cap from the body and dry out any
                    water in the cap. Remove the piston. Clean and relube the piston with low temperature grease (DOW 55
                    or equivalent) before reinstalling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the washer (Item 5,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 85</hotlnk>
                    ) into the plunger body with your thumb. It should depress with very little effort. Travel should be
                    approximately 1/4 inch and the washer should return flush with the end of the body when released. If
                    the plunger does not function as described above, remove the valve and disassemble the plunger.
                    Determine the reason for the failure and repair the assembly. Unloader valve repair kits are
                    available from your Parts Department.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the plunger travel is normal, reassemble the valve with the
                    <emph type="bold">open side of the piston</emph>
                    toward the plunger washer (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 85</hotlnk>
                    ). Tighten cap fully onto the body. Tighten lock nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Air Dryer</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to remove the air dryer or any component from the air dryer while the air
                        system is under pressure. High pressure air can cause personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels of the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from the air system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the compressor discharge and sensor lines at the dryer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the discharge line at the check valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug the heater electrical connector from the heater on the dryer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the dryer mounting bolts and remove the dryer from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Unloader Valve</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to remove the air dryer or any component from the air dryer while the air
                        system is under pressure. High pressure air can cause personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels of the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from the air system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the sensor line from the compressor at the unloader valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unthread the unloader valve from the nipple in the side of the dryer base (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400286">Figure 86</hotlnk>
                    ).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0400286" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0400286" filename="../figg04/g0400286.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="502px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 86. Air Dryer Exploded View</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Check Valve</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to remove the air dryer or any component from the air dryer while the air
                        system is under pressure. High pressure air can cause personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels of the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain all air from the air system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the air dryer discharge line from the check valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unthread the check valve from the dryer.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Heater</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unplug the heater electrical connector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unthread the heater from the base of the dryer.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassemble (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400286">Figure 86</hotlnk>
                ) - Air Dryer
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bolt that secures the bottom of the dryer mounting bracket to the dryer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two bolts that secure the mounting bracket to the top head (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400286">Figure 86</hotlnk>
                    ). Mark the two bolts that secure the dryer mounting bracket to the top head to insure they are
                    reinstalled in the same location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the remaining six bolts that secure the top head to the body assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0400286">Figure 86</hotlnk>
                    ). Care should be taken while removing these bolts. The components held inside the dryer by these
                    bolts are under spring tension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully lift the top head off the dryer and remove the upper filter spring, upper
                    strainer plate, filter material, lower strainer plate, lower filter spring, baffle, exit tube and
                    gasket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the support ring from inside the dryer cavity.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unthread the unloader valve, heater and emergency plug assembly from the base of the
                    dryer.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400204">
            <title>Disassemble - Unloader Valve</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 85</hotlnk>
                for all item numbers in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the lock nut (Item 7) and unscrew the cap (Item 1) from the valve body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the piston (Item 2) from the valve body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the O-ring (Item 3) from the piston.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the piston end of the plunger assembly, remove the snap ring (Item 4) on the outside
                    of the washer (Item 5).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lightly tap the washer end of the plunger assembly against the palm of your hand to
                    remove the washer (Item 5).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the inner snap ring (Item 4).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the spring (Item 6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the plunger (Item 8) out the opposite end of the housing from the washer end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the quad ring (Item 9) from the plunger.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean and Inspect</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe out the inside of the air dryer housing and check for damage to the baffle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the baffle is damaged, if must be replaced to insure proper cooling of the air.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Soak the mesh filter in solvent to remove accumulated oil.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The filter must be completely dry before it is reinstalled in the dryer.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe the piston, washer, plunger and inside of the unloader valve body clean. Check for
                    wear. If the piston and/or bore of the plunger body are damaged or worn, the complete valve must be
                    replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assemble - Unloader Valve</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400285">Figure 85</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">As each part is installed, lubricate with low temperature grease (DOW 55 or equal).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new quad ring (Item 9) on the plunger (Item 8).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the plunger into the plunger body (Item 10) so the quad ring end of the plunger
                    is on the pipe nipple end of the plunger body.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the washer end, install a new spring (Item 6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new snap ring (Item 4) on the inner groove of the plunger shaft.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new washer (Item 5).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new snap ring (Item 4) on the plunger shaft to hold the washer in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the washer (Item 5) into the plunger body with your thumb. It should depress with
                    very little effort. Travel should be approximately 1/4 inch and the washer should return flush with
                    the end of the body when released. If the plunger does not function as described above, disassemble
                    the plunger assembly, determine the reason for the failure and repair the assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring (Item 3) on the piston (Item 2).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the piston (Item 2) with the open end toward the washer (Item 5) in the plunger
                    body (Item 10).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install and tighten the cap (Item 1) fully onto the plunger body. Tighten the lock nut
                    (Item 7) to hold the cap in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assemble - Air Dryer</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400286">Figure 86</hotlnk>
                for all items referenced in the following text.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new gasket on the upper flange of the body assembly. The gasket is installed
                    by the manufacturer without a sealer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the support ring in the dryer housing cavity so that it rest completely on the
                    indentations inside the lower end of the cavity.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the exit tube so it rests completely on the support ring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the baffle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lower filter spring, lower strainer plate, filter material, upper strainer plate
                    and upper filter spring in this order.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the top head over the assembly so the upper filter spring is centered on the
                    bottom side of the top head.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the top head down (against the spring tension) so it rests against the gasket.
                    Install two top head bolts (not the bolts that secure the hanger bracket to the assembly). Tighten
                    finger tight. Install the remaining bolts and the mounting bracket. Use the bolts that were marked
                    during disassembly to hold the mounting bracket in place. Tighten all bolts to 25 to 30 ft-lbs. (34
                    to 41 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bolt that secures the bottom of the hanger bracket to the dryer. Tighten to
                    25 to 30 ft-lbs. (34 to 41 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the unloader valve, check valve, heater and emergency plug assembly.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the air dryer assembly to the vehicle. Tighten all mounting bolts to 30 to 38
                    ft-lbs. (41 to 51 N&#183; m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect and tighten the governor sensing line to the unloader valve, the compressor
                    discharge line to the air dryer and the air dryer discharge line to the check valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical connector to the heater.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Build air pressure in the system and check the air dryer and all fittings for air leaks.
                    Repair as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The discharge cycle should last for only a few seconds. A faulty check valve will allow
                    a longer discharge period and cause constant cycling, probably from 30 to 50 seconds apart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The unloader valve should open only when pressure is applied from the governor during
                    the governor unload cycle. If the valve stays open during the pumping cycle, the air system cannot
                    be brought up to operating pressure since air intended for the system will be escaping through the
                    unloader valve exhaust port. To determine the source of the condition, disconnect the air line at
                    the unloader valve cap. If the valve does not close, it should be repaired or replaced. If it does
                    close, it is functioning properly and the governor may be faulty.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is no blow down when the compressor is in the unload cycle, the unloader valve
                    should be repaired or replaced as soon as possible. Continued operation over a period of time can
                    allow the water level to build up in the sump of the unit. If the water level reaches a point higher
                    than the inlet port, the air pressure can lift the water with sufficient force to damage the baffle.
                    A damaged baffle will not allow the unit to cool the air flow and will result in high moisture
                    content in the reservoirs.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Torque Chart</title>
            <table id="t0400216" tblwidth="full-page" frame="all" numbered="no" view="reveal">
                <title>Torque Chart - Cyclo-Gard</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center" charoff="50" char="c">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.86in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="0.96in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.01in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Component</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Ft-Lbs.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Nm</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Mounting Bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>30-38</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>41-51</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Top Head Bolts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>25-30</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>34-41</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Lower Mounting Bracket Bolt</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>25-30</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>34-41</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_118.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_120.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
