<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Brakes - Brake System - General Information - General Procedures</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="6">
        <title>General Procedures</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Bleeding</title>
            <table id="t0600007">
                <title>Special Tool</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.94*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figEZT/EZTECH.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="112px"
                                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>EZ-Tech</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Master Cylinder Priming - In-Vehicle or Bench</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Brake fluid contains polyglycol ethers and polyglycols. Avoid contact with eyes. Wash hands
                        thoroughly after handling. If brake fluid contacts eyes, flush eyes with running water for 15
                        minutes. Get medical attention if irritation persists. If taken internally, drink water and
                        induce vomiting. Get medical attention immediately.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not allow the brake master cylinder reservoir to run dry during the bleeding operation.
                        Keep the brake master cylinder reservoir filled with the specified brake fluid. Never reuse the
                        brake fluid that has been drained from the hydraulic system.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Brake fluid is harmful to painted and plastic surfaces. If brake fluid is spilled onto a
                        painted or plastic surface, immediately wash it with water.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When any part of the hydraulic system has been disconnected for repair or replacement, air can
                        enter the system and cause spongy brake pedal action. This requires bleeding of the hydraulic
                        system after it has been properly connected. The hydraulic system can be bled manually or with
                        pressure bleeding equipment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the brake master cylinder has been replaced or the system has been emptied, or partially
                        emptied, it should be primed to prevent air from entering the system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For in-vehicle priming, disconnect the brake lines.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For bench priming, mount the brake master cylinder in a vise.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install short brake tubes with the ends submerged in the brake master cylinder
                    reservoir, and fill the brake master cylinder reservoir with DOT 3 brake fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f060007" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0076712.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Have an assistant pump the brake pedal, or slowly depress the primary piston until clear
                    fluid flows from both brake tubes, without air bubbles.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the brake master cylinder is being primed at the bench, install it in the vehicle.
                    For additional information, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s04049_X2060657.xml" xrefid="x2060657">Hydraulic Brake Actuation</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the short brake tubes and install the brake outlet tubes.</para>
                <para>&#8226; Tighten the fittings to 25 Nm (18 lb-ft).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bleed each brake tube at the brake master cylinder as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Have an assistant pump the brake pedal and then hold firm pressure on the brake
                        pedal.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the rearmost brake tube fittings until a stream of brake fluid comes out.
                        While the assistant maintains pressure on the brake pedal, tighten the brake tube fitting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Repeat this operation until clear, bubble-free fluid comes out.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Refill the brake master cylinder reservoir as necessary. Repeat the bleeding
                        operation at the front brake tube.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Four Wheel Anti-Lock Brake System (4WABS) Hydraulic Control Unit (HCU)</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure only needs to be performed if the 4-wheel anti-lock brake (4WABS) hydraulic
                        control unit (HCU) has been replaced or if air is suspected in the HCU.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f060010" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0081697.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Clean all dirt from and remove the brake master cylinder filler cap, and fill the brake master
                        cylinder reservoir with the specified brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect a clear waste line to the RH rear bleeder screw and submerge the free end of the tube
                        in a container partially filled with clean brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the RH rear bleeder screw open, cycle the brake pedal until no more air is seen in the
                        waste line.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tighten the RH rear bleeder screw, and disconnect the waste line.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Repeat Steps 2 through 4 for the LH rear bleeder screw, the RH front disc brake caliper
                        bleeder screw and the LH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw, in that order.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connect the diagnostic tool cable adapter into the vehicle data link connector (DLC) under the
                        dash, and follow the diagnostic tool instructions.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Repeat the system bleed procedure as outlined in Steps 1 through 5.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Caliper</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is not necessary to perform a complete brake system bleed if only the disc brake caliper
                        was disconnected.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f060011" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0081697.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Place a box-end wrench on the disc brake caliper bleeder screw. Attach a rubber drain tube to
                        the disc brake caliper bleeder screw and submerge the free end of the tube in a container
                        partially filled with clean brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Have an assistant pump the brake pedal and then hold firm pressure on the brake pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loosen the disc brake caliper bleeder screw until a stream of brake fluid comes out. While the
                        assistant maintains pressure on the brake pedal, tighten the disc brake caliper bleeder screw.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Repeat until clear, bubble-free fluid comes out.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Refill the brake master cylinder reservoir as necessary.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tighten the disc brake caliper bleeder screw to 35 Nm (26 lb-ft).</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake System Bleeding</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Manual</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Brake fluid contains polyglycol ethers and polyglycols. Avoid contact with eyes. Wash hands
                        thoroughly after handling. If brake fluid contacts eyes, flush eyes with running water for 15
                        minutes. Get medical attention if irritation persists. If taken internally, drink water and
                        induce vomiting. Get medical attention immediately.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not allow the brake master cylinder reservoir to run dry during the bleeding operation.
                        Keep the brake master cylinder reservoir filled with the specified brake fluid. Never reuse the
                        brake fluid that has been drained from the hydraulic system.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Brake fluid is harmful to painted and plastic surfaces. If brake fluid is spilled onto a
                        painted or plastic surface, immediately wash it with water.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When any part of the hydraulic system has been disconnected for repair or replacement, air may
                        get into the system and cause spongy brake pedal action. This requires bleeding of the hydraulic
                        system after it has been properly connected. The hydraulic system can be bled manually or with
                        pressure-bleeding equipment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f060013" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0081697.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Clean all dirt from and remove the brake master cylinder filler cap and fill the brake master
                        cylinder reservoir with the DOT 3 motor vehicle brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Place a box-end wrench on the RH rear bleeder screw. Attach a rubber drain tube to the RH rear
                        bleeder screw and submerge the free end of the tube in a container partially filled with clean
                        brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Have an assistant pump the brake pedal and then hold firm pressure on the brake pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loosen the RH rear bleeder screw until a stream of brake fluid comes out. While the assistant
                        maintains pressure on the brake pedal, tighten the RH rear bleeder screw.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Repeat until clear, bubble-free fluid comes out.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Refill the brake master cylinder reservoir as necessary.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tighten the RH rear bleeder screw to 35 Nm (26 lb-ft).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Repeat Steps 2 through 5 for the LH rear bleeder screw.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Place a box-end wrench on the RH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw. Attach a rubber drain
                        tube to the RH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw, and submerge the free end of the tube in
                        a container partially filled with clean brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Have an assistant pump the brake pedal and then hold firm pressure on the brake pedal.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loosen the RH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw until a stream of brake fluid comes out.
                        While the assistant maintains pressure on the brake pedal, tighten the RH front disc brake
                        caliper bleeder screw.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Repeat until clear, bubble-free fluid comes out.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Refill the brake master cylinder reservoir as necessary.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Tighten the RH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw. For additional information, refer to
                        Specifications in this section.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Repeat Steps 7 through 10 for the LH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Pressure</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all dirt from and remove the brake master cylinder filler cap and fill the brake
                    master cylinder reservoir with the DOT 3 motor vehicle brake fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Master cylinder pressure bleeder adapter tools are available from various manufacturers of
                        pressure-bleeding equipment. Follow the instructions of the manufacturer when installing the
                        adapter.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bleeder adapter to the brake master cylinder reservoir, and attach the
                    bleeder tank hose to the fitting on the adapter.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Bleed the longest line first. Make sure the bleeder tank contains enough specified brake fluid
                        to complete the bleeding operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a box-end wrench on the RH rear bleeder screw. Attach a rubber drain tube to the
                    RH rear bleeder screw and submerge the free end of the tube in a container partially filled with
                    clean brake fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f060015" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figa00/A0081697.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the valve on the bleeder tank.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the RH rear bleeder screw. Leave open until clear, bubble-free brake fluid flows,
                    then tighten the RH rear bleeder screw to 35 Nm (26 lb-ft) and remove the rubber hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue bleeding the rear of the system, going in order from the LH rear bleeder screw
                    to the RH front disc brake caliper bleeder screw, ending with the LH front disc brake caliper
                    bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the bleeder tank valve. Remove the tank hose from the adapter and remove the
                    adapter.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake System Leak Check</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Brake fluid is water soluble and it is possible that all evidence of fluid leakage has been
                        washed off if the vehicle has been operated in rain or snow.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the brake master cylinder reservoir is full.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply the brakes several times and make sure the pedal feel is not spongy. If necessary,
                    bleed the system. For additional information, refer to Brake System Bleeding in this section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the reservoir level is dropping.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the reservoir level is dropping, inspect the brake components, fittings and lines to
                    locate the source of the leak.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049_X2060318.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04049.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
