<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK BRAKES/TRACTION CONTROL: BENDIX - TROUBLESHOOTING - 2000, 4000 &#38; 8000 MODELS - TROUBLESHOOTING
        - DIAGNOSTICS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSTICS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>All diagnostics begins by observing the ABS Warning Light and the Traction Active Light located on the
                instrument panel. While the controller diagnostic display locates a specific problem area, it is
                necessary to confirm whether the problem is in the component or the connecting circuits. The diagnostic
                tables, beginning with
                <hotlnk document="s04033_7.xml" xrefid="t0403301">INITIAL START-UP TEST PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                guide the technician to the specific fault.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Important</title>
            <para>Before beginning the troubleshooting process:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine if the vehicle has traction control installed. With traction control there
                    will be a Traction Active light and ON/OFF switch on the instrument panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Place the traction control ON/OFF switch in the ON position, before beginning troubleshooting.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Troubleshooting Tips</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before beginning these test procedures, make sure the vehicle batteries are at 75% state
                    of charge (SOC) or higher. This represents an open circuit voltage (OCV) of 12.4 volts. Batteries
                    with an OCV of 12 volts or less are either completely discharged or have a dead cell.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before beginning these test procedures, check any light or indicator lamp filaments that
                    are suspected of being open (burned out). This is done to avoid unnecessary extensive circuit
                    checks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before beginning these test procedures, inspect all connectors for loose or damaged
                    pins, wires, etc. Refer to section in GROUP 08 - ELECTRICAL in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the mechanic determines that a fuse is blown, while checking its condition, he is
                    directed to locate the cause of the overload condition and to repair it. While no further
                    instruction on this procedure is listed in the diagnostic tables, the common procedure is as
                    follows: isolate sections of the circuit by disconnecting connectors, and measure the resistance to
                    ground to find the circuit that is shorted to ground. Then locate the damaged spot in the wire or
                    connector and repair.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Diagnostics for circuits that are malfunctioning by sticking in the position are
                    generally not covered in detail. It is assumed that the mechanic knows to check for a malfunctioning
                    switch, relay, or solenoid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin the troubleshooting process by performing
                    <hotlnk document="s04033_7.xml" xrefid="t0403301">INITIAL START-UP TEST PROCEDURE</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The service technician should record all findings and action taken during
                    troubleshooting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No voltage or resistance tests are performed into the controller.
                    <emph type="bold"></emph>All tests in this manual will be on the vehicle harness side of controller
                    connectors (277) and (288).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04033_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04033_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
