<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - TRACTOR PROTECTION VALVE - BENDIX TP-5
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="3">
        <title>BENDIX TP-5</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>The Bendix TP-5 is a panel or crossmember mounted tractor protection valve. It has two additional
                double check valve and quick release functions. It contains a service line shut-off valve with exhaust
                function, a service line QRV (quick release valve) and two double check valves.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Operation</title>
            <para>The function of the TP-5 is to receive all pneumatic signals pertinent to the operation of the trailer
                braking system, transmit same to the trailer and also to protect the tractor air supply in case of
                separation of the connecting lines to the trailer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400247">Figure 47</hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400247" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400247" filename="../figg04/g0400247.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Tractor Protection Valve (Bendix TP-5)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FRONT SERVICE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TRACTOR PROTECTION CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TRAILER EMERGENCY SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. EXHAUST</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TRAILER CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. TRAILER SERVICE SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. STOP LIGHT SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. REAR SERVICE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>Tractor Protection Portion</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400248">Figure 48</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400248" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400248" filename="../figg04/g0400248.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Tractor Protection Portion</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FROM REAR SERVICE (PRIMARY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TO STOP LIGHT SWITCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FROM TRAILER CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. TO TRAILER SERVICE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SERVICE LINE QUICK RELEASE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. VENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. TO TRAILER EMERGENCY SUPPLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. FROM TRACTOR PROTECTION CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SERVICE LINE SHUT-OFF VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. FROM FRONT SERVICE (SECONDARY)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Air from the tractor protection control valve in the cab enters at the tractor protection delivery
                port (Item 8) and passes out the trailer supply port (Item 7) and simultaneously acts upon the service
                line shut off plunger (Item 9) moving the service line inlet valve off its seat and opening the service
                line passage. With common air to the supply side and service side of the manifold, the valve should open
                at approximately 45 psi. If the Tractor Protection Control Valve is manually or automatically moved to
                the exhaust position, the service line shut-off valve will close at approximately 10 psi and the exhaust
                passage in the plunger will vent the trailer service line (Item 5).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Double Check Valves</title>
            </para>
            <para>The two double check valves in the TP-5 serve to pick up the highest pressure service signal from
                either the tractor front brake circuit (secondary) (Item 10), rear brake circuit (primary) (Item 1) or
                trailer control valve signal (Item 3), operating the trailer brakes accordingly. The stop light switch
                port also picks up this signal and actuates the stop light switch (Item 2).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Service Line Quick Release Valve</title>
            </para>
            <para>The trailer service line port is in the cover as illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400249">Figure 49</hotlnk>
                This cover also houses a quick release valve. The diaphragm seals off the exhaust port on application
                and upon release of service line application, permits the trailer service line air to exhaust through
                the exhaust port, thus permitting faster release times for trailer brake release.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400249" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400249" filename="../figg04/g0400249.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. Tractor Protection Valve - Service Checks</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. QRV DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INLET VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. O-RING (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. O-RING (LARGE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. O-RING (SMALL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. O-RING (3)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. EXHAUST CHECK VALVE DIAPHRAGM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. DOUBLE CHECK SHUTTLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. CAP NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. CAP NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. CAP NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. CAP NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. DOUBLE CHECK GUIDES</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. SNAP RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. PAN HD SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. CONTROL PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>20. SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Maintenance</title>
            <para>Every 3600 operating hours or after 100,000 miles (160,000 km) or yearly, disassemble, clean and
                inspect all parts. Install new parts if they show signs of wear or deterioration. A maintenance kit is
                available to service the valve.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl0400210">
            <title>Service Checks</title>
            <para>
                <title>Operating and Leakage Checks</title>
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400249">Figure 49</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the wheels, charge air brake system to governor cut-out, and pull out the tractor
                    protection control valve knob (emergency position).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the trailer service line hose coupling. Make a trailer hand control valve
                    application. Hold a finger over the 1/16 inch vent hole in the service line shut-off valve area of
                    the TP-5 casting. Check for leakage at hose coupling and at exhaust port at the TP-5. Leakage of a
                    one inch (25 mm) soap bubble every 3 seconds at either port indicates a faulty inlet valve (Item 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With hand control valve still applied, turn on ignition and check for stop light
                    function.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">.Release hand control valve application and place tractor protection valve in normal
                    position.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Only test gauges known to be accurate are to be used for checking brake valve delivery
                            pressures, gover- nor pressure settings and other tests.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the tractor service hose coupling to a test gauge, re-apply the hand control
                    valve and note that there is pressure at the service hose coupling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for leakage at the service line QRV. Leakage of a one inch (25 mm) soap bubble
                    every 3 seconds indicates a defective diaphragm (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With service line pressure still applied through the hand control valve, check for
                    leakage at the brake valve exhaust. Leakage of a one inch (25 mm) soap bubble every 3 seconds
                    indicates a defective double check valve shuttle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for leakage at 1/16 inch vent hole. Leakage indicates either O-ring (Item 6) or
                    O-ring (Item 5) is defective. [O-ring (Item 5) referred to is on the control piston (Item 19); the
                    same O-ring is also used on a cap nut (Item 10).]
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the hand control valve application and re-check for leakage at the vent hole. If
                    the leakage continues, it is the large O-ring (Item 5) which is leaking. If the leakage stops, it
                    was the smaller O-ring (Item 6) which was leaking.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make and hold a foot brake application. Check for leakage at exhaust of hand control
                    valve. Leakage of a one inch (25 mm) soap bubble every 3 seconds indicates a faulty double check
                    valve shuttle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release foot brake application, disconnect line from primary service brake circuit at
                    TP-5 delivery port (PCD) and block off the end of the line from the brake valve. Make a foot brake
                    application and observe for leakage at the PCD delivery port.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the primary circuit line and reverse the procedure with the secondary circuit
                    line (SCD). Leakage of a one inch (25 mm) soap bubble every 3 seconds in either (11) or (12)
                    indicates a faulty double check valve shuttle. Restore the secondary circuit connection to the TP-5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If the valve does not function as described above or leakage is a one inch (25 mm) soap bubble every 3
                seconds, the valve should be repaired or replaced.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disassembly</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400249">Figure 49</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the wheels and drain the air brake systems.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all air lines and stop light switch from the manifold and remove the unit from
                    the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four cap nuts (Items 10, 11, 12 and 13) from the body. Identify the cap nuts
                    to their respective ports before removing. Remove the O-rings (3 of Item 7 and 1 of Item 5).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the double check guides (Item 14) and double check shuttles (Item 9).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reach into the port marked BLK-SLS with a set of snap ring pliers and remove the snap
                    ring (Item 15), spring (Item 16), and valve (Item 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two screws which hold the cover (Item 18) to the body. Remove the two small
                    O-rings (Item 4) and one large O-ring (Item 3). Remove the quick release valve diaphragm (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 6-32 pan head screw (Item 17) and remove the exhaust check valve diaphragm
                    (Item 8).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all parts, bores, and passages with a solvent equivalent to mineral spirits.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Assembly</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before assembly, lubricate all O-rings, bores, pistons, etc. with lubricant.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400249">Figure 49</hotlnk>
                for items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall inlet valve (Item 2), spring (Item 16) and snap ring (Item 15) in body.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install shuttle guides (Item 14) and shuttles (Item 9) and their respective cap nuts
                    (Item 10 and 11).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the O-rings (Item 5 and 6) on the service line shut off plunger, and install
                    spring (Item 20), plunger and corresponding cap nut (Item 12) with O-ring (Item 7).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the quick release valve diaphragm in the body and the O-rings (Items 3 and 4)
                    on the cover and install the cover in its cavity in the body using the two screws to secure it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the exhaust seal diaphragm (Item 8) in the cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall unit into vehicle. Install all air lines and stop light switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Testing</title>
            </para>
            <para>Test the reassembled valve as described under
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl0400210">
                    <xref refid="hl0400210"/>SERVICE CHECKS
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_99.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_101.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
