<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - BENDIX E6-TREADLE AND E7-SUSPENDED PEDAL TYPE (FOOT) BRAKE VALVES - INSTALL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Treadle Type Valve</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start all air lines into the (foot) brake valve. Be sure the lines are in the same
                    fitting location from which the line was removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position (foot) brake valve onto mounting plate, and secure with screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all air lines that are attached to the brake (foot) valve.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before putting vehicle back into service, check all air connections that were removed
                    for leaks. Use a soap solution on connections and check for leaks (bubbles). No leaks on air line
                    connections are acceptable.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Suspended Type Valve</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position valve into mounting plate. Install mounting bolts, but do not tighten.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start all air lines. Be sure that the lines are on the same connections from which the
                    lines were removed. After all lines have been started, tighten all lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten foot valve mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install coolant reservoir or air filter if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill coolant reservoir if applicable.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before putting vehicle back into service, check all air connections that were removed
                    for leaks. Use a soap solution on connections and check for leaks (bubbles). No leaks on air line
                    connections are acceptable.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_53.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_55.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
