<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - REMOVE AND INSTALL - parking brake travel switch (MOUNTED on sahr
        canister)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04048615" graphiccount="0">
        <title>parking brake travel switch (MOUNTED on sahr canister)</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The parking brake travel switch (located on the SAHR canister) can be removed without opening the
                brake fluid system. The switch can be replaced without depressurizing the brake system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048614.xml" xrefid="f0404865">FIGURE 71</hotlnk>
                for component location information while performing the following procedures .
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Removal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks and turn key off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully clean the outside of the SAHR canister in the area of the parking brake travel
                    switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connection to the parking brake travel switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 2 screws securing the switch to the SAHR canister, and remove the switch with
                    its short pigtail harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cover the hole where the travel switch was located to prevent contamination.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the replacement switch so that the mounting screw holes are aligned.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the switch with the 2 mounting screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical connection to the parking brake travel switch.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING to make the necessary repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn key on; then apply and release the parking brake several times to verify correct
                    operation. Also verify that the SERVICE PARK BRAKE warning indicator does not light, and no new
                    fault codes are generated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the key off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048614.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048616.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
