<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK MODULATOR ASSEMBLY: BENDIX M-21 AND M-22 - OPERATION - ANTILOCK HOLD</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ANTILOCK HOLD</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0403008">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0403008" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0403008" filename="../figg04/G0403008.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Antilock Hold</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The antilock controller will place the modulator in the Hold position when it senses that the correct
            wheel speed (braking force) has been attained. The antilock controller will also place the modulator in the
            Hold position, prior to entering the Re-Apply, when it detects recovery from a locked wheel condition. In
            this mode of operation, the modulator supply solenoid remains energized while the exhaust solenoid is
            de-energized. De-energizing the exhaust solenoid opens its inlet and closes its exhaust. Opening the exhaust
            solenoid inlet allows application air to flow to the control side of the exhaust diaphragm, which then seals
            the exhaust passage. With the exhaust diaphragm seated, further exhaust of brake chamber air pressure is
            prevented. Because the supply solenoid remains energized, the supply diaphragm remains seated, thus
            preventing application air from flowing to the delivery port and out to the brake chamber. The modulator can
            enter the Antilock Exhaust or Re-Apply mode from the Antilock Hold mode.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
