<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - automatic traction control (ATC) system
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>automatic traction control (ATC) system</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>While servicing an ATC equipped vehicle, the ATC system
                    <emph type="underscr">MUST BE DISABLED</emph>
                    before operating the vehicle with only one drive wheel lifted off of the ground. Performing this
                    operation on a vehicle with an active ATC system may result in the vehicle moving and falling from
                    the jacks as power will be transferred to the wheel that is still on the ground.
                </para>
                <para>The ATC system cannot be disabled by placing the dash mounted switch in the "Disabled" position.
                </para>
                <para>The ATC system can be TEMPORARILY disabled using the EZ-Tech service tool, running the TOOLBOX
                    diagnostic program. Use extreme caution. When the ATC system is disabled using the EZ-Tech, it will
                    remain disabled only until the next ignition cycle. The TOOLBOX screen will indicate when the ATC
                    function is disabled.
                </para>
                <para>Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.</para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>The ATC system uses the components of the ABS system, with two additional ATC solenoid valves, to prevent
            the driven wheels from spinning while accelerating on slippery surfaces. The ECU monitors the wheel speed to
            determine wheel spin (wheel is losing traction). The ECU then signals the solenoid valves in the Hydraulic
            Compact Unit (HCU) to deliver the brake fluid pressure to that wheel end. Braking pressure is applied to the
            wheel to prevent it from slipping and to transfer the driving force to the drive wheel with better traction.
        </para>
        <para>When an ATC event affecting
            <emph type="bold">BOTH</emph>
            drive wheels occurs at speeds below 31 mph, the ATC system will also send a message to the engine controller
            to limit engine torque. At speeds above 31 mph all ATC events are controlled with engine torque only. No
            differential braking is applied above 31 mph.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Several different traction control Mud and Snow switches have been used in these vehicles. While
                    the switches may vary in appearance they function identically. Regardless of appearance, the switch
                    selects the Mud and Snow mode when the switch indicator is lit. When the switch indicator is unlit,
                    the vehicle is in the Normal ATC mode. The ATC system cannot be
                    <emph type="bold">DISABLED</emph>
                    using the dash mounted switch.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The dash mounted traction control Mud and Snow switch is used to select the Mud and Snow mode when the
            driving conditions require it. The following paragraphs describe the difference between the Mud and Snow
            mode and normal ATC operation.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Normal Traction Control (Normal Driving Conditions)</emph>
                </para>
                <para>When the traction control switch (and vehicle) are in the normal traction control mode, the
                    indicator on the switch and the TRAC CTRL indicator in the gauge cluster will both be unlit. (NOTE:
                    the TRAC CTRL indicator will be on solid during an ATC event, or if an active ATC fault is
                    detected.) In this mode differential braking is used to control traction when one drive wheel loses
                    traction and vehicle speed is 31 mph or less. Engine torque limiting is used to control traction
                    when both drive wheels lose traction. This is the normal operating mode and should be used for most
                    driving conditions.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Mud and Snow Mode (Off-Road Driving Conditions)</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The driver should use the traction control switch to select the Mud and Snow mode when driving in
                    deep snow or off-road conditions. This signals the ECU to allow more wheel spin than normal. When in
                    the Mud and Snow position, the indicator on the switch will be lit, and the TRAC CTRL indicator in
                    the gauge cluster will be flashing. (NOTE: the TRAC CTRL indicator will be on solid during an ATC
                    event, or if an active ATC fault is detected.) The switch should be returned to the Normal Traction
                    Control position when the vehicle is no longer operating in deep snow or mud.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>The traction control indicator (TRAC CTRL) located in the electronic gauge cluster is used to indicate the
            following three conditions.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The TRAC CTRL lamp will be flashing whenever the Mud and Snow mode is selected using the traction
                    control switch (switch indicator lit).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The TRAC CTRL indicator will be continuously lit whenever a traction control related fault has
                    been detected.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If no ATC related faults have been detected, the TRAC CTRL indicator will be continuously lit only
                    during an ATC event.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>In the event of an ATC system malfunction, diagnostic codes identifying the source of the ATC malfunction
            will be stored in the ECU memory. Retrieval of the diagnostic codes is explained in Section 5,
            <hotlnk document="s04048_HL04048500.xml" xrefid="hl04048500">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
            . The ATC system is normally disabled when most ATC or ABS malfunctions are detected.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
