<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-30 ABS / ATC CONTROLLER - INSTALLING A NEW EC-30 CONTROLLER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INSTALLING A NEW EC-30 CONTROLLER</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When replacing the EC-30, verify that the unit you are installing has the correct default
                    settings. Failure to do so could result in a loss of features, such as ATC and PLC, or noncompliance
                    with U.S. regulations such as FMVSS 121. It is recommended to use only the correct replacement part
                    number. However, most configuration settings can be altered using the Bendix ACom for Windows
                    program.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Verify correct operation of the EC-30 system and warning lamps prior to putting the vehicle back into
            service. Towing vehicles manufactured after March 1, 2001 must support the trailer ABS warning lamp located
            on the dash.
        </para>
        <para>For further information, contact either the vehicle manufacturer, Bendix or your local authorized Bendix
            dealer.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position and secure the EC-30 in the original mounting orientation using the four hex head
                bolts.
                <emph type="bold">Torque the hex head EC-30 mounting bolts to 98 in. lbs. Over- tightening the ECU bolts
                    can cause damage to the EC-30.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For a valve-mounted EC-30, position and secure the EC-30 assembly to the vehicle, in the
                original mounting orientation. Reconnect all air lines to the EC-30 assembly. All air lines and fittings
                should be checked for leaks prior to returning the vehicle to service.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Reconnect the electrical connectors to the EC-30 and
                <emph type="bold">torque the connector retaining jack-screws to 15- 20 in. lbs. Over-tightening the ECU
                    connector jack-screw(s) can cause damage to the EC-30.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply power and monitor the EC-30 power-up sequence to verify proper system operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When necessary, it is possible to road test the ABS function by making an abrupt stop from a
                vehicle speed of about 20 mph to check for proper function. The wheels should not enter a prolonged lock
                condition and ABS function should be audible. It is the responsibility of the technician to perform the
                tests in a safe location.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When necessary, it is possible to road test the ATC function by accelerating on a road
                surface with reduced traction. The drive wheels should not sustain substantial spin. Audible bursts of
                air or engine throttle-down should be noticed. It is the responsibility of the technician to perform the
                tests in a safe location.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f0404313" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg04/G0404313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 13. EC-30 System Schematic</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04043.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
