<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-17 ANTILOCK TRACTION CONTROLLER - OPERATION - TRACTION CONTROL - TRACTION CONTROL AT VEHICLE SPEEDS OF 0
        TO 25 MPH
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TRACTION CONTROL AT VEHICLE SPEEDS OF 0 TO 25 MPH</title>
        <para>When wheel spin is detected and the vehicle is stopped, or moving at any speed up to 25 mph, the EC-17
            controller simultaneously executes the following operations:
        </para>
        <para>It instantly blinks the traction dash lamp to advise the driver that a wheel spin is occurring.</para>
        <para>If the Torque Limiting feature is active, the EC-17 uses its link to the engine control module and sends a
            signal to reduce engine torque to a level suitable for the available traction.
        </para>
        <para>If the Differential Braking feature is configured into the system, the EC-17 energizes the solenoid in the
            ATR valve which then applies air to each of the rear axle modulators. Because the modulators are controlled
            by the EC-17, the solenoid valves in the appropriate modulator are opened and closed to gently pump the
            brake on the spinning wheel only. This gentle brake application forces the differential to drive the
            stationary or slowly spinning wheel.
        </para>
        <para>Once wheel spin is eliminated, the dash lamp goes out and the traction system disengages control.</para>
        <para>In the event that extended periods of traction operation are experienced, without vehicle motion being
            detected, the ABS traction system will disable traction control to prevent brake fade. The system will
            re-enable traction control after a short period of time.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
