<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>EC-16 CONTROLLER - PREVENTIVE MAINTENANCE - EVERY 3 MONTHS, 25,000 MILES OR 900 OPERATING HOURS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EVERY 3 MONTHS, 25,000 MILES OR 900 OPERATING HOURS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check all wiring and connectors to ensure they are secure and free from visible damage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Although the EC-16 controller incorporates self-check diagnostics, the LED display should be
                inspected to ensure that it is functional. With the vehicle ignition on, a magnet (800 gauss; capable of
                picking up 3 ounces) held to the LED reset switch should cause all of the LEDs to illuminate. If one or
                more of the LEDs DO NOT ILLUMINATE and the dash condition lamps indicate the system is functioning
                properly, the non-illuminated LED(s) should be noted for future reference. Although the diagnostic
                capabilities will be limited, the system will continue to function as designed.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Road test the vehicle by making an antilock stop from a vehicle speed of 20 miles per hour.
                When an antilock stop is made, the modulator solenoids pulsate and an audible burst of air can be heard
                from outside of the cab. The wheels should not enter a prolonged "lock" condition. Also, make a traction
                acceleration by accelerating on a road surface with reduced traction. As with antilock, audible bursts
                of air can be heard when the traction system is functioning.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
