<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE - ADJUST - AUTOMATIC ADJUSTERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>AUTOMATIC ADJUSTERS</title>
        <para>New System or Complete Reline and Drum Reconditioning:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Cage spring brake units manually or by air pressure. Check, clean, and apply penetrating
                lubricant to the adjusting bolt if accessible.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to release (cage) the spring brake when the spring brake shows structural
                        damage. Caging the spring may result in the forceful release of the spring chamber and its
                        contents which could cause death, severe personal injury and/or property damage. Remove complete
                        spring brake chamber and replace with new unit.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Manually adjust brakes for heavy drag. (Make periodic static brake applications to position
                floating shoes.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Back off adjusters to .020-.040 inch (0.508-1.016 mm) clearance. Measure at the crown
                (center) of the shoe, using a long feeler gauge to permit checking the entire lining width. A light drum
                drag should be evident. If not, check for misaligned or bent shoes, improper lining grind, drum runout,
                etc.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not rely on automatic adjusters to take up excessive initial clearance. Also, adjusters may
                        not function if adjusting bolts are tight against the plunger. Dual-actuated brakes will not
                        adjust on stationary vehicle.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
