<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DIAMONDLIFE&#8482; (BOSCH PIN SLIDE) DISC BRAKES For Vehicles Built Before June 3, 2002 - ADJUSTMENTS -
        BLEEDING INSTRUCTIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x0404017" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BLEEDING INSTRUCTIONS</title>
        <para>The bleeder screw
            <hotlnk document="s040402_X0404015.xml" xrefid="f0404085">(Item 4, Figure 85)</hotlnk>
            <xref refid="f0404085"/>
            is located in the upper (top) brake fluid port of caliper. It is not necessary to remove the wheel (tire and
            rim) to bleed the brakes.
        </para>
        <para>A brake fluid distribution passage between the two pistons is cast into the caliper, allowing brake fluid
            to pass from piston bore to piston bore. This requires only one bleeder screw. Tighten to 7.5 to 15 ft-lbs.
            (10 to 20 N&#8226;m).
        </para>
        <para>Check the master cylinder reservoir and fill if necessary. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in the Master
            Service Manual for proper brake fluid.
        </para>
        <para>Bleed brakes in the following order: Right Rear, Left Rear, Right Front and Left Front.</para>
        <para>For brake bleeding procedure, refer to GROUP 04 - BRAKES in the Master Service Manual.</para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>All International vehicles equipped with hydraulic disc brakes are equipped with a Hydro-Max Brake
                    Booster System. This system has two sections and each section is separate from the other. Each
                    section uses different types of fluid. The two fluids are NOT compatible and if mixed, severe damage
                    will occur to the contaminated component.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>The Hydro-Max Booster is operated by the power steering system and uses power steering fluid only.</para>
        <para>The Braking System (Master Cylinder) uses hydraulic brake fluid only.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Contaminated brake fluid is a maintenance error and is not covered by warranty.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402_41.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402_43.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040402.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
