<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - SPRING BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (MIDLAND ROSS) - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>The spring brake control valve serves to apply and release the spring actuated parking brakes. The valve
            is in the "in" position under normal operation on either a straight truck or bus. Air supply passes through
            the valve, delivering system pressure to retract and hold parking brakes in the released position. Manual
            pull "out" closes off air supply and vents delivered air to the atmosphere, applying the parking brakes.
        </para>
        <para>When valve is pushed IN, it will remain in as long as the air supply is above 7 to 17 psi on straight
            trucks and buses built before April 3, 1992, and above 25 to 35 psi on straight trucks and buses built after
            April 3, 1992. During normal operation, the air valve will automatically apply, moving OUT if air pressure
            should drop below 7 to 17 psi on straight trucks and buses built before April 3, 1992, and 25 to 35 psi on
            straight trucks and buses built after April 3, 1992.
        </para>
        <para>Pushing the piston in moves the valve assembly off the body seat until contacting end cap seat. Air
            pressure at the inlet has free passage to the outlet and is blocked from exhausting to atmosphere.
        </para>
        <para>Pulling the piston out moves the valve assembly away from end cap seat and contacts body seat. Air
            pressure at inlet is blocked from entering either outlet or exhaust passages. Air pressure in outlet has
            free passage to exhaust to atmosphere.
        </para>
        <para>The spring in the valve assists to move piston out automatically if inlet pressure drops and effective
            opposing force across the valve seat is overcome.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_72.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_74.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
