<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - PRESSURE LIMITING VALVE - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <para>The pressure setting of the pressure limiting valve is determined by the setting of the adjusting cap,
            which exerts a force on the spring on top of the piston. Compressed air enters the supply port and passes
            out the delivery port. When the air pressure on the bottom of the piston overcomes the force of the spring
            on top of the piston, the piston moves upward and the inlet valve spring forces the inlet valve on its seat,
            closing off the supply of air. As the pressure in the delivery line drops, the force of the spring above the
            piston becomes greater than the air pressure below the piston, allowing the piston to move downward, moving
            the inlet valve off its seat and allowing air to pass out the delivery port (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0400217">Figure 17</hotlnk>
            ).
        </para>
        <figure id="f0400217" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g0400217" filename="../figg04/G0400217.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="192px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
            <caption>Figure 17. Pressure Limiting Valve - Cross Section</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PISTON</callout1>
                <callout1>2. VALVE GUIDE WIRE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. INLET VALVE SPRING</callout1>
                <callout1>4. INLET AND EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>5. PISTON O-RING</callout1>
                <callout1>6. EXHAUST VENT</callout1>
                <callout1>7. PRESSURE REGULATING SPRING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>If pressure in the delivery line exceeds the pressure setting of the pressure limiting valve, the force
            exerted by the air pressure below the piston will be greater than the spring force above the piston. The
            piston will move up from the exhaust valve, permitting air to pass by the exhaust valve, through the hollow
            piston and valve guide and escape through the slot in the adjusting cap. When the force of the spring above
            the piston overcomes that of the air pressure below the piston, the exhaust valve is seated, and the
            pressure in the delivery line is the same as the setting of the pressure limiting valve.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_42.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_44.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
