<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Lucas Varity/TRW Hydraulic Antilock Brake System - DESCRIPTION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The Lucas Varity Automotive (formerly Kelsey-Hayes Brake Systems) EBC 410M hydraulic antilock brake
                system (ABS) is designed to provide the optimum balance between stopping distance and vehicle stability
                during hard brake maneuvers or when stopping on wet or slippery surfaces.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SYSTEM</title>
            <para>The system accomplishes this task by monitoring wheel rotation in order to identify wheel lockup. The
                wheel information is generated by wheel speed sensors, which are mounted at each wheel. The ABS
                electronic control unit (ECU) monitors the wheel speed output to identify conditions of wheel lock. When
                the ECU identifies a wheel which is about to lock, hydraulic pressure is momentarily reduced, allowing
                the wheel to "recover".
            </para>
            <para>The ABS is equipped with a warning lamp located in the vehicle instrument cluster. Each time the
                ignition is turned on the ABS performs a self check. The ABS warning lamp will illuminate and if the ABS
                passes the self check, the lamp will turn off a few seconds after the ignition is turned on. In the rare
                event of an ABS malfunction, the warning lamp will illuminate and codes identifying the source of the
                ABS malfunction will be electronically stored in the ECU. Retrieval of the malfunction codes is
                explained in the
                <hotlnk document="s040393_S0403901.xml" xrefid="s0403901">diagnostic section</hotlnk>
                of this manual.
            </para>
            <para>A fault has been detected if the warning lamp does not come on with ignition, fails to go off, or
                comes on at any other time.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an ABS fault develops, the ABS warning lamp will illuminate, the ABS will be disabled, and
                        the vehicle brake system will simply function as a standard brake system. The standard brake
                        system is still operational, but the anti-lock system will not operate to prevent wheel lock up
                        if the driver over applies the brakes for existing conditions.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Antilock brake systems are designed to enhance overall vehicle safety when a vehicle is driven
                        within its normal safety limits. ABS cannot compensate for a vehicle which is being driven
                        beyond the physical limits of control. Drivers operating an ABS equipped vehicle should employ
                        safe driving skills and assume no additional driving risks.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s040393.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
