<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Traction Control (Mud and Snow) Switch</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>While servicing an ATC equipped vehicle, the ATC system
                    <emph type="underscr">MUST BE DISABLED</emph>
                    before operating the vehicle with only one drive wheel lifted off of the ground. Performing this
                    operation on a vehicle with an active ATC system may result in the vehicle moving and falling from
                    the jacks as power will be transferred to the wheel that is still on the ground.
                </para>
                <para>The ATC system cannot be disabled by placing the dash mounted switch in the "disabled" position.
                </para>
                <para>The ATC system can be TEMPORARILY disabled using the EZ-Tech service tool, running the TOOLBOX
                    diagnostic program. Use extreme caution. When the ATC system is disabled using the EZ-Tech, it will
                    remain disabled only until the next ignition cycle. The TOOLBOX screen will indicate when the ATC
                    function is disabled.
                </para>
                <para>Failure to follow this warning could result in property damage, personal injury or death.</para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Two different traction control Mud and Snow switches have been used in these vehicles. The
                    switches function identically but are labeled differently. On early production switches the two
                    positions are labeled as DISAB and TRAC ENAB (the DISAB position selects the Mud and Snow mode). On
                    later production switches the two positions are labeled as MUD/SNOW and TRAC CTRL to more accurately
                    indicate the mode selected.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The dash mounted traction control Mud and Snow switch (see
            <hotlnk xrefid="f0404817">FIGURE 18</hotlnk>) is used to select the Mud and Snow mode when the driving
            conditions require it. The following paragraphs describe the difference between the Mud and Snow mode and
            normal ATC operation.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Normal Traction Control (Normal Driving Conditions)</emph>
                </para>
                <para>When the traction control switch is in the TRAC CTRL position (TRAC ENAB on early production
                    switches), the ATC system operates in its normal traction control mode. The indicator on the switch
                    and the TRAC CTRL indicator in the gauge cluster will both be unlit. (NOTE: the TRAC CTRL indicator
                    will be on solid during an ATC event, or if an active ATC fault is detected.) In this mode
                    differential braking is used to control traction when one drive wheel loses traction and vehicle
                    speed is 31 mph or less. Engine torque limiting is used to control traction when both drive wheels
                    lose traction. This is the normal operating mode and should be used for most driving conditions.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Mud and Snow Mode (Off-Road Driving Conditions)</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The driver should set the traction control switch to the MUD/SNOW position (DISAB on early
                    production switches) when driving in deep snow or off-road conditions. This signals the ECU to allow
                    more wheel spin than normal. When in the Mud and Snow position, the indicator on the switch will be
                    lit, and the TRAC CTRL indicator in the gauge cluster will be flashing. (NOTE: the TRAC CTRL
                    indicator will be on solid during an ATC event, or if an active ATC fault is detected.) The switch
                    should be returned to the Normal Traction Control position when the vehicle is no longer operating
                    in deep snow or mud.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>For complete system electrical diagrams, refer to the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS manual listed
            in ISIS. For information concerning troubleshooting the electrical circuits in the full power brakes system,
            refer to the applicable ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0404817" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic id="g0404817" filename="../figg04/G0404817A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="104px"/>
            <graphic id="g0404817" filename="../figg04/G0404817.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="104px"/>
            <caption>Figure 18. Traction Control Switch</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048_22.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04048.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
