<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Spanish - Gu&#237;a para Localizaci&#243;n de Fallas del Sistema El&#233;ctrico - 3200, 4200, 4300, 4400,
        7300, 7400, 7500, 8500, 8600 - STOPMASTER WEDGE TYPE BRAKE - OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="2">
            <title>ACTUATING SYSTEM</title>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401308">Figure 8</hotlnk>
                illustrates the actuating system of a double-actuated, air operated brake group (RDA) in the released
                position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401308" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401308.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Cross Section View of Actuating System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BRAKE SHOE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PLUNGER HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. ANCHOR PLUNGER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WEDGE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PLUNGER AND SEAL RETAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. GUIDE SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. ADJUSTING PLUNGER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. ADJUSTING BOLT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The air chamber is threaded into the wedge bore of the plunger housing, and held in position with a
                collet (lock) nut. The socket in the end of the diaphragm push rod connects the air chamber to the wedge
                rod.
            </para>
            <para>The wedge retracting spring acts as the return spring for both the wedge and the diaphragm. A pair of
                rollers are held in place on the wedge head by a retaining cage and are engaged in corresponding slots
                in the inner ends of the plungers. The unslotted portions of the inner ends of the plungers are resting
                on abutments in the plunger housing. The outer ends of the plungers are engaged with and supporting the
                brake shoes.
            </para>
            <para>On a double-actuated brake, each of the two actuating systems has one anchor (solid) plunger and one
                adjustable plunger (as illustrated). On a single actuated brake, the one actuating system would have two
                adjustable plungers. All of the plungers are retained in the housings, and the roller slots are kept in
                proper alignment by means of guide screws which engage slots in the side of the plungers.
            </para>
            <para>When the brake is actuated (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401309">Figure 9</hotlnk>), the air chamber pushes the wedge head deeper in between
                the rollers. This spreads the rollers and plungers apart and pushes the brake shoes outward. Initially,
                all the plungers are lifted off the plunger abutments and momentarily suspended. As the shoes (linings)
                contact the drum, the drum drags the shoes and moves the suspended plungers with it. This causes the
                plunger at the trailing end of each shoe to seat on its abutment and thus absorb and transfer the brake
                torque to the brake support. When the brake is released, the wedge spring returns the wedge and
                diaphragm to the off position. At the same time, as the shoes are pulled away from the drum by the
                return springs, the plungers are pushed back to their abutments.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401309" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg04/G0401309.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Actuating System "Applied"</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04013.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
