<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ANTILOCK AIR BRAKE SYSTEM: BENDIX - 3000 - EC - 15 DIAGNOSTIC STEPS - INITIAL START - UP SELF TEST
        PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INITIAL START - UP SELF TEST PROCEDURE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>For a vehicle
                <emph type="bold">without any system defects</emph>, the following information describes "normal
                behavior" during the engine start-up.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The ECU will begin start - up diagnostics when the key is turned to IGN. However, when the
                        starter is engaged, the crank relay cuts power to the ECU during engine cranking. When engine
                        cranking stops, power is re - applied to the ECU and the "Initial Start - up Procedure" starts
                        over.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Normal Start - Up</title>
            <para>Test Explanation - Each M - 21 modulator contains (1)
                <emph type="italic">exhaust solenoid</emph>
                and (1)
                <emph type="italic">hold solenoid</emph>. During this test with service brakes applied, the ECU
                controller will "fire" or energize each solenoid briefly in a test cycle making a "chuff" sound as the
                air exhausts. The exhaust solenoid will be "fired" for 10 milli - seconds, then a pause for only a few
                milli-seconds and the hold solenoid will "fire" for 20 milli - seconds. The two firing in rapid sequence
                produces a single "chuff" sound. If the solenoids are wired incorrectly, or if only one is firing, the
                sound will be distinctly different. The ECU will begin at the right front, then go to the left front,
                then the right rear, and finish the cycle on the left rear. It will then repeat the cycle, making two
                complete cycles. The second cycle is a repeat of the first.
            </para>
            <para>When the vehicle engine is started (or key switch turned to IGN), the ECU first runs the described
                series of modulator tests. The controller begins at the
                <emph type="italic">right front</emph>
                M - 21 modulator and fires each of the (2) solenoids contained in the modulator, then moves to the left
                front modulator and fires each of the (2) solenoids in that modulator and moves to the right rear
                modulator, again firing both solenoids, and finally moves to the left rear and fires each of the (2)
                solenoids in that modulator. The cycle will be repeated one more time, in the same sequence.
            </para>
            <para>After the modulator test is complete, the ECU will energize the "Engine Brake Relay" five or six times
                rapidly, causing a "chattering sound" from the relay (if vehicle is equipped with engine brake), then
                the yellow instrument panel warning light will flash twice and remain on until the vehicle speed is at
                least 7 - 10 mph for several seconds, then the warning light will "go out."
            </para>
            <para>This indicates the antilock system is performing correctly. The ECU will continue to monitor system
                performance and turn on the warning light if there is a problem.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the vehicle is warm, and shut - off briefly, then restarted and quickly driven past the
                        seven to ten miles per hour point, the system may not go through the diagnosis process of
                        flashing twice, then staying on until the seven miles per hour is attained.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_28.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024_30.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04024.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
