<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>FULL POWER HYDRAULIC ABS BRAKE SYSTEM - SYSTEM MAINTENANCE - PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKES
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl04051401" graphiccount="4">
        <title>PRESSURE BLEEDING THE FULL POWER BRAKES SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>During bleeding procedures, brake fluid level must not be allowed to fall below the MIN mark
                        on the Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. The MC reservoir should be regularly checked and filled
                        to the MAX mark with new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid. Failure to keep the brake reservoir level
                        above the MIN mark could result in more air entering the system, making it impossible to
                        effectively bleed the system.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not add fluid above the MAX mark. When the system is depressurized during service, fluid
                        stored in the accumulators is returned to the MC reservoir. If the reservoir is filled above the
                        MAX mark a fluid spill could occur when these conditions exists.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Each bleeding procedure may be performed as a standalone procedure or in conjunction with
                        installation or other bleeding procedures. In this section, the bleeding procedures are provided
                        as standalone procedures including all of the necessary preparation steps. When a bleed
                        procedure is referenced from another procedure, it is not necessary to repeat preparation steps
                        that are duplicated.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Pressure bleeding is REQUIRED to properly bleed the Full Power Brake system. It requires the use of a
                clean, regulated pressure source with gauge, tubing and adapter. Pressure bleeders are available from a
                number of manufacturers and include instructions for use. Do not attempt to use a vacuum bleeder on this
                system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Required bleed equipment:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>One clean graduated glass or plastic bottle/receptacle. #</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>One rubber/plastic bleed hose (preferably transparent). #</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Suitable crow's foot adapters for torque wrench (bleeder screws and brake lines).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pressurized fill and bleed equipment. Either of the following three types may be used:</para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>Fluid over fluid. Provides brake fluid (under pressure) from an external tank to the
                                Master Cylinder (MC) reservoir. Regulated shop air may be used as the pressure source.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Air over fluid. Pressurizes the master cylinder reservoir with clean, dry, regulated
                                shop air. Air regulator/filter ZTSE4757-1, or equivalent, is required.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Air over fluid. Pressurizes the master cylinder reservoir with regulated dry
                                nitrogen.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>One MC reservoir cap adapter (International Service Tool - ZTSE4678).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A sufficient supply of new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para># (must be impervious to the effects of brake fluid).</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl04051401a">
            <title>Master Cylinder (MC) Circuit Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. The fuses are bundled in the cowl wire harness located near the master cylinder
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405125">FIGURE 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405125" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405125" filename="../figg04/g0405125.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Location of Motor Fuses</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. MOTOR FUSES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the brake fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the pressure bleeder according to the instructions provided with the
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a fluid bleeder system is used, fill the pressure bleeder with new specified brake
                            fluid from a sealed container.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If an air bleeder system is used,
                            <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the MC reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                            to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark during the bleed procedure. A
                            typical air-over-fluid bleeder setup using service tools ZTSE4757-1 and ZTSE4678 is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0405126">FIGURE 26</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service tool adapter (ZTSE4678) between the bleed equipment and the MC
                    reservoir filler neck. Ensure that the adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler
                    neck.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 2.4 bar (35 PSI) pressure on the MC reservoir with the bleeding equipment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit bleeder hose onto one relay valve bleeder screw located on the HCU. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405127">FIGURE 27</hotlnk>. (NOTE: Both MC circuits can be bled at the same time
                    by connecting two bleeder bottles.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405126" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405126" filename="../figg04/g0405126.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Typical Air-Over-Fluid Bleeder Setup</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SERVICE TOOL ADAPTER (ZTSE4678)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. AIR REGULATOR/FILTER (ZTSE4757-1)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0405127" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405127" filename="../figg04/g0405127.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 27. Bleeder Screws on HCU</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BLEEDER PORT - PRIMARY MC CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MC INPUT PORT - PRIMARY CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. MC INPUT PORT - SECONDARY CIRCUIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BLEEDER PORT - SECONDARY MC CIRCUIT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Submerge free end of bleeder hose into the bleed bottle. (Note the fluid level in the
                    bottle before starting.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the 7 mm bleeder screw until the fluid begins to flow (about 3/4 turn). After
                    draining 250 cc (8.5 oz) of fluid, check the stream for air bubbles. When no further air bubbles
                    enter the bleed bottle, close the bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bleeder hose and torque the bleeder screw to 4 to 4.5 Nm (35.4 to 39.8
                    Lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If only one MC circuit was bled, repeat the previous four steps with the second bleeder
                    screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the wheel calipers are to be bled, refer to the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl04051401b">BRAKE CALIPER CIRCUIT BLEEDING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no further bleeding procedures are to be performed, connect the battery and install
                    the two pump motor fuses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release pressure from the MC reservoir via the bleed equipment. Disconnect bleed
                    equipment from MC reservoir filler neck and install the MC reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill (or drain) the MC reservoir to the MAX mark. Use new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid
                    from a sealed container if filling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the MC reservoir cap is installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you were referred to this procedure from an installation procedure, return to the
                    original procedure now; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), refer to Section
                5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl04051401b">
            <title>Brake Caliper Circuit Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This is a brief explanation of the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function performed in the following
                        procedure. This is a software controlled function selected from within the TOOLBOX diagnostic
                        program. With the accumulators fully pressurized, the relay valves are actuated (opened). Then
                        the ABS outlet valves for the rear accumulator are opened allowing fluid from the accumulator to
                        flow out of the outlet valves to the reservoir. While the motor/pump attempts to maintain
                        accumulator pressure by pumping more fluid into the accumulator, the pressure actually decreases
                        due to the open relay valve and outlet valves. The rapid flow of fluid clears any air bubbles
                        from the HCU. After a predetermined period of time, the outlet valves are closed allowing the
                        rear accumulator to build pressure to its shutoff value, which turns off the motor/pump. The
                        front accumulator circuit performs the same operation, but is slightly delayed from the rear
                        circuit. The front accumulator will complete the cycle about 12 seconds after the rear
                        accumulator. The changes in the accumulator pressures can be observed on the TOOLBOX diagnostic
                        screen. When accumulator pressures have been re-established, a dialog box will be displayed
                        indicating that the function has been completed.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">In vehicles equipped with ATC</emph>, the relay valves are opened and
                        closed automatically by a pair of ATC valves. No user input is required during the DEPLETE
                        ACCUMULATORS function.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">In vehicles WITHOUT ATC</emph>, the relay valves must be actuated by
                        depressing the brake pedal while initiating the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function. The brake pedal
                        must remain depressed until the pressure in BOTH accumulators begins to rise (as observed on the
                        diagnostic screen); or until the 'completed' dialog box is displayed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and remove the two 30 Amp fuses that provide power to the
                    brake system motors. The fuses are bundled in the cowl wire harness located near the master cylinder
                    (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405125">FIGURE 25</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    to the diagnostic connector located under the instrument panel just left of the steering column. Set
                    the ignition key to ON, start the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and open the TOOLBOX&#8482; program.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the brake fluid level in the MC reservoir is at the MAX mark.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depressurize the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Depress the brake pedal a minimum of 30 times.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use the EZ-TECH
                        <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                        and TOOLBOX&#8482; to verify that pressure at both accumulators is at 0 psi.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the battery negative cable (including the ECM
                    ground cable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the pressure bleeder according to the instructions provided with the
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If a fluid bleeder system is used, fill the pressure bleeder with new specified brake
                            fluid from a sealed container.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If an air bleeder system is used,
                            <emph type="bold">the fluid level in the MC reservoir must be monitored</emph>
                            to ensure that the level never drops below the MIN mark during the bleed procedure. A
                            typical air-over-fluid bleeder setup using service tools ZTSE4757-1 and ZTSE4678 is shown in
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0405126">FIGURE 26</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service tool adapter (ZTSE4678) between the bleed equipment and the MC
                    reservoir filler neck. Ensure that the adapter is securely tightened onto the MC reservoir filler
                    neck.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply 2.4 bar (35 PSI) pressure on the MC reservoir with the bleeding equipment.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If all wheel ends are being bled, they should be bled in the following order: right rear, left
                        rear, right front, left front.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit bleeder hose onto the caliper bleeder screw at the first wheel end.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Submerge free end of bleeder hose into the bleed bottle. (Note the fluid level in the
                    bottle before starting.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the bleeder screw until the fluid begins to flow (about 3/4 turn). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0405128">FIGURE 28</hotlnk>. After draining 250 cc (8.5 oz) of fluid, check the
                    stream for air bubbles. When no further air bubbles enter the bleed bottle, close the bleeder screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bleeder hose and torque the bleeder screw to 12 to 16 Nm (8.6 to 11.5
                    Lbf-ft).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0405128" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0405128" filename="../figg04/g0405128.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. Typical Caliper Bleeding Setup</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 10 through 13 for the other calipers being bled.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the battery and install the two pump motor fuses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Switch ON the ignition. HCU pump motors will start up automatically and fill the
                    accumulators (running time approximately 45 seconds).*
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function from the EOL pull down
                    menu. This function helps clear air from the HCU. A dialog box will indicate when the function is
                    complete.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles equipped WITH ATC</emph>
                            - Select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;.
                            No user input is required. The changes in the accumulator pressures can be observed on the
                            TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic screen.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">Vehicles WITHOUT ATC</emph>
                            - While depressing the brake pedal, select the DEPLETE ACCUMULATOR function from the EOL
                            pull down menu within TOOLBOX&#8482;. The pedal must remain depressed until the pressure in
                            BOTH accumulators begins to rise (as observed on the diagnostic screen), then release the
                            brake pedal.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release pressure from the MC reservoir via the bleed equipment. Disconnect bleed
                    equipment from MC reservoir filler neck and install the MC reservoir cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function again by selecting DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS from the
                    EOL pull down menu.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function has completed, fill (or drain) the MC reservoir
                    to the MAX mark. Use new DOT 3 or DOT 4 brake fluid from a sealed container if filling.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the MC reservoir cap is installed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you were referred to this procedure from an installation procedure, return to the
                    original procedure now; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    and the TOOLBOX&#8482; program, clear all brake system related inactive fault codes. (Codes may have
                    been set while disconnecting and reconnecting power to the system.) If active fault codes are
                    indicated, refer to Section 5,
                    <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING
                    </hotlnk>
                    to make the necessary repairs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the ignition key to OFF and disconnect the EZ-TECH
                    <supscript>&#174;</supscript>
                    from the diagnostic connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove wheel chocks.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>* If HCU pump motors fail to deliver a sufficient amount of fluid, the ECU-Module will control the HCU
                pump motors in a self priming procedure. HCU pump motors should stop within 3 minutes, with brake
                warning light and buzzer OFF. If that is not the case (one or both pumps do not prime), performing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function in the following steps should correct the problem. After completing the
                DEPLETE ACCUMULATORS function, both accumulators should be fully charged as indicated on the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                screen. If an accumulator is still not charging correctly refer to Section 5,
                <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051500.xml" xrefid="hl04051500">DIAGNOSTICS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                to make the necessary repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051400.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051_HL04051402.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04051.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
