<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>DCM AND DDM DRUM TYPE PARKING BRAKE - BENDIX AIR AND HYDRAULIC ACTUATED PARKING BRAKE - OPERATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="7">
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The parking brake is applied by manually pulling the parking brake control knob. Air or hydraulic
                pressure will hold the brake in the parked position. It should not be used to brake the vehicle during
                normal driving.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Actuated Parking Brake</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402130">Figure 30</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402130" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402130" filename="../figg04/G0402130.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Air Actuated Parking Brake</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The air actuated parking brake is equipped with an air gauge and warning light. When air pressure in
                the parking brake air storage system has been reduced to approximately 70 psi (483 kPA), the light will
                activate.
            </para>
            <para>If air pressure is reduced to approximately 30 psi (207 kPA), the parking brake control knob will
                automatically pop out and apply the parking brake.
            </para>
            <para>It should be noted that upon loss of air pressure, partial parking brake application will occur prior
                to automatic application of the control valve.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>If air system pressure falls below 70 psi (483 kPA), the vehicle should not be moved.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air or Hydraulic Actuated Parking Brake</title>
            <para>To release the parking brake, have the engine running and your foot on the service brake pedal, then
                push in the parking brake control knob and shift out of park. If the parking brake will not release and
                the vehicle must be moved, the spring chamber must be manually released (caged) by turning the adjusting
                nut on the push rod clockwise until bottomed on the chamber (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402131">Figure 31</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402131" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402131" filename="../figg04/G0402131.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Turn Adjusting Nut</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When manually releasing the spring chamber assembly, be sure to block the wheels so that the
                        vehicle cannot move when the parking brake is released. This will prevent vehicle movement which
                        could result in possible property damage and personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Under no circumstances should the spring chamber be disassembled. Disassembly will release a
                        powerful spring that may cause severe personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hydraulic Actuated Parking Brake Circuit</title>
            <para>The following explanation is with the engine running.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parking brake control valve out- transmission in park position.</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402132">Figure 32</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses. Hydraulic pressure is present at the supply port of the HR-1 valve (Item
                4) and the supply port of the parking brake push-pull control valve TW-11 (Item 1). The parking brake
                (Item 3) remains in the engaged position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402132" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402132" filename="../figg04/G0402132.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Parking Brake Control Valve Out - Transmission in Park Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parking brake control valve in- transmission in park position.</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402133">Figure 33</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses. Hydraulic pressure is present at the supply port of the HR-1 valve (Item
                4) and the supply port of the parking brake push-pull control valve TW-11 (Item 1). With the control
                valve TW-11 in the IN position, pressure is available at the supply port of relay valve TW-12 (Item 2)
                located at the transmission and connected to the shift linkage. With the transmission in the park
                position, the pressure is exhausted. The parking brake remains engaged.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402133" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic id="g0402133" filename="../figg04/G0402133.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Parking Brake Control Valve In - Transmission in Park Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parking brake control valve in- transmission shifted out of park position.</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402134">Figure 34</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses. Hydraulic pressure flows through HR-1 valve (Item 4) and the parking brake
                push pull control valve TW-11 to relay valve TW-12 (Item 2). With the transmission shifted out of park,
                pressure flows to the control port of relay valve HR-1 (Item 4) opening a path to pressurize the spring
                brake chamber (Item 3) releasing the parking brake. Excess hydraulic pressure flows through the
                reservoir port of relay valve HR-1 (Item 4). The parking brake is released and the vehicle may be
                driven.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402134" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402134" filename="../figg04/G0402134.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Parking Brake Control Valve In - Transmission Shifted Out of Park Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After initial vehicle operation, the parking brake can be applied by shifting the transmission
                        into the park position or by moving the parking brake push pull control valve TW-11 (Item 1) to
                        the OUT position.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parking brake control valve out - transmission in gear or neutral.</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402135">Figure 35</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses. Hydraulic pressure flows through the relay valve HR-1 (Item 4) to the
                parking brake push pull control valve TW-11 (Item 1). With the valve in the OUT position, hydraulic
                pressure flow is diverted to the exhaust port. The absence of pressure at the control port of relay
                valve HR-1 (Item 4) opens a path for the spring brake chamber (Item 3) to exhaust hydraulic pressure
                allowing the parking brake to engage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402135" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402135" filename="../figg04/G0402135.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Parking Brake Control Valve Out - Transmission in Gear or Neutral</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Parking brake control valve in - transmission shifted to park position.</emph>
                Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0402136">Figure 36</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses. Hydraulic pressure flows through relay valve HR-1 (Item 4) and the parking
                brake push pull control valve TW-11 (Item 1) to the supply port of relay valve TW-12 (Item 2). With the
                relay valve TW-12 (Item 2) in the park position, the hydraulic pressure flow is diverted to the exhaust
                port. The absence of pressure at the control port of relay valve HR-1 (Item 4) opens a path for the
                spring brake chamber (Item 3) to exhaust hydraulic pressure allowing the parking brake to engage.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0402136" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g0402136" filename="../figg04/G0402136.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Parking Brake Control Valve in - Transmission Shifted to Park Position</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta_HL0402102.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04021ta.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
