<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BP-R1 BOBTAIL BRAKE PROPORTIONING RELAY VALVE AND LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE - OPERATION - LQ-5 BOBTAIL
        LIMITING VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="5">
        <title>LQ-5 BOBTAIL LIMITING VALVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>During initial brake application, the LQ-5 limits front axle brake pressure during normal
                tractor-trailer operation. The LQ-5 has two spring-loaded pistons: a blend back piston and a
                proportioning piston. The "stepped" proportioning piston determines actual air pressure reduction and
                the blend back piston allows the valve's delivery pressure to "blend back" and reach a 1:1 ratio during
                high pressure brake applications.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Application - LQ-5 Limiting (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401204">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401204" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401204" filename="../figg04/G0401204.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. LQ-5 Limiting Valve</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT AXLE BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INITIAL DELIVERY SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BLEND BACK SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>During tractor-trailer operation, the trailer air supply valve (red octagonal button) is depressed and
                delivers air pressure at the same time to the trailer and to the LQ-5 control port (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s04012_1.xml" xrefid="f0401203">Figure 3</hotlnk>, System Diagram). Air pressure
                enters the LQ-5 control port and displaces the blend back piston against the resistance of its spring,
                until the piston contacts the cover.
            </para>
            <para>Control pressure holds the blend back piston against the cover and the "initial delivery spring"
                forces the proportioning piston to its seat in the body, which opens the inlet. The "initial delivery"
                pressure is designed to ensure that the brake linings contact the brake drums before proportioning
                occurs. The exhaust valve is sealed due to its spring. Brake control valve (foot valve) air pressure
                enters the supply port, moves through the center of the pistons, around the inlet/exhaust valve, and out
                to the QRV and then to the front axle brake chambers.
            </para>
            <para>Air pressure being delivered to the front axle brake chambers is also present beneath the
                proportioning piston. Because the area on the delivery side of the proportioning piston is larger than
                the area on the supply side, the delivery side needs less air pressure to apply the same force.
            </para>
            <para>Therefore after the initial delivery pressure, the LQ-5 delivers less air pressure to front axle than
                it receives from the brake control valve (foot valve).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Balanced Brake Valve Application-LQ-5 Holding (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401205">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401205" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401205" filename="../figg04/G0401205.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. LQ-5 Holding</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. APPROXIMATELY 1/2 OF BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE) APPLICATION PRESSURE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. FRONT AXLE BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. INITIAL DELIVERY SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. BLEND BACK SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. BRAKE VALVE APPLICATION PRESSURE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The forces acting on the proportioning piston are equal when air pressure beneath the piston is
                approximately one-half of that above the piston. (For example, if a 40 psi brake application is made,
                approximately 20 psi would be present beneath the proportioning piston.) At this point, the
                proportioning piston lifts and closes the inlet. The exhaust passage remains sealed. With both the inlet
                and exhaust valves closed, the LQ-5 is balanced - front axle air pressure is neither increasing nor
                decreasing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Valve Release - LQ-5 Releasing (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401206">Figure 6</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401206" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401206" filename="../figg04/G0401206.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. LQ-5 Releasing</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT AXLE BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INITIAL DELIVERY SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BLEND BACK SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Upon brake control valve (foot valve) release, air pressure above the blend back piston returns to the
                brake control valve (foot valve) and exhausts. Air pressure from the delivery line lifts the
                proportioning piston and inlet/exhaust valve away from the exhaust seat in the body. Air then flows out
                the open exhaust passage. Air from the brake chambers exhausts through the QRV.
            </para>
            <para>If the service brakes are rapidly released, air pressure may lift the inlet/exhaust valve further
                against the relatively light resistance of the valve spring. Air would then also flow back through the
                open inlet and out to the brake control valve (foot valve).
            </para>
            <para>When air pressure beneath the proportioning piston depletes to less than approximately 8 psi, the
                valve spring is able to seat the exhaust valve. The "initial delivery spring" keeps the inlet open and
                allows air from the LQ-5 delivery to flow through the valve, out the supply and back to the brake
                control valve (foot valve).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Application - LQ-5 Blending Back (Tractor-Trailer Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401207">Figure 7</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401207" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401207" filename="../figg04/G0401207.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. LQ-5 Blending</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT AXLE BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INITIAL DELIVERY SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BLEND BACK SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Service brake pressure enters the LQ-5 supply port and combines with the force of the blend back
                spring to work against control pressure. When service pressure is sufficiently high, the total downward
                force begins to overcome the upward force of control pressure on the blend back piston. The blend back
                piston is forced into contact with the proportioning piston. Both pistons now move as one. Because of
                the added surface area of the blend back piston, LQ-5 delivery pressure "catches up" as supply pressure
                increases. When the piston assembly contacts its seat in the body, the LQ-5 delivers full application
                pressure. There is then a 1:1 ratio between supply and delivery.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Brake Valve Application, Balance and Release (Bobtail Tractor Mode)</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0401208">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0401208" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0401208" filename="../figg04/G0401208.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Brake Valve Application, Balance and Release</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TRAILER AIR SUPPLY VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BRAKE CONTROL VALVE (FOOT VALVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BODY</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. INLET/EXHAUST VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT AXLE BRAKE CHAMBER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. PROPORTIONING PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. INITIAL DELIVERY SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. BLEND BACK PISTON</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. BLEND BACK SPRING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The LQ-5 delivers full service application pressure in bobtail mode.</para>
            <para>When the trailer air supply valve is pulled out, air in the LQ-5 control port flows back to the
                trailer air supply valve and exhausts to the atmosphere. With no control pressure, the blend back piston
                is forced by its spring to contact the proportioning piston. The inlet/exhaust valve is held by its
                spring and seals the exhaust passage. Both pistons, now moving as one, reach their stop in the body.
            </para>
            <para>This is the piston position for "bobtail" mode apply, hold and release. The LQ-5 delivers full service
                application pressure in bobtail mode. Upon brake control valve (foot valve) release, delivery air
                pressure flows back through the LQ-5, to the brake control valve (foot valve) and out to the atmosphere.
                Air from the front axle brake chambers exhausts through the quick release valve. Refer to System
                Diagram,
                <hotlnk document="s04012_1.xml" xrefid="f0401203">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
