<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>BRAKE COMPONENTS: This Service Manual Section should be used for reference only. For more current service
        information on all components go to the Bendix website from the ISIS Suppliers menu and refer to the Service
        Data Sheets. - AIR COMPRESSOR GOVERNOR (TYPE D-2)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>AIR COMPRESSOR GOVERNOR (TYPE D-2)</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="IDcomponent" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The air compressor governor, along with the compressor unloader mechanism, automatically limits system
                pressure to a predetermined range by opening unloading valves and stopping compression when system
                pressure has been built up to maximum pressure limit, and by closing unloading valves and starting
                compression when system pressure has dropped to minimum pressure limit.
            </para>
            <para>The D-2 governor (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0400287">Figure 87</hotlnk>
                ) has a piston upon which air pressure acts to overcome the pressure setting spring and control the
                inlet and exhaust valve to either admit or exhaust air to or from the compressor unloader mechanism.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0400287" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g0400287" filename="../figg04/g0400287.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 87. D-2 Governor</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. UNLOADER PORTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MOUNTING HOLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. RESERVOIR PORTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. EXHAUST PORT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The governor can be attached to the compressor or mounted remotely. It is adaptable to either
                mounting. Connections in this system are to the reservoir and compressor unloader ports. It also has an
                exhaust port.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_119.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r_121.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04002r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
