<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR COMPRESSOR: HOLSET SS 296 AND QE 296/338 - TROUBLESHOOTING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl0401401" svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <table id="hl0401405">
            <title>Troubleshooting Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="3">
                <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.25in"/>
                <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="2.74in"/>
                <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="2.99in" colsep="1"/>
                <thead>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1" align="center">
                            <para>Condition</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2" align="center">
                            <para>Cause</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3" align="center">
                            <para>Remedy</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </thead>
                <tbody valign="top">
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry morerows="11">
                            <para>Compressor will not build up air pressure or has slow buildup</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Vehicle plumbing leakage.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for ruptured lines and loose or cracked fittings.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Sticking unloader valve.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Check, clean and lube with high temperature grease in the kit.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Broken intake or exhaust valve.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Replace intake or exhaust valve. Check for cause of failure (discharge line
                                blocked).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Governor fails to exhaust air from unloader.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Replace governor. Be sure control line is open.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Automatic spitter on wet tank sticking open.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Service or replace as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Compressor discharge and wet tank supply hoses reversed at air dryer.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Reverse the hoses.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Air dryer purge valve leaking.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Clean or replace if necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Air dryer purge valve frozen open.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Thaw valve and test dryer heater and thermostat, power, and ground. Replace if
                                necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Blown or leaking head gasket.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Replace cover, head and valve body gaskets. Check for cause of blown gasket (loose
                                head bolts, restricted discharge, carbon, ice, etc.).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Kinked or restricted air intake (20 inches water is maximum vacuum allowable).</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Check and correct as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Damaged intake or exhaust seat of valve body, or debris holding valve open.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Check for damage or debris. Service and correct as necessary.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>-</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="2">
                            <para>Carbon buildup: exhaust line, ECON valve, or dryer inlet.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colname="3">
                            <para>Clean and replace affected parts. Check exhaust line and replace if necessary. Duty
                                cycle may be excessive (over 25%).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor builds too much air pressure</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Defective governor will not send air pressure signal to unloader.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace governor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Unloader cap stuck in loaded position.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Remove, clean and lubricate well with high temperature grease in the kit. Replace if
                                necessary.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Unloader valve body vee seal broken or worn.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace unloader valve body vee seal.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Pressure builds slowly above governor limit</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Unloader cap seat leak.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Repair or replace unloader cap.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cracked/porous inlet connection body.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace the inlet connection body.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leak at air intake gasket between valve body and inlet connection body.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tighten mounting bolts to specified torque or replace air intake gasket.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Mechanical noise in compressor</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Too much backlash in drive coupling or gear.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Adjust mounting position of compressor (
                                <emph type="bold">ONLY WITH ENGINE COLD</emph>!).
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Pneumatic noise or ping in air tank</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Single cylinder air pulse into tanks (air delivery is normal).</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If the noise is objectionable, a ping tank can be installed between the compressor and
                                wet tank.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor cycles frequently-CAB PRESSURE GAUGES FALL TO BOTTOM OF GOVERNOR RANGE
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Brake, accessory, or suspension leaks.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Locate and correct the leaks. Check for stuck valves.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive demand duty cycle (pumping over 25% of the time).</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Reduce air system demands or use greater output compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Compressor cycles frequently-DRY TANK'S (CAB GAUGES) PRESSURE REMAINS NEAR TOP OF
                                GOVERNOR RANGE
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air dryer outlet check valve leaks. (Approximately 30 second cycle)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Repair, lubricate or replace air dryer outlet check valve.</para>
                            <para>HINT: Check the dryer's discharge check valve by adding a known good check valve at
                                the dryer's outlet port. If this makes a difference, the dryer's check valve is not
                                working right.
                            </para>
                            <note>
                                <para>The vehicle air system should be checked regularly for air leaks by timing the
                                    interval between dryer purge blasts, while the vehicle is stationary with engine
                                    idling and with no air system demands, or from start-to-start of compressor pumping
                                    intervals, if there is no air dryer. Times of ten minutes or more are desirable
                                    between dryer purge blasts. Times noticeably shorter indicate significant air system
                                    leakage from the vehicle's wet tank, or from something connected to the wet tank.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Incorrect check valve in the makeup line, so that ECON valve malfunctions. (Approx. 3
                                minute cycle)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Replace with Holset differential check valve. Dryers without internal inlet cut-off
                                valve may use non-Holset check valve in makeup line.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks from items connected to the wet tank. (Approx. 3 to 7 minute cycle)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Use soap bubbles to locate leaks: fittings, sensing line to governor, governor to
                                compressor gasket or hose, signal hose from governor to dryer and/or ECON valve, and
                                makeup line.
                            </para>
                            <para>HINT: Let system pump to top of governor range so that signal hose will be
                                pressurized, then start checking for leaks.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>ECON valve leaking-because of debris or carbon on the seat.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clean or replace the ECON valve.</para>
                            <para>HINT: If air continues to escape from the purge port of the dryer for more than a
                                minute after purge begins, and the known good redundant check valve has been added at
                                the dryer's outlet port, then leakage past the ECON valve (and the dryer's internal
                                boost cut-off valve, if there is one) is likely the source of continued air escape
                                beyond the normal purge air release (30 to 45 seconds is typical). This will cause short
                                cycles, desiccant saturation and then possible freezing problems inside the ECON valve.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air dryer internal inlet cut-off valve leaks with result similar to that of leaking
                                ECON valve.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Clean or replace the valve at the dryer inlet.</para>
                            <para>HINT: Several dryers now have an internal inlet f valve with elastomeric seat, which
                                takes the place of an external ECON valve.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive oil carryover into air system</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive duty cycle (pumping more than 25% of time running)</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Reduce legitimate air system needs, repair leaks, or up-size compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for leak at dryer spitter port during loaded mode. Replace dryer spitter
                                valve.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check for holes rubbed in discharge line.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Runs hot.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check and repair coolant circuit. Consider duty cycle.</para>
                            <para>HINT: Consider overall cycle time. A short cycle time while tank gauges remain near
                                top of range indicates severe leak or dryer outlet check valve malfunction. High duty
                                cycles result in air compressor doing more work and operating at elevated temperature,
                                which thins oil on cylinder wall and aggravates oil carryover. Carbon deposits indicate
                                that the compressor is running too hot.
                            </para>
                            <para>HINT: Check for discharge line pressure above 135 psi due to excessive restriction
                                between compressor and wet tank or misadjustment of the air governor.
                            </para>
                            <para>HINT: Check for pumping longer than one minute with inlet pressure above 10 psi and
                                outlet pressure above 100 psi.
                            </para>
                            <para>HINT: Verify that compressor discharge line is connected to dryer inlet, not outlet,
                                which would result in high back pressure and long buildup times with E-type system.
                            </para>
                            <para>HINT: A leaking compressor exhaust valve or a leaking discharge line will cause both
                                the slow buildup and rapid decay of wet tank pressure, which may not be noticed by
                                checking cycle time alone, since cycle time is the sum of buildup and decay times. But
                                the duty cycle will be very high and the compressor will run hot!
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Failure to maintain discharge line pressure near system pressure during unloaded
                                operating mode.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>HINT: The patented E-type compressor system requires near wet tank pressure to deliver
                                the benefits of reduced power consumption, lower operating temperature, and superior oil
                                control during unloaded operation.
                            </para>
                            <para>Check to assure that a check valve has not been installed at the entrance to the wet
                                tank, preventing the supplying of wet tank pressure to the discharge line when there is
                                no air dryer.
                            </para>
                            <para>Inspect differential or other check valve located in the makeup line to assure it is
                                in good working condition and
                                <emph type="bold">not installed backwards</emph>. Check valve must permit flow toward
                                inlet side of air dryer.
                            </para>
                            <para>Check to be sure the makeup line and check valve are
                                <emph type="bold">not plugged.</emph>
                                With the engine off, loosen the makeup line at the entrance to the ECON valve or dryer
                                inlet if there is no ECON valve. Air should escape from the makeup line. If no air
                                escapes from the loosened fitting, bleed off wet tank pressure, and remove the makeup
                                line and check valve for further inspection.
                                <emph type="bold">Be careful!</emph>
                                If a check valve is broken, look for its parts which could block the makeup line.
                            </para>
                            <para>When there is a dryer without internal "makeup" line,
                                <emph type="bold">there must be an external makeup line</emph>
                                which includes a check valve which permits air to flow from wet tank to the inlet side
                                of the air dryer.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>No ECON valve.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Add ECON valve, or use an air dryer which has an internal inlet cutoff valve with
                                elastomeric seat capable of holding full system pressure. Some means of sealing the
                                downstream end of discharge line must be provided to maintain system pressure in the
                                discharge line during unloaded compressor operation. Dryers with internal elastomeric
                                inlet cutoff valve have the advantage of a heated valve where condensation is less
                                likely to freeze during extremely cold weather operation.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Cylinder bore or piston ring wear, scoring, or bore polishing.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check air intake plumbing and filter for any source of contaminant ingestion. Replace
                                rings or the entire compressor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Piston rings improperly installed or broken.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Repair or replace compressor.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive engine oil drain intervals.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Change oil at proper intervals to avoid the breakdown of multi-viscosity oils. Broken
                                long-chain polymers aggravate oil carryover in the air compressor, just like oil burning
                                in the engine.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Abnormal amount of moisture in the wet tank</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check valve missing or backwards.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Sometimes, it happens. Some check valves look like a fitting and vice versa. The main
                                purpose of the check valve is to prevent air from bypassing the air dryer and thus,
                                carrying moisture to wet tank.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air dryer saturated/ineffective.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Excessive duty cycle/long-duration, short purge, desiccant "poisoned" by oil, inlet
                                air too hot (over 150 degrees F) or spitter blocked.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks: air-to-coolant or coolant-to- air.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Inadequate clamp load on head or cover gasket.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Tighten head bolts to specified torque. Chase threads at center of valve body. Replace
                                valve body, head and cover gaskets.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air system freeze-up - Flow path blockage with compressor damage the likely result
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Low spots (potential water/ice traps) in compressor discharge line.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The discharge line should slope downward from the compressor to the dryer inlet. (An
                                immediate rise within the first two feet of the line is acceptable if this allows the
                                following line to slope downward to dryer inlet for drainage.)
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Condensation accumulates and freezes at ECON valve.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If an ECON valve is necessary, locate it where condensation will not form upstream and
                                where discharge air temperature is below 150 degrees F. This will usually be two to
                                seven feet from the compressor if the dryer is more than eight to ten feet from the
                                compressor.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Long discharge line causes condensation which freezes.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>If the discharge line length must exceed ten feet, then consider insulating after the
                                first five feet.
                                <emph type="bold">NOTE: 150 degrees F is maximum dryer inlet temperature.</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air system freeze-up - Moisture in wet tank spreads throughout air system, causing
                                valves to malfunction
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Maximum dryer inlet temperature exceeded.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The discharge line arrangement should reduce A/C outlet air temperature to 150 degrees
                                F maximum. Otherwise, the desiccant's water-holding efficiency will be degraded.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dryer does not purge.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dryer may not be receiving the required signal from the governor due to a bad
                                governor, or a plugged or badly leaking actuating line.
                            </para>
                            <para>Dryer may have a frozen purge port due to faulty heater, thermostat or improper
                                electrical ground. Check the dryer's heater and thermostat to be sure they are
                                functioning properly, not just that there is power present and that there is a good
                                ground path. In general, there must be a reasonable electrical resistance from heater
                                power supply contact to ground for a 50 to 100 watt heater when the dryer is cooled
                                below thermostat closure temperature. Look for about 1.5 to 3.0 ohms for a 12 volt
                                system.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check valve backwards.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Reverse the check valve if it is backwards.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Leaks from the wet tank, brake or suspension system.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Locate and repair the leaks.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Design demand excessive (Long Duration Pumping Cycle). Under occasionally adverse
                                operating conditions, the sum of the air system demands may become excessive. Wet tank
                                pressure may not reach the top of the governor range/dryer purge point for a long time!
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Check the air dryer. Replace if necessary. If the dryer becomes saturated and the
                                system gets wet, a continuous flow dryer may improve performance.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air dryer outlet check ball malfunctioning.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>The check ball hangs open allowing wet tank pressure to be lost through the dryer
                                purge port. Pressure falls to the bottom of the governor range in a few seconds. The air
                                compressor is forced to resume pumping after these few seconds. The purge volume of the
                                dryer is never allowed to do its job of drying the desiccant. The dryer becomes
                                saturated. The compressor runs hot and suffers a premature failure. Be alert for dryer
                                purge blasts about 30 seconds apart at idle with water in the wet tank. The dryer outlet
                                check valve must be replaced or serviced. Contact dryer manufacturer for advice.
                                Silicone grease on the ball is one possible temporary solution.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Condensation in wet tank.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Make it a habit to regularly (daily) drain all of the system tanks. This will minimize
                                the spread of moisture to system valves and help you avoid serious problems. It may also
                                allow the origin of the problem to be identified and corrected to avoid or minimize
                                downtime.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="0">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air dryer purge volume too small.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Dryer purge volume needs to be sufficient for the application. High air demand (by
                                design or by leaks not corrected) may require larger or supplementary purge volume to
                                adequately dry the desiccant.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row rowsep="1">
                        <entry>
                            <para>&#160;</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Air demand beyond the rated capacity of the air dryer.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry>
                            <para>Consider the addition of another dryer in parallel, or a dryer with greater capacity
                                to successfully remove moisture at the demand flow rate. All air dryers have a maximum
                                rated air handling capacity which should be matched with the compressor output
                                capability for a successful application.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s04014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
