<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - Hydraulic ABS Bleeding
        Procedure for Unfilled (Dry) Modulator Assembly
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Hydraulic ABS Bleeding Procedure for Unfilled (Dry) Modulator Assembly</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Brake Bleeding Procedure</title>
            <para>The following brake bleeding methods explain how to bleed an add-on hydraulic ABS dry modulator
                assembly during installation, or in the event of air in the brake system. These instructions are for
                manual bleeding with electronic control equipment and include the procedure for bleeding both the master
                cylinder and the brake system. In some cases, for example if you are replacing only the modulator
                assembly, it may not be necessary to bleed the master cylinder. If you have any questions, please
                contact the Meritor Service Center at 800-535-5560.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Wet modulator assembly refers to a prefilled component; dry refers to a component shipped
                        without hydraulic brake fluid. The modulator must be handled with appropriate care and should
                        not be exposed to excessive impact or compressed air at the hydraulic ports prior to assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to bleed the system whenever any hydraulic system fitting is loosened or disconnected
                        will allow air to remain in the system. This will prevent the hydraulic pressure in the brake
                        system from rising enough to apply the brakes properly. This will cause the stopping distance to
                        increase and can result in serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                    <para>Properly discard hydraulic brake fluid that is removed from the brake system. Hydraulic brake
                        fluid that is removed can be contaminated and can cause damage, loss of braking and serious
                        personal injury.
                    </para>
                    <para>Use only DOT 3 or DOT 4 hydraulic brake fluid, as specified by the original equipment
                        manufacturer. Do not use or mix different types of hydraulic brake fluid. The wrong hydraulic
                        brake fluid will damage the rubber parts of the brake caliper and can cause damage, loss of
                        braking and serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                    <para>Hydraulic brake fluid is a caustic substance. Contact with hydraulic brake fluid can case skin
                        irritation. Do not let hydraulic brake fluid touch any painted surfaces, as it will remove the
                        paint. Hydraulic brake fluid may also damage certain non-metal surfaces. Do not let fluid get on
                        brake pads, shoes, rotors or drums.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
