<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - D VERSION HYDRAULIC ABS -
        BODY BUILDER INFORMATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>D VERSION HYDRAULIC ABS - BODY BUILDER INFORMATION</title>
        <para>Before modifying a bus, truck or motor home chassis equipped with Meritor WABCO D version hydraulic ABS,
            review the following information. These tips will help you understand the ABS system and help avoid possible
            damage to that system when the chassis is altered. Typical Meritor WABCO Hydraulic ABS systems are
            illustrated in Figures of this bulletin.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Do not mount extreme heat sources (sources exceeding 158&#176;F, 70&#176;C) near the ECU. These
                    include cab heater, engine exhaust, etc.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Do not install RFI-emitting devices (such as radios, electric motors or pumps) on or near the ECU
                    or other ABS components to help isolate the system from electrical interference.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Perform all chassis welding with all connections to the ECU disconnected.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When installing other components, be aware of - and do not damage - the ABS harness or
                    connectors.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Do not cut or splice the ABS harness to provide power to other sources on the vehicle. Cutting or
                    splicing the ABS harness may cause the system to malfunction.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When extending an OEM chassis, use the appropriate ABS harness extension cables and connectors.
                    Maintenance Manual 39, available from Meritor WABCO, provides installation information.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All ground connections of the modulator assembly and ECU MUST have separate grounding points.
                    Meritor WABCO recommends that no other loads be connected to the grounds.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When painting or undercoating, make sure all connections are securely fastened. Protect unfastened
                    or exposed connectors.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Any ABS component removed during modification must be reinstalled per Meritor WABCO
                    specifications.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Before putting the vehicle into operation, perform the appropriate end of line test to ensure
                    proper hydraulic ABS operation.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
