<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - GENERAL GUIDELINES - ABS
        MODULATOR ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ABS MODULATOR ASSEMBLY</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The modulator assembly contains hydraulic brake fluid, a caustic substance. Remove the valve
                    carefully so that fluid does not leak and cause skin irritation or damage to components.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Operating temperature of the modulator assembly is -40&#176;F to 176&#176;F (-40&#176;C to 80&#176;C).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Maximum operating pressure of the modulator assembly is 3335 psi (230 bar).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use only brake fluid equivalent to DOT 3 or DOT 4 in accordance with Federal Motor Vehicle Safety
                    Standard 116. Refer to the vehicle specifications to determine which fluid to use.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DO NOT mount proportioning valves downstream from the ABS modulator assembly.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Plumb hydraulic lines so fluid will continually run down from the master cylinder, the highest
                    point, to the wheel end brake, the lowest point. This helps prevent air from being trapped in the
                    system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>To provide proper fluid drainage, mount the ABS modulator assembly within 5 degrees of horizontal
                    from side to side and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1005415a">5 to 30 degrees of horizontal (maximum) from front to back</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Mount hydraulic brake lines on the chassis in areas where they will not be pinched or scraped. The
                    inside of the frame rail is ideal for mounting hydraulic brake lines.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Whenever any hydraulic brake system components are installed, fittings are loosened, or lines are
                    disconnected, air can enter the system. This air must be removed from the brake system to allow
                    sufficient hydraulic pressure for applying the brakes. Follow the instructions in "Hydraulic ABS
                    Bleeding Procedures for Prefilled (Wet) Modulator Assembly" or in Maintenance Manual 39.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All prefilled (Wet) modulators require a manual or pressure bleed procedure. Follow the
                    instructions in "Hydraulic ABS Bleeding Procedures for Prefilled (Wet) Modulator Assembly."
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All unfilled (Dry) modulators require a fill and bleed procedure that activates each solenoid
                    valve in order to remove air trapped in the valve cavities. Follow the instructions in "Hydraulic
                    ABS Bleeding Procedure for Unfilled (Dry) Modulator Assembly."
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f1005415a" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figR10/R105415A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
