<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - Hydraulic ABS Bleeding
        Procedure for Unfilled (Dry) Modulator Assembly - Manual Bleed Procedure with Electronic Control Equipment
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Manual Bleed Procedure with Electronic Control Equipment</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The electronic control equipment must be capable of actuating (energizing) the outlet solenoid
                    valves for each wheel for approximately 10 seconds and activating the pump of the modulator. The
                    inlet solenoid valve should be open (de-energized). The Meritor WABCO Diagnostic Controller can be
                    used to do this.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply the parking brake and chock the tires. Turn the ignition OFF.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The ignition must remain off for the initial bleed procedure; energizing the unit during bleeding
                    must be impossible.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform brake bleed procedure for wet module, bleeding the circuit and master cylinder if
                required prior to connecting electronic control equipment. Use Pressure Bleed Method if equipment is
                available; if not, use the Manual Bleed Method.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install electronic control equipment to ECU, or to the modulator assembly and pump.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn ignition switch ON or power electronic control equipment.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push on brake pedal with maximum force (firm pedal) and hold.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Activate the pulse function on the electronic control equipment starting with the longest
                brake circuit, typically the rear.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release brake pedal for 5 seconds and activate the pump of the modulator for approximately 5
                seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat Steps 5 through 7 three additional times.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform manual bleed on appropriate wheels.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To perform a manual bleed, follow Steps 2 through 8 under "Manual Bleed Procedure (Wet Modulator
                    Assembly)."
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat Steps 5 through 9 for the remaining 2 brake actuators.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a firm brake pedal resistance is felt and the brake pedal pushes back when the solenoids and
                    pump are simultaneously actuated for each brake circuit, the system bleed procedure is complete. If
                    there is no firm pedal resistance, repeat the bleed procedure and/or look into brake system defect,
                    (leaks, etc.).
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1005426a" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figR10/R105426a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="600"/>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
