<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - Hydraulic ABS Bleeding
        Procedure for Unfilled (Dry) Modulator Assembly - EVACUATION AND FILL PROCEDURE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EVACUATION AND FILL PROCEDURE</title>
        <para>Meritor WABCO recommends using the Evacuation and Fill Method for filling the dry modulator and brake
            system simultaneously. This method requires special equipment capable of vacuuming air from the entire brake
            system. If you do not have this special equipment, follow the "Manual Bleed Procedure with Electronic
            Control Equipment" below.
        </para>
        <para>The evacuation and fill procedure is as follows:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">During the evacuation and fill cycle the following conditions apply:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Inlet valves deactivated, power off.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Outlet valves continually activated, cycled with power on for one second and power off
                    for one second.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Recirculation pump deactivated, power off.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The total outlet valve pulse time must not exceed more than 150 seconds for 12-volt
                    systems at temperatures of 68&#176;F (20&#176;C).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The valve pulse time may be different for various conditions.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Evacuate system to 2.2 mmHg (0.0425 lbs per square inch absolute [psia]/3 mbar), measured at
                the furthest brake, for approximately 60 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check for vacuum leakage for 10 seconds. If pressure rises above 6.65 mmHg (0.13 psia/9
                mbar), then additional evacuation is required for approximately 10 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Brake fluid filling phase requires pressure to reach 14.5 to 43.5 psi (1 to 3 bar) measured
                at the brake. Filling time approximately 30 to 60 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
