<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - GENERAL GUIDELINES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>GENERAL GUIDELINES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                        maintenance or service.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to the electrical system or ABS components when welding on an ABS-equipped
                        vehicle, disconnect the power connector from the ECU.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid damage to internal components, do not store ABS parts in areas where temperatures
                        exceed 194&#176;F (90&#176;C).
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>ABS components must be installed where they are best protected from the environment, yet accessible
                for service.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect each vehicle installation using the Meritor WABCO Diagnostic Controller with Hydraulic ABS
                program card or Meritor WABCO TOOLBOX Software, a PC-based diagnostics program. A sample checklist that
                can be used to record the results of these inspections appears in the
                <hotlnk document="v04001_12.xml" xrefid="f1005423a">Checklist figure
                    <xref refid="f1005423a"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . You may want to make extra copies of this form.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ELECTRONIC CONTROL UNIT (ECU)</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>To protect the internal components of the ECU, mount it away from extreme heat sources such as
                        cab heaters, engine exhaust, radiators, etc. Maximum heat tolerance for the ECU is 158&#176;F
                        (70&#176;C).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To help isolate the system from electrical interference, install the ECU, ABS wire harnesses
                        and all other ABS components away from Radio Frequency Interference (RFI) emitting devices, such
                        as radios, electric motors or pumps.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>To avoid water penetration, cab-mounted ECUs must be installed with the connectors facing down
                        or to the side. Do not mount the ECU with the connectors facing up. Frame-mounted ECUs must be
                        installed with connectors parallel to the ground, not facing up.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Secure the ECU so that 5g permissible acceleration is not exceeded.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ABS controls the vehicle retarder system (if installed). These include engine compression
                        brakes, exhaust brakes, transmission retarders or drive line retarder. An electronic relay
                        controlled by the ECU is required.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
