<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - Hydraulic Anti-Lock Braking System (HABS) Installation
        Guide for OEMs and Body Builders (Includes Body Builder Installation Information) - GENERAL GUIDELINES -
        ELECTRICAL WIRING, CABLES AND CONNECTORS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ELECTRICAL WIRING, CABLES AND CONNECTORS</title>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Use weatherproof connectors when electrical connections are exposed to outdoor environmental
                    conditions.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Protect wiring exposed to extreme environmental or mechanical conditions. For example, wiring
                    routed near an engine exhaust must be shielded from heat.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Secure excess component wiring lengthwise to the frame rail. Do not coil wiring. Coiled wire can
                    act as an antenna and increase susceptibility to RFI.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Route all wiring within strain relief and bend radius allowance. Keep bend radius approximately
                    seven times the cable diameter minimum.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use cable clamps, grommets and tie straps to properly route and secure ABS component wiring.
                    Verify sufficient cable length is available for steering and suspension travel. Route single cables
                    (such as sensor leads) along hydraulic brake flexible hoses. Support wiring every 8 to 12 inches.
                    Loose, dangling cables are unacceptable.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sensor cable must be twisted pair wire with a minimum of 20 turns per meter. Do not splice these
                    wires.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>All ground connections of the modulator assembly and ECU must have separate grounding points. It
                    is recommended no other loads be connected to the grounds.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="v04001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
