<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Feature Functions</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Feature Functions</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The following functions are performed by the system.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Monitoring Tire Pressure and Tire Temperature</title>
            <para>The TPMS controller monitors pressure in conjunction with temperature to detect system faults. For
                example, if a low tire pressure condition exists while the temperature is increased it is likely that
                the condition is due to low tire pressure, since low tire pressure causes excess friction/heat.
                Likewise, if a temperature related condition exists in the absence of a low pressure condition it is
                likely that the condition is due to friction from a faulty wheel bearing or dragging brake. The tire
                pressure displayed in the VID, however, reflects the actual tire pressure gauge reading and is not
                temperature compensated.
            </para>
            <para>The TPMS system knows what the corresponding pressure should be at any given temperature, and
                therefore will not set erroneous faults based on normal pressure changes in proportion to temperature.
                The system generates warnings based on the difference between the target tire pressure, programmed into
                the VID "Pressure Setup" parameter, and the expected pressure for a particular tire temperature.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the Tire Pressure Diagnostics section to understand the thresholds at which tire pressure
                diagnostics are performed and warnings are displayed.
            </para>
            <para>The feature will monitor tire information if all of the following conditions are true:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The key switch is placed in the ACCESSORY position (See Note 1).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No active 'loss of communication' errors are present.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No active TPMS antenna related diagnostic trouble codes are present.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note 1:</emph>The voltage received by the TPMS controller via the ACCESSORY relay must
                be greater than 3.5 volts for the controller to 'wake up'. Otherwise, the controller will remain
                'asleep' in which the following conditions will be true:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>All TPMS related functions are inoperative.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the VID cannot receive data from the TPMS controller on the SAE J1939 data link.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the TPMS screens will be accessible, but the VID will display all tires in RED.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Because the tire sensors normally transmit data only once every minute, it may be necessary to wait up
                to 2 minutes for the feature to receive data from all of the sensors. The wheel may appear BLACK on the
                VID TPMS screen before the data is received from the tire sensor.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
