<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES - TIRE CARE - TIRE WEAR</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TIRE WEAR</title>
        <para>Radial tires can exhibit three types of normal wear patterns: 1. Even, 2. Erosion, 3. Shoulder.</para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Even Wear.</emph>
            Like a bias tire, radial tires which have an even wear pattern is a sign that they are being properly used
            and maintained.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Erosion Wear</emph>
            has also been called rolling wear, channel or river wear and can be found in both bias or radial tires.
            Erosion wear is found more often at free rolling tires. This is an indication that the tire is used in a
            slow wearing operation. What happens is that the belt plies are held very rigid and the tread is not allowed
            to distort as it passes through the contact area. Wear will only occur at the edge of the tread. The tire is
            not being worn fast enough through normal driving. No corrective action required. If erosion gets to be 1/16
            inch (1.588mm) or more, the tire should be rotated.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Shoulder Wear</emph>even with tires inflated properly is a normal wear of certain radial
            tire designs. If both inside and outside shoulders are wearing evenly around the tire, no further action is
            required. Do not over-inflate tire to correct this effect. To do so could lead to premature failure when
            impact of road hazard is encountered.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_22.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_24.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
