<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Tire Transmitter ID Programming - Rotating the
        Wheels
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="8">
        <title>Rotating the Wheels</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">If rotating tires (such as LF with RF), Tire Transmitters must be disassociated with
                    both wheels and then both Transmitter IDs must be reprogrammed to their new wheel locations. Actual
                    tires may be rotated before or after programming.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Keeping Track of Wheel Locations</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">It's important to ensure that tire sensors are not being reprogrammed back into the
                    same location.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT!</emph>
                Prior to servicing a particular TPMS equipped wheel, keep track of its location with respect to the
                vehicle. Each wheel indicates the respective Tire Transmitter ID on a sticker in case wheels are moved
                from their original orientation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">If the TPMS sensor ID sticker on the wheel has been removed:</emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Either</emph>, write the Tire Transmitter ID being received for that wheel
                        location (displayed on the VID) by placing a sticker with that ID on the appropriate wheel
                        before removing the wheel from the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Or</emph>, write the wheel's location (left front, for example) using a
                        sticker on the wheel being serviced before removing the wheel from the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">If the Tire Transmitter ID is unknown AND the wheel was moved from its original
                    orientation:
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Either</emph>, remove 2-3 PSI air pressure from the tire with the unknown Tire
                        Transmitter ID within one second. This will place the tire sensor in fast transmit mode for
                        approximately 2 minutes. That Tire Transmitter ID will then appear 1st in the list of detected
                        sensors on the Tire Transmitter ID screen (and with an asterisk).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Or</emph>, retrieve the Tire Transmitter ID (sensor serial #) from the tire
                        sensor by removing the tire.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the starting wheel highlighted as shown (LF in this case), press SEL 2 times.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700311" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700311.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 24.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The screen below will then be displayed on the VID.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700312" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 25.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>At this point (screen above) the tire sensor (0300060432) has been disassociated from the LF location
                and either a Tire Transmitter ID must now be added or the tire location must be "blanked" (no IDs will
                be associated with the location). Since we don't want to reprogram the LF tire back to that location,
                we'll leave it blank as instructed in the next step.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note:</emph>
                In this case, the sensor removed is the only one in the list. In a shop environment, however, other IDs
                may be present due to the system receiving other TPMS equipped vehicles/wheels. If other sensors are
                detected, the first Transmitter ID in the list will be the one which was removed (LF).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press BACK to leave the current wheel location blank. All sensors will remain
                    disassociated with this location and 0000000000 will be displayed (as shown below) for this location
                    when the wheel is selected.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700313" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 26.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press the down arrow until the RF wheel location is highlighted (as shown below).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700314" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700314.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 27.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press SEL 2 times while the RF wheel location is highlighted.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700315" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700315.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 28.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point (screen above) the previously programmed RF sensor (0300060115) has been
                    disassociated from the RF location (shown first in the list). The only other sensor in the vicinity
                    is the LF wheel (0300060432). That is the wheel which needs to be programmed into the RF location,
                    so we'll select and add that wheel to the RF location by using the down arrow followed by pressing
                    SEL. The screen below illustrates the results of the newly programmed RF sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700316" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700316.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 29.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press the up arrow to go back to the LF wheel location, then press SEL 2 times.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700317" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700317.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 30.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>0000000000 will be the first Transmitter ID in the list (shown above). The second Transmitter ID
                (0300060115) is the one that was previously associated with RF location.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press down to select the sensor that was previously associated with the RF location
                    (0300060115) and press SEL to associate that sensor with the LF location. The association is shown
                    is the example below.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1700318" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700318.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 31.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Procedure completed.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
