<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Description and Operation - Tire Pressure Sensors
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Tire Pressure Sensors</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Tire pressure and temperature are measured periodically by an intelligent tire pressure sensor located
                inside each wheel. The sensor uses sensitive silicon microelectronics to detect changes in tire pressure
                (similar to a diaphragm being pushed). Each sensor is powered by a lithium battery and contains a radio
                frequency (RF) transmitter.
            </para>
            <para>The tire pressure sensor sends tire pressure/temperature information along with the unique
                identification number (ID) of the current tire via 433 MHz RF signal to the tire pressure antenna. The
                tire pressure antenna processes the RF signals received from the tire pressure sensors and transfers the
                data via TPMS LIN-bus to the TPMS controller. The tire transmitter ID allows the TPMS controller to
                determine the wheel location.
            </para>
            <para>The tire pressure sensor also provides status information such as remaining life of sensor battery,
                sensor battery under voltage, fast pressure loss, and over temperature information. Sensor battery life
                is typically 5 years, however, life will be reduced under critical system conditions in which fast data
                transmission is required.
            </para>
            <para>Under normal operating conditions, the tire pressure sensors transmit data to the tire pressure
                monitoring controller once every minute.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Diagnostics</title>
            <para>If any tire sensor is moved out of the range of the antenna, fails to transmit, has a low sensor
                battery, or is unable to measure tire information correctly, the TPMS controller will detect the
                condition and set a corresponding DTC. Refer to the Diagnostic Trouble Codes section for more
                information about the DTC associated with the tire pressure sensor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fast Transmit Mode</title>
            <para>The sensor will be placed in 'fast transmit mode' (transmits data once every second) if:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The sensor is replaced
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the tire has been newly pressurized
                        <emph type="bold">(See Note 1)</emph>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                        if a 'fast leak' condition occurs
                        <emph type="bold">(See Note 1)</emph>.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note 1:</emph>
                2 - 3 PSI air pressure must be added or removed from the tire within 1 second for 'fast transmit' mode
                to occur. The sensor will remain in fast transmit mode for approximately 3 minutes after the above
                conditions are true.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note 2:</emph>
                Placing the tire sensor in 'fast transmit' mode by releasing air from the appropriate tire can be useful
                in locating tires on the VID screen.
            </para>
            <para>The following will occur if the sensor is placed into 'fast transmit mode':</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The VID will display
                        <emph type="bold">"WARNING: Fast Tire Pressure Loss"</emph>
                        as a popup message
                        <emph type="bold">(See Note 3)</emph>
                        if air has been removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        a corresponding 'fast leak' DTC will be set by the TPMS controller
                        <emph type="bold">(See Note 3)</emph>
                        if air has been removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        any sensor in 'fast transmit' mode will appear first in the list of detected sensors on the
                        vehicle information display (VID).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        any sensor in 'fast transmit' mode will have an asterisk next to that tire transmitter ID on the
                        VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        sensor battery life will be reduced while in 'fast transmit' mode.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Note 3:</emph>
                Warnings and diagnostic trouble codes will only be generated for sensors that have been programmed into
                the system. Sensors can be programmed only after they have been initialized. Refer to the
                <emph type="italic">Sensor Initialization</emph>
                section for more information.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sensor Initialization</title>
            <para>To preserve sensor battery life, tire sensors are in 'sleep mode' while in storage and will not
                transmit data. When a tire sensor is installed (must be pressurized) for the first time, the sensor will
                be placed into 'fast transmit mode' for 3 minutes, but no warnings will be generated by the TPMS
                controller.
            </para>
            <para>During this first pressurization, if the pressure is reduced to less than 22 PSI within 3 minutes, the
                tire sensor goes back into 'sleep mode'. After the first pressurization, 'sleep mode' is no longer
                available. After the tire sensor has been programmed into the system, YELLOW or RED tire pressure
                warnings may be displayed in the VID depending on the programmed value in the VID "Pressure Setup"
                screen.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
