<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Tire Pressure SetUp</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>Tire Pressure SetUp</title>
        <para>
            <title>Menu Descriptions</title>
        </para>
        <para>The following sections describe the functions available on the VID through the various menu screens.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Main Menu Screen</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The MAIN MENU screen will display as shown in Figure 32.</para>
        <figure id="f41368" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700333.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 32.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The Setup Menu will display as shown in Figure 33.</para>
        <figure id="f41390" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700334.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 33. Setup Menu</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The TPMS Setup screen will display as shown in Figure 34.</para>
        <figure id="f41398" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700335.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 34. TPMS Setup</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>If no password is assigned, the VID will skip over password protection screens and all screens will be
            available. This is the default configuration from the factory, however, this screen can be set as password
            protected.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Pressure Setup</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Selecting Pressure Setup will display a screen indicating tire locations and current value of the desired
            pressure setting, as shown in Figure 35.
        </para>
        <figure id="fVID31" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700336.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 35. Pressure Setup</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>An on-screen arrow will indicate the tire location. To change the pressure setting, press the SEL button.
            The on-screen arrow will then point to the pressure setting and allow it to be changed. Pressing the UP or
            DOWN buttons will increase or decrease the pressure setting in 1 PSI increments (pressure settings are
            limited to 88 PSI minimum and 117 PSI maximum). When the desired pressure is entered, press the SEL button
            to return to selecting tire location.
        </para>
        <para>Select the next tire location by pressing the UP or DOWN buttons and repeat the process.</para>
        <para>When the desired pressure for all tires is correct, move the on-screen arrow to Save and press the SEL
            button.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Tire Type</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Selecting Tire Type allows selection of the type of rear axle tires, dual or single (see Figure 36).
            Select the proper type by pressing either the UP or DOWN button and then the SEL button.
        </para>
        <para>If the Tire Type is changed, a screen will appear warning that the TPMS sensor assignments must also be
            changed. On this screen, press SEL to continue with the change or BACK / HOME to cancel the change.
        </para>
        <figure id="fVID32" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700337.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 36. Tire Type</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
