<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Frequently Asked Questions</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
        <para>1.&#9;
            <emph type="bold">Question:</emph>
            "Why do I keep getting low tire pressure warnings displayed on the VID?"
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Answer:</emph>
            This is part of the normal operation of the system as described in the Tire Pressure Diagnostics section of
            this document.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The threshold at which certain tire pressure warnings appear is adjustable on the VID "Pressure
                    Setup" screen. However, the default value is preset by the vehicle manufacturer.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">To ensure tire pressure warnings are displayed properly on the VID, set the current
                pressure value in the "Pressure Setup" screen to the recommended cold inflation pressure as specified in
                your Operator's Manual. This should include adjustments based on vehicle loading.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>2.&#9;
            <emph type="bold">Question:</emph>
            "Why are the low tire pressure warnings being displayed in the VID when the tire pressure is at or above the
            recommended inflation?"
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Answer:</emph>
            By the laws of physics, pressure increases with increasing temperature. Tire temperature is increased as a
            result of friction from normal driving and braking. Therefore, although the tire pressure displayed in the
            VID may be close to the recommended cold inflated tire pressure; due to increased tire temperature while
            driving, tire pressure should have also increased.
        </para>
        <para>If the system detects that the tire pressure has not increased with the rise in temperature, it assumes
            that the air volume has changed (air has leaked from the tire); hence the YELLOW (or RED) warning appears in
            the VID. This loss of air needs to be replaced until the YELLOW (or RED) warning in the VID goes out (the
            wheel turns GREEN on the VID TPMS screen).
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">As a standard practice, tire inflation should be done only when tires are cold, or
                incorrect air pressures will result.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>3.&#9;
            <emph type="bold">Question:</emph>
            "Why is the tire information not being displayed on the VID when I turn the key switch to the IGNITION ON
            position OR when I start the vehicle? Several wheels are BLACK (empty) on the TPMS screen for almost a full
            minute."
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Answer:</emph>
            It may take up to 2 minutes before the TPMS controller receives all of the sensor's information, due to the
            rate at which they transmit (once per minute). Therefore, the sensor's information may not be received by
            the TPMS controller immediately following an ignition key cycle.
        </para>
        <para>4.&#9;
            <emph type="bold">Question:</emph>
            "Why are the low tire pressure warnings being displayed in the VID? Although the VID indicates that the air
            pressure for the tire is low on the TPMS screen, the tire pressure gauge reading indicates that the tire
            pressure is sufficient when I checked it."
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Answer:</emph>
            Ensure all of the Tire Transmitter IDs have been programmed to the correct wheel location. The VID does not
            actually know the location of the tire sensors. Each tire sensor has been programmed to a wheel location,
            and these locations can be changed manually using the VID.
        </para>
        <para>If a Tire Transmitter has been programmed into the wrong wheel location, the wheel location corresponding
            to the YELLOW or RED wheel on the TPMS screen will be incorrect. The fact that one of the wheels has lost
            air will be true, however.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
