<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to neutral or park, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If you notice either a label located in the wheel hand hole area or what appears to be a stud
                        mounted 180 degrees from the valve stem, you must follow the instructions on the attached
                        bulletin from the manufacturer when removing and installing a tire. Failure to follow these
                        instructions when removing or mounting a tire could cause the tire pressure monitor to break off
                        inside the wheel resulting in a loose sensor inside of the tire and wheel assembly. This can
                        eventually lead to tire damage or failure of the tire sensor.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The tire pressure monitoring system (TPMS) is an optional feature used to monitor and display tire
                pressure. The vehicle information display (VID), standard on vehicles equipped with TPMS, is used to
                display and program TPMS related information. Refer to the Vehicle Information Display Operator's Manual
                for detailed information on using the VID menus.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1700320" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700320B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Front Tire Pressure Monitoring Antenna</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Antenna Module</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1700319" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700319A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Rear Tire Pressure Monitoring Antennas</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Antenna Module</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Vehicles equipped with TPMS will be equipped with the following additional electrical
                    components:
                </emph>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">TPMS controller</emph>
                        located under the engine cover on the module plate next to the ICON module.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Up to 3 tire pressure antennas</emph>
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Front tire pressure antenna</emph>
                                located below the cab and behind the front axle, near the horn.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Left rear tire pressure antenna</emph>
                                located on the outer portion of the left rear frame rail.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Right rear tire pressure antenna</emph>
                                located on the outer portion of the right rear frame rail.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">10 tire pressure sensors</emph>
                        (1 sensor mounted in each wheel)
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="dash">
                        <item>
                            <para>If equipped with super single wheels - located 180 degrees from the valve stem hole.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>If equipped with dual wheels - located on the back of the valve stem.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
