<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Wheels and Tires - Wheels and Tires - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not mix different types of tires, such as radial, bias or bias-belted, on the same vehicle
                        except in emergencies. Vehicle handling can be seriously affected and can result in loss of
                        control.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Factory-installed tires and wheels are designed to operate satisfactorily with loads up to and
                including full-rated load capacity when inflated to recommended inflation pressures.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tire Inflation Information</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>An inflated tire and rim can be very dangerous if incorrectly used, serviced or maintained. To
                        avoid serious injury, never attempt to reinflate a tire which has been run flat or seriously
                        underinflated without first removing the tire from the wheel assembly for inspection. Do not
                        attempt to add air to tires or install new tires or wheels without first taking precautions to
                        protect persons and property.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The vehicle is equipped with an all-steel radial tire. All-steel radial tires utilize steel cords in
                the sidewalls, and also require increased inflation pressures of up to 85 psi. As such, they cannot be
                treated like normal light truck tires. Tire service, including adjusting tire pressure, must be carried
                out by personnel trained, supervised and equipped according to Federal Occupational Safety and Health
                Administration (OSHA) regulations. For example, during any procedure involving tire inflation, the
                technician or individual must utilize a remote inflation device, and make sure that all persons are at a
                safe distance.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Tire and Wheel Runout</title>
            <para>Excessive radial and lateral runout of a wheel and tire assembly can cause roughness, vibration, wheel
                tramp, tire wear and steering wheel tremor.
            </para>
            <para>Before checking runout, and to avoid false readings caused by temporary flat spots in the tires, check
                runout only after the vehicles has been driven far enough to warm the tires. For additional information,
                refer to Noise, Vibration and Harshness in S10019.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Precautions</title>
            <para>CAUTION and SAFETY FIRST are bywords when handling truck tires. Careful attention to the safety
                precautions that follow can prevent crippling injuries or even death. Make it a rule to respect the
                terrific force contained in an inflated tire.
            </para>
            <para>Wheels must be correctly maintained. Incorrectly maintained wheels can adversely affect the life of
                the tire and the wheel. When inflated, a tire is potentially very destructive. Accidents are caused by
                careless handling and inexperience.
            </para>
            <para>Follow the safety precautions in this section and obtain safety literature from your wheel and rim
                distributor, wheel and rim manufacturer, NHTSA or OSHA. For additional questions, consult the
                distributor or manufacturer directly.
            </para>
            <para>The load carrying requirements of each vehicle should be determined before selecting the correct
                tire/wheel combination. Always remember that the weakest weight carrying component of the vehicle (tire,
                wheel, axle, bearings, etc.) determines the overall maximum and safe load carrying capacity for the
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never run the engine with one wheel off the ground, for example, when changing a tire. The
                        wheel(s) resting on the ground could cause the vehicle to move.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The tire and wheel must always be correctly matched. It is very important to determine the
                        size of each component before any assembly operations commence. Failure to adhere to these
                        instructions can result in an explosive separation and cause serious bodily injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Aftermarket aerosol tire sealants are extremely flammable. Always question the customer to
                        make sure these products have not been used.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Aftermarket wheel assemblies may not be compatible with the vehicle. Use of incompatible wheel
                        assemblies can result in equipment failure and possible injury. Use only approved wheel
                        assemblies.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Use only wheels and wheel nuts that have been designed for current model year International&#174;
                        trucks. Aftermarket wheels or wheel nuts may not fit or function correctly and can cause
                        personal injury or damage the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always wear safety goggles or a face shield when carrying out any work with tire and wheel
                        assemblies.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not clean aluminum wheels with steel wool, abrasive-type cleaners or strong detergents. Use
                        Custom Bright Metal Cleaner or equivalent meeting International&#174; specifications.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Reduce the air pressure as much as possible by pushing the valve core plunger in prior to
                        removing the valve core. Avoid working in a position in which the face or body is directly over
                        a tire in which there is pressure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>When carrying out any inspection or repair procedures on wheels and tires, follow the preceding safety
                precautions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Each individual axle, wheel and tire has its own maximum weight and inflation rating. Do not
                        overinflate or overload beyond the capacity of the lowest rated component of the system.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Rims and wheels are designed to sustain their rated load using the maximum tire size recommended for
                that rim width by the Tire and Rim Association.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>An inflated tire and wheel can be very dangerous if misused or worn out. Many accidents, some
                        fatal, have resulted from incorrect handling and operation of truck wheels and tires. It is of
                        the utmost importance that the precautions described on these pages be carefully followed by all
                        persons servicing truck wheels, to avoid personal injuries and costly damage.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The tire and wheel must always be correctly matched. It is very important to determine the
                        size of each component before any assembly operations commence. Failure to adhere to these
                        instructions can result in an explosive separation and cause serious bodily injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never mount a smaller diameter tire on a larger diameter wheel. When installing new tires,
                        always match the tire size to the wheel size. Incorrect matching can cause the tire bead to
                        break during mounting or inflation propelling both the tire and wheel into the air with enough
                        force to inflict property damage, serious injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>When installing new tires, use the same size, load range and construction type as originally installed
                on the vehicle. When installing new wheels, use original equipment manufacturer's wheels or equivalent
                available from the International dealer with equivalent capacity, width, offset and mounting
                configuration as those originally installed on the vehicle. Use of incorrect tires and wheels can
                adversely affect ride, handling, load carrying capacity, bearing life, tire clearance to body and
                chassis components, vehicle ground clearance, vehicle width and brake cooling.
            </para>
            <para>Prepare for any tire repair operation in a safe and efficient way. In servicing all tires, use caution
                not to drop them (or the wheels) on the feet, hands or body, or heavily on the floor. Truck tires are
                heavy and a wheel jack or equivalent should be used to maneuver tires.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0404003" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0028385.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Excessively corroded or cracked wheels can be dangerous. Deflate tires on corroded or cracked
                        wheels prior to removal of wheels from the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never position body in front of the wheel during deflation. Always keep eyes away from the
                        valve when deflating tires.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Deflating a tire correctly is very important for safety. First, reduce the pressure as much as
                possible by depressing the valve core plunger. Only then should the valve core be removed to completely
                deflate the tire before removal from the vehicle or disassembly. On duals, deflate both tires
                completely.
            </para>
            <para>Demounting tires from the wheels requires special care. Use only standard tire mounting tools and
                equipment. The use of makeshift tools to force tires on or off the wheels is dangerous and must be
                avoided.
            </para>
            <para>Always lubricate tire beads to make sure the tire beads are sealed on the rim. Use a rubber lubricant
                meeting specifications.
            </para>
            <para>Make sure all the air is out before removing the tires from the wheels. Use special care when using
                tire irons. Grip the tire irons firmly and keep them free of oil and grease. They can slip and fly with
                tremendous force.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When painting used wheels, do not use excessive amounts of paint. This can cause the wheel
                        nuts to loosen, which can lead to premature failure or loose wheels, resulting in serious,
                        perhaps fatal, injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When painting any wheel, always allow the paint to dry thoroughly. If the paint is not dry
                        when the wheels are mounted, torque values will not be maintained because of the paint being
                        forced out. Excess paint thickness will cause the wheels to loosen. Retighten the wheel nuts
                        after 80-160 km (50-100 miles) when newly painted wheels are installed on the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always wear safety goggles or a face shield when carrying out any work with tire and wheel
                        assemblies.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always wear safety goggles or a face shield when carrying out any buffing operation.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Tires and wheels often require a buffing operation before being mounted, once the regular service has
                been completed.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Avoid hammering with a steel hammer; you can damage the rim. Any hammering can dislodge
                        particles. Never hammer on an inflated assembly.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always inflate the tire in an OSHA-approved portable tire safety cage. This is an important
                        safeguard against incorrect assembly, inadvertently mismatched parts and other assembly errors.
                        Remember, an inflated tire contains potentially explosive energy and assemblies can be propelled
                        if there is a sudden release of air. In emergency situations, where a safety cage or a portable
                        safety device is not available, use the vehicle's spare wheel and tire assembly.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Stand clear when using a safety cage or an OSHA-approved restraining device. Always use a
                        clip-on air chuck with a remote valve and pressure gauge. Do not rest any part of the body
                        against the device during inflation. If the components are not seated correctly and an explosive
                        separation occurs, the air blast or movement of the restraining device can cause injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Place the wheel and tire assembly in the safety cage and inflate to a maximum of 10 pounds. Check to
                see that the beads are correctly seated. Continue to inflate to recommended pressure.
            </para>
            <para>Use only accurate, tested gauges to make sure of correct air pressure. Check all gauges regularly with
                a master gauge.
            </para>
            <para>Never attempt to short-cut the above procedures.</para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Correct precautions should always be taken when jacking a vehicle up to prevent personal
                        injury or damage to the vehicle:
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Always block one axle with wheel chocks to prevent unexpected movement.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Always use correct heavy-duty jack stands.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Manually cage parking brake chambers when working on the rear axle.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Apply the parking brake when working on the front axle.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not exceed maximum tire inflation pressures. This is determined by the size and ply rating
                        of the tire, but is not to exceed the maximum cold inflation pressure listed for the wheel even
                        if the tire is approved for a higher load or inflation. It is also important to maintain uniform
                        inflation so that weight is equally sustained.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not run the vehicle on one tire of a dual assembly. When there is loss of air in a dual
                        tire, the carrying capacity is reduced and the load must be sustained by the other tire. Inflate
                        both tires to balanced, recommended pressures before further operation.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Thumping or simply looking at the tire does not give an accurate pressure reading.
                        Periodically check your air pressure gauge for accuracy and use it to check tire pressure.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never run the engine with one wheel off the ground, for example, when changing a tire. The
                        wheel(s) resting on the ground could cause the vehicle to move.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Aftermarket aerosol tire sealants are extremely flammable. Always question the customer to
                        make sure these products have not been used.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Aftermarket wheel assemblies may not be compatible with the vehicle. The use of incompatible
                        wheel assemblies can result in equipment failure and possible injury. Use only approved wheel
                        assemblies.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Use only wheels and wheel nuts that have been designed for current model year International&#174;
                        vehicles. Aftermarket wheels or wheel nuts may not fit or function correctly and can cause
                        personal injury or damage the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>When carrying out any inspection or repair procedures on wheels and tires, follow the preceding safety
                precautions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17002_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17002_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
