<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Recommendation for Mounting and Demounting Tires
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="6">
        <title>Recommendation for Mounting and Demounting Tires</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The following pages show the recommendation for mounting and demounting tires, including rim mounted
                wheel sensors. These recommendations should provide the basic information on how to handle tires with
                rim mounted wheel sensors. In general there are 3 different situations:
            </para>
            <randlist type="dash">
                <item>
                    <para>(1) Demounting Tire (Service)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>(2) Manually Mounting Process (Service)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>(3) Mounting process using automated assembly machine</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(1) Demounting tire process (demount wheel SENSOR before removing the tire):</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Wheel sensor must be removed before tire is disassembled.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the wheel sensor is not removed before demounting the tire, the sensor will be destroyed as shown
                in the pictures below.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0717015" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700344.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="484px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The wheel sensor has to be removed before demounting the tire. The easiest way to remove the wheel
                sensor is to push the tires sidewall away from the rim using the assembly machines shovel, until the
                wheel sensor is easily accessible. Then the wheel sensor attaching screw can be removed along with the
                wheel sensor. The mounting stud is not removed.
            </para>
            <para>When the tire is removed, the wheel sensor can be mounted on the rim. A new attaching screw must be
                used!
            </para>
            <para>If replacing the tire pressure sensor, it will come with a label imprinted with a bar code and a
                serial number. Remove the label and retain it so the serial number can be manually entered into the
                control unit via the display unit installed on the vehicle (Follow prompts from setup menu in the second
                section of this manual ). If a bar code label is not included, record the serial number from the sensor.
            </para>
            <para>Mount the threaded bolt on the rim and tighten the mounting nut with a tightening torque of 10 Nm
                (7.35 lbf-ft). The threaded bolt is mounted on the rim with the help of a
                <emph type="bold">mounting nut which is to be torqued to 10 Nm</emph>.
            </para>
            <para>Mount the tire pressure sensor to the back of the threaded bolt. Torque the screw to 4 Nm (3 lbf-ft) .
                Please be advised that the tire pressure sensor is mounted to a threaded mounting bolt with a
                <emph type="bold">screw which is to be torqued to 4 Nm</emph>(Figure 39 and 40). If the screw is torqued
                to 10 Nm , the housing will break.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a new screw for attaching the wheel sensor to the mounting stud. The attaching screw can
                        only be used once. Never reuse an attaching screw .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(2) Standard Mounting Process (installed wheel SENSOR):</title>
            <figure id="f0717016" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700345.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 44.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Figure 44 shows the principle of mounting the tire under service conditions without using an assembly
                machine. In this case mounting should be started with wheel sensor position opposite to the mechanic.
                The pictures in Figure 45 show the 3 steps of mounting the tire.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0717017" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700346.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 45.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>(3) Mounting tire process using automated equipment (installed wheel SENSOR):</title>
            <figure id="f0717018" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700347.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 46.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Figure 46 shows the top view of a typical assembly machine arrangement used for mounting tires. It is
                very important to prevent the wheel sensor from being stressed during the mounting process. Therefore,
                positioning the wheel sensor and performing the assembly routine has to be done in a way that the tire
                bead does not stress the wheel sensor.
            </para>
            <para>In the configuration shown in Figure 46, the wheel sensor starting position is 10 o'clock. The
                assembly head is at the 3 o'clock position. The tire is applied to the rim by the mechanic in a way that
                the squeezing edge is 3" counter-clockwise away from the wheel sensor and the 1st tire bead is put into
                the drop center of the rim at the position where the mechanic is standing.
            </para>
            <para>The assembly head is pulled downwards so the 1st tire bead is also pulled into the drop center of the
                rim in the assembly head region. Additional assembly aids may have to be used to prevent the squeezing
                edge from moving counter clockwise. The assembly machines turntable is now moved in a clockwise
                direction until the 1st tire bead is slipped fully over the wheel run flange. The region where the tire
                bead finally slips over the wheel run flange should be in the wheel sensor position area. This insures
                that there will be no tension on the tire bead when the tire bead passes the wheel sensor.
            </para>
            <para>The 2nd tire bead should be mounted in the same as the 1st tire bead. With the wheel sensor starting
                position at 10 o'clock, mounting head at 3 o'clock - mechanic puts the 2nd tire bead into the drop
                center of the rim - then the assembly head is used to put the 2nd tire bead into the drop center at the
                assembly head region (additional assembly aids may have to be used to prevent the squeezing edge from
                moving counter clockwise) - the assembly machines turntable is now moved in a clockwise direction until
                the 2nd tire bead is slipped fully over the wheel run flange. For high volume fully automated in line
                production, the mechanic should be replaced by an automatic supply and positioning device.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0717019" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700348.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 47.</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>As shown in Figure 47, the wheel sensor will be damaged. Starting the mounting process while putting
                the tire bead into the drop center at the wheel sensor mounting position will destroy the wheel sensor
                because the tension on the tire bead increases when finally slipping the tire over the wheel run flange.
                The beads high tension will apply a high amount of force to the wheel sensor housing. The housing of the
                wheel sensor will crack and the tire bead may be damaged.
            </para>
            <figure id="f071701a" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700349.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 48. Possible Wheel Sensor Damage When Mounted as Shown in Figure 47</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_19.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
