<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Wheel Sensor Service procedure</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
        <title>Wheel Sensor Service procedure</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to neutral or park, set parking brake, and
                    block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If you notice either a label located in the wheel hand hole area or what appears to be a stud
                    mounted 180 degrees from the valve stem, you must follow the instructions on the attached bulletin
                    from the manufacturer when removing and installing the tire. Failure to follow these instructions
                    when removing or mounting a tire could cause the tire pressure monitor to break off inside the wheel
                    resulting in a loose sensor inside of the tire and wheel assembly. This can eventually lead to tire
                    damage or failure of the tire pressure sensor.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Mounting Locations</emph>: On Super Singles, the wheel sensor is mounted to a stud and nut
            (Figure 39 and 40). On regular tires, the sensor is mounted inside the rim on a special valve stem (Figures
            41 and 42). Follow the procedures below.
        </para>
        <figure id="f0717011" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700340.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 39. Super Single Wheel Sensor</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0717012" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700341.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 40. Super Single Wheel Sensor with Exploded View of Mounting Hardware</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0717013" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700342.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 41. Standard Rim Wheel Sensor Mounting Hardware</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f0717014" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/g1700343.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 42. Standard Rim Wheel Sensor Assembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">NOTICE:</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use with
            its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on representations
            made to the company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions accompanying the product,
            International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps resulting from such errors, or
            from any misuse of the product.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
