<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES - CARE AND MAINTENANCE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>CARE AND MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Wheel rims should be periodically inspected both on the vehicle and during tire changes for cracks,
                loose wheel studs, worn mounting holes or being bent.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Disc wheels</emph>
                have rims which are integral with the wheel itself; the important thing to note is that the wheel stud
                nuts must be kept tight. This means they should be inspected and tightened at regular intervals. When
                checking the mounting studs and nuts on dual disc wheels (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700116">Figure 16</hotlnk>), the outer nut should be backed off before attempting to
                tighten the inner nut. Try all cap nuts after the first trip or any wheel change. When properly
                installed, they should remain tight indefinitely.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1700116" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1700116" filename="../figg17/G1700116.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Dual Disc Wheel Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. INNER WHEEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. OUTER WHEEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INNER NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. OUTER NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. STUD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Left-hand thread nuts can be identified by the small groove machined around the flats, or the letter
                "L" stamped on the nut. Left-hand studs can be identified by the letter "L" stamped on the head. Use
                left-hand nuts on the left side of the truck.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Cast spoke wheels</emph>
                have the rim and tire assembly mounted to the spoke wheel by rim clamps; the rim clamp nuts should also
                be kept tight. Rim and tire to wheel alignment should be checked frequently to make sure the tire is
                running true.
            </para>
            <para>Whenever a tire is removed, clean off all grease and road dirt. Use a wire brush or steel wool to
                remove the rubber from the wheel/rim bead seat.
            </para>
            <para>Projections on the side wall of the gutter may cause uneven seating of the side ring and lead to
                chipping of the gutter. Remove these and other projections in the mounting area to assure the best
                possible fits.
            </para>
            <para>Nicks and gouges in the vicinity of the fixed flange may lead to rim fracture.</para>
            <para>Do not heat or weld wheels or rims in an attempt to straighten or repair severe road damage; replace
                component. The special alloy used in these components is heat-treated, and uncontrolled heating from
                welding torch affects the properties of the material.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid possible corrosive effects to aluminum wheels, use only a slight amount of water and neutral
                soap (similar to Ivory Snow, etc. - no detergents) when mounting tires. Do not use commercial rubber
                lubricants.
            </para>
            <para>Do not allow dirt to enter the mounting area during installation.</para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
