<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - Feature Functions - Tire Pressure Diagnostics
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Tire Pressure Diagnostics</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The system alerts the operator on the VID and sets a corresponding DTC if a fast leak, low pressure,
                extremely low pressure, or excess pressure condition exists.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Scroll to "TPMS Setup", "Pressure Setup" menu on the VID to verify the current
                    programmed pressure value.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>If the tire pressure becomes less than the pressure expected at that particular temperature, the TPMS
                controller will set a DTC and the VID will display a YELLOW or RED warning depending on the pressure
                value below the pressure needed for that particular temperature.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Low Pressure Diagnostic Mode</title>
            <para>The tire sensor goes into 'low pressure diagnostic mode' if the difference between the programmed
                "Pressure Setup" parameter, and the expected pressure for a particular tire temperature reaches a
                predetermined threshold.
            </para>
            <para>For example, if the tire temperature is at approximately 70F (20C), a YELLOW caution appears if the
                tire pressure falls more than approximately 10 PSI below the programmed "Pressure Setup" value in the
                VID. This means the tire pressure must drop to 91 PSI for 'low pressure diagnostic mode' to occur if the
                programmed value is set to the default value of 102 PSI.
            </para>
            <para>The following will occur while the tire sensor is in the 'low pressure diagnostic mode'.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">"CAUTION Low Tire Pressure Detected"</emph>
                        popup message is displayed in the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the corresponding tire will be displayed in YELLOW on the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the tire pressure monitoring controller will set a DTC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The low pressure DTC will remain active and the VID will display the appropriate tire in YELLOW until
                adequate pressure has been restored to the tire.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT!</emph>
                As tire temperatures increase, the expected tire pressure also increases. Both the tire temperature and
                the programmed "Pressure Setup" value change the point at which the warnings will be displayed. The Tire
                Pressure Warnings diagram illustrates this concept. Refer to the
                <emph type="italic">Tire Pressure Warnings</emph>
                section for more information.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Extremely Low Pressure Diagnostic Mode</title>
            <para>The tire sensor goes into 'extremely low pressure diagnostic mode' if the difference between the
                programmed "Pressure Setup" parameter, and the expected pressure for a particular tire temperature
                reaches a predetermined threshold.
            </para>
            <para>For example, if the tire temperature is at approximately 70F (20C), a RED warning appears if the tire
                pressure falls more than approximately 17 PSI below the programmed "Pressure Setup" value in the VID.
                This means the tire pressure must drop to 84 PSI for 'extremely low pressure diagnostic mode' to occur
                if the programmed value is set to the default value of 102 PSI.
            </para>
            <para>The following will occur while the tire sensor is in the 'extremely low pressure' diagnostic mode:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">"Warning Extremely Low Tire Pressure Detected"</emph>
                        popup message is displayed in the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the corresponding tire will be displayed in RED on the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the tire pressure monitoring controller will set a DTC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The extremely low pressure DTC will remain active and the VID will display the appropriate tire in RED
                until adequate pressure has been restored to the tire.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT!</emph>As tire temperatures increase, the expected tire pressure also
                increases. Both the tire temperature and the programmed "Pressure Setup" value change the point at which
                the warnings will be displayed. The Tire Pressure Warnings diagram illustrates this concept. Refer to
                the Tire Pressure Warnings section for more information.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>High Pressure Diagnostic Mode</title>
            <para>The tire sensor goes into 'high pressure diagnostic mode' if the tire pressure reaches 196 PSI or
                higher.
            </para>
            <para>The following will occur while the tire sensor is in the 'high pressure diagnostic mode':</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">"Caution High Tire Pressure Detected"</emph>
                        popup message is displayed in the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the corresponding tire will be displayed in YELLOW on the VID.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the tire pressure monitoring controller will set a DTC.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The high pressure DTC will remain active and the VID will display the appropriate tire in RED until
                the proper pressure (default = 102 PSI) has been restored to the tire.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
