<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES - CARE AND MAINTENANCE -
        INSTALLATION, TIGHTENING AND ALIGNMENT (LATERAL RUN-OUT)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1700102" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="6">
        <title>INSTALLATION, TIGHTENING AND ALIGNMENT (LATERAL RUN-OUT)</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disc Wheels or Cast Spoke Wheels</title>
            <para>When installing disc wheels or demountable rims with cast spoke wheels, be certain that the threads on
                studs and nuts are clean to permit correct torquing of nuts. The mounting surfaces of rims, wheels,
                spacer rings and clamps should be free of dirt, rust or damage. Use a wire brush to clean mounting
                contact surfaces. Do not use lubricant on threads.
            </para>
            <para>After rim or wheel has been properly torqued, the assembly should be checked for tire lateral run-out.
                This can be accomplished by attaching a tire run-out dial indicator to a steady, firm surface and placed
                to just barely touch the outside surface of tire curb rib (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700121">Figure 21</hotlnk>). If this area is scuffed, cut or gouged, you will get an
                improper reading on the dial indicator. The lateral run-out on front steering tires should not exceed
                0.125 inch. For rear axles with dual wheels, the lateral run-out should not exceed 0.187 inch. If the
                lateral run-out exceeds these measurements, check for bent or cocked rims, improperly adjusted wheel
                bearings, and/or improper tire bead seating. Make corrections as needed. Loosen all lug nuts and rim
                clamps and re-torque to specifications. Then re-check lateral run-out.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1700121" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1700121" filename="../figg17/G1700121.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 21. Checking Total Lateral Run-out</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cast Spoke Wheels</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide inner rear or front tire and rim assembly over the cast spoke wheel and push it
                    back into position against tapered mounting surface. Be sure valve stem faces out and is centered
                    between two spokes (and clears disc brake calipers if applicable).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide spacer ring over wheel. Check spacer ring for concentricity by rotating spacer
                    ring around cast spoke wheel (rear wheel only).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the outside rear tire and rim assembly on the wheel, making sure the valve stem
                    faces inboard and is located in the same relative position as the inner valve stem (rear wheel
                    only).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble all rim clamps and nuts. Turn nuts on studs until each nut is flush with end of
                    stud.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn top nut "1" (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700122">Figure 22</hotlnk>) until it is snug.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1700122" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1700122" filename="../figg17/G1700122.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Cast Spoke Wheel Tightening Sequence</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate wheel and rim until nut "2" (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700122">Figure 22</hotlnk>) is at top position and snug nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate wheel and rim until nut "3" (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700122">Figure 22</hotlnk>) is at top position and snug nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate wheel and rim until nuts "4," "5" and "6" are respectively at op and snug these
                    nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Since the entire weight of tire and rim assembly is on top spoke, the foregoing procedure (crisscross
                sequence) will assure even application of force at all points on the rim, keeping the rim in proper
                alignment.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the sequence of tightening the nuts to torque value listed in the
                    <hotlnk document="s17001y_27.xml" xrefid="x1700101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <para>After wheel assembly is properly torqued, check for rim alignment as mentioned above.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After operating the vehicle approximately 50 miles (80 km), check the stud nuts for
                    tightness in same sequence shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700122">Figure 22</hotlnk>
                    . Once each week, inspect and re-torque wheel stud nuts (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700123">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1700123" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1700123" filename="../figg17/G1700123.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Using Torque Wrench to Torque Wheel Nuts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disc Wheels with (Ball Seat) Nuts</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide inner/rear or front tire and wheel in position over studs and push back as far as
                    possible. Use care to avoid damage to threads on studs and inspect the valve stem to caliper for
                    clearance if applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the wheel nut on front wheels and inner wheel nut on rear dual wheels. Run nuts
                    on studs until the nuts start to contact the wheel. Rotate wheel a half turn to allow parts to seat
                    naturally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Draw up stud nuts alternately following the sequence (crisscross pattern) illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700124">Figure 24</hotlnk>. Do not fully tighten the nuts at this time. This
                    procedure will allow a uniform seating of nuts and insure the even face-to-face contact of wheel and
                    hub.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1700124" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1700124" filename="../figg17/G1700124.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 24. Disc Wheel Tightening Sequence</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue tightening the nuts to the torque value in the
                    <hotlnk document="s17001y_27.xml" xrefid="x1700101">TORQUE CHART,</hotlnk>
                    using the same alternating method shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700124">Figure 24</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the outer rear wheel and nuts. Repeat the preceding method. Be sure that both
                    inner and outer tire valve stems are accessible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After operating the vehicle approximately 50 miles (80 km), check the stud nuts for
                    tightness. Some natural seating of parts may be encountered and the torque on nuts will drop.
                    Retighten all nuts to specified torque value.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>To check and tighten the inner wheel to proper torque, first loosen the outer wheel nuts several turns
                and tighten the inner nuts, then retighten the outer nuts (rear wheel only).
            </para>
            <para>To prevent losing the seating of the outer wheel when checking the inner wheel torque, it is suggested
                that alternate outer nuts be loosened and tighten the inner nuts, then retighten the outer nuts. Then
                loosen the remaining outer nuts, tighten inner nuts and then retighten the outer nuts.
            </para>
            <para>Once each week inspect and re-torque wheel stud nuts, if necessary (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700123">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disc Wheels with Flange Nuts</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700125">Figure 25</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700126">Figure 26</hotlnk>
                for cross section view of flange nut installation.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1700125" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1700125" filename="../figg17/G1700125.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 25. Flange Nut System, Front Wheel Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FLANGE NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WHEEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. WHEEL STUD (22mm)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WHEEL HUB</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1700126" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1700126" filename="../figg17/G1700126.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="352px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 26. Flange Nut System, Rear Wheel Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. FLANGE NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. WHEELS</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BRAKE DRUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. WHEEL STUD (22mm)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. WHEEL HUB</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide inner rear or front tire and wheel in position over studs and push back as far as
                    possible. Use care so that the threads on studs are not damaged. Inspect the valve stem to brake
                    caliper for clearance, if applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position outer rear tire and wheel in place over the studs and push back as far as
                    possible. Again use care so that the threads on studs are not damaged.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the nuts on the studs until nuts contact the wheel or wheels. Rotate wheel assembly
                    a half turn to permit parts to seat naturally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Draw up nuts alternately following the (crisscross pattern) sequence illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700124">Figure 24</hotlnk>
                    . Do not fully tighten nuts at this time. This procedure will allow uniform seating of nuts and
                    assure even face-to-face contact of wheel and hub.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue tightening the nuts to values in the
                    <hotlnk document="s17001y_27.xml" xrefid="x1700101">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>using the same alternating
                    method shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1700124">Figure 24</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Once each week inspect and re-torque wheel stud nuts, if necessary (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1700123">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
