<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES - WHEEL AND TIRE BALANCING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>WHEEL AND TIRE BALANCING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Front wheel and tire assemblies must be balanced to prevent wheel vibration and bounce. While the
                correct front wheel alignment is necessary for easy steering and maximum tire life, the cause of
                unstable steering can frequently be traced to improper balance of front wheels. When this condition
                exists, the wheel and tire assembly should be properly balanced.
            </para>
            <para>A vulcanized or retreaded tire, or a tire that has a boot in it, MUST NOT be used as a front steering
                tire.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>STATIC BALANCING</title>
            <para>A wheel out of balance statically has a tendency to bounce up and down, resulting in rapid tire wear
                in round or oblong spots.
            </para>
            <para>Static balancing is performed while wheel is stationary by attaching weights to rim flange to offset
                an opposite heavy point.
            </para>
            <para>Static balancing may be sufficient in some instances where vehicle is operated only at slow speeds,
                however, dynamic balancing (in motion) balances the wheel and tire assembly statically as well as
                dynamically, thereby eliminating vibrations and wheel bounce at both low and high speeds.
            </para>
            <para>A wheel may be perfectly balanced statically (not in motion) but may still vibrate and bounce at high
                speed rotation because of its being out of balance dynamically.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
