<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>Tire Pressure Monitoring System (Feature Code 16VCM) - TIRE PRESSURE MONITORING SYSTEM Setup</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="9">
        <title>TIRE PRESSURE MONITORING SYSTEM Setup</title>
        <para>INTERNATIONAL VEHICLE INFORMATION DISPLAY (VID)</para>
        <para>THE INFORMATION ON YOUR VEHICLE DISPLAY SCREEN MAY LOOK DIFFERENT THAN THE FOLLOWING EXAMPLES, DEPENDING
            ON THE SYSTEM YOUR VEHICLE IS EQUIPPED WITH.
        </para>
        <figure id="fVID40" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700324.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 7.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>The VID is a user interface that provides visual information helpful to the driver, video views to aid in
            the safe operation of the vehicle, and diagnostic messages. In this manual we will only address the VID
            interaction with the TPMS.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not use the VID while driving. Driving while distracted may result in an accident causing
                    property damage, personal injury, or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Be sure to read and understand this manual completely before attempting to operate the VID.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>
            <title>Power-Up/Down Conditions</title>
        </para>
        <para>This condition is triggered when the VID receives power from the ignition or ACC key positions. While
            powering up, a logo screen will be displayed. The VID will power-up and be fully operational within
            approximately 10 seconds. During power-down, the VID will save the current data and settings.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Warnings</title>
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Startup Warning Messages</emph>
        </para>
        <para>When the power-up sequence is completed, the system may display warning messages indicating that
            maintenance is required. The operator is required to acknowledge these conditions (by pressing the SEL
            button) before the VID will continue to the Main Menu.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Pop-Up Warning Messages</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Pop-up warnings may occur at any time during normal operation of the VID. These messages are the result of
            the VID receiving a new diagnostic message from the various electronic modules on the vehicle. It is
            important to pay particular attention to these messages as some may indicate a severe problem while others
            may indicate that some form of maintenance needs to be performed in the near future. These warning messages
            must be acknowledged by the operator in the same manner as startup warnings (there is a 2 second time out
            period during which acknowledgement cannot be performed to ensure the message is read).
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Power LED</title>
        </para>
        <para>The Power LED is located under the BACK button in the lower right-hand corner of the VID and is
            illuminated constantly while power is supplied to the VID.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Standby LED</title>
        </para>
        <para>The standby LED is an amber light located under the BACK button in the lower right-hand corner of the VID.
            The VID will turn off backlighting after no button presses and no unacknowledged alerts are present for
            approximately 20 minutes. When this occurs, the standby LED will flash.
        </para>
        <para>Pressing any key will revive the unit from standby mode, returning it to the previous screen selected.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>LCD Screen</title>
        </para>
        <para>The LCD Screen is enabled or disabled based on operating conditions and power-up/down conditions. The
            backlighting is controlled by a photocell located under button number 3, at the lower left-hand corner of
            the VID. When enabled, the photocell measures the amount of light and adjusts the backlighting as needed.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>Keypad Functionality</title>
        </para>
        <para>Located on the face of the VID are eight keypad buttons that are used to operate and toggle through the
            many screens of information available on the VID. The backlighting for the keypad is provided and controlled
            by the dash dimmer switch.
        </para>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">HOME Button</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Pressing the HOME button takes the operator to the MAIN MENU screen immediately.</para>
        <figure id="f41359" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700325.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 8.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">SELECT Button</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Pressing the SELECT button allows the operator to select an option that is highlighted. In addition, it
            will allow the operator to acknowledge any diagnostic warnings.
        </para>
        <figure id="f41363" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700326.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 9.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">UP and DOWN Button</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Pressing the UP or DOWN button allows the operator to scroll through the items listed on the screen to
            select individual items.
        </para>
        <figure id="f41364" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700327.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 10.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>When entering numerical data is required, the UP and DOWN buttons will increment and decrement the value
            displayed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f41365" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700328.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 11.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">BACK Button</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Pressing the BACK button will immediately take the operator to the previous screen, data field, or up one
            level in the menu hierarchy.
        </para>
        <figure id="f41366" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700329.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 12.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Hot Buttons: 1, 2 and 3</emph>
        </para>
        <para>The operator has the ability to program each of these Hot Buttons by moving the cursor to the desired menu
            item and holding the selected Hot Button down for three seconds. Upon updating the Hot Button setting, a
            screen will be provided to indicate to the user his command was fulfilled. Once programmed, the Hot Button
            will allow direct selection of the programmed screen from any other screen.
        </para>
        <para>Hot Buttons will not permit the operator to switch to a screen that is restricted while moving. Likewise,
            Hot Buttons will not permit the operator to circumvent password entry to secured screens.
        </para>
        <para>These are also used for entering passwords.</para>
        <figure id="f41360" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700330.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 13.</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f41361" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700331.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 14.</caption>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f41362" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg17/G1700332.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="72px"
                     scalefitheight="72px"/>
            <caption>Figure 15.</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <emph type="bold">Password Security</emph>
        </para>
        <para>Certain functions/screens may be set up to require a password in order to be accessed. When this is
            required, the VID will display the Enter Password screen.
        </para>
        <para>The operator will be required to enter the correct password using the 1, 2, 3 keys, followed by the SEL
            key.
            <emph type="bold">NOTE: The BACK key can be used as a delete/backspace in the event an incorrect digit is
                entered.
            </emph>
        </para>
        <para>Once password access is granted for a screen, access will bypass password requests on other screens. This
            access will persist until the ignition is cycled to the OFF position.
        </para>
        <para>In the event the wrong password is entered, the Incorrect Password Entered screen will be displayed.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>A maximum of three failed attempts will be allowed. When this limit is reached, a special screen
                    will be displayed indicating no more attempts allowed.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
