<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WHEELS, RIMS AND TIRES - OSHA STANDARDS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OSHA STANDARDS</title>
        <para>The Occupational Safety and Health Administration (OSHA) has established rules and regulations pertaining
            to servicing Multi-Piece Rim Wheels.
        </para>
        <para>The text herein refers to selected excerpts from the OSHA standard. For complete details, refer to the
            complete OSHA standard 1910.177 to ensure compliance.
        </para>
        <para>Basically, the regulations state that it is up to the employer to provide employee training to instruct
            all employees who service multi-piece rims in the safety hazards involved and the safety procedures to be
            followed.
        </para>
        <para>The employer shall see that no employee services multi-piece or single piece rim wheels unless trained,
            and demonstrates and maintains the ability to service multi-piece rim wheels safely.
        </para>
        <para>This shall include the following tasks:</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Demounting of tires, which includes deflation.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Inspection of components.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Mounting of tires, which includes inflator with restraining device.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Use of restraining device.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Handling of wheels.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Inflation of tires when a wheel is mounted on the vehicle.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>An understanding of the necessity of standing outside the trajectory both during the inflation of
                    the tire and during inspection of the rim wheel following inflation.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Installation and removal of wheels.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>OSHA also states the type of tire servicing equipment to be used.</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>Restraining device (inflation cage).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clip-on-chuck with enough hose to permit employees to stand clear of potential trajectory of wheel
                    components. An in-line valve with gauge or pressure regulator preset to a desired value must also be
                    provided.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Current charts must be posted in service area.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Current rim manual containing instructions for types of rims being serviced shall be available in
                    service area.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The employer must assure that only tools recommended in the rim manual are used to service
                    multi-piece rim wheels.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s17001y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
