<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 00-08-04 - Heavy Duty Command Center Instrument Cluster Diagnostics</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi000804" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>00-08-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2000</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Heavy Duty Command Center Instrument Cluster Diagnostics</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/01/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/01/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This letter provides information for the heavy duty instrument cluster operation and diagnostics
                    for 5000, 5000i, 9000 and 9000i Models built between January 1, 1994 and January 1, 2000 excluding
                    9600, 9700 and 9800 Models.
                </para>
                <para>The heavy duty command center cluster consists of a speedometer/tachometer module and 2 six packs
                    of gauges. The cluster may have either a mechanical odometer or a multi-functional digital VF
                    odometer (VFO).
                </para>
                <para>The information contained in this letter will supplement and clarify the information available in
                    Service Sections CTS-5257, CTS-5180 and CTS-5180S found in Group 08 of the CTS-5000 Master Service
                    Manual.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS</title>
                <para>The following is a description of the tools available for troubleshooting and diagnosing the heavy
                    duty command center instrument cluster.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">MPSI Pro-Link with IPC Cartridge-</emph>
                    This tool can be used to set the internal program and exercise the data link driven gauges in the
                    cluster. Note that this tool will exercise the gauges only if they are programmed to read from the
                    data link.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">MPSI Pro-Link with General Purpose Heavy Duty Cartridge-</emph>
                    This tool can be used to read and display the information on the data link and verify that the
                    cluster is displaying the data it is receiving.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EZ-Tech with IPC Software (New)-</emph>This software may be used to either
                    exercise the data link driven gauges or program the instrument cluster. It is more user friendly
                    than the Pro-Link tool. A training program will be provided for this tool in the near future.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EZ-Tech with 32-bit Master Diagnostics (New)-</emph>This may be used to monitor
                    the data link. For cluster specific data link monitoring go to Sessions>>Open>>double click on
                    Instrumentpanelcluster.ssn.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Flow Diagram (New)-</emph>
                    The diagram will guide the troubleshooting effort and indicate when a diagnostic tool should be used
                    and what test to perform. The flow diagram includes pin-outs, gauge pins, voltage levels and circuit
                    numbers (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008041">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008042">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Diagnostics for Frequently Asked Questions/Issues About Instrument Clusters</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The cluster appears to have locked up.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    Use one of the diagnostic tools listed in this letter to check the data link to insure that data is
                    available. A data driven gauge will lock-up (cease to function) if the data is not available.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The cluster appears to go through diagnostic sweeps.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    Check for poor or intermittent power and ground feeds within the vehicle. The cluster will reset
                    even if power or ground is removed for only a fraction of a second.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    Mechanical odometer is not changing or incrementing.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis 1:</emph>
                    If the odometer is clicking but not changing or incrementing, either the odometer is defective or
                    the odometer is binding in the holding bracket.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis 2:</emph>
                    If the odometer is not clicking, the circuit board may be defective or the cluster is not receiving
                    vehicle speed data on the data link.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The new service cluster installed doesn't work.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    The installed cluster must be programmed using the Pro-Link with IPC cartridge or the EZ-Tech tool.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>All cluster DIP switches must be set to "0" for the EZ-Tech program to be active.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    What program should be used for the cluster.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    The vehicle line set ticket will indicate the required program.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Intermittent Problems</title>
                <para>Intermittent problems are the most difficult to diagnose but are usually caused by one of the
                    following:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Loose connections caused by corroded, spread or improperly seated terminals.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Intermittent data link information.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Bad, untwisted data link wires.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>An electrically noisy alternator causing communication problems on the data link.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Miscellaneous Issues</title>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The voltmeter in service clusters with date codes later than 3897 may not function
                            properly. To remedy this, use a Pro-link or EZ-Tech tool and change the voltmeter source
                            from data link driven to sensor driven.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>When changing the VF odometer mode, the vehicle must be driven at least 1 full mile (1.6
                            kilometers) to retain the mode change.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The VF odometer will not retain tenths of a mile or tenths of a kilometer. It only retains
                            whole numbers.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The VF odometer will sporadically increment in 2 tenths of a kilometer if the cluster is
                            not programmed to metrics. The odometer is still accurate regardless of the mode to which it
                            is set.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <figure id="f0008041" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0008041.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Troubleshooting Flow Chart</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0008042" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0008042.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Troubleshooting Flow Chart (Cont.)</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
