<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 00-08-07 - Auto Neutral Circuit Revision for 2000 and 4000 Models Built Between November 1, 1997 and
        April 3, 2000 with Allison WTEC III Transmissions, International Code 813AAS
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi000807" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>00-08-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 2000</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Auto Neutral Circuit Revision for 2000 and 4000 Models Built Between November 1, 1997 and April 3,
                2000 with Allison WTEC III Transmissions, International Code 813AAS
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/01/1997</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/03/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/01/1997</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/03/2000</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>813AAS</ucode>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Allison</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>2000 and 4000 Models Built Between November 1, 1997 and April 3, 2000 with Allison WTEC III
                    Transmissions, International Code 813AAS, have a circuit configuration that may not ramp-up engine
                    RPM's for PTO operation when the Auto-Neutral feature is turned on and the parking brake switch is
                    on.
                </para>
                <para>To assure Auto-Neutral functionality, a circuit modification was implemented in production on
                    April 3, 2000. Vehicles produced prior to this date can be modified following the Service Procedure
                    provided.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to circuit diagram,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0008071">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                , for existing circuit configuration and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f0008072">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                for the modification to current production.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the battery cable from the negative terminal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the neutral indicator relay (962)
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008071">(Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008072">Figure 2)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove jumper wire 146F located between relay terminals 85 and 30.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move circuit 114NO to terminal 30 on neutral indicator relay (962).Splice into circuit
                    114NO at terminal 30 on neutral indicator relay with 18 gauge wire
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008071">(Figure 1)</hotlnk>
                    and make a connection to connector 386, terminal B
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008072">(Figure 2)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a 16 gauge jumper wire between terminals 87 and 85 on the neutral indicator
                    relay
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008072">(Figure 2)</hotlnk>. Insure that circuit 146E is still connected to
                    terminal 85 or 87 of the neutral indicator relay.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a 14 gauge jumper wire from terminal 87A on the neutral indicator relay to
                    terminal 87 on the neutral relay
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008072">(Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008073">Figure 3)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the negative battery cable to the battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the circuit modifications.</para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Place the vehicle in a safe surrounding, away from other parked vehicles, buildings and
                        people. Start the vehicle, place the gear selector in drive and place the auto-neutral switch to
                        the on position. Verify that the transmission shifts into neutral and proper PTO operation is
                        available when the parking brake is set.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Use the throttle pedal to increase the engine speed from idle to approximately 1200 RPM.
                        Release the parking brake and verify that the transmission does not shift into gear. Bring the
                        engine RPM back to idle, move the gear selector from drive into neutral, then back into drive
                        and verify that the transmission now shifts into gear.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the gear selector still in drive, turn the engine off. Verify that the engine cannot be
                        re-started until the gear selector is moved back into the neutral position.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Troubleshooting</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Auto-Neutral Indicator Light</title>
                <para>The auto-neutral indicator light will be ON for the following conditions:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The gear selector is in the neutral position.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>During Auto-Neutral operation with the gear selector in drive and the transmission is in
                            neutral.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Engine Stalls during Auto-Neutral Operation</title>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the engine stalls during Auto-Neutral operation, the gear selector must be moved to the
                            neutral position to re-start the engine.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Auto-Neutral Function</title>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Set parking brake: ties circuits 161C and 117 through park brake connector 466 and
                            transmission spare I/O terminals B and C.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Auto-Neutral switch ON: grounds circuit 153 through park brake connector 466 and
                            transmission spare I/O terminal E.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission in neutral: circuit 114 on connector 466 and transmission spare I/O terminal
                            F will go to ground by command of the transmission ECU.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the engine stalls this input will open releasing the neutral indicator relay.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>PTO operation: With circuit 114 grounded, the neutral indicator relay will be actuated,
                            applying 12 volts to the DDC circuit on the engine ECM and the neutral indicator light will
                            come ON. This will allow normal PTO operation.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Transmission Will Not Shift into Neutral while the Engine is Running</title>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>With the Auto-Neutral switch in the on position and the park brake on, check continuity
                            between terminals B and C on the transmission spare I/O connector 466. If there is no
                            continuity between the terminals check for correct park brake operation and the connecting
                            circuits.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify that terminal E on transmission spare I/O connector 466 is grounded. If the
                            terminal is not grounded, check for proper operation of the Auto-Neutral ON/OFF switch and
                            ground circuits.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify that terminal F on transmission spare I/O connector 466 is grounded. If the
                            terminal is not grounded, check for correct grounding of the Allison transmission ECU or ECU
                            malfunction.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Engine Will Not Crank</title>
                <para>The transmission gear selector must be in the neutral position.</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check for 12 volts at the engine (ECM) connector 379 (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0008074">Figure 4</hotlnk>), between terminal 26 (DDS) to ground and
                            terminal 46 (ECI) to ground.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>With the gear selector in the neutral position and the key in the run position, check
                            circuit 123 on the Allison "V" connector for 12 volts. If the voltage is 0.0 check the
                            transmission ECU for correct power and ground feeds.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check fuse F17, circuit 97P from fuse F17 to the neutral relay and operation of neutral
                            relay (615).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For the engine to crank, 12 volts must be present at the engine ECU DDS input on connector
                            379.
                        </para>
                        <para>Circuit 123 on Allison ECU "V" connector 632 will only have 12 volts present whenever the
                            transmission gear selector is in the neutral position. This will actuate the neutral relay,
                            applying 12 volts to circuit 97AV through circuit 97A to the engine ECU DDS input and allow
                            the engine to crank.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0008071" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0008071.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Neutral Indicator Relay Circuit Before Modification</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0008072" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0008072.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Neutral Indicator Relay Circuit After Modification</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0008073" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0008073.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. Reference Circuit for Neutral Relay</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0008074" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0008074.cgm" type="cgm" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Reference circuit for ECM Connector 379</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
