<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 00-08-05 - Medium Duty Instrument Cluster Diagnostics</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi000805" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>00-08-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2000</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Medium Duty Instrument Cluster Diagnostics</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This letter provides information for the medium duty instrument cluster operation and diagnostics
                    for 2000, 3000, 4000 and 8000 Models built from January 1, 1994 to the present time.
                </para>
                <para>There are two types of medium duty instrument clusters in use:
                    <emph type="bold">Early Design Medium Duty (MD)-</emph>This design has two sets of 8 dip switches on
                    the rear of the cluster, a mechanical oil pressure gauge, requires programming for proper function
                    and can be used with mechanical or electronic engines.
                    <emph type="bold">Medium Duty Data Link (MDDL)-</emph>This design uses two jumpers on the rear of
                    the cluster, does not require programming and can only be used with electronic engines.
                </para>
                <para>The information contained in this letter will supplement and clarify the information available in
                    Service Sections CTS-5257 and CTS-5228 found in Group 08 of the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>DIAGNOSTIC TOOLS</title>
                <para>The following is a description of the tools available for troubleshooting and diagnosing the
                    medium duty instrument cluster.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Pro-Link with IPC Cartridge-</emph>
                    This tool can be used to set the internal program and exercise the data link driven gauges in the
                    MDDL cluster. Note that this tool will exercise some of the gauges in the MD cluster only if they
                    are programmed to read from the data link.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The IPC cartridge will not work with a vehicle equipped with an International NGD 3-Box
                            engine controller.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Pro-Link with General Purpose Heavy Duty Cartridge-</emph>
                    This tool can be used to read and display the information on the data link and verify that the
                    cluster is displaying the data it is receiving.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EZ-Tech with IPC Software (New)-</emph>This software may be used to either
                    exercise the data link driven gauges or program the instrument cluster. It is more user friendly
                    than the Pro-Link tool. A training program will be provided for this tool in the near future.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EZ-Tech with 32-bit Master Diagnostics (New)-</emph>This may be used to monitor
                    the data link. For cluster specific data link monitoring go to Sessions>>Open>>double click on
                    Instrumentpanelcluster.ssn.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Flow Diagram (New)-</emph>
                    The diagram (attached) will guide the troubleshooting effort and indicate when a diagnostic tool
                    should be used and what test to perform. The flow diagram includes pin-outs, gauge pins, voltage
                    levels and circuit numbers
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008051">(Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0008052">Figure 2)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Diagnostics for Frequently Asked Questions/Issues About Instrument Clusters</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The cluster appears to have locked up.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    Use one of the diagnostic tools listed in this letter to check the data link to insure that data is
                    available. A data driven gauge will lock-up (cease to function) if the data is not available.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The cluster appears to go through diagnostic sweeps.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    Check for poor or intermittent power and ground feeds within the vehicle. The cluster will reset
                    even if power or ground is removed for only a fraction of a second.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    Mechanical odometer is not changing or incrementing.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis 1:</emph>
                    If the odometer is clicking but not incrementing, either the odometer is defective or the odometer
                    is binding in the holding bracket.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis 2:</emph>
                    If the odometer is not clicking, the circuit board may be defective or the cluster is not receiving
                    vehicle speed data on the data link.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    The new service cluster installed doesn't work properly.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis1:</emph>If an MDDL cluster is installed in a vehicle that is not
                    equipped with an electronic engine it will not function. An MD cluster must be installed.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis 2:</emph>If an MD cluster was installed, it must be programmed to
                    function. Use the EZ-Tech tool with IPC software to facilitate programming.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>All cluster DIP switches must be set to "0" for the EZ-Tech program to be active.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>
                    What program should be used for the cluster?
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>
                    The vehicle line set ticket will indicate the required program.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Issue:</emph>What program should be used to program a vehicle with an
                    International NGD 3-Box electronic engine controller?
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Diagnosis:</emph>The speedometer program must be set to
                    <emph type="bold">0101111100</emph>. The tachometer set to
                    <emph type="bold">011</emph>. If the vehicle is equipped with a 2-speed axle,with an axle ratio of
                    1.39, set the axle ratio switch to the
                    <emph type="bold">1</emph>position. If the odometer is to increment in kilometers, place the
                    kilometer/miles switch to the
                    <emph type="bold">1</emph>position.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Intermittent Problems</title>
                <para>Intermittent problems are the most difficult to diagnose but are usually caused by one of the
                    following:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Loose connections caused by corroded, spread or improperly seated terminals.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Intermittent data link information.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Bad, untwisted data link wires.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>An electrically noisy alternator causing communication problems on the data link.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <figure id="f0008051" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0008051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Troubleshooting Flow Chart</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0008052" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0008052.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Troubleshooting Flow Chart</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
