<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-03-01 - Ride Quality Improvement for 3400, 4700 and 4700LP/LPX Models with 8000 Lb. Parabolic Spring
        Front Suspension, Codes 003AAN, 003ADA and 003AEM and Rear Air Suspensions
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi010301" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>01-03-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Ride Quality Improvement for 3400, 4700 and 4700LP/LPX Models with 8000 Lb. Parabolic Spring Front
                Suspension, Codes 003AAN, 003ADA and 003AEM and Rear Air Suspensions
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>03AAN</ucode>
                <ucode>03ADA</ucode>
                <ucode>03AEM</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Improved ride quality can be achieved on 3400, 4700 and 4700LP/LPX Models with 8000 Lb. parabolic
                    spring front suspensions and rear air suspensions having a 9.5 inch ride height as noted on the
                    lineset (12.5 inch air spring height ).
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Many chassis are lightly loaded and tire pressure, particularly drive tire pressure, can
                            be reduced considerably from the maximum cold inflation pressure, indicated on the tire side
                            wall, to match actual tire loading. This will improve ride quality significantly. Refer to
                            the Tire Load/ Inflation Charts in Service Manual S17001Y, found in Group 17 in the Master
                            Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Beginning in July, 1999, 19.5 inch tires and rims are matched mounted. The tire high spot
                            is assembled to match the rim/ wheel low spot yielding a more uniform round assembly. Tire
                            and wheel assembly radial runout exceeding .045 inch total runout, particularly on steer
                            axles, can cause undesirable chassis vibration at certain speeds in the normal driving
                            range. Tire and wheel assembly runout should be verified when low frequency ride vibration
                            is experienced at road speeds near 60 MPH on a smooth black top road surface.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Beginning April, 2001, chassis with air brakes are equipped with dual step piloted brake
                            drums that assure drum/wheel assembly concentricity for improved ride and brake feel.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Front steer axle shocks, calibrated and optimized for parabolic springs, softer bushings
                            for air suspension torque rods, and a lower spring rate air spring rated at 15,500 pounds
                            for rear axle suspensions (excluding 4700LPX) are available in Service Parts and will
                            improve ride quality.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0103011">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="colspec0" colwidth="1.35in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="3.92in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.29in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>2504419C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Shock Absorber, for 8000 Lb. Parabolic Spring Front Suspension</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                                <para>2504420C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Torque Rod, for Rear Air Suspension</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                                <para>GY1R11170</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Suspension Air Spring, for 9.5 Inch Ride Height, 12.5 Inch Air Spring Height
                                    (excluding LPX)
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>2</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Weigh the vehicle with a typical load. Record the weight at each axle. Refer to the
                    Service Load and Inflation Charts in Service Section S17001Y in Group 17 of the Master Service
                    Manual and match the cold inflation pressure to the maximum loads actually being carried. This will
                    optimize the tire, relative to ride, and soften ride harshness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If vehicle vibration is being experienced at a certain road speed, and the vibration
                    diminishes or disappears above or below that road speed, the tire and wheel assembly runout,
                    exceeding .045 inch total runout, is the likely cause particularly on the steer axle.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support a vehicle while chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support the
                            vehicle with floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Park the vehicle on a flat level surface, chock the wheels, and with a suitable jack and
                            floor stands raise the tire and wheel assemblies so that the tire is not in contact with the
                            ground. Measure for runout exceeding .045 inch total runout. To decrease the runout, mark
                            the tire relative to wheel rim position, disassemble the tire and wheel assembly, rotate the
                            tire 180&#176; relative to the wheel and re-assemble.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>On steel wheels, the rim low spot is marked with a blunt 1/8 inch diameter punch mark on
                            the deep dish (soup) side, the side visible on the rear outer dual with 22.5/24.5 inch
                            wheels. 19.5 inch wheels may be marked on either side of the wheel near the tire bead seat
                            and may be covered by the mounted tire. On aluminum wheels, the tire high point is mounted
                            next to the valve stem.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the vehicle ride quality needs to be improved further, consider replacing the front
                            suspension shock absorbers, rear air suspension torque rods and rear suspension air springs
                            depending on the vehicle suspension configuration.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
