<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-04-01 - Unbalanced Brake Drums Result in Ride and Vibration Issues</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi010401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>01-04-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Unbalanced Brake Drums Result in Ride and Vibration Issues</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>New International vehicle models are equipped with balanced brake drums and tire and wheel
                    assemblies as a standard feature. On specific combinations the tire runout and wheel runout are
                    measured so that at assembly the tire high point is matched to the wheel low point providing the
                    most concentric assembly possible.
                </para>
                <para>Disregarding brake drum balance or tire runout specifications when servicing a vehicle, most
                    likely, will result in decreased ride quality.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Always use balanced brake drums when servicing International vehicles to maintain ride
                            quality.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>When ordering a balanced brake drum, specify the brake drum part number listed on the vehicle line set
                ticket. If the line set ticket is not available, the vehicle VIN number can be used to retrieve the
                correct brake drum part number from the Parts Access System.
            </para>
            <para>When ordering a brake drum by description; i.e., 15x4 brake drum, inspect the replacement drum
                identification to determine if it is balanced. If the brake drum was manufactured by Gunite, it will be
                identified with an "X" suffix after the basic part number to indicate the drum is balanced. If the
                replacement brake drum was manufactured by Meritor/Dayton Walther, it will be identified with a "BD" or
                "MTB" suffix after the basic part number to indicate it is balanced.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
    </tsi>
</isis>
