<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-08-06 - Troubleshooting Intermittent Instrument Panel Data Link Gauges and Fuel Gauge that Lock-up or
        Freeze in Position in 5000i and 9000i Models Built Between February 21, 2000 and April 18, 2001 with Instrument
        Panels that have a Date Code Less Than 1501
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi010806" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>01-08-06</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Troubleshooting Intermittent Instrument Panel Data Link Gauges and Fuel Gauge that Lock-up or
                Freeze in Position in 5000i and 9000i Models Built Between February 21, 2000 and April 18, 2001 with
                Instrument Panels that have a Date Code Less Than 1501
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000I
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/21/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/18/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000I
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/21/2000</startdate>
                        <enddate>04/18/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Intermittent lockup of the road speed, engine speed, engine coolant, engine oil pressure and
                    voltmeter data link driven gauges and the fuel gauge may occur in instrument panels with a date code
                    prior to 1501 (manufactured during week 15, year 2001) used in 5000i and 9000i Models built between
                    February 21, 2000 and April 18, 2001.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TroubleShooting Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the customer complaint is that the cluster appears to either lock up or freeze, first
                    verify all power connections and grounds are clean and tight. Note that the cluster will normally
                    resume functioning when ignition power is cycled.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the cluster appears to lock up on specific events, such as during Jake Brake
                    operation, verify the electrical circuits for that particular feature. Specifically look for shorted
                    circuits, or chafed wires on that system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After verification of the electrical system, if there are no apparent problems with the
                    vehicle or cluster, replace the instrument cluster circuit board housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the date code on the replacement cluster is after '1501'.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
