<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-08-03 - Entertainment Radio on 4300 and 4400 Models</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi010803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>01-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Entertainment Radio on 4300 and 4400 Models</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Radio does not respond when any of the Function Buttons are operated and the display stays
                    illuminated.
                </para>
                <para>The entertainment radios have several programmable memory features, including station pre-sets,
                    clock and alarm, as well as error codes. There is a small rechargeable non-replaceable battery in
                    the radio that maintains these settings even when the vehicle battery is discharged or disconnected.
                    If the radio's internal battery is not charged and the vehicle batteries are discharged or
                    disconnected, the radio may not function even after the vehicle batteries are connected and properly
                    charged. Use the following reset procedure to resolve this condition.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Radio Reset Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the vehicle batteries are connected and properly charged.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ignition key may be on or off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the small radio reset button that is just above and to the right of the volume
                    control. (Refer to the vehicle Operator's Manual, page F-64, for a picture of the Reset button, and
                    page F-66 for information on error messages {E1, E2 and E3}).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress the small reset button using a small pointed object, such as a ballpoint pen or
                    pencil. Any stored memory settings will be erased and restored to their default values.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Restore radio memory settings. The radio will prompt you to set the time after the reset
                    button is depressed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Current leakage draw in this condition is approximately 270 mA (1/4 amp). Over time, this can
                        cause the vehicle batteries to become discharged. Do not leave the radio in this condition.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Once the radio's internal battery is charged, this condition is unlikely to occur.</para>
            <para>Entertainment radios should be checked during Pre-Delivery Servicing to assure they are not in this
                condition.
            </para>
            <para>Performing a radio reset is not a warrantable repair.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
