<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-09-02 - Headlight Aiming on 4300 and 4400 Models</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi010902" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>01-09-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT END SHEET METAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Headlight Aiming on 4300 and 4400 Models</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/24/2000</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Headlights on above models can be aimed without the use of special tools.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Headlight Aiming Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate a flat level surface that faces a clean wall. A clear distance of 25 feet between
                    the front of the truck and the wall is required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform this procedure in an area out of direct sunlight as darker areas make it easier
                    to see headlight beam definition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure that the hood is latched in the normal driving position, tire pressure is
                    equalized, the truck has a typical load and there is no heavy accumulation of snow, ice or mud on
                    the vehicle
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Park the vehicle perpendicular to the wall with 25 feet between the headlights and the
                    wall.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the vertical distance from the ground to the horizontal centerline of the
                    headlight bulb. Each headlight assembly has a small circle in the headlight lens that identifies the
                    headlight bulb centerline.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the same vertical height as measured in Step 5, mark a horizontal line on the wall
                    at the same height as the headlight bulb. The horizontal line should be the width of the vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the hex head adjusting screw on the backside of the headlight housing. It is
                    located inboard and just below the headlight bulb access cap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the headlight vertical adjustment with a 4-mm socket. The right light should be
                    blocked while aiming the left, and vice versa.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the headlight low beam so that the top of the beam pattern is even with the line
                    on the wall. Horizontal (side to side) adjustment is preset and should not be changed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the event this headlight adjustment procedure conflicts with state or provincial
                        regulations, then the state or provincial regulations must prevail.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
