<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01-12-01 - HEUI Injectors</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi011201" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>01-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>HEUI Injectors</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E High Torque</engfam>
                <engfam>International 530E</engfam>
                <engfam>International 530E High Torque</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The injector test is designed to detect problems with injection and combustion events. Performing
                    a cylinder contribution test will analyze the individual contribution of each of the power
                    cylinders. Its
                    <emph type="bold">primary function</emph>
                    is to detect a bad injector, although it will also detect problems that could affect the overall
                    performance of the power cylinders (i.e.: valves, pushrods, pistons, rings, etc.). Further
                    diagnostic testing (outside the scope of this TSI) may be necessary to resolve mechanical issues.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="1">
            <title>KEY-ON ENGINE-RUNNING INJECTOR TEST</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid engine damage, personal injury, possible death, be certain that the transmission is
                        in neutral, parking brake is applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to starting the engine.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>During this test the Electronic Control Module (ECM) will control fuel delivery and determine each
                cylinder's power contribution. If a cylinder is not performing satisfactorily, a Diagnostic Trouble Code
                (DTC) will be set.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1750402" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                         scalefitheight="392px" resolution="94"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Good Cylinder Contribution Test Recording</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1750402">Some of the key areas to examine on the graphical display of the cylinder
                    contribution test
                    <xref refid="f1750402"/>
                </hotlnk>
                are:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the test begins, the engine speed increases in increments up to 850 rpm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The ECM increases fuel delivery to cylinder #1 (over-fuels) which causes engine speed to
                    increase.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fuel is reduced to remaining cylinders to maintain 850 rpm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The ECM decreases fuel delivery to cylinder #1 (under-fuels) which causes engine speed
                    to decrease.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fuel is increased to the remaining cylinders to maintain 850 rpm.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At this point 2 key observations are noted:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The ECM compares fuel delivery of the remaining 5 cylinders during over-fuel condition.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The ECM compares fuel delivery of remaining 5 cylinders during under-fuel condition.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>If the difference is not what the ECM expects, a Diagnostic Trouble Code is set for the
                    non-contributing cylinder. The procedure will repeat for the remaining cylinders until the test is
                    complete.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The engine speed returns to low idle. The test is complete.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>During the cylinder contribution test, the fuel rate graph represents fuel delivery to the
                        remaining 5 cylinders.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The cylinder contribution test begins with cylinder #1 (front cylinder) and is performed sequentially.
                The rpm fluctuation on engines with more than one severely scuffed injector can be enough to stop the
                cylinder contribution test.
            </para>
            <para>Low or erratic fuel pressure can be enough to stop a Cylinder Contribution Test (CCT) or worse, give
                erroneous graphs and Diagnostic Trouble Codes.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">TROUBLESHOOTING</emph>
            </para>
            <para>A scuffed injector can be very difficult to diagnose. The best way to troubleshoot a scuffed injector
                is by using the EST and Master Diagnostics. Using Master Diagnostics KOER_CCT_I6.SSN:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Visualize - use the online graphs to compare one cylinder trace to another. Even the slightest
                        scuffed injectors can display a significant change in pattern from a good injector.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Listen - watch the real-time graph and carefully listen to the sound characteristics of the
                        engine.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify - when a Diagnostic Trouble Code is set, verify that there is a significant change in
                        the graphic displays for that cylinder.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="7">
            <title>TEST PROCEDURE - USING THE EST AND MASTER DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title></title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>All of the following screen views are based off of MD32 Version 2.3 default settings
                            unless otherwise stated. You may have variations of views if you are using a different
                            version of MD. If you have customized settings you may have a different view.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury, engine damage, possible death, be certain that the transmission
                            is in neutral, parking brake is applied, and drive wheels are blocked prior to starting the
                            engine.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the engine and bring it up to its normal operating temperature above 160&#176;F
                        (71&#176;C).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start Master Diagnostics.
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504003">Select the appropriate ECM application
                            <xref refid="f17504003"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        . Selecting the wrong application will give you erroneous readings.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">MD32 3BX</emph>
                                - Three box engine controllers consisting of an Engine Control Module (ECM), Injector
                                Driver Module (IDM), and a Vehicle Personality Module (VPM).
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">MD32 DLC</emph>- Diamond Logic Controller. This single box Engine
                                Control Module (ECM) performs all of the functions that the three box can, however it is
                                contained in one single unit.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504003" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg8742.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the EST with the International&#174; Truck interface cable to the 6 pin ATA
                        connector located near the left side kick panel. For 9 pin ATA connectors, use the pigtail
                        connector (6 pin to 9 pin) adapter tool ZTSE4467.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Session</emph>
                        drop-down menu bar and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504004">select
                            <emph type="bold">Open</emph>
                            to begin a session
                            <xref refid="f17504004"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504004" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8584.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="272px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504005">Select the file
                            <emph type="bold">KOER_CCT_I6.SSN</emph>
                            (Key-On Engine-Running Cylinder Contribution Test)
                            <xref refid="f17504005"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        from the
                        <emph type="bold">Open Session File</emph>
                        dialog window. The file name should now appear in the
                        <emph type="bold">File Name</emph>
                        box. Select
                        <emph type="bold">Open</emph>.
                    </para>
                    <para>When selecting a factory default session from International&#174; Engine, Master Diagnostics
                        automatically selects the correct
                        <emph type="bold">COM</emph>
                        port. Refer to the Master Diagnostics Software User's Manual for additional information.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504005" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg8585.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the engine coolant temperature (ECT) is greater than 160&#176;F (71&#176;C).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">It is essential to run the
                        <emph type="bold">Key-On Engine-Running Standard Test</emph>
                        in order to gain access to cylinder contribution testing. Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostics</emph>
                        drop-down menu bar, then select the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504006">
                            <emph type="bold">Key-On Engine-Running Standard Test</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504006"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>The status bar will display the message
                    <emph type="bold">DIAGNOSTICS RUNNING</emph>
                    at the bottom of the screen
                    <xref refid="f17504008"/>.
                </para>
                <para>If a diagnostic message appears, take note of the message, select
                    <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                    and try again. If the message reappears, refer to the Diagnostic Tests section in the Master
                    Diagnostics Software Users Manual.
                </para>
                <figure id="f17504006" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8586.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="352px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">When the standard test is complete, select the
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostics</emph>
                        drop-down menu and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504007">select the
                            <emph type="bold">Key-On Engine-Running Injector Test</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504007"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                    <para>If a diagnostic message appears, take note of the message, select
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                        and try again. If the message reappears, refer to the Diagnostic Tests section in the Master
                        Diagnostics Software Users Manual.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504007" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8588.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="392px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">While the test is running, the following parameters are observed in the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504008">Typical Graphical View
                            <xref refid="f17504008"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        :
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine Speed (RPM) (500-1000 rpm)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Engine Load (EL) (0-127.5%)</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fuel Rate (FR) (0-4 gal/hr)</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </step1>
                <para>The status bar will display the message
                    <emph type="bold">DIAGNOSTICS RUNNING</emph>
                    at the bottom of the screen.
                </para>
                <figure id="f17504008" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9019.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="432px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Typical Graphical View - Good (Consistent) Cylinder Contribution</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The following graphic is
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504009">an example of how a low fuel delivery injector appears during the
                            test
                            <xref refid="f17504009"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Figure represents a graphical replay (SnapShot recording).</para>
                        <para>The graphical replay provided for interpretation was not severe enough to generate a
                            Diagnostic Trouble Code.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f17504009" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9018.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="432px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. Interpreting Graphical Data - Poor Cylinder Contribution</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>When the over-fuel condition is compared to the under-fuel condition a significant difference is
                    observed. This indicates that a particular cylinder is a strong contributor, or that the injector
                    and power cylinder are functioning properly providing optimum output. CYL #1, 2, and 3 show evidence
                    of well defined graphic traces, while CYL #4, 5, and 6 are viewed with suspicion. A weak
                    contributing cylinder could be the result of a poorly functioning injector or a mechanical problem.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Strong Contributor Indicators - Cylinders 1-3</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Key Observations:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>To maintain constant engine speed the ECM makes greater changes to the fuel rate than seen
                            in weaker cylinders (cylinders 4-6).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>There is a greater impact on Engine Load (EL).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Weak Contributor Indicators- Cylinders 4-6</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Key Observations:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>To maintain constant engine speed the ECM makes minimal changes to the fuel rate than seen
                            in stronger cylinders (cylinders 1-3).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>There is a minimal impact on Engine Load (EL).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>The previously described procedure allows the technician to troubleshoot and repair the engine by
                    replacing only the scuffed or defective injector(s). In the previous example the suspect injector(s)
                    #6, #5, #4, (weak contributors) should be replaced.
                </para>
                <para>If this fails to improve performance or significantly improve the graphical display, further
                    mechanical diagnostic testing beyond the scope of this TSI is necessary.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To prevent engine damage, do not start the engine without priming the fuel system. Failure
                            to do so will overload the injector tips. Priming the fuel system will be necessary. It has
                            been found that "dry starts" after engine/fuel system maintenance contributes to injector
                            tip failures. After engine service, when the fuel injection system is dry, cranking the
                            engine to start without first priming the fuel system can result in an overload condition in
                            injector tips. This overload occurs because there isn't any fuel present to cushion the
                            needle valve as it lifts and seats. To avoid this condition, follow the procedure below
                            after performing any maintenance that may allow air to enter the fuel system.
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Disconnect the CMP (Camshaft Position Sensor).</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Use the hand primer to fill the majority of the fuel system. Pump until hand
                                    primer is hard to depress.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Crank the engine three times for 15 seconds each. Reapply the hand primer after
                                    each crank cycle.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Once the hand primer is hard to depress (usually three
                                    <emph type="italic">crank and hand prime cycles</emph>), reconnect the CMP and start
                                    the engine.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>In cases where rust or corrosion is present within the injectors, some additional precautions are
                    required.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Clean the entire fuel system of any water or other foreign contamination, including fuel
                            tanks, fuel filter housings, strainers and fuel supply manifold.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After cleaning the fuel system, install and run existing injectors to purge the fuel
                            system of any remaining contamination. Installation of new injector(s) can now be made.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>It is recommended to replace all injectors that show signs of rust or corrosion.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Normally this is not considered a warrantable failure.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="12">
            <title>SNAPSHOT RECORDING AND REPLAY OF A CYLINDER CONTRIBUTION TEST</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Snapshot Recording Of Cylinder Contribution Test</title>
                <para>The snapshot feature is an option that can be used to document the engine condition.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>After the
                            <emph type="bold">KOER_CCT_I6.SSN</emph>
                            (session file) is open you may proceed with the following steps.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostic</emph>
                        drop-down menu and then
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504010">select
                            <emph type="bold">Key-On Engine-Running Standard Test</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504010"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not arm the trigger when performing the
                            <emph type="bold">KEY-ON ENGINE-RUNNING STANDARD TEST</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f17504010" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8586.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="432px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">SnapShot</emph>
                        drop-down menu and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504011">select
                            <emph type="bold">Arm Trigger</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504011"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8608.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="432px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504012">Verify the message
                            <emph type="bold">Trigger Armed</emph>
                            is active in the status bar
                            <xref refid="f17504012"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504012" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8609.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Select the
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostic</emph>
                        drop-down menu and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504013">select the
                            <emph type="bold">Key-On Engine-Running Injector Test</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504013"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504013" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8588.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="432px" resolution="94"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504014">Verify that the
                            <emph type="bold">Trigger Armed</emph>
                            message changes to
                            <emph type="bold">Recording</emph>
                            as soon as the engine rpm is increased by the test
                            <xref refid="f17504014"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        . You will also see the message
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Running</emph>
                        message in the status bar.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504014" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg8857.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">When the test is complete the
                        <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Running</emph>
                        message disappears. To stop SnapShot recording
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504015">select
                            <emph type="bold">Stop</emph>
                            from the setup menu
                            <xref refid="f17504015"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        . When recording is complete, the
                        <emph type="bold">Record</emph>
                        message disappears.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504015" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9022.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="272px" resolution="96" box="no"/>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>To save multiple record files, the record file name must be changed for each recording.
                            Failure to rename the record file will result in the file being overwritten. Refer to the
                            Master Diagnostics Software Users Manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Replay Of Cylinder Contribution Test</title>
                <para>The following procedure provides step by step instructions to replay a recorded session.</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">To review a SnapShot recording file,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504016">select
                            <emph type="bold">Graphical Replay</emph>
                            from the toolbar
                            <xref refid="f17504016"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504016" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="272px" resolution="96" box="no"/>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504017">Select file
                            <emph type="bold">koer_cct_I6.rec</emph>
                            from the pop-up window
                            <xref refid="f17504017"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If you saved multiple recording files, select the designated file.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f17504017" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9024.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="392px" resolution="96" box="no"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Opening SnapShot Recording</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504018">Select
                            <emph type="bold">Engine Speed</emph>
                            and
                            <emph type="bold">Fuel Rate</emph>
                            from the pop-up menu to modify default attributes. To display, select
                            <emph type="bold">Attributes</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504018"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504018" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9025.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Selecting Parameters</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504019">Modify
                            <emph type="bold">Engine Speed Attributes</emph>. Enter 500 for minimum value and 1000 for
                            maximum value. Select
                            <emph type="bold">OK</emph>
                            <xref refid="f17504019"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504019" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9030.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" resolution="96" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Modified Engine Speed Attributes</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504020">Modify
                            <emph type="bold">Fuel Rate Attributes</emph>. Enter 4 for maximum value
                            <xref refid="f17504020"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        . Select
                        <emph type="bold">OK</emph>.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f17504020" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9026.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" resolution="96" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Modified Fuel Rate Attributes</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f17504021">To display a SnapShot recording file, select
                            <emph type="bold">Display All</emph>
                            then select
                            <emph type="bold">OK</emph>. The recorded session will open
                            <xref refid="f17504021"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para></para>
                <figure id="f17504021" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/Eg9027.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" resolution="97" box="yes"/>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
