<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 01 12 12 - Flywheel Machining Dimensions and Guidelines</stitle>
    <tsi id="xxxxxxxxxxx" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>01 12 12</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>8, 2001</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Flywheel Machining Dimensions and Guidelines</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>To avoid personal injury and possible death, this resurfacing procedure should be
                                    carried out by a skilled technician, using specialized equipment specifically for
                                    this function. Flywheel machining must be performed at a reputable servicing
                                    location.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Flywheel machining information is provided for guidance only. International Truck
                                    and Engine Corporation assumes no responsibility either for the results of any work
                                    performed in accordance with this information or for the ability of service
                                    personnel to detect heat cracks.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Carefully examine the flywheel for any cracks or heat checks. If there is any
                                    question, discard the flywheel. Any crack or heat check in the flywheel could cause
                                    it to separate. Should separation occur, the operator or bystanders may be injured.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If the flywheel is machinable, be sure to recheck the flywheel for cracks and heat
                                    checks after it has been machined. If any cracks or heat checks are detected,
                                    replace the resurfaced flywheel with a new one.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The following is provided for your information.</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Flywheels used in manual transmission vehicles with T 444E Engines may be ground to a minimum
                thickness of
                <emph type="bold">1.768 inches (44.907 mm)</emph>. Resurfacing should only be done to correct minor wear
                and scoring. Before resurfacing the flywheel, determine whether or not it was previously resurfaced, or
                has adequate stock for resurfacing. To make this determination
                <hotlnk xrefid="f12099">
                    <xref refid="f12099"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTE:
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f12099">
                        <xref refid="f12099"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . If the minimum dimension depicted in Figure 1 cannot be maintained, the flywheel must be replaced.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CLEANING</title>
            <para>Clean the flywheel with a non-caustic solvent. Dry it with compressed air.</para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Visually inspect the flywheel for cracks, heat checks, and extensive scoring, which
                    would make it unfit for further service. Replace or resurface the flywheel as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect ring gear for worn, chipped, or cracked, teeth. If the teeth are damaged,
                    replace the ring gear.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Repair (For Manual Transmissions ONly)</title>
            <para>The flywheel may be ground to correct minor wear and scoring.
                <emph type="bold">Do not</emph>
                grind beyond the minimum permissible thickness of 1.768 inches (44.907 mm). Replace the flywheel if it
                is not repairable by surface grinding.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f12099">
                    <xref refid="f12099"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Remove material from clutch face only.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="measure" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <figure id="f12099" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="f12099" filename="../tsifigures/F0701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" resolution="400"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Flywheel Surface Grinder Specifications for Manual Transmissions Only</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Dimension "A"
                        <callout2 type="alpha">Flywheel mounting face to flywheel clutch face</callout2>
                        <callout2 type="alpha">New flywheels have a thickness of 1.804 inches plus or minus .010 inches
                            (45.822 mm plus or minus 0.254 mm).
                        </callout2>
                        <callout2 type="alpha">1.768 inches (44.907 mm) is the minimum thickness permissible after
                            resurfacing.
                        </callout2>
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Post-Machining Flywheel inspection</title>
            <para>Once the flywheel has been machined, recheck it for cracks and heat checks. If any cracks or heat
                checks are detected, replace the resurfaced flywheel with a new one.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
