<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-05-02 - Steering Column Kits for 42/43/4400, 73/74/75/7600, 85/8600 Models</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi020502" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-05-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Steering Column Kits for 42/43/4400, 73/74/75/7600, 85/8600 Models</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions and cautions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="18">
            <stitle>TSI 02-05-02 - Steering Column Kits for 42/43/4400, 73/74/75/7600, 85/8600 Models</stitle>
            <title>Bendix Installation Instructions</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Steering Column Kits: Piece Nos. 5008670 and 5008674</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Description:</emph>
                    This kit contains all of the necessary components to replace the steering column.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0205021" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="392px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Steering Column Replacement Kit</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>IMPORTANT CAUTION</title>
                <para>When working on or around a vehicle, the following general precautions should be observed.</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brakes, and always block the
                            wheels.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with air brakes, make certain to drain the air pressure from
                            all reservoirs before beginning ANY work on the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Following the vehicle manufacturer's recommended procedures, deactivate the electrical
                            system in manner that removes all electrical power from the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When working in the engine compartment the engine should be shut off. Where circumstances
                            require that the engine be in operation, EXTREME CAUTION should be used to prevent personal
                            injury resulting from contact with moving, rotating, leaking, heated, or electrically
                            charged components.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip. Never remove
                            a component or plug unless you are certain all system pressure has been depleted.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety glasses.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until you have read
                            and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper tools and observe
                            all precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use only genuine Bendix replacement parts, components, and kits. Replacement hardware,
                            tubing, hose, fittings, etc. should be equivalent size, type and strength as original
                            equipment and be designed specifically for such applications and systems.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Components with stripped threads or damaged parts should be replaced rather than repaired.
                            Repairs requiring machining or welding should not be attempted unless specifically approved
                            and stated by the vehicle or component manufacturer.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                            restored to their proper operating condition.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Disassembly</title>
                <para>Be sure to park the vehicle with the wheels straight ahead. The wheels must remain straight during
                    this procedure.
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the intermediate shaft (located in the engine compartment) from the
                        steering column.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the power source before working on electrical components.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205022" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205022.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Front Cover</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the front cover of the steering wheel by inserting a phillips head
                        screwdriver into each of the four apertures (two per side) as shown in Figure 3. When the
                        latching mechanism is released, pull the front cover forward.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205023" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205023.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. Releasing and Removing Front Cover</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connector of the clockspring wiring harness (to the horn)
                        near the steering wheel. Do not attempt to disconnect the harness near the clockspring.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the steering wheel nut. See figure 4.</para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205024" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205024.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Removing Steering Wheel Nut</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a wheel puller to loosen, remove the steering wheel from the shaft spindle.
                        Refer to figure 5.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205025" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205025.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Wheel Puller</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">As shown in figure 6, remove the steering column covers by removing the two post
                        screws and one column screw with a torx wrench. Separate the bottom and top cover halves. A
                        wiring harness is attached to the bottom cover half and will prevent the cover from being
                        removed from the steering column area. Complete removal of this cover is necessary to facilitate
                        the installation of this kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205026" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205026.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Removing Column and Post Screws (Bottom Side)</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connector on the bottom side of the clockspring by prying
                        the locking tab gently with a flat blade screwdriver. The locking tab is located on the steering
                        column side of the housing. Refer to figure 8.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify that the wheels are straight then tape the top cover of the clockspring to
                        the bottom housing of the clockspring. Using a phillips head screwdriver remove the three screws
                        that secure the clockspring to the steering column assembly. See figure 7.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205027" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205027.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Removal of Clockspring</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0205028" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205028.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Clockspring - Bottom View</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With a long handle phillips screwdriver remove the two turn signal screws that
                        secure the turn signal housing to the steering column. See figure 9.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0205029" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0205029.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Turn Signal</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical connector located on the back side of the turn signal
                        housing by gently squeezing the tab of the wiring harness connector while pulling it away from
                        the turn signal.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If applicable, locate the TC-7 Trailer Control Brake Valve on the steering column
                        pedestal. Identify, mark and disconnect all of the air lines connected to the brake valve. All
                        of the ports contain push to connect fittings. To disconnect push the fitting toward the valve
                        with one hand and pull the air line out, away from the valve, with the other.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If applicable, remove the three TC-7 mounting screws securing the valve to the
                        steering column housing. Pull the TC-7 down, sliding it through the opening in the steering
                        column housing. Removal of the handle is not necessary to remove the brake valve.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502a" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. TC-7 Removal</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Locate the cross-cab beam. Remove the two cross-cab beam screws that secure the
                        steering column to the cab beam.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502b" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502b.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Cross-cab Beam</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove and discard the four 5/16 inch torx screws that secure the top portion of the
                        steering column to the steering column housing and the four 8mm flange nuts (3) that secure the
                        bottom of the steering column to the firewall.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lift up and pull forward (toward driver's seat) on the steering column to disengage
                        the splined shaft of the steering column.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the gasket material from the steering column mounting surface of the
                        firewall.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Assembly</title>
                <para>Use all of the components contained in this kit.</para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Position the gasket (4) on the four steering column mounting studs that are secured
                        to the firewall.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the steering column (1) with the opening in the firewall. Using extreme
                        caution align the steering column splined shaft with the mating coupling. See figure 12.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502c" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502c.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Steering Column Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosely install the four 8mm flange nuts (3) that secure the steering column to the
                        firewall and the four 5/16 inch Torx screws (2) that secure the steering column to the support
                        bracket.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the four 5/16 inch Torx screws (2) to 240-350 inch pounds and the 8mm flange
                        nuts (3) to 200-240 inch pounds.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the two cross-cab beam mounting screws and tighten to 125-210 inch pounds.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">As shown in figure 13, install the TC-7 Brake Valve using the three screws removed
                        during the disassembly, tighten to 30-40 inch pounds. Reconnect the air lines. Push the fitting
                        in, towards the valve and insert the air line. When the air line can't be inserted further, pull
                        back on the fitting to secure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502d" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502d.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. TC-7 Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Installing the Clockspring</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Clocksprings can be one of two types, either "canceling" or "non-canceling." A "canceling"
                    clockspring cancels, or turns off, the turn signal when the steering wheel is turned, whereas a
                    "non-canceling" clockspring requires the driver to manually cancel the turn signal upon completion
                    of the turn. To convert to a non-canceling assembly remove the canceling hub by gently pulling and
                    rocking the hub to disengage the three locking tabs. See figure 14.
                </para>
                <figure id="f020502e" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502e.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Clockspring</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the clockspring verifying the tape that was installed in step 9 of the
                        Disassembly is intact. IF THE TAPE IS BROKEN, THE CLOCKSPRING MUST BE CENTERED BEFORE IT CAN BE
                        PLACED IN SERVICE. Follow the instructions on the front surface of the clockspring for resetting
                        the assembly. See figure 15.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502f" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502f.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Clockspring Label</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the three holes on the clockspring with the column mounting holes. The
                        clockspring holes will align in one direction only. Using the three clockspring screws, secure
                        the clockspring and torque the screws to 15-30 inch pounds.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the clockspring electrical connector on the bottom of the housing to the
                        wire harness. See figure 14. An audible "click" ensures the connector is secure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the mounting holes of the turn signal with the holes in the steering column
                        housing. See figure 16. Ensure the positioning tab is centered in the steering column housing
                        locating slot as shown in figure 17. Secure the turn signal screws and torque to 25-45 inch
                        pounds.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502g" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502g.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Turn Signal Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f020502h" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502h.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. Positioning Tab</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the wire harness to the turn signal electrical connector on the bottom of
                        the housing. An audible "click" ensures the connector is secured.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the column cover halves, starting with the bottom cover. Secure the wire
                        harness and clip to the cover before installation. Align the steering column screw hole of the
                        bottom cover with the steering column hole. As shown in figure 18, the locating tab inside the
                        cover rests against the TC-7 Trailer Control mounting plate when properly positioned. Install
                        the column screw and torque to 15-35 inch pounds.
                    </para>
                    <para>Align the top cover with the bottom cover and install the two post screws. Tighten the post
                        screw to 15-30 inch pounds.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f020502i" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g020502i.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" resolution="200"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18. Bottom Cover Installation</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect the intermediate shaft to the steering column.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the steering wheel on the steering column shaft. Also align the clockspring
                        clip with the slot in the steering wheel. Exercise extreme caution to prevent misalignment and
                        possible damage to the clockspring, shaft and steering wheel.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace the steering wheel nut and torque to 660-720 inch pounds.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect the clockspring wire harness to the steering wheel (horn) connector.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the front cover.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reconnect the power source.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Testing The Vehicle</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Activate the horn to verify the electrical connection to the horn is complete.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn on the turn signal then turn the steering wheel to verify that the system
                        operates correctly as either a "non-canceling" or "canceling" switch.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the horn and/or turn signals are not functioning properly verify that the power
                        source is connected and that all electrical connections are properly seated.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Verify the vehicle wheels turn when the steering wheel is turned and that the
                        steering wheel features such as tilt and telescoping, if applicable, are also functioning
                        properly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
