<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-05-01 - Power Steering Diagnostics</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi020501" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-05-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Power Steering Diagnostics</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This Technical Service Information letter is designed to help the service technician troubleshoot
                    steering complaints. Following the Service Procedure will assist in completing proper diagnosis and
                    repair.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t010501">
                <title>Special Tools</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="colspec0" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="4.52in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1" colsep="1" rowsep="1" valign="top" align="center" charoff="50"
                                   char="">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" colsep="1" rowsep="1" align="center" charoff="50" char="">
                                <para>ZTSE2780</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Power Steering Analyzer (Note 1)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                                <para>ZTSE4402</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Plug, TRW Steering Gear (Note 1)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0" align="center">
                                <para>3331812K</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Plug, Sheppard Steering Gear (Note 2)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Note 1: Available from Kent Moore/OTC, 1-800-520-2584</para>
            <para>Note 2: Available from International PDC</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
            <stitle>TSI 02-05-01 - Power Steering Diagnostics</stitle>
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To properly diagnose a steering complaint, it is important to understand the complaint,
                    talk to operator and get specific details of what exactly the complaint is, when does it happen,
                    when was the problem first noticed. Does the problem happen when the vehicle is loaded/empty? Also,
                    over loaded front axles and tires may cause intermittent hard steering feel. The better your
                    understanding of the circumstances, the better your ability will be to solve the problem.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the vehicle for maintenance items that would influence problem. Inspect the
                    tractor fifth wheel, front axle king pins and all linkages for excessive wear, seized parts and
                    proper lubrication. Inspect for correct tire pressures, unusual tire wear on all axles. Inspect the
                    steering column and intermediate shaft for binding or sticking in the cowl boot and in the slip
                    joint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect hydraulic system for correct fluid level and condition of the fluid. Discolored
                    fluid with a burnt smell may be caused by extended maintenance intervals or high operating
                    temperature. Inspect the fluid filter element in the reservoir. Use care to avoid introducing dirt
                    into the steering fluid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully inspect power steering hoses, paying close attention to the supply hose from
                    the reservoir to the pump. This hose is critical and is sometimes overlooked in steering diagnosis.
                    The hose should be free of sharp bends, should be pliable, without being spongy. A supply hose that
                    doesn't provide fluid to the pump during all operating conditions could be the cause of a complaint
                    that is thought to be a component issue. Steering that is reported to exhibit periodic binding or
                    hard to steer could be a supply hose that is kinking or closing off during high pump RPM or has a
                    restriction, preventing adequate fluid supply to the pump.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect power steering analyzer, ZTSE2780, as described in the service manual S05002y,
                    and perform tests according to the steering troubleshooting checklist (Figure 1). Each test must be
                    performed for proper diagnosis. Compare test results with the customer's description of the
                    complaint.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Oil temperature affects performance of hydraulic components. When tests are performed, a
                    suitable thermometer should be installed in the power steering reservoir. Test should be performed
                    at system operating temperatures of 180 degrees F. If the complaint indicates an intermittent
                    problem, it may be necessary to perform tests at a higher oil temperature of 220 degrees F.
                    Temperature can be increased by partially closing off the valve on the power steering analyzer to
                    1500 psi long enough to raise the temperature, then fully open the valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform the following tests and record the data on the Steering Troubleshooting
                    Checklist
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0205011">(Figure 1)</hotlnk>
                    :
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent property damage, personal injury or death, watch the power steering analyzer
                            pressure gauge closely when closing the shutoff valve. A bad relief valve may not relieve
                            pump pressure and cause pump damage or a high pressure hose to rupture. If pressure rises
                            rapidly or goes above 2500 PSI,
                            <emph type="bold">STOP</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Measure and record temperature (this can be increased to 180 degrees by partially closing
                            off the valve on the power steering analyzer to 1500 psi long enough to achieve the desired
                            temperature).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Measure and record system back pressure. This is done by reading the pressure on the gauge
                            with wheels straight, no steering wheel input.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Maximum system pressure test is made by closing and opening the power steering analyzer
                            valve quickly three times and reading maximum (pump relief) pressure. Use caution if
                            pressure goes over 2500 psi. You must not go any further; this means the pump is not
                            relieving and damage or injury could occur. Do not leave the valve closed for more than a
                            few seconds.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Measure and record flow at idle, back pressure only; this is read in gallons per minute.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Measure and record flow at idle with 1500 psi load applied (closing valve to read 1500 on
                            gauge).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Measure and record flow at full governed rpm with 1500 psi load applied.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn steering wheel at idle and record pressure on left turn and right turn.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With an inch pound torque wrench, record inch pound effort to turn steering wheel (engine
                            at idle).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To evaluate the results of the tests, it is necessary to understand pump
                    specifications.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Each pump is designed for specific applications and has performance specifications. Changing
                        pumps to a different specification is not recommended without Engineering approval.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Each steering gear has flow and pressure recommendations . Refer to RH Sheppard or TRW
                        specifications for the steering gear being serviced. If pump flow is lower than the minimum for
                        the specific gear, you could experience a slow or lumpy feel in the steering wheel.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the test results are within specifications and the cause of the steering complaint is
                    not discovered, it may be required to perform a steering gear internal leakage test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Identify if the steering gear is fitted with a pressure relief valve. These will typically be
                        1000, 2000, 3000, 4000, and 8000 series vehicles.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The pressure relief valve is identified by a 1.250 inch nut on the input end cap. To properly
                        test this type of gear, the relief valve must be removed and a special plug installed. The plug
                        part number for a Sheppard gear is 3331812K, the plug for a TRW gear is part number ZTSE4402.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>As an alternative to using a 1 inch steel block between the axle stop and the axle for this
                        test, it may be more desirable to install a suitable wooden 4x4 block long enough to fit between
                        the tire/wheel and the chassis frame rail. This tests the steering gear leakage at maximum pump
                        delivery.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After placing the block of wood in contact with the tire and wheel evenly, so not to push only
                        against the tire, and the other end against the frame rail, turn the steering wheel in the
                        direction of the block. This will be maximum pump pressure.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Read the flowmeter; if the flow is over one gallon per minute, the gear has excessive internal
                        leakage.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refer to ISIS (
                    <emph type="bold">I</emph>nternational
                    <emph type="bold">S</emph>ervice
                    <emph type="bold">I</emph>nformation
                    <emph type="bold">S</emph>olutions) for the appropriate service manual section for trouble shooting
                    charts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For current steering gear oil flow and pressure specifications refer to RH Sheppard or
                    TRW depending on the steering gear being serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For technical assistance in steering performance diagnostics, call the Technical Service
                    Help Line 1-800-336-4500. You will be asked to fax a completed diagnostic form (Figure 1) for
                    evaluation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0205011" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0205011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Steering Troubleshooting Checklist</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
