<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-08-03 - Replacement Turn Signal Switches</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi020803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Replacement Turn Signal Switches</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1452</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>1652</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2554</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2574</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2654</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2674</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Since initial production in 1989, there have been several changes to production and Service Part
                    turn signal switches and part numbers. The replacement chart below provides a summary of the switch
                    configurations and part numbers. It gives the new Service Part numbers, their applications, and a
                    guide to determine which switches should be used to replace existing switches in the vehicles you're
                    repairing. At this time, the only part numbers available are the switches listed under "Service Part
                    Replacement". Originally there were Service Kits which contained a switch and an adapter harness.
                    Since many switches have previously been replaced and do not need another adapter harness, kits
                    which included a switch and harness are no longer available.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <figure id="f0208033" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0208033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Parts Information</caption>
            </figure>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>When replacing a non-functioning turn signal switch, locate the part number tag attached to the switch
                and find its part number in the chart above.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If your vehicle is a pre 1996 vehicle and the switch has never been
                        replaced</emph>, you'll find the broken switch part number in the "Pre 2/1/96 Production"
                    column. Follow that number across to the right to the appropriate "Adapter Harness Part Number"
                    column, then again to the right to the replacement switch number in the "Service Part Replacement"
                    column. Since the switch is a pre 1996 switch, it will also need to have an adapter harness of the
                    part number listed and a new service part switch in order to keep the brake lights operational when
                    the hazard flashers are in use.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If your vehicle is a pre 1996 vehicle but the switch has already been
                        replaced</emph>, you'll find the switch part number in the "1996 Through End of Production"
                    column. Follow that number across to the right to the corresponding number in the "Service Part
                    Replacement" column. If the switch number is found in the 1996 Through End of Production column, it
                    will not need a new adapter harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If your vehicle is a 1996 through present</emph>
                    you should find the broken switch part number in the "1996 Through End of Production" column. Follow
                    that number across to the right to the appropriate number in the "Service Part Replacement" column.
                    If the switch number is found in the 1996 Through End of Production column, it will not need an
                    adapter harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If you're unable to locate the part number on the broken switch or in the chart, consider the switch
                functions and the type of connector it uses. The chart lists the switches by function and connector
                type, either 56 Series or Metri-Pak as illustrated below, or the pre 9/93 which had neither type
                connector and has to be adapted by splicing adapter number 203285C92 to the vehicle harness which then
                allows the use of a switch which is equipped with a 56 Series connector.
            </para>
            <figure id="f0208031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0208031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Metri-Pak Connector</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0208032" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0208032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. 56 Series Connector</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
