<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02&#8211;12&#8211;09 - Release of New Fractured Connecting Rod Assembly</stitle>
    <tsi id="fracturedConnectingRod" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>02&#8211;12&#8211;09</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Release of New Fractured Connecting Rod Assembly</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>International&#174; DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530E</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; DT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; HT 530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid engine damage when servicing, do not mix old tongue and groove connecting rods
                            with new fractured connecting rods in the same engine. The weights of the connecting rods
                            are different and will cause engine vibration if mixed.
                        </para>
                        <para>The old tongue and groove connecting rod will still be available for servicing individual
                            power cylinders that predate the change. The new fractured connecting rods can be used in
                            engines with S/N 1194039 &#8212; 1363043 only if a complete set of six new rods is
                            installed.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Keep the fractured mating surfaces clean and free of lint and debris. Do not allow the
                            mating surfaces to rest on any surface. Do not bump the mating surfaces or drop the
                            connecting rod or cap. This could cause chipping and wear on the mating surface, resulting
                            in improper mating during installation and possible engine damage.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>A new fractured connecting rod assembly (1841615C91) has been implemented into production engines
                    (S/N 1363044 and up) to replace the tongue and groove connecting rod assembly (1830153C91). The new
                    assembly consists of the connecting rod, cap and two bolts.
                </para>
                <para>The fractured connecting rod joint provides better mating between the rod and the cap than the
                    current tongue and groove machined joint. The new connecting rod bushing has a larger outside
                    diameter than the old bushing to accommodate a larger wall thickness. The inside diameter has also
                    been increased slightly to increase piston pin rotation.
                </para>
                <table id="t01">
                    <title>Specification Changes for Fractured Connecting Rod Assembly</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.38*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.82*"/>
                        <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Specification</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Old</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">New</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Connecting Rod Assembly Weight</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>3.20 kg (7.05 lb)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>3.40 kg (7.50 lb)</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Connecting Rod Bushing Bore Diameter</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>48.88 mm (1.9245 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>49.90 mm (1.9645 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Connecting Rod Bushing Outside Diameter</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>49 mm (1.9300 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>50 mm (1.9685 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colname="col1">
                                    <para>Connecting Rod Bushing Inside Diameter (installed)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col2">
                                    <para>46.37 mm (1.8258 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry colname="col3">
                                    <para>46.39 mm (1.8266 in)</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not use the service bolts for old tongue and groove connecting rods with the new
                            fractured connecting rods.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Special Features</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>If the rod cap is reversed when assembled to the connecting rod or a rod cap is not installed
                        on its original matching connecting rod, the fractured mating surfaces will be ruined. This may
                        cause the rod cap to come loose and cause engine damage. The entire connecting rod must be
                        replaced.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="tsi03" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F0403.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="96" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Serial Number Locations</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The fractured mating surfaces of each rod and cap pair are precisely matched. Always keep each cap
                with its respective rod. If unsure, match the serial numbers on the sides of each rod and cap.
            </para>
            <figure id="tsi02" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F0402.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Offset for Incorrect Rod Cap Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The rod cap can only be correctly installed on the connecting rod if it is oriented in the correct
                direction. If the rod cap is reversed during assembly of the connecting rod, an obvious offset will be
                seen at the mating surfaces. If the connecting rod assembly is installed on the crankshaft in this
                manner, the connecting rod must be replaced. Also check the crankpin fillets for damage. Such damage
                will require replacement of the crankshaft.
            </para>
            <figure id="tsi01" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F0401.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Arrow for Correct Orientation</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Each rod cap has an arrow for correct orientation in the engine during installation. The arrow must
                point toward the front of the engine.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Separating the Cap From a Fractured Connecting Rod</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>Use the following special procedures to avoid damaging the mating surfaces.</para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal from Engine</title>
                <figure id="tsi05" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F0405.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Removing the Connecting Rod Cap from the Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen both connecting rod bolts two turns.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Use a brass hammer to tap on the bolt heads until the cap comes loose from the
                        connecting rod.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the bolts and the cap.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>New Service Part</title>
                <figure id="tsi04" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F0404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. New Service Part</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove both connecting rod bolts.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the cap can be pulled away from the connecting rod, proceed with the assembly
                        procedure in the service manual.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the cap cannot be pulled away from the connecting rod, place the connecting rod
                        on a work bench with the cap extending over the edge of the work bench.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Grasp the connecting rod with one hand and the cap with the other. Press down on the
                        cap to bend it away from the connecting rod.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
