<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-12-21 - High-Pressure Oil Pump Service Kit and Instruction Video</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021221" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>02-12-21</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>High-Pressure Oil Pump Service Kit and Instruction Video</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466E
                    <snrange>1216428 through 1328024</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>1216428 through 1328024</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>530E
                    <snrange>1216428 through 1328024</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530
                    <snrange>1216428 through 1328024</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 530
                    <snrange>1216428 through 1328024</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI is to inform that there is an O-ring service kit with instructions for the high-pressure
                    oil pump available through service parts dealers. An instruction video will be shipped to all
                    primary and secondary dealers describing how to install the O-ring Service Kit properly.
                </para>
                <para>This kit should be installed on all I6 electronic injection controlled engines within engine
                    serial number range 1216428 through 1328024 with OEM factory installed high-pressure oil pumps that
                    are leaking oil at the outlet fitting, oil ferry plug, or construction port plug area. See Figure 2
                    of the instructions below for fitting locations.
                </para>
                <para>These engine serial numbers correspond to engine build dates 12/01/99 through 10/01/01. Use of
                    this kit also applies to replacement high-pressure oil pumps purchased between the above dates.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use of this kit on engines outside this range may result in an unsuccessful repair. Use of
                            this kit on engines which have already received a replacement pump outside the above date
                            range may result in an unsuccessful repair. For these instances, replacement is recommended
                            with new service parts pump.
                        </para>
                        <para>Pumps manufactured outside the defined build time line have more sealant on the threads
                            and therefore have the potential for damaging the housing threads upon plug removal.
                        </para>
                        <para>These damaged housing threads may go undetected, resulting in continued leaks.</para>
                    </note>
                    <para>Below are the work instructions that are already available in the kit.</para>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>O-ring Service Kit, P/N 1842109C92</para>
            <para>Instruction video cassette, P/N TMT-3438</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Instruction Sheet 1171798R2 O-RING SERVICE KIT</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Application:</emph>
                    All I6 electronic injection controlled engines within engine serial number range 1216428 through
                    1328024 with OEM factory installed high-pressure oil pumps. These engine serial numbers correspond
                    to engine build dates 12/01/99 through 10/01/01. Use of this kit also applies to replacement
                    high-pressure oil pumps purchased between the above dates.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use of this kit on engines outside this range may result in an unsuccessful repair. Use of
                            this kit on engines which have already received a replacement pump outside the above date
                            range may result in an unsuccessful repair. For these instances, replacement is recommended
                            with new service parts pump.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Kit Contents</title>
                <para>This oil pump O-ring kit contains the following parts:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Loctite&#174; 680 Sealant</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>O-ring seal (1) large</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>O-ring seal (2) small</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Instruction Sheet (1171798R2)</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>IDENTIFYING PARTS</para>
                <figure id="f0212211" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F1304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. O-rings: One (1) Large and Two (2) Small</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0212212" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F1307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Location of Plugs, Fittings, and Pump Body</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Seal housing</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Pump body</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Outlet fitting</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Oil ferry plug</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Construction port plug</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal and Installation</title>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not attempt this repair with the pump on the vehicle. The ferry plug check ball will
                            fall out when the ferry plug is removed and cannot be properly installed with the pump on
                            the engine. If the ferry check ball falls out, the engine will not start.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the high-pressure oil pump from engine by following the procedures in the
                        proper service manual.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not clamp the vise to the pump on the seal housing as seen in Figure 3 photo A. It may
                            cause damage to the seals.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the high-pressure oil pump in a shop vise in a vertical position and with
                        vise-jaw liners on the body as seen in Figure 3 photo B.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0212213" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F1312.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="192px" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. A: Incorrect Way of Mounting Pump into Vise and B: Right Way of Mounting Pump
                        into Vise
                    </caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Pump body position to be used to mount pump into vise.</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Pump body position to be used to mount pump into vise.</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the ferry plug.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the construction port plug.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the outlet fitting.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>When using compressed air, use air lines that are completely free of oil and
                                moisture.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove and discard O-rings from the outlet fitting and plugs.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean the fitting and plugs with brake clean. Then dry them with compressed air.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not clean the high-pressure pump with compressed air. The check ball may come out
                                of the pump. The check ball is not a serviceable part.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install new O-rings on the outlet fitting and the two plugs. Use care when
                        installing them and make sure the O-rings are properly seated.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Do not oil O-rings. Use only O-rings supplied with kit because of special Teflon
                                coating. If O-ring is loose, cut, or damaged prior to installation a new kit must be
                                ordered. Failure to follow this caution will cause the pump to leak.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean the high-pressure pump and port openings with brake clean and dry with a clean
                        shop towel.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Before installing the outlet fitting and the two plugs into the high-pressure pump,
                        verify that the check ball is in place by inserting a small pointer from the front (machined
                        surface) of the pump.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply Loctite&#174; 680 only to the first three threads of the fitting and plugs.
                        For this repair, only Loctite&#174; 680 can be used. Do not apply more than is needed to cover
                        the first three threads.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Loctite&#174; 680 Sealant is to be added on to only the first three threads of the
                                fittings as shown in Figure 4.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0212214" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/F1306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" box="yes"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Loctite&#174; 680 On First Three Threads</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Ferry Plug</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Construction Port Plug</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Supply Fitting</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is very important to come up to torque without stripping the threads. If torque cannot
                            be achieved, then pump will have to be replaced.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install outlet fitting and torque to 34 N&#183;m (25 lbf&#183;ft).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install construction plug and torque to 11 N&#183;m (97 lbf&#183;in).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install oil ferry plug and torque to 11 N&#183;m (97 lbf&#183;in).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Refer to the proper service manual for installing of the high-pressure pump on the
                        engine.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the engine and check for oil leaks.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Stop the engine and check engine oil level. Add oil if needed.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
