<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-12-16 - Procedure for containment of injector hold down snap rings during removal of fuel injector
        assembly.
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="xxxxxxxxxxx" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>02-12-16</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August 16, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Procedure for containment of injector hold down snap rings during removal of fuel injector
                assembly.
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 365</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>During the removal process of injectors from a VT 365 engine, the ring retaining the bolt within
                    the hold down assembly could fall off and find its way into the lube oil system. The following
                    service procedure is intended to eliminate the possibility of a lost or broken piece of a snap ring
                    entering the crankcase.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <figure id="f01" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/D08106.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Injector Hold Down Clamp Assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector hold down clamp</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector hold down bolt</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Injector hold down snap ring</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to removing injector assembly, insert clean shop towels into oil drain holes
                    adjacent to each glow plug. A thin screwdriver at least six inches in length can be used to position
                    shop towels into the oil drain holes
                    <xref refid="f03"/>. This step will enable the recovery of a snap rings or pieces if they become
                    dislodged during the injector removal process.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The shop cloth towels can be positioned without the removal of glow plugs and buss bar.</para>
                    <para>Repeat this procedure for each injector assembly.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f02" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/D08107.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Location of Oil Drain Hole to Glow Plug</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Oil Drain Hole</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Glow Plug</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f03" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/D08108.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Positioning Shop Towels into Oil Drain Holes with a Screwdriver</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the injector assembly has been removed from the engine, verify snap ring is in
                    place on injector hold down bolt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If snap ring or a piece of snap ring is missing from injector hold down assembly, it must be
                        located prior to removing any shop towels.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Failure to account for all snap rings and / or pieces prior to placing vehicle back in service
                        can cause engine damage. A missing snap ring can be ingested into the lube oil system causing
                        severe damage to internal engine components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of the oil pan assembly will be necessary to recover missing snap ring(s) if not
                    found under the valve cover. Once all snap rings are accounted for. shop towels can be pulled out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that all oil drain holes are clear before installing valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure must be followed for any injector assembly that is being removed for service or
                        replacement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
