<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-12-01 - In Chassis Cleaning Procedure for Vehicle Cooling Package for All International&#174; Models
        Except 3000RE Bus (Note: For 3000RE Model Refer to TSI-98-12-18)
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>In Chassis Cleaning Procedure for Vehicle Cooling Package for All International&#174; Models Except
                3000RE Bus (Note: For 3000RE Model Refer to TSI-98-12-18)
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The performance and life of heat exchangers are significantly affected by the proper scheduled
                    maintenance of the system. If an engine overheats or low engine power occurs, visually inspect the
                    radiator core and charge air cooler fins for signs of dirt or debris. Fluid leaks greater than
                    seepage can cause the charge air cooler or radiator fin clogging.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Engine compartment fluid leaks should be repaired as soon as possible to prevent charge
                            air cooler clogging.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following procedure is recommended as part of the scheduled maintenance program to ensure road
                    dirt and debris are removed from the cooling systems to insure optimum performance.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t021201">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="colspec0" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="3.26in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.29in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>SG13005</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Simple Green Cleaner</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1 Gal.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Deck Sprayer with Flexible Extension Wand and Fan Tip</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Pressure Washer or Steam Cleaner</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Garden Hose with Pistol Grip Nozzle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Extendable Technicians Mirror</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Flashlight</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Side by Side or Over-Under Charge Air Cooler and Radiator Assemblies</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is equipped with Air Conditioning, pressure wash or steam clean the
                    condensor from the front of the vehicle. Then move the AC condensor out of position without
                    disconnecting the refrigeration lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix Simple Green cleaner in a 50/50 mixture with water in the sprayer tank.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray the front of the charge air cooler and radiator with the Simple Green cleaning
                    solution. Allow the cleaning solution to soak 20 to 30 minutes. Additional cleaning solution may be
                    applied to heavily plugged areas.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not spray the charge air cooler or radiator fins at an angle as fin damage may occur and
                        reduce cooling efficiency. Use caution and maintain distance from the cooling module with the
                        pressure washer or steam cleaner to prevent cooling module fin damage.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the soak period, pressure wash or steam clean the cooling package from the front
                    of the vehicle. Thoroughly clean each row of fins slowly vertically then horizontally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the cooling module with the garden hose and nozzle from the front side. Spray
                    water at a 45 degree angle or less to dislodge and rinse debris from the charge air cooler. Inspect
                    the fins with the technicians mirror and a flashlight to insure adequate cleaning. If areas were
                    missed, spot clean those areas following the above procedure Steps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the AC condensor.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Front to Back Charge Air Cooler and Radiator Assemblies</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is equipped with air conditioning, pressure wash or steam clean the
                    condensor from the front of the vehicle. Then move the AC condensor out of position without
                    disconnecting the refrigeration lines.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the CAC unit from the vehicle and plug the CAC hoses and CAC inlets to prevent
                    debris from entering.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix Simple Green cleaner in a 50/50 mixture with water in the sprayer tank.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray the front of the charge air cooler and radiator with Simple Green cleaning
                    solution. Allow the cleaning solution to soak 20 to 30 minutes. Additional cleaning solution may be
                    applied to heavily plugged areas.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not spray the charge air cooler or radiator fins at an angle as fin damage may occur and
                        reduce cooling efficiency. Use caution and maintain distance from the cooling module with the
                        pressure washer or steam cleaner to prevent cooling module fin damage.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the soak period, pressure wash or steam clean the charge air cooler and radiator
                    from the front of the vehicle. Thoroughly clean each row of fins slowly vertically then
                    horizontally.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the charge air cooler and radiator with the garden hose and nozzle from the front
                    side. Spray water at a 45 degree angle or less to dislodge and rinse debris from the cooling module
                    cores. Inspect the fins with the technicians mirror and the flashlight to insure adequate cleaning.
                    If areas were missed, spot clean those areas following the above procedure Steps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the CAC unit and the AC condensor.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
