<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-12-06 - Vocational Lower Water Inlet Tube Available</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021206" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-12-06</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Vocational Lower Water Inlet Tube Available</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Vehicles involved in snow plowing operations where the engine is operating under full load may
                    experience lower radiator hose contact with the front engine crossmember. A new lower water inlet
                    tube is available that increases I-6 water inlet to engine front crossmember clearance an additional
                    0.4 inch.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>3574645C1 - Water inlet tube</para>
            <para>1817974C1 - Water inlet gasket</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury from hot coolant and steam, always allow an engine to cool before
                        performing cooling system repairs. Once the engine has cooled, slowly loosen the pressure cap,
                        then pause for a moment to allow any residual pressure to escape. Continue to unscrew cap and
                        remove only after pressure in cooling system is fully released.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain coolant from radiator and engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all hoses from the engine water inlet.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove engine water inlet.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the mounting surface on the engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Move makeup line fittings from old water inlet to new water inlet duplicating fitting
                    orientation and sealing pipe tapers with Teflon tape as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new gasket and new water inlet on the engine and torque bolts to 18 ft-lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hoses on the new engine water inlet.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refill to proper fill level with correct coolant.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start and operate engine until it reaches normal operating temperature.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Let engine cool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Observe coolant reservoir for proper coolant level and adjust as needed.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
