<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-13-03 - Detroit Diesel Optimized Idle System Faulting Out when used with Eaton Fuller Lightning
        Transmission Models FRLO/F-xx410C/T2
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-13-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Detroit Diesel Optimized Idle System Faulting Out when used with Eaton Fuller Lightning
                Transmission Models FRLO/F-xx410C/T2
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Detroit Diesel</vendor>
                <vendor>Eaton Fuller</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>TSI 02-13-03 - Detroit Diesel Optimized Idle System Faulting Out when used with Eaton Fuller
                Lightning Transmission Models FRLO/F-xx410C/T2
            </stitle>
            <title>Eaton Fuller Transmissions TMIB-0119</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Bulletin Type:</emph>
                Service Information
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Topic:</emph>
                Detroit Diesel Optimized Idle W/ Lightning
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Affected Models:</emph>
                All Lightning models, FRLO/F-xx4l 00 / T2 with Detroit Diesel Optimized Idle system.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Issue/Background:</emph>
                Driver complaints of the Optimized Idle system faulting out during automatic engine crank sequence. The
                transmission may log active fault code 35 (SID 231, FMI 2) or the engine may log fault code 74 (PID 070,
                FMI 4). This complaint is caused when the Optimized Idle system is active and a non- zero output shaft
                speed is received but the park brake digital input is grounded. (speed and brake sensor do
                <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                agree). Lightning model transmissions broadcast unfiltered output speed information over the SAE J1939
                data link. When the vehicle is stopped, non-zero output shaft readings of 3-5 mph can be produced during
                engine crank when normal oscillation of the transmission output shaft occurs in combination with partial
                alignment of the speed sensor and tone wheel.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Correction/Action:</emph>
                To correct this complaint it may be necessary to re-configure the Vehicle Speed Sensor (VSS) used by the
                Optimized Idle system. A separate speed sensor must be added and hard wired to the engine. The VSS
                provides vehicle speed information to the engine ECM and is required for Optimized Idle. It must be
                installed so it can sense low road speed but not trigger false speed when the vehicle is not moving.
            </para>
            <para>The following actions have been effective to correct these VSS / transmission / Optimized Idle system
                issues:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">VSS configuration, two options are available.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">(most effective) Make sure the transmission output bearing cover has provisions for
                        both; push-in style (non-adjustable) and thread-in style (adjustable) output speed sensors.
                        Reference Lightning Illustrated Parts List (TRIP-0586) for specific bearing cover P/N'S. A
                        push-in style speed sensor must be installed specifically for use by the Lightning transmission.
                        A second adjustable thread-in speed sensor must be added to provide VSS information for the
                        Optimized Idle system. The second sensor can be adjusted by increasing the air gap as required
                        so the Optimized Idle system does not fault out.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">(effective) Make sure the transmission output bearing cover has provisions for two
                        push-in style (non-adjustable) output speed sensors. A push-in style speed sensor must be
                        installed specifically for use by the Lightning transmission. A second low-output/low gain
                        push-in speed sensor (Eaton P/N A-7421) must be added to provide VSS information for the
                        Optimized Idle system. Reference Lightning Illustrated Parts List (TRIP-0586) for specific
                        bearing cover P/N's.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Engine Configuration for Transmission _ ID: The transmission ID must be set at #0 -
                    Manual. This configuration will allow transmission and engine communication over J1939 but force the
                    engine to use the separate (hard-wired) speed sensor for engine VSS information.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Warranty Statement:</emph>
                The above transmission configuration changes are required to allow the DDEC Optimized Idle system to
                operate correctly. Eaton does not accept any responsibility for transmission failures or costs
                associated with changes to the transmission to accommodate this vehicle-related system. Please contact
                Detroit Diesel for technical assistance for any issues regarding the Optimized Idle system.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
