<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-15-01 - Fuel Tanks and Fuels</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021501" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-15-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FUEL TANKS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Fuel Tanks and Fuels</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage or personal injury, or both, possibly death, do not perform any
                            service on the fuel system in the presence of open flames, intense heat, sparks, lighted
                            cigarettes, or similar hazards in your work area.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Proper fuel tank preventive maintenance is required to maintain maximum engine performance.
                    Specifically, vehicle operators should:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Use only a known good quality of Grade No. 1-D or Grade No. 2-D diesel fuel.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Purchase only from reputable suppliers who sell large amounts of diesel fuel.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>A premium grade of Grade No. 1-D or Grade No. 2-D diesel fuel that meets Engine
                            Manufacturer's Association (EMA) spec. FQP-1A may also be used. It has a minimum Cetane
                            number of 50 that provides better cold weather performance and enhanced lubricity
                            characteristics for improved fuel system durability.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Keep fuel tanks topped off with fuel to reduce condensation due to temperature and
                            humidity changes.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If vehicles are operated infrequently, consider adding an algaecide and a bactericide to
                            the fuel to retard microbial growth.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If on-site fuel storage and dispensing equipment is used:</para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Keep storage tanks full and use up fuel frequently (diesel fuel degrades over
                                    time).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Consider adding an algaecide and a bactericide to the fuel to retard microbial
                                    growth.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Use a high quality filter in the fuel dispensing line.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Inspect vehicle fuel tanks periodically for evidence of contamination. Particularly
                            inspect for rust in steel tanks.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
            <stitle>TSI 02-15-01 - Fuel Tanks and Fuels</stitle>
            <title>PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>If interior fuel tank contamination is found, thorough steam cleaning is recommended. Steel tanks
                    with fine interior surface rust can be steam cleaned. However, steel fuel tanks should be replaced
                    if interior flaking or deep pitting due to rust is found.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Fuel Types Permitted</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">International Engines require Grade No. 1-D or Grade No. 2-D diesel fuel, with or
                        without EMA spec. FQP-1A designation.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">International Engines require fuel with a minimum Cetane number of 45.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">International Engines require that fuel sulfur content be no higher than 0.05%.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Fuels sold as heating or furnace oil must not be used in International Engines.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Diesel fuels blended with used engine oil, gasoline, gasohol or alcohol must not be
                        used in International Engines.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">See Figures below on the use of Biodiesel fuels in International Engines.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Refer to other diesel engine manufacturers fuel requirements for fuels to be used in
                        their respective engines.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0215011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0215011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="592px" resolution="300"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0215012" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0215012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="592px" resolution="300"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0215013" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0215013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="472px" resolution="300"/>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
