<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-16-02 - Environmental Paint Contamination</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021602" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-16-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Environmental Paint Contamination</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>In today's environment, it's not unusual for vehicle horizontal paint surfaces to develop tiny
                    spots as a result of industrial fallout and other environmental contaminants (rail dust, brake dust,
                    other environmental sources of iron and steel dust, acid rain and other pollutants). Typically this
                    is surface rust and has come from particles lying on the painted surface and may appear on either
                    the cab or the hood. This results in oxidation that can stain the surface of the clearcoat. Upon
                    close examination (a magnifying glass may help), a small black dot often appears in the center of
                    the spot. This is the offending material that is causing the oxidation.
                </para>
                <para>International has tested and approved the following procedure that can effectively remove this
                    unsightly spotting. Buffing, polishing, sanding or painting prior to using this procedure may result
                    in unsatisfactory results.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0216021">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="5.51in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Finish Kare No. 1119 Soil and Coating Remover</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Finish Kare No. 833 Rust Remover</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>Finish Kare No. 118SC Liquid Neutralizer Concentrate Shampoo</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Finish Kare products are available from the following distributors:</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Primary:</emph>
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Crest Industries</line>
                <line>231 Larkin Williams Ind Court</line>
                <line>Fenton, MO 63026-2412</line>
                <line>1-800-733-2737</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Secondary:</emph>
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>ELW Enterprises</line>
                <line>PO Box 331</line>
                <line>Uniontown, OH 44685</line>
                <line>1-330-699-0097</line>
            </verbatim>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Manufacturer:</emph>
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Finish Kare Products, Inc.</line>
                <line>1750 Floradale Ave</line>
                <line>South El Monte, CA 91733-3406</line>
                <line>1-888-346-5273</line>
            </verbatim>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury, wear eye protection, rubber gloves and protective clothing.
                        Carefully follow manufacturer's recommended application procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash the vehicle to remove unwanted dirt and dust, and then proceed as follows:</para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>DO NOT allow the mixture to dry or streak down the side of the vehicle.</para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mix Finish Kare #1119 Soil and Coating Remover, 1 part of #1119 to 4 parts of COLD
                        water. Prepare 1-2 gallons as needed.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a dry, clean wash mitt and apply the mixture to areas where spots have occurred.
                        Lightly rub the surface with the mixture for 5 to 10 minutes depending upon the degree of
                        spotting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rinse thoroughly with cold water.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the vehicle is clean and dry.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using a dry, clean wash mitt or sponge, apply Finish Kare #833 Rust Remover to the
                        surface, one panel at a time. Do not use the same wash mitt as used in step 1.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Lightly rub the surface with the Rust Remover for 5 to 10 minutes depending upon the
                        degree of spotting.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the surface with a strong jet of cold water to completely remove the particles.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the particles are not completely removed, repeat steps 1 and 2.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the iron particles are removed, apply Finish Kare #118SC Liquid Neutralizer
                    Concentrate Shampoo or equivalent (The Neutralizer Concentrate is a heavy-duty shampoo). This is
                    required to neutralize the removal action.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mix the concentrate as 1 part concentrate to 100 parts water.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply the neutralizer shampoo with a clean mitt or sponge.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rinse with clean cold water and dry vehicle.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If fine scratches appear on the surface, use an available aftermarket light "finishing"
                    compound with a foam pad to remove scratches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Polish as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Frequent washing and waxing can help prevent further spotting.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
