<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 02-16-05 - Cab Door Opening, Cracking In Upper Rear Corner</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi021605" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>02-16-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 2002</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Cab Door Opening, Cracking In Upper Rear Corner</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/01/1999</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/01/1999</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/01/1999</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Reports have been received that repeated door closings on the above models can produce cracking of
                    the upper rear door opening along the drip rail. In extreme cases, cracking may continue down the
                    glamour edge of the opening from the drip rail. See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216051">Figure 1</hotlnk>. This process is to be applied only to those cabs,
                    driver and/or passenger sides that exhibit any of these cracks.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0216051" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Arrows Designate Areas Where Cracks may Occur</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0216051">
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.93*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.52*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.55*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3577235C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Left Side Bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3577236C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Right Side Bracket</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>TSI 02-16-05 - Cab Door Opening, Cracking In Upper Rear Corner</stitle>
            <title>Vehicle Preparation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prior to beginning the actual repair, make certain that a suitable, non-flammable
                    barrier is in place to assure that grinding dust and sparks, as well as welding sparks do not enter
                    cab and ignite flammable materials such as seats and floor mats.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull door opening trim away from opening flange at least six inches either side of area
                    where bracket is to be welded.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent damage to vehicle modules/computer circuitry disconnect both the positive and
                        negative battery cables from the battery before welding on the vehicle. Attach the welder ground
                        cable as close as possible to the part being welded.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Alwats wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to prevent personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect positive and negative battery terminal and all electronic grounding circuits
                    in accordance with TSI 98-08-01 prior to welding.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="5">
            <stitle>TSI 02-16-05 - Cab Door Opening, Cracking In Upper Rear Corner</stitle>
            <title>Bracket Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position bracket (left or right) in place at door opening corner
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216052">(Figure 2)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0216052" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216052.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="232px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Bracket in Position</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect fit of bracket. Make certain that there isn&#x2019;t any sealant in corner
                    preventing the bracket from seating properly. If the angle of flanges prevents the bracket from
                    seating tightly into corner, bend flanges slightly to minimize air gap between bracket and door
                    opening. Clamp bracket in place
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216052">(Figure 2)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark all twelve holes in bracket onto the door opening using a marking pencil. These
                    marks locate the areas where puddle welds are required to attach the bracket to the cab skin
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216053">(Figure 3)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0216053" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216053.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Marking Weld Positions</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bracket and assure that all welding areas are properly marked.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If crack has progressed from horizontal to vertical and is visible at rear edge of
                    opening
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216051">(see Figure 1)</hotlnk>, remove any sealant from cracked area and grind
                    paint &#188; inch back from cracked corner.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara></specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grind paint from the marked areas to assure good welding. Use a small diameter disk to
                    minimize unnecessary removal of paint or metal thickness
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216054">(Figure 4)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0216054" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216054.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Preparing Surface for Welding</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refit bracket to opening and make sure that no cab paint is showing through the holes in
                    the bracket. Make sure this is true of all holes, horizontal and vertical. Reclamp bracket in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use clean "C" clamp to attach bracket to door opening. Attach welder ground to "C" clamp.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Invisible ultraviolet and infrared rays emitted in welding can injure unprotected eyes and
                        skin. To avoid personal injury a welders helmet with dark colored filter lenses of the proper
                        density must be used. GTAW or TIG welding will produce intense radiation, therefore, filter
                        plate lenses of the deepest shade providing adequate visibility are recommended. It is also
                        recommended that persons working in the welding area wear flash safety glasses and protective
                        clothing.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set up MIG welder and test on similar metal thickness to assure a full puddle weld
                    between bracket and cab sheet metal without producing excessive heat to cause a burn through of the
                    sheet metal.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully weld all twelve holes in bracket to producing a full puddle weld in each
                    location. If vertical crack was observed and metal prepared per instructions in Step 5. above,
                    carefully weld edge of bracket to both sides of crack
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216055">(Figure 5)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grind weld puddles flush with bracket and dress up vertical weld if performed
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0216056">(Figure 6)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0216055" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216055.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Welding the Bracket</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0216056" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0216056.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Grinding Puddle Welds</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>TSI 02-16-05 - Cab Door Opening, Cracking In Upper Rear Corner</stitle>
            <title>Sealing and Painting</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove sealant from drip rail in area above weld if it appears to be bubbled or lifted
                    from rail. Remove only the damaged area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply Fusor T-123 sealant or equivalent to drip rail and all exposed surfaces where
                    bracket meets the sheet metal. Make sure sealant will prevent moisture from entering gap between
                    bracket and cab. Find Fusor products on ISIS supplier link.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spot paint repaired areas per Master Service Manual, Group 16, S16002, Paint and
                    Refinishing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
