<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-04-02 - Removal and Replacement of Air Tank Fittings</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi030402" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-04-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Brakes</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Removal and Replacement of Air Tank Fittings</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04091</ucode>
                <ucode>04092</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product. Please refer to the
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/030402.pdf" bookname="TSI">pdf for this TSI</exhotlnk>
                    for the Removal and Replacement Procedures.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a level surface,
                            set the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <note>
                        <para>Air tanks with fittings and valves (excluding pressure protection valve) that were
                            installed with roll wire rings can be reinstalled with flat snap rings as a substitute. If
                            the pressure protection valve was installed with a roll wire ring it must be reinstalled
                            with a roll wire ring.
                        </para>
                        <para>Air tanks with fittings and valves that were installed with flat snap rings must be
                            reinstalled with flat snap rings. Roll wire rings should not be used as a substitute.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
