<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-04-01 - New Hydraulic Disc Brake Slide Pins, Bolts, and Lubricant</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi030401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-04-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>New Hydraulic Disc Brake Slide Pins, Bolts, and Lubricant</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000FE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1998</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Effective June 3, 2002, all International Hydraulic Disc Brake vehicles began using a newly
                    designed caliper mounting slide pin and bolt configuration. The new slide pins and bolts are
                    compatible with previous production Pin Slide Brakes but have the following physical differences:
                    The new design uses fine thread, flanged head patch bolts which must be torqued to 100 ft./lbs., not
                    75 ft./lbs. and, as with the previous design, the leading pin should still be torqued first. Once
                    the new design patch bolts have been removed, the thread area should be buffed with a wire brush to
                    remove any Loctite buildup, and then a single stripe of Loctite 2440 must be applied to the threads
                    before reusing. The leading and trailing slide pins are no longer interchangeable because the
                    trailing pin now has a notched head and a rubber bushing on the pin diameter (See Bosch ZOH-T Anchor
                    Plate Repair Kits Installation Procedure below). When servicing hydraulic Pin Slide Disc Brakes,
                    International recommends that the slide pins and bolts be updated to the latest generation slide
                    pins and bolts and that the existing lubricant be cleaned from the pins and bores and replaced with
                    improved lubricant 2585384C1. It is important that the slide pins and bolts not be mixed on the same
                    axle. Both wheels on each axle must have the same type slide pins and bolts. Order one Slide Pin and
                    Bolt Repair Kit per wheel.
                </para>
                <para>The Bosch Technical Summary below describes the component and assembly torque changes.</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTICE</emph>
                    - The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Slide Pin and Bolt Repair Kit #2509252C92</emph>. Kit contains one wheel set (front or
                rear) - 2 Slide Pins, 2 Bolts, 2 Boots, and 1 Packet of improved grease
            </para>
            <para>Shell Albida PPS-1 grease, 3oz. Tube 2585384C1 (to be used when servicing Slide Pin Brakes and not
                ordering Slide Pin and Bolt Repair Kit )
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="7">
            <title>Bosch ZOH-T Anchor Plate Repair Kit Installation Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>: Because the two ZOH-T caliper pins are different from each
                    other, and it is important that they are installed in the correct anchor plate location. The
                    following diagrams show how to determine leading vs. trailing pin location for correctly installing
                    ZOH-T guide pins. Definition of anchor plate
                    <emph type="bold">LEADING</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">TRAILING</emph>
                    position: Imagine a point on the outboard surface of the rotor on the opposite side from the
                    caliper. Now rotate the rotor as if the vehicle were moving in the forward direction. The FIRST
                    mounting pin that this point passes is the
                    <emph type="bold">LEADING</emph>
                    position. The other is the
                    <emph type="bold">TRAILING</emph>
                    position.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0304011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="550px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <title>ZOH-T Caliper Mounting Bolt Styles After June 3, 2002</title>
                </para>
                <figure id="f0304012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Without Adhesive Patch</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0304013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. With Adhesive Patch</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Anchor Plate Service Repair Kit Installation Procedure</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">INFORMATION</emph>
                    - The anchor plate assembly includes lubricated floating guide pins sealed by rubber boots and
                    stainless steel slippers which protect the anchor plate pad abutments. A tie bar is used on 2x73 mm
                    pin slide disc brake only. A 2x66mm pin slide disc brake does not have a tie bar and will have
                    shorter bolts to plug the threaded holes used to mount the tie bar.
                </para>
                <para>Important notes:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Prior to June 3, 2002, the ZOPS caliper mounting
                            <emph type="bold">guide pins</emph>
                            were the
                            <emph type="bold">same</emph>
                            and used a M12x1.75x30mm course thread and heavy hex-head mounting bolt with an installation
                            torque of 75+/-5 ft-lbs.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After June 3, 2002, ZOH-T caliper mounting
                            <emph type="bold">guide pins</emph>
                            are
                            <emph type="bold">different</emph>
                            between the leading and trailing anchor plate locations. The separate pieces (guide pins and
                            bolts) are NOT individually interchangeable or backward compatible between the ZOPS and
                            ZOH-T caliper designs. This is because the mounting threads have been changed from coarse
                            (M12x1.75mm) to fine (M12x1.25mm). Also, the ZOH-T bolt is a longer (40mm) flange-head style
                            vs the ZOPS bolt which is a shorter (30mm) heavy hex-head style.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When servicing the guide pins manufactured prior to June 3, 2002 (i.e. the original ZOPS
                            caliper design),
                            <emph type="bold">it is permissible to use the ZOH-T pins and bolts as long as they are
                                changed as a set.
                            </emph>
                            However, since the ZOH-T pins are now different, it is VERY IMPORTANT that they are
                            installed in the correct anchor plate bore position as shown on the proceeding diagram. The
                            leading pin must be installed in the leading anchor plate location, and the rubber bushed
                            trailing pin must be installed in the trailing anchor plate location.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>You
                            <emph type="underscr">MUST</emph>
                            use the correct bolt
                            <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                            mounting torque with the correct pin hardware level during servicing.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Anchor Plate Assembly Repair Kit - Service Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Position vehicle on suitable floor stands and remove wheel (tire and rim).</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>A jack must never be used alone to support a vehicle while under-chassis service is being
                            performed. The jack may lower and serious personal injury could result. Always support
                            vehicle with suitable floor stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the brake hose retaining bolt attached to the caliper housing. This will
                        allow easier caliper removal and installation. (Not required on all applications)
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove lower (bottom) caliper mounting bolt securing the caliper to the anchor
                        plate.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove upper (top) caliper mounting bolt securing the caliper to the anchor plate.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Move caliper assembly away from rotor and place it in a secure location on the
                        vehicle suspension. Secure the caliper assembly with a tie wrap in place so that it does not
                        fall. Be sure brake hose or line is not kinked and does not support the weight of the caliper.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove inboard and outboard disc brake pads from anchor plate pad abutment
                        slippers.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check machined surfaces of caliper ears. If any rust or contaminants are present,
                        use a hand held wire brush to clean these surfaces. If any grease or oil is present, use solvent
                        on a clean shop cloth to remove it.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>It is important to clean those areas of the caliper, guide pins and anchor plate that
                                are in contact with the brake pads or each other.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Visually inspect caliper for leakage, damage or defects to piston boots or pistons.
                        If leakage or damage is found, repair or replace as required.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Visually inspect anchor plate for damage or defects to mating surfaces and at anchor
                        plate pad abutment slippers. IF NO damage is found, continue with step 11. If damage is found,
                        remove anchor plate and replace with ANCHOR PLATE REPLACEMENT KIT. Install anchor plate
                        replacement kit and move to step 19.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove and discard caliper guide pins, guide pin boots and caliper mounting bolts.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>: See "Information" section regarding pin differences
                        between the ZOPS and ZOH-T caliper designs.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>DO NOT cut, grind or modify in any way, the guide pins or vehicle components when
                                attempting guide pin removal or installation. Brake assembly or component functional
                                degradation may occur if altered in any way. If ample clearance does not exist to remove
                                and install the caliper guide pins, then removal of the anchor plate is necessary for
                                proper guide pin service. Refer to service manual for anchor plate removal and
                                installation.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the anchor plate tie bar bolts that are opposite the caliper guide pins.
                        (ONLY ON 2X73 CALIPER ASSEMBLIES). This will aid in the new guide pin installation.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Visually inspect anchor plate guide pin bores for rust or contamination. If
                        contamination is found, clean anchor plate guide pin bores with wire brush and solvent. Dry with
                        compressed air.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lightly lubricate guide pin boot ridges with a thin film of Albida PPS1 Grease
                        provided in packets contained in the service kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install guide pin boots onto both leading and trailing pins.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Completely grease anchor plate guide pin bore surfaces with Albida PPS1 Grease
                        provided in packets contained in the service kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Completely grease the leading and trailing guide pins with Albida PPS1 Grease
                        provided in packets contained in the service kit.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install leading pin into anchor plate leading position.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>: See diagram for determining "leading" position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install rubber bushed trailing pin into the anchor plate trailing position.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>: See diagram for determining the "trailing" position.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Make sure that the guide pin heads, mounting bolts, and mating caliper surfaces are
                        clean of any grease or foreign matter. Use clean shop cloth and solvent to remove foreign
                        debris.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT NOTE</emph>: Do not allow cleaning solvent to come into contact with
                        guide pin boots.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall inner and outer pads onto the anchor plate abutments.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If re-using caliper mounting bolts, See "Caliper Mounting Preparation Procedure" in
                            Appendix A before proceeding with step 21.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align flat on upper (top) guide pin head with the flat on caliper upper (top) guide
                        pin boss. Be careful when positioning caliper over the disc brake pads, rotor and upper (top)
                        guide pin head to avoid tearing, cutting or dislodging piston boots or guide pin boots.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install upper (top) flange head mounting bolt FINGER tight securing the caliper to
                        the anchor plate.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Align the flat on the lower pin flange and then carefully rotate the caliper closed
                        and install lower mounting bolt FINGER tight. Do not allow the brake line hose to become pinched
                        or kinked.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Always tighten the leading caliper mounting bolt first.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the leading ZOH-T caliper mounting bolt to 93 - 107 ft-lbs. (126 - 145
                        N-m).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten the trailing ZOH-T caliper mounting bolt to 93 - 107 ft-lbs. (126 - 145
                        N-m).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Reminder: If either caliper mounting bolt has been loosened, it is important to
                        tighten the mounting bolts in the proper sequence shown in steps 24 and 25. Increased brake drag
                        may result from not tightening in proper sequence.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall brake hose retaining clip bolt and torque to manufacturer service manual
                        specifications.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten anchor plate tie bar bolts. Torque to 40-50 ft-lb (54-68 N-m).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall wheel (tire and rim) on vehicle and torque wheel attachment nuts per
                        vehicle manufacturer recommendation. Remove floor stands.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Before starting engine, depress brake pedal several times to reseat the brake pads
                        to the rotor. Check the master cylinder reservoir and fill if necessary. Consult service manual
                        for proper brake fluid.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After brake service, be sure to test brakes prior to returning vehicle into service
                        to ensure a firm pedal during brake application.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>APPENDIX A: Recommended Procedure for Re-using the Caliper Mounting Bolts</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Visually inspect the removed bolts for any thread damage, contamination, or
                        corrosion. If damaged replace.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Visually inspect the caliper mounting bolts for a white/yellow residue resulting
                        from a previously applied Loctite adhesive patch, as shown in Figure 4. If no patch appears skip
                        Step 3 and continue on to Step 4.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0304014" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Used Caliper Mounting Bolt with Adhesive Patch on the Threads</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Using a steel brush buff the adhesive residue from the bolt threads, as shown in
                        Figure 5. Buff ONLY the area where the adhesive is present so as not to remove the protective
                        black coating on the remainder of the threads. Be sure to completely remove the existing
                        adhesive so that bare steel is now showing where the adhesive once was, as shown in Figure 6.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0304015" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Use A Steel Brush To Buff Away Existing Adhesive Residue</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0304016" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Once Adhesive Is Removed A Clean Shiny Steel Surface Should Remain</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply a small patch of liquid Loctite 2440 to the area indicated in Figure 4. For
                        best Loctite 2440 performance, surfaces should be clean and free of grease. Product should be
                        applied to the bolt in sufficient quantity
                        <emph type="bold">to fill all engaged threads</emph>; develops useable strength within 1 hour
                        and full strength at room temperature in 3 hours.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0304017" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0304017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="208px"
                             scalefitheight="176px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Liquid Loctite 2440 Applied to Clean Threads for Reinstallation</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Return to Step 21 of Anchor plate Repair Procedure above.</para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
