<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-05-02R - Douglas Autotech Tilt Steering Column Lower Bearing Realignment</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi030502R" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-05-02R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>03-05-02</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>November, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Steering</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Douglas Autotech Tilt Steering Column Lower Bearing Realignment</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>05708</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product. Please refer to the
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/030502r.pdf" bookname="TSI">pdf for this TSI</exhotlnk>
                    for the Douglas AutoTech Bulletin TIB Number 20053003, which provides information on the Steering
                    Column Lower Bearing Realignment.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a level surface,
                            set the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When performing the following procedure, save the pinch bolt, washer, and nut for
                            re-installation.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>If the pinch bolt, flat washer, and nut have signs of damage, they must be replaced with
                            SAE Grade 8 components to avoid property damage, personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
