<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-09-01R - Grille Removal</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi030901" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-09-01R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>03-09-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>May, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT END SHEET METAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Grille Removal</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>04/23/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The 8600 utilizes double-sided tape along the upper edge of the grille to prevent the grille from
                    warping when exposed to high temperatures. The tape is applied in the assembly plant and fully cures
                    in three days. Removal of the grille after the tape adhesive cures, without damaging the grille, can
                    be difficult, particularly in cold weather. This TSI is being revised to update the size and
                    configuration of the double-sided tape.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>3M Tape Removal Kit #07498</para>
            <para>3M Double Sided Tape #VHB 4956, 3/8" wide, International Part Number 3585047C1</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent vehicle damage and personal injury, park the vehicle on a level surface, set the
                        parking brake, chock the wheels, and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the vehicle in a warm environment. Heat helps to reduce the adhesion forces of the
                    tape.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the eight "star" fasteners from the grille. See Figure 1.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the hood and apply heat to underside of the hood for 3-4 minutes. Make certain that
                    the heat is applied where the hood overlaps with the top of the grille. Too much heat will discolor
                    the hood and/or grille. Keep the heat gun moving. See Figure 1 for approximate location of tape.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and position yourself in front of the hood facing the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Firmly grasp the lower edge of the grille and pull outward/upward as if pivoting the
                    grille about the upper edge where it meets the hood. Since the tape has such high retaining force, a
                    minimum of two people lifting is recommended to maintain an even force across the bottom of the
                    grille. Pull slowly!
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the grille and hood have separated, clean the tape residue from the hood and grille
                    using 3M Tape Removal Kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut one 41" piece of 3/8" wide 3M Double Sided Adhesive Tape.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the tape on the hood. The tape should be centered on the hood and placed one inch
                    forward of the rear grille contour. See Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the paper backing from one side of the tape and place it on the hood. Firmly
                    press on the backside of the tape to seat it against the surface of the hood.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the grille into position against the hood.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not remove the protective paper from the second surface of the tape!</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain that the grille is in the proper position with mounting holes aligned and
                    mark its location by placing masking tape on the hood and grille at several locations. Mark the tape
                    so the grille can be precisely located once the adhesive tape is exposed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protective paper from the second surface of the adhesive tape.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully locate the grille slightly above its proper location on the hood and lower it
                    slowly into position against the hood. Make certain that the locating marks previously made on the
                    masking tape are in the proper location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Press the grille down firmly against the hood. Apply approximately 20 pounds of force
                    along the grille area above the tape.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the 8 "star" fasteners removed earlier.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f030901" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0309011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="336px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Grille Removal</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
