<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-09-02 - Fender Paint Surface With Star Cracks</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi030902" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-09-02</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>99-09-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>February, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT END SHEET METAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Fender Paint Surface With Star Cracks</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5900</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>07/01/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>07/01/1996</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>04/01/2001</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Star cracks, in the painted surface of hand sprayed fiberglass fenders, can occur when stones or
                    other solid debris thrown by the tires strike the inner (underside) fender surface. To prevent star
                    cracking before it occurs or after repairs have been made, it is recommended that adhesive-backed
                    urethane sheet material, International Part Number 991917C1, or undercoating, 3M Part Number
                    051135-08881, be applied to the inner fender surfaces.
                </para>
                <para>Prior to applying the urethane sheeting or undercoating, the inner surfaces of the fender must be
                    prepared. For maximum performance, the surfaces should be cleaned and primed using primer wash with
                    Scotch-Brite&#8482; scrub pads and clean rags, or cleaned with solvent and brush primed. The
                    recommended primer wash is Ashland Chemical, Inc' s PLIOSEAL&#8482; 5637A.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Urethane Sheeting</emph>
                    </para>
                </specpara>
                <para>Before installing the urethane sheeting, determine the size and shape of the area to be covered.
                    Cut the urethane sheet to fit.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Do not remove the protective paper backing until you are ready to install onto the
                            prepared surface. Exposing the adhesive may cause contamination and affect the maximum bond
                            strength.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Move the fitted urethane sheet into contact with the prepared inner fender surface (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0309021">Figure 1</hotlnk>) and slowly peel off the protective paper backing to
                    minimize the formation of air bubbles, taking care not to touch the adhesive while applying the
                    material. Maximum adhesion will be obtained if a small firm roller is used to exert additional
                    pressure on the urethane sheet after the application is complete.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0309021" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0309021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Apply Urethane Sheet to Underside of Fender (Arrow)</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">3M Undercoating</emph>
                    </para>
                </specpara>
                <para>Prepare the inner fender surface as described in the previous section. Apply 3M undercoating Part
                    Number 051135-08881 to a thickness of .030 inch. Approximately 5 aerosol cans of 3M undercoating
                    will be needed per vehicle. Allow 24 hours cure time before placing the vehicle in service.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
