<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-12-17 - Optimized Radiator Life</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi031217" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-12-17</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>November, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Optimized Radiator Life</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to the above listed vehicles with pre-2002 emission engines.</para>
                <para>Radiator life is dependent on the effectiveness of its mounting to the chassis and its plumbing
                    connections to the engine. Poor isolation from these contact points can induce severe vibrations and
                    shock loads into the radiator's structure. The following are some critical areas to inspect on a
                    regular basis to assure long radiator life.
                </para>
                <para>While the effectiveness of the radiator mounting protects its structural integrity, its cooling
                    effectiveness is dependent on its cleanliness and its ability to transfer heat. See
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/021201.htm" bookname="TSI">TSI-02-12-01</exhotlnk>
                    for instructions on keeping the radiator clear for good air passage through the core area.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Radiator Mounting Isolator, 3560217C1</para>
            <para>Stay Rod Bushing, 2038724C1</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Upper Radiator Hose Mounting</title>
                <para>The upper radiator pipe and hose were originally a metal pipe with a 90&#176; bend and a straight
                    coupling hose to the radiator inlet. The pipe now has a 47&#176; bend and is inserted into a
                    coupling hose with a 43&#176; bend. See FIGURE 1. The change dates depend on the model of the
                    vehicle, but most were changed between October 1995 and January 1996. The last model to change was
                    the 2000 Series with the N-14 Engine in January 2002. Refer to
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/021217.htm" bookname="TSI">TSI 02-12-17</exhotlnk>
                    for more detailed information.
                </para>
                <para>An important detail of assembly is the amount of insertion the upper pipe and radiator inlet neck
                    make into the 43&#176; coupling hose. At their closest point inside the coupler there should be a
                    minimum of 1 inch between the upper radiator pipe and radiator neck. Any contact in this area will
                    affect radiator durability.
                </para>
                <para>Production offered a choice between Premium Rubber or Silicone Hose. The Premium Rubber Hose can
                    be identified by its black color and the Silicone Hose by its blue color. Both of these hose types
                    provide long life, but it is important to check the hoses. The hoses should be checked for cuts,
                    cracks, and for becoming hard. If any of these conditions appear the hose should be replaced. The
                    Premium Rubber Hose is more flexible than the Silicone Hose when used for the upper radiator
                    connection. The part number for the 43-degree Premium Rubber Hose is 485794C1.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0312171" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0312171.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                             scalefitheight="432px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Radiator Isolators</title>
                <para>The radiator isolators shown in FIGURE 2 are necessary to stabilize the radiator and isolate it
                    from various road shock inputs and/or engine vibrations. It is also important to check the condition
                    of these isolators. If the isolators show signs of wear or damage they should be replaced. The part
                    number of the radiator mounting isolator is 3560217C1. This isolator part number consists of
                    two-rubber isolators bonded to the two steel washers, and the steel stop as one unit. It is also
                    important to check the stay rod bushings for wear or damage. If damaged the bushings should be
                    replaced. The part number for the stay rod bushings is 2038724C1.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0312172" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0312172.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="432px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
