<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-12-16 - Rear Oil Seal Carrier And Rear Seal Carrier Gasket Material For International Inline 6
        Cylinder Engines Starting At Model Year 1994 Through 2003 With Serial Number 850,000 And Above
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi031216" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>03-12-16</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>02-12-25</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>September 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Rear Oil Seal Carrier And Rear Seal Carrier Gasket Material For International Inline 6 Cylinder
                Engines Starting At Model Year 1994 Through 2003 With Serial Number 850,000 And Above
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530E</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>HT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>The International&#174; 530E With Green Diesel Technology&#174;</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI replaces 02-12-25 and adds an additional part number 1823733C3 for the rear PTO seal
                    carrier.
                </para>
                <para>The rear oil seal carrier and rear seal carrier gasket have now eliminated the paper gasket and
                    flat flange oil seal carrier for production and service.
                </para>
                <para>The new machined groove in the oil seal carrier gasket flange, for push-in place seal, is more
                    effective for sealing. The push-in place seal will ensure accurate alignment during assembly and
                    adequate clamp load on the seal. A machined surface has been added to the bottom of the carrier to
                    ensure a proper sealing surface for the oil pan.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>When installing the oil seal carrier to the crankcase, the carrier must be flush with the
                            crankcase pan rail.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>When the old style oil seal carrier and paper rear seal carrier gasket is removed for any reason,
                    it is recommended to replace with the new oil seal carrier with machined groove gasket flange and
                    push-in place rear seal carrier gasket.
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>New part number for the standard oil seal carrier, 1815699C3</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>New part number for the rear PTO oil seal carrier, 1823733C3</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>New part number for the rear seal carrier gasket 1841974C1. This new gasket works with
                            both new seal carriers.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>See EGES-210 Service Manual for step-by-step replacement procedures.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
