<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-12-09 - Inability to Run an Air Management Test</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI031209" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>03-12-09</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Inability to Run an Air Management Test</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>HT530
                    <snrange>1319430</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to HT530 I-6 engines equipped with the EVRT&#174; Electronically Controlled
                    Turbocharger beginning with engine serial number 1319430.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                            sure the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before
                            doing diagnostic or service procedures on the engine or vehicle. Read all safety
                            instructions in the "Safety Information" section of the service manual for this engine.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Service Technicians diagnosing problems related to the EVRT&#174; Electronically Controlled
                    Turbocharger are often called on to run an air management test. This test has been available since
                    February 2003. The air management test will not run if the EVRT&#174; Electronically Controlled
                    Turbocharger equipped engine being evaluated has a calibration prior to PVD6AU01.
                </para>
                <para>Check which calibration is in the Engine Control Module (ECM) by opening MasterDiagnostics&#174;
                    software and click VIN+ on the tool bar.
                </para>
                <para>The calibration will be listed as the reference number in one of the windows that comes up.</para>
                <para>If the engine calibration is required to run this test, the service technician, during
                    programming, must check the box that asks if the ECM is being replaced. Then, prior calibrations
                    will automatically update to the latest available when the programming is completed.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Initiate Air Management Test</title>
            <figure id="d31201" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/D31201A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Air Management Test</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This test can only be done with the Electronic Service Tool (EST) and MasterDiagnostic&#174; software
                is required. The Standard Test must be done before doing the Air Management Test.
            </para>
            <para>The Air Management Test allows the technician to check the operation of the air management system and
                the turbocharger control valve.
            </para>
            <para>During the Air Management Test, the ECM commands the turbocharger through a step test sequence so
                technicians can determine if actuators and the Air Management System are performing as expected.
            </para>
            <para>When the test is done, the ECM restores normal engine operation.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Diagnostics from the menu bar.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select Key-On Engine-Running Tests from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Select I6 with EVRT from the drop down menu.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From Key On Engine Running Diagnostics menu, select Air Management Test, and click run
                    to start the test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The air management test will perform the following steps:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Turbocharger duty offset will go to 0.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine RPM will increase above idle and the turbocharger vanes will open completely. The
                        expected Manifold Absolute Pressure (MAP) sensor reading at this point is 0 or very low psi.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM will command medium duty cycle, partially closing the vanes in the turbocharger. The
                        expected MAP sensor reading at this point is greater than 1 psi.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ECM will command high duty cycle, fully closing the vanes in the turbocharger. The
                        expected MAP sensor reading at this point is greater than 4 psi.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE: The ECM will not log Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC) during the air
                            management test. Changes in the MAP reading during the test indicates that the vanes in the
                            turbocharger are operational.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The engine RPM will return to idle.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Using the VGT section of the Key-On Engine-Running Diagnostics; allows turbocharger control to
                        be stepped manually through each cycle.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
