<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-12-10R - Belt Wear On International VT 365, T 444E, DT 466, and 530 Engines</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi031210R" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-12-10R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>03-12-10</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>October, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Belt Wear On International VT 365, T 444E, DT 466, and 530 Engines</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>530
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>T 444E
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>02/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>VT 365
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>International equipped vehicles that exhibit main drive belt wear on the front or rear edge of the
                    fan belt may be experiencing alignment issues. Items to inspect are the alternator mounting, fan hub
                    and automatic belt tensioner.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a level surface,
                            set the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>In general, placing a simple straight edge across the face of the alternator pulley can check belt
                    alignment. Place the straight edge on the face of the alternator pulley and rotate it up to the fan
                    hub pulley. The belt should maintain the same distance from the straight edge at the fan hub pulley
                    as it is from the alternator pulley. The same procedure can be used to verify alignment to the
                    tensioner, water pump pulley, and crankshaft pulley. Using this method will determine which pulley
                    and/or drive system is out of alignment and needs adjustment using one of the following
                    procedure(s).
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Alternator Mounting Alignment</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the drive belt from the alternator pulley.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the top mounting bolt of the alternator.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Loosen the lower mounting bolt of the alternator. Make sure the bolt is loose enough
                        that tapping the bushing rearward will provide clearance between the bushing and the mounting
                        bracket.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten and torque the top mounting bolt to 81-95 Nm (60-70 lbf-ft).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten and torque the lower mounting bolt to 81-95 Nm (60-70 lbf-ft).</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the fan belt. Make sure the belt is properly seated in the pulley grooves.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Fan Hub (water pump mounted on V8s) with Viscous Fan Drive, Horton EC-450 Fan Drive, and
                    BorgWarner Fan Drive (SFN 03-12 discusses Horton Drive Master mounting instructions)
                </title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the belt from the fan pulley.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the four bolts holding the pulley to the fan hub, remove pulley.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Inspect the fan hub to make sure the bearings have not worked rearward toward the
                        engine. If the bearing has moved, replace the hub and inspect the vehicle for an engine or
                        driveline vibration.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the fan hub does not need to be replaced, reassemble the hub and look for other
                        component misalignment.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Automatic Fan Belt Tensioner</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the fan belt.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the following tensioner component.</para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Rust between the arm and the base</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Rotation of the pulley and pivot of the tensioner arm must be free and smooth
                            without any noise or roughness
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Pulley for excessive wear</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Looseness in the pulley bearings</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Wear at the arm to base joint</para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Replace tensioner if any of the above conditions are found.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the fan belt.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
