<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 03-16-04 - Seat Belt "Reverse Lockup"</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi031604" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>03-16-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 2003</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Seat Belt "Reverse Lockup"</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Due to certain conditions, which can only be met prior to or during initial seat belt
                    installation, self-retracting seat belt assemblies can experience what is known as "Reverse
                    Lock-up". When it occurs, the belt cannot be pulled out of the retractor and appears to be "locked".
                    This condition is either caused by excessive webbing spooled into the retractor before it is
                    installed into the vehicle or the belt retractor not being in the vertical position. The seat belts
                    in International Trucks are a part of a critical occupant protection system. The individual
                    components of these safety belt systems are carefully designed, factory calibrated and tested to
                    meet exacting Federal Motor Vehicle Safety Standards. Follow the procedures to assure continued
                    compliance.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not attempt to repair a seat belt component. This action could expose the truck occupants
                        to serious injury or death in the event of a significant vehicle crash.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>To unlock an installed seat belt assembly that exhibits "Reverse Lock-up" characteristics, perform the
                following steps:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the retractor becomes locked up after installation in the vehicle,
                    <emph type="bold">verify that the retractor is mounted in the 90 degree position as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0316041">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0316042">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Firmly grasp the webbing close to the retractor as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f0316042">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0316041" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0316041.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0316042" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0316042.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull the webbing with enough force to tighten the webbing on the spool.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release the webbing. This should allow &#189;" of webbing to feed back into the
                    retractor storage spool; the retractor should unlock.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the above steps do not correct the seat belt function or if the unit continues to lockup
                        without a load, REPLACE THE ENTIRE SEAT BELT ASSEMBLY!
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>To unlock an uninstalled seat belt assembly that exhibits "Reverse Lock-up" characteristics, perform
                the following steps:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Clamp the retractor assembly in a vice at a 90 degree orientation as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0316043">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pull on the webbing with enough force to tighten the webbing on the spool.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Release the webbing. This should allow &#189;" of webbing to feed back into the retractor
                        storage spool; the retractor should unlock.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After the retractor is unlocked, pull the webbing out of the retractor, allow only 12-15" to
                        retract, and lock the Komfort Latch on the webbing as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0316044">Figure 4</hotlnk>. This will prevent the webbing from fully retracting
                        onto the spool and permitting the system to lock-up.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0316043" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0316043.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0316044" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0316044.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Some applications do not include a Komfort Latch. These units usually include a cardboard stop
                        to prevent excessive webbing from spooling back onto the retractor. This cardboard stop should
                        only be removed after the vehicle installation is complete.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
