<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-03-03 - Air Suspension Dump Operation With Dual Solenoid Control Valves</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-03-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Air Suspension Dump Operation With Dual Solenoid Control Valves</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>09/05/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>0595273</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The effective dates for the models listed above are:</para>
                <verbatim>
                    <line>Springfield Production September 5, 2003 through present</line>
                    <line>Garland Production September 7, 2003 through present</line>
                    <line>Escobedo Production September 7, 2003 through present</line>
                </verbatim>
                <para>After the above referenced dates the HPV Air Suspension Control System was revised to be
                    controlled by the ESC using two air solenoids and a shuttle valve. The revision was accompanied by
                    the changing of the 0595042 code to 0595273. The suspension input is provided by a two position,
                    bi-stable switch that has an indicator light in the upper (Dump) position. When the Air Suspension
                    Dump (ASD) switch is in the "DUMP" position, the operator is requesting the ESC to release air from
                    the air suspension. When the ASD is in the "SUSP" position, the operator is requesting the air
                    suspension to be, or remain, supplied with air pressure. When requesting suspension dump, the system
                    is applying air pressure to the Dump Control Line port of the Hadley Height Control Valve mounted
                    above the rear axle. The following will provide additional information to help the technician better
                    understand the system function to aid in the troubleshooting process.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <para>The two air solenoids mentioned above in the system description control a two position shuttle valve
                that either feeds air pressure (dump) or vents (suspension active) the control line that is connected to
                the dump port of the Hadley Control Valve. The two normally open (when no power is applied) air
                solenoids will be set to opposite states under normal key on conditions. The suspension dump operation
                will only change state when the key switch is in the run, crank, or acc position. When the key is off,
                or there is an error, both air solenoids will be de-energized. See Figure 1 for system layout and
                function.
            </para>
            <para>NORMAL OPERATION (Key On)</para>
            <para>When the ESC commands the "DUMP" operation:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The ASD solenoid A will be de-energized (open)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD solenoid B will be energized (closed)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shuttle valve passes air pressure from solenoid A to Dump Control Line</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>When the ESC commands the "SUSP" operation:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The ASD solenoid A will be energized (closed)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD solenoid B will be de-energized (open)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shuttle closes air pressure feed to Dump Control Line and vents it</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>When switching from "SUSP" to "DUMP" the suspension will dump if:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>The vehicle is moving less than the maximum allowable dump speed</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the ASD switch is in the "DUMP" position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the key is in the RUN or ACC position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the key state signal must report a good status</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And the Wheel Based Vehicle Speed signal must report a good status</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>And there is not a Traction Control or ABS event.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f0403031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0403031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="562px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
