<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-04-01 - Discussion of the Interaction Between the Hydraulic Brake Booster and the Power Steering
        System in International Vehicles
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-04-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Discussion of the Interaction Between the Hydraulic Brake Booster and the Power Steering System in
                International Vehicles
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1652</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000FE</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000RE</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4900</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <figure id="f0404011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0404006.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Hydraulic Brake Booster System</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Referring to Figure 1, the hydraulic brake booster operates in series with the power steering
                    gear. The power steering pump supplies the fluid flow and pressure demand to both units during
                    steering and braking. When steering and braking action occurs simultaneously the pressure demand
                    from the steering gear and brakes is additive.
                </para>
                <para>The power steering gear is balanced so that it can handle the pressure generated in the steering
                    gear return line. The power steering gear also has an internal relief valve setting that is lower
                    than the power steering pump relief valve to allow the steering gear to relieve before the power
                    steering pump. This maintains power assist to both brakes and steering.
                </para>
                <para>The hydraulic brake booster has a reserve electric pump which will provide hydraulic pressure
                    boost in the event of an engine shut down. The signal for operation of the electric pump comes from
                    the integral flow switch in the hydraulic brake booster assembly.
                </para>
                <para>The power steering pump receives the greatest demand when the vehicle is stationary, the engine is
                    at idle (low power steering pump RPM), and the service brakes are applied while turning the steering
                    wheel. Under these conditions, the booster pump will supply some assist to the brake and steering
                    system and it is possible to get a warning light and audible warning activation. Under these
                    conditions the brake booster system is still working and there are no adverse effects to operator
                    vehicle control.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
