<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-08-07 - Instrument Cluster Individual Circuit Board Replacement</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040807" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-08-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Instrument Cluster Individual Circuit Board Replacement</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                        <enddate>11/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000 FE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000 RE
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1989</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>IC Bus
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/01/1999</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Prior to this time the only way to make a repair to the Instrument Cluster was to replace the
                    entire housing and circuit board assembly. It is now possible to replace only the problem circuit
                    board, left, right, or center without replacing the entire assembly. Vehicles built prior to
                    November 1997 should have center cluster boards with "Dip" switches as shown in Figure 6. After
                    November 1997 they should have Data Link Clusters without the "Dip" switches. Removal and
                    reinstallation of the cluster assembly has not changed; see Service Manual Section S08034 for the
                    proper method of removing and reinstalling the cluster in the vehicle dash.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0408071">
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.92*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.95*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.24*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Model</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Left Board</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Center Board</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Right Board</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pre 11/97</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587517C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587520C1- W/Dip Switches</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587519C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>RE Bus</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Not Applicable</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587521C1-W/Data Link</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Not Available</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Post 11/97</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587517C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587521C1- W/Data Link</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2587519C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Left and right boards are designated as the cluster is viewed from the drivers seat.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="6">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other
                            ignition sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when
                            working near batteries to avoid property damage, personal injury, or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent electrical shock that could result in property damage, personal injury or
                            death, always disconnect the negative battery terminal before working on the electrical
                            system.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Static electricity can cause permanent damage to the cluster. Before working with the
                            cluster be sure to remove all static electricity from your body by touching the metal part
                            of the dash.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Disconnect the negative battery terminal at the vehicle battery.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Remove the instrument cluster in accordance with Service Manual Section S08034.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place the instrument cluster face down on a suitable smooth surface that will not scratch
                            the cluster face as shown in Figure 1. Leave the front lens and gauge bezel in place in
                            order to keep gauges located when the circuit boards are removed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Circuit boards are labeled left and right as viewed from the drivers seat.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0408071" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408071.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Left Side PC Board Replacement</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the five Phillips head screws shown in Figure 2.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Note whether or not there are gauges attached to the circuit board to be removed.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If there are no gauges attached simply lift the circuit board away from the
                        housing.
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">If there are gauges, carefully pry the circuit board upward from the cluster
                            housing, move the pry device around the board so it raises equally on all sides until the
                            gauge pins release the connectors attached to the circuit board.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the light holders from the board being replaced and install them into the
                        replacement circuit board.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0408072" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408072.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0408073" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408073.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully locate the new circuit board above the gauge pins (or mounting holes if no
                        gauges are present) and uniformly push the new circuit board over the gauge pins until the new
                        board is flat against the cluster housing.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the five Phillips head screws previously removed. DO NOT OVER TORQUE THE
                        SCREWS!
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Right Side PC Board Replacement</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the four Phillips head screws from the large circuit board shown in Figure
                        3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the two Phillips head screws from the small circuit board shown in Figure
                        3.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If there are no gauges attached simply lift the circuit boards away from the
                        housing.
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">If there are gauges, carefully pry the circuit board upward from the cluster
                            housing, move the pry device around the board so it raises equally on all sides until the
                            gauge pins release the connectors attached to the circuit board.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The replacement large and small boards are molded together and must be cut apart
                        prior to installation. DO NOT CUT THE TWO WIRES BETWEEN THE BOARDS!
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the light holders from the boards being replaced and install them into the
                        correct locations on the replacement circuit boards.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully locate the new large circuit board above the gauge pins (or mounting holes
                        if no gauges are present) and uniformly push the new circuit board over the gauge pins until the
                        new board is flat against the cluster housing.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the four Phillips screws previously removed from the large circuit board
                        and the two from the smaller board mounted above. DO NOT OVER TORQUE THE SCREWS!
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Center PC Board Replacement</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the six Phillips head screws holding the metal shield in place and remove the
                        metal shield from the cluster as shown in Figure 4.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the two remaining Phillips head screws under the metal shield removed in step
                        1. See Figure 5.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Figure 5 shows a center circuit board for a vehicle built Nov. 1997 or after with a "Data
                            Link" center circuit board and no "Dip" switches. Figure 6 shows a center board from a
                            vehicle built before Nov. 1997 with "Dip" switches.
                            <emph type="underscr">If the cluster being replaced has "Dip" switches and all switches are
                                set to "0" the cluster is the original unit and was programmed at the assembly plant.
                                The replacement cluster is not factory programmed and will have to have the "Dip"
                                switches set according to the "Dip" switch label on the old cluster. If the cluster
                                being replaced has switches in positions other than "0", record the switch positions and
                                set the replacement cluster "Dip" switches to the same position as the switches being
                                replaced.
                            </emph>
                            See Service Manual 08034x, INSTRUMENTS, SPEEDOMETER, MANUAL PROGRAMMING for specific
                            instructions.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the electrical connectors attached to the odometer and/or hour meter located
                        on the rear of the center circuit board.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully pry up on the edges of the circuit board. The only thing attaching the
                        board at this time are the pins from the gauges which are still being retained by the bezel and
                        lens on the front of the cluster assembly. Once an edge is up continue to lift the board by
                        prying near the gauge pins of the individual gauges. Once the circuit board is loose, carefully
                        lift it from the cluster assembly making sure the odometer and/or hour meter feed wires and
                        connectors exit through the holes in the board.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0408074" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408074.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Place the hour/odometer leads through the holes in the new circuit board (Figure
                        5).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the new center board by carefully aligning the gauge pins to the circuit
                        board holes and the mounting holes to the mounting studs on the cluster frame. Once in place
                        carefully push the board down onto the gauge pins, making certain that the new board is flat
                        against the cluster frame.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the two Phillips head screws retaining the board to the cluster frame
                        (Figure 5).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the KPH/MPH jumper and/or the transmission gear resolution jumper from the
                        old circuit board (used on center boards without "Dip" switches) and install in the same
                        position on the new board as shown in Figure 5. See Service Manual Section S08155x for
                        applications.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the odometer and/or hour meter connectors to the pins on the circuit
                        board.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall the metal shield over the centerboard and replace the six Phillips head
                        screws removed in step 1. DO NOT OVER TORQUE THE SCREWS.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0408075" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Nov. 1997 and After</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0408076" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408076.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                             scalefitheight="392px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Pre Nov. 1997</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
