<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-08-04 - Battery Supervisor With Latching Relay</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040804" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-08-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Battery Supervisor With Latching Relay</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9100i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/07/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/07/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/07/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/07/2002</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The Battery Supervisor monitors the vehicle battery voltage at all times. The system will activate
                    an audible alarm and a red warning light (LED) for 60 seconds if the battery voltage decreases to
                    the preset level of 12.1 Volts DC or lower. Once the vehicle voltage drops to 12.1 Volts DC or lower
                    and the audible alarm has sounded for 60 seconds, the system will disconnect any accessory circuit
                    connected to the control relay if the engine is not running. After 60 seconds the alarm stops and
                    the warning light (LED) will start flashing until the system is reset. The system is reset
                    automatically when the engine starter is activated. This system is designed to provide adequate
                    voltage for restarting the engine. The control relay doesn't require any voltage to stay open or
                    closed, a voltage pulse is sent to the relay to activate the open or close feature.
                </para>
                <para>The system has a feature that prevents disconnecting accessories while the engine is running. A
                    Normally Closed (N/C) oil pressure switch is used for this purpose.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Troubleshooting Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a flat, level surface,
                        set the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>See Figure 1 for all circuit and connector references.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">Low Battery warning light doesn't turn ON at the preset voltage or below with
                        engine OFF, however all other system functions work as designed.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify the connector (816F) located approximately 6" from the LED is fully mated with the
                            system harness and all other connectors to the system are fully mated.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check WHITE wire circuit 11GDC (Pin F on control module connector 815M), using an
                            ohmmeter, verify if the wire has continuity to ground, it must be connected to a reliable
                            chassis ground.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Disconnect the LED connector (816F) from the main harness. On the LED side of the
                            connector verify the LED is working by using the diode test mode on an appropriate DVOM. If
                            LED doesn't show voltage in one direction and an open circuit in the other, change the LED.
                            If the LED checks OK, verify wires from LED connector (816F) to the control module using a
                            continuity meter. Disconnect connector (815M) from the control module and check for
                            continuity between the LED connector (Pin A) through to the control module (Pin D) and LED
                            connector (Pin B) through the control module (Pin F). If the continuity of all wires is
                            good, change control module.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">The system doesn't disconnect the accessories when battery is low with the engine
                        OFF, however all other system functions work as designed.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify all system harness connectors are fully mated.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure the three (3)-pin connector (1255) near the control relay is mated properly.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check for constant + 12 volts on the RED wire circuit 14DMH (Pin H) on the control module
                            using a voltmeter. If no voltage, check fuse F10-A in harness, if blown, replace with a 10
                            amp. fuse. If fuse is good and still no voltage, verify connection of the RED wire circuit
                            14DAF from Battery Feed pin at the control relay. If not connected or the wire connection is
                            broken, repair appropriately.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check WHITE wire circuit 11GDC (Pin F) on the control module connector (815M), using an
                            ohmmeter verify if the wire has continuity to ground, it must be connected to a reliable
                            chassis ground.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The system has a disabling feature when the engine is running. The wiring from the control
                            module goes through the oil pressure switch (Normally Closed) and then to the control relay.
                            With the engine OFF, using a continuity meter, check the continuity between the control
                            relay BLUE wire circuit 14DMC (Pin C) on connector (1255) and the control module BLUE wire
                            (Pin C) on connector (815M). If no continuity, locate oil pressure switch in the engine
                            compartment and make sure that the oil pressure switch connector (817M) is fully mated with
                            the switch and test the system again. If no continuity, disconnect the pressure switch
                            connector and check the continuity between the Pin C of the control relay and one of the
                            terminals of the pressure switch harness connector (817M). If no continuity, repair wire
                            appropriately. Then check the continuity between the other switch connector terminal and the
                            Pin C of the control module. If no continuity, repair wire appropriately. If all prior tests
                            are good, verify the continuity of the oil pressure switch with an ohmmeter. Connect the two
                            leads from the ohmmeter to the two terminals of the switch; the circuit must be closed. If
                            the circuit is open change the oil pressure switch.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">The system disconnects the accessories when battery is low, however, no warning
                        light and warning buzzer turn on.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Warning Light</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>To test the warning light circuitry, see Step 1 above.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Warning Buzzer</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify that all system harness connectors are fully mated.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Verify the RED wire circuit 14DMG (Pin 3) at the warning buzzer connector (201M) for + 12
                            Volts using a voltmeter. If no voltage, verify the constant power feed source for broken
                            wire. The power feed comes from the RED wire from the Battery Feed on the Control Relay and
                            through F10-A fuse. Repair appropriately.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Using an ohmmeter, check for continuity between the BLACK wire circuit 14DME (Pin A) at
                            the control module connector (815M) and the BLACK wire (Pin 1) at the buzzer connector
                            (201M). If no continuity, repair wire appropriately.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>On the warning buzzer connector (201M), using a wire jumper, apply ground to Pin 1. The
                            warning buzzer should function. If not, change warning buzzer. If warning buzzer functioned,
                            change the control module.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">System doesn't reconnect the accessories when engine is started.</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure the control relay connector (1255) is fully mated with the module harness.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Using a voltmeter, check on the control module connector (815M) Pin E, you must have +12
                            volts only when the vehicle engine is being started. If no voltage, verify that the PINK
                            wire circuit 17DSK is connected to the start feed. If connected, verify continuity of the
                            PINK wire between the start feed and the control module (Pin E). If no continuity, repair
                            wire appropriately. If continuity, verify continuity of the GREEN wire from the relay
                            connector (1255) Pin A and the RED wire circuit 14DMB from the control module connector
                            (815M) Pin B. If no continuity, repair wire appropriately. If you have continuity, change
                            control module.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">The system disconnects the accessories when the engine is running.</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>ENGINE RUNNING: Locate the oil pressure switch in the engine compartment. Unplug harness
                            connector from the oil pressure switch. Using an ohmmeter connect the two leads from the
                            ohmmeter to the two terminals of the oil pressure switch, with the engine running the
                            circuit must be open, if the circuit is closed change the oil pressure switch.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The system disconnect feature has a disabling feature while the engine is running. The
                            wiring from the control module goes through the oil pressure switch (Normally Closed -
                            Engine OFF) to the control relay.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>ENGINE OFF: Using an ohmmeter, check the continuity between the control relay connector
                            (1255) BLUE wire circuit 14DMC (Pin C) and the control module connector (815M) BLUE wire
                            circuit 14DMD (Pin C). If you have continuity with the engine off and did not have
                            continuity with the engine running the switch is working properly and the control module
                            should be changed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">With the engine running, the low battery light and the buzzer turn on. After one
                        minute, the low battery light starts flashing, the buzzer stops, however the system doesn't shut
                        down any accessory.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the above condition occurs when driving, the battery supervisor is working as designed,
                            however most likely one of these following vehicle problems has occurred:
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>A faulty charging circuit.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>The alternator doesn't put out enough current to keep up with the actual current
                                    draw of the vehicle.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>A broken wire on the alternator input or output.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">How to verify the oil pressure switch disabling feature.</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>With the engine
                            <emph type="bold">OFF</emph>, locate oil pressure switch in the engine compartment.
                            Disconnect the switch connector (817M) from the oil pressure switch. Using an ohmmeter,
                            connect the two leads from the ohmmeter to the two terminals of the switch; the circuit must
                            be closed (showing continuity), if the circuit is open (no continuity) change the oil
                            pressure switch. If the switch is good, go to next step.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Make sure that the oil pressure switch harness connector (817M) is re-connected and fully
                            mated with the switch and check the continuity between the control relay BLUE wire (Pin C)
                            and the control module BLUE wire (Pin C). If no continuity, disconnect the switch connector
                            and check the continuity between the Pin C of the relay and one of the terminals of the
                            switch connector. If no continuity, repair wire appropriately. If you have continuity, then
                            check the continuity between the other switch connector terminal and the Pin C of the
                            control module. If no continuity, repair wire appropriately.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0408041" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408041.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
