<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-08-01 - Parking Brake Indicator Lamp "Glow"</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040801" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-08-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Parking Brake Indicator Lamp "Glow"</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9100i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/31/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/31/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/31/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/31/2003</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>16WJY</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>TSI-03-08-02 contained the operating instructions for the new RKE systems installed in the 9000i
                    Model Series built after January 31, 2003. With the introduction of the new system, it was
                    discovered that some vehicles exhibit a slight glow in the Parking Brake Indicator Lamp when the
                    parking brake is not applied. The glow may not be noticed during daylight but can be seen when the
                    cab is dark. This glow does not affect the operation of the vehicle parking braking system or RKE.
                    If a customer complains of the glow in the Parking Brake Indicator Lamp and the vehicle meets the
                    above parameters, performing the following procedure will eliminate the Parking Brake Indicator Lamp
                    glow.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>220 Ohm 1 watt resistor, obtain locally. Resistor should have two red and one black colored band near
                one end.
            </para>
            <para>1660577C1 Terminal</para>
            <para>2" Section of &#188;" Heat Shrink Tubing</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to disconnect the negative battery terminal before performing work on the vehicle
                        electrical system could cause an electrical short and could result in property damage, personal
                        injury, or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to avoid property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the negative battery terminal at the battery.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the driver side kick panel under the dash to allow access to the under side of
                    the vehicle ignition switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove connector from the ignition switch "G" terminal. The connector should contain
                    both circuits 81X (18GY) and 44 (16GY) as shown in Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the connector and terminal from the end of the two circuits.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shorten 81X approximately 1 1/2" and strip the wire end to allow for solder
                    connection.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install one two-inch piece of &#188;" heat shrink tubing over the ends of both wires.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Solder 220 Ohm-1 watt resistor to the end of the striped circuit 81X wire. Shorten both
                    ends of the resistor so its total length is approximately the same length as the length removed from
                    circuit 81X in 4. above.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Join the other end of the resistor and circuit 44 together and crimp a new terminal
                    (1660577C1) on the resistor and wire.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the shrink wrap tubing over the solder joint, resistor, and the terminal end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply heat to tubing and shrink it snugly around the resistor and wire.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lock the terminal back into the connector and reinstall connector on terminal "G" at the
                    ignition switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the negative terminal on the battery and verify that the Parking Brake Warning
                    Lamp is no longer illuminated when the Parking Brake is off and that the RKE works properly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the driver's side kick panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0408011" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0408011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
