<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-08-02 - Radio Repair Checklist</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi040802" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-08-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Radio Repair Checklist</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Many radios are judged to be defective before the technician has checked for some of the basic
                    symptom causes. This TSI is issued as a guideline to be used for basic radio troubleshooting in an
                    effort to reduce the number of units that are replaced but are not defective. These guidelines
                    contain the most common complaints along with simple tests that will help find and correct problems
                    while the radios are still in the truck.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <para>The following checklist should be used to diagnose radio problems before a radio is replaced.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No power - radio appears to be dead.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check fuse in truck. Both ignition and power (+12VDC all the time) feed (when
                        applicable). These feeds are the red and yellow leads in the radio harness.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check inline fuse in radio harness (if applicable).</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Reset the radio. Models CRW400, CQ4300, CQ4400, CQ4500, CQ5200, CQ5300, CQ5400 and
                        CQ5500 can be reset with the reset switch on the front of the radio faceplate, see Figure 1. If
                        the unit does not respond when the function buttons are pressed, press the reset switch with a
                        small pointed object such as a pencil point. This will restore the radio to its default
                        settings. Radio power switch has to be pushed after resetting to turn power back on. The memory
                        on the 6 preset station buttons will be lost when the radio is reset.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0408021" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0408021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">No sound but faceplate display is on.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check balance and fade controls on radio.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check wiring to radio (radio wire harness), make sure connectors are tight.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check wiring to speakers. Test at radio for shorts between wires and each speaker
                        wire to ground. These radios are protected for shorts and overloads on the speaker output. If
                        speaker wires are shorted to themselves or ground the audio will shutdown (self-protect) with no
                        audio output. Should this occur, the display will remain active.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reception problem</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check antenna lead connections.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Check antenna and antenna ground.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cassette Problems</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Volume is lower on tapes than radio, check for dirty tape heads.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Unit destroys tapes.</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Check for warped tape cartridge.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Check for tape fragments or other foreign matter in the tape player.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">CD problems</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">No sound with CD loaded</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>CD is inverted.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>CD is very dirty.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Excessive moisture or temperature extremes.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Volume control is at the minimum level.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Sound distorted</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>CD may be defective.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>CD is scratched.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CD skips</para>
                    <step3>
                        <para>Vibration of radio can cause CD to skip. This is normal.</para>
                    </step3>
                    <step3>
                        <para>CD player may skip with dirt or scratches on bottom side.</para>
                    </step3>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">CD won't eject, check for pressure on top of unit.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
