<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-01R - Correct Fuel System Priming Procedure To Prevent Injector Tip Failures</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi041201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-12-01R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>04-12-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>June, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Correct Fuel System Priming Procedure To Prevent Injector Tip Failures</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>530E</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Because "dry starts" cause injector tip failures, a procedure that primes the fuel system before
                    starting the engine must be followed. When the fuel injection system is dry after engine service,
                    cranking the engine to start without first priming the fuel system will result in an overload
                    condition in the injector tips. This overload occurs because there is no fuel present to cushion the
                    needle valve as it lifts and seats. To avoid this condition, follow the procedure below after
                    performing any maintenance, including fuel filter replacement that may allow air to enter the fuel
                    system.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>FUEL SYSTEM PRIMING PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always place transmission in neutral, apply parking brake, and chock the wheels prior to
                        engaging the engine starter. Failure to do so could result in unexpected vehicle movement and
                        cause property damage, personal injury, or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not start the engine without priming the fuel system.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the injector harness at the valve cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the hand primer to fill the fuel system.
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Pump until hand primer is hard to depress.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Crank the engine three times for 15 seconds each. Re-apply the hand primer after each
                    crank cycle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the hand primer remains hard to depress after the 15 second crank, reconnect the
                    injector harness and start the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear fault codes 513 (low side to bank 1 open) and 514 (low side to bank 2 open) that
                    was logged by cranking the engine with the injector harness disconnected.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
