<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-22 - Convert the International&#174; VT 365 on-road engine emission calibration to off-road engine
        emission calibration
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI041222" year="2004" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>04-12-22</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Convert the International&#174; VT 365 on-road engine emission calibration to off-road engine
                emission calibration
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 365
                    <snrange>000534 to 112360</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Off-road conversion is being offered to eliminate the catalytic converter due to plugging and
                    performance issues on vehicles that operate at low speeds and loads.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <regulation>
                        <para>It is against the law to operate a vehicle on any public road or highway with an engine
                            calibrated for off-road emissions.
                        </para>
                    </regulation>
                </specpara>
                <para>This conversion must not be performed on engines that will continue to operate on public roads for
                    any length of time.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                            sure the transmission is in neutral, the parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before
                            performing diagnostic or service procedures on the engine or vehicle. Read all safety
                            instructions in the "Safety Information" section of the Engine Service manual and the Engine
                            Diagnostic manual.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following are requirements to convert on-road International&#174; VT 365 diesel engine
                    calibration to off-road calibration:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Electronic Control Module (ECM) must be part 1839368C1, or the ECM/IDM must be upgraded to
                            meet this requirement.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>ECM mounting kit must be part 1844247C92.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Calibration of the ECM must be PRG2PA05 or later and the Injector Drive Module (IDM) must
                            be AHZ7AI01, or the ECM/IDM must be upgraded to meet these requirements.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The engine must be 175 horsepower, or must be converted to a 175 horsepower engine (Engine
                            Family Rating Code (EFRC) 2111).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <figure id="f0412221" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/d3412.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="264px"
                             scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Off-road emission label</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>There are a number of steps that need to be performed by the dealer to send and receive
                    information from International and the environmental staff at the Vehicle Programming Center. The
                    following steps are suggested to perform the off-road conversion and obtain the new off-road
                    emission label. The Vehicle Programming Center will provide the actual steps:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Change the needed components on the vehicle.</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Upgrade the ECM/IDM, if required, to meet requirements.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Enable Road Speed Limit, set for 24 miles per hour or less.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Remove Catalyst muffler, replace with muffler, part 2587076C1.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Send the ECM and vehicle parameters, using the EZ Tech&#174; or compatable computer and
                            program, to International.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fax the signed form to the Vehicle Programming Center. They will process the parameters
                            and notify the dealer.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Receive the parameters and programs of the vehicle for off-road emission calibration.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Send the following to International Environmental Staff D-575, attention Reconfiguration
                            Team, Melrose Park, to obtain the new emission label, part 1846147C1:
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Legible copy of the line set ticket with the full engine serial number</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Old emission label</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Copy of Dealer work order</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Copy of the signed horsepower quote</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Dealer's address and name of person at dealer who needs to receive the new
                                    emission sticker
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Affix new off-road emission label.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <regulation>
                        <para>It is against the law to operate a vehicle on any public road or highway with an engine
                            calibrated for off-road emissions.
                        </para>
                    </regulation>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
