<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-23RA - Coolant Sealant Conditioner To Eliminate Engine Front Cover Leaks</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi041223RA" year="2004" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>04-12-23RA</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>04-12-23R</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>November 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Coolant Sealant Conditioner To Eliminate Engine Front Cover Leaks</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam></engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E
                    <snrange>1134351 through 1999999</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>1134351 through 1999999</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530
                    <snrange>1134351 through 1999999</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 530
                    <snrange>1134351 through 1999999</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>530E
                    <snrange>1312588 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>A campaign identification label and use instructions were added to this TSI. This TSI applies to
                    all International&#174; I6 electronic injection controlled engines with serial number range 1134351
                    through 1999999 (excluding 2000000 serial number series). Engines equipped with an Exhaust Gas
                    Recirculation (EGR) valve, a 2004 MY emission label, and a serial number that starts with 2000000
                    and above are excluded from use of this service kit. This procedure may be used for any
                    International&#174; I6 engine developing front cover leaks. Applicable diesel engines have two front
                    cover gaskets made of silicone material. The two gaskets are allowing coolant to leak externally
                    because they are not compatible with International&#174; Extended Life Coolant (ELC).
                </para>
                <para>To reduce down time, International is introducing a coolant sealant conditioner kit to service
                    engines leaking from front covers.
                </para>
                <para>The kit contains a specified number of tablets and charted instructions which cover all
                    International&#174; DT 466, DT 530, HT 530, 530E, and 530E Green Diesel Technology&#174; diesel
                    engines.
                </para>
                <para>1850155C92 service kit [20 tablets plus an additional six tablet kit (the 6 tablet kit should be
                    used only for large capacity cooling systems such as bus)]
                </para>
                <para>1171823R1 instruction sheet (supplied with service kit)</para>
                <para>Should an applicable series engine develop a leak in one or both front cover gaskets, add the
                    specified number of tablets. This sealant conditioner is designed as a lasting repair.
                </para>
                <para>Do not apply the coolant sealant conditioner more than one time.</para>
                <figure>
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/a05001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="592px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>Place a Campaign Identification Label CTS-1075 C (comes in a pack of 25) over the existing
                    Texaco/Shell ELC decal (located on the surge tank). Mark the label "CSC added and the addition date"
                    to prevent accidental reapplication of the sealant conditioner. See Figure.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Addition of sealant conditioner as part of this TSI and kit instruction does not violate
                            the note in the "Cleaning the Cooling System" subsection of Section 6 of the Engine
                            Operation and Maintenance Manual and will not invalidate the warranty.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
