<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-28 - Replacement of Copper / Brass Core Radiators with Aluminum Core Radiators in 5000 Models
        Built from 1994 to Current Production and 9000 Models Built Between 1994 and October 2002
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi041228" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-12-28</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Replacement of Copper / Brass Core Radiators with Aluminum Core Radiators in 5000 Models Built from
                1994 to Current Production and 9000 Models Built Between 1994 and October 2002
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5500i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5600i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>10/01/2002</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>When replacing a copper / brass core radiator with an aluminum core radiator the radiator frame to
                    core isolators must be changed.
                </para>
                <para>Care must be exercised when installing the new aluminum radiator to not pry the end frames onto
                    the radiator to avoid damage to the radiator core.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0412281">
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.50*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.60*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2502216C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Radiator Isolator Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>park the vehicle on a level surface</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>set the parking brake</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>turn the engine off and chock the wheels</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>allow the engine cooling system to cool before performing the Service Procedure.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death from hot coolant or steam use only the following procedure
                        to remove the pressure cap from the radiator or expansion tank. Allow the engine to cool. Wrap a
                        thick, heavy cloth around the pressure cap. Push down, loosen the cap slowly to its first notch
                        position; then pause a moment to allow pressure to release through the overflow tube. After
                        pressure has been released, the pressure cap may be removed.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>On the copper/ brass radiator there are two support rods on the front and back sides of the
                        radiator that run from the top of the radiator to the bottom for added strength. The aluminum
                        radiators do not require these four support rods so do not attempt to transfer the support rods
                        from the old radiator to the new radiator. Refer to TSI-03-12-12 for more details.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the radiator cap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain the cooling system into a clean suitable container. Retain the coolant to refill
                    the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the radiator hoses and remove the radiator assembly from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the copper/brass radiator core from the radiator frame. Clean the radiator frame
                    of any debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new isolators, from Kit 2502216C91, into the bottom channel of the radiator
                    frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the aluminum core onto the bottom channel. Support the aluminum core in the
                    upright position and install both side channels.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new isolators into the top channel and place the top channel onto the radiator
                    (Figure 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0412281" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0412281.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Assembly Of Frame Channels To The Radiator Core</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use pry bars or screwdrivers to compress the isolators or to align bolt holes while
                        assembling the radiator. To do so may result in damage to the radiator core (Figure 3 and Figure
                        4).
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Compress the radiator frame with hand pressure or a clamping means to draw the radiator
                    core into the isolators and bolt hole alignment (Figure 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0412282" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0412282.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Clamping Radiator Frame</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0412283" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0412283.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Area Of Damage (Circle) When Pry Bar Is Used</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0412284" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0412284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Close Up Of Damaged Area In Circle From Figure 3</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the frame mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the radiator assembly into the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the radiator hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the cooling system and check for leaks.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
