<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-32 - Convert The International&#174; VT 365 2004 Model Year Engine Emission Calibration (Highway
        Use) To Non-Road (Off-Road) Engine Emission Calibration
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi041232" year="2004" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>04-12-32</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Convert The International&#174; VT 365 2004 Model Year Engine Emission Calibration (Highway Use) To
                Non-Road (Off-Road) Engine Emission Calibration
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 365
                    <snrange>0109728 and up</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Non-road conversion is being offered to eliminate the catalytic converter due to plugging and
                    performance issues on vehicles that operate at low speeds and loads.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <regulation>
                        <para>It is against the law to operate a vehicle on any public road or highway with an engine
                            calibrated for non-road emissions.
                        </para>
                    </regulation>
                </specpara>
                <para>This conversion must not be performed on engines that will continue to operate on public roads or
                    highways.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                            sure the transmission is in neutral, the parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before
                            performing diagnostic or service procedures on the engine or vehicle. Read all safety
                            instructions in the "Safety Information" section of the Engine Service manual and the Engine
                            Diagnostic manual.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following are requirements to convert highway use International&#174; VT 365 2004 MY diesel
                    engine calibration to non-road calibration:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Calibration of the ECM must be PRG2PJ50 or later or the engine must be upgraded to meet
                            these requirements.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>International&#174; VT 365 MY 2004 engines with ECM not calibrated to PRG2PJ50 or
                                    later will have a Federal Emission Label (FEL) and will not have a special right
                                    side exhaust tube assembly with an EGR scoop attached.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>The FEL must be removed, right side exhaust tube assembly (1843175C1) must be
                                    removed and replaced with the special right side exhaust tube assembly (1845235C1),
                                    and the ECM calibrated to PRG2PJ50 or later.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The engine must be 175 horsepower, or must be converted to a 175 horsepower engine (Engine
                            Family Rating Code (EFRC) 2111).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>There are a number of steps that need to be performed by the dealer to send and receive
                    information from International and the environmental staff at the Vehicle Programming Center.
                </para>
                <para>The following steps are suggested to perform the non-road conversion and obtain the new non-road
                    emission label. The Vehicle Programming Center will provide the actual steps:
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Change the needed components on the vehicle.</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Remove the FEL and right side exhaust tube assembly (1843175C1).</para>
                                <para>Install special right side exhaust tube assembly with EGR scoop (1845235C1), if
                                    required, to upgrade the engine.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Calibrate the ECM, if required, to meet PRG2PJ50 or later requirements.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Enable Road Speed Limit and program for 24 miles per hour or less.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Remove Catalyst muffler, replace with muffler, part 2587076C1.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Retrieve and upload the ECM and vehicle parameters, using the EZ Tech&#174; or compatible
                            computer and program, to International.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Fax the signed form to the Vehicle Programming Center. The program center will process the
                            parameters and notify the dealer.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Receive the parameters and programs of the vehicle for non-road emission calibration.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install new program in ECM.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Send the following to International Environmental Staff D-575, attention Re-configuration
                            Team, Melrose Park, IL., to obtain the new emission label, part 1854565C1:
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Legible copy of the line set ticket with the full engine serial number</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Old emission label and FEL (if applicable)</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Copy of Dealer work order</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Copy of the signed horsepower quote</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Dealer's address and name of person at dealer who needs to receive the new
                                    emission sticker
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Affix new non-road emission label in place of the old emission label.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <figure figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/d31313.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="168px"
                             scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. New non-road emission label</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <regulation>
                        <para>It is against the law to operate a vehicle on any public road or highway with an engine
                            calibrated for off-road emissions.
                        </para>
                    </regulation>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
