<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-12-29 - Priming Fuel System after Running Out of Fuel</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI041229" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>04-12-29</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Priming Fuel System after Running Out of Fuel</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="yes" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 570
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 570
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI provides instructions on how to prime the fuel system after running out of fuel.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="prime" graphiccount="4">
            <title>Priming Fuel System</title>
            <figure id="H11033" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/H11033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="256px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Fuel system components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>Water drain valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>Fuel filter cover</callout1>
                    <callout1>Fuel filter header</callout1>
                    <callout1>Drain valve (fuel)</callout1>
                    <callout1>Fuel primer pump assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1>Fuel Pressure Test Valve</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, possible death or damage to the engine or vehicle, make sure the
                        transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set and wheels are blocked before doing diagnostic
                        or service procedures on engine or vehicle.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, make sure that the engine has cooled down
                        sufficiently before attempting to prime the fuel system.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury be sure to follow the safety procedures outlined in the "Safety
                        Information" section of the Diagnostic Manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death: do not allow engine fuel to stay on your
                        skin. Clean your skin and nails with soap and water, or a good hand cleaner. Wash or properly
                        throw away clothing or rags containing used engine fuel. Used engine fuel contains certain
                        elements that may be unhealthy for skin.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not add fuel to the fuel filter header, this can add contaminants to the fuel.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the engine runs out of fuel, do the following:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set parking brake and place transmission control lever to NEUTRAL or PARK.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the fuel tank with 15 to 19 liters (4 to 5 gallons) of fuel.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If your vehicle is equipped with dual fuel tanks, fill each tank with 15 to 19 liters (4 to 5
                        gallons) of fuel.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unlock the fuel primer pump assembly (5, Figure 1) by turning the knob
                    counter-clockwise.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the fuel filter header and fuel rail by pumping the fuel primer pump.</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Push the fuel primer pump until the pressure has built up enough that the knob cannot be
                            pushed anymore. Be sure the fuel primer pump knob is pushed in when finished pumping. It is
                            not necessary to lock the fuel primer knob at this time. If the fuel primer pump knob is
                            hard to push, do steps 10, 11, and 12. If the fuel primer pump knob is easy to push, do step
                            4B.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If very little pressure is felt after pushing the knob of the fuel primer pump several
                            times, air has to be bled out of the fuel rail. Do steps 5 through 12.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, wear safety glasses with side shields when
                        performing the following procedure.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Be sure to place a rag or suitable container under the fuel pressure test valve when bleeding
                        the fuel rail. Dispose of fuel in a correct container clearly marked DIESEL FUEL according to
                        local regulations.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Engine fuel can be a threat to the environment. Never dispose of engine fuel by putting it in
                        the trash, pouring on the ground, in the sewers, in streams, or bodies of water.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="h11060" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h11060.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Shrader valve assembly</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>Center stem</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="H11061" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h11061.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Diagnostic coupling</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>Valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>Center section</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place either a shop rag or suitable container under the fuel pressure test valve (6,
                    Figure 1). Engines are equipped with a fuel pressure test valve in the form of either a Shrader
                    valve (Figure 2) or a diagnostic coupling (Figure 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Depress and hold the center stem or center section of the fuel pressure test valve and
                    pump the fuel primer pump knob until a steady stream of fuel flows out the test valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="H31285" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h31285.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Fuel Pressure Test Adapter</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is recommended to use the Fuel Pressure Test Adapter to avoid bending the needle in the
                        Shrader valve. The Fuel Pressure Test Adapter is part of Fuel Pressure Test Kit ZTSE4657.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once air has been released and fuel flows from the fuel pressure test valve, release the
                    stem or center section. Remove the Fuel Pressure Test Adapter, if used.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dispose of fuel in a correct container clearly marked DIESEL FUEL according to local
                    regulations.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the fuel primer pump knob until the pressure has built up enough that the fuel
                    primer pump knob cannot be pushed anymore. Be sure the fuel primer pump knob is pushed in when
                    finished pumping. It is not necessary to lock the fuel primer pump knob at this time. Do steps 10,
                    11, and 12.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine. It is not necessary to lock the fuel primer pump knob of the fuel
                    primer pump to start the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the engine does not start in 20 seconds, repeat the priming procedure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the engine starts, let it run for five to 10 seconds, then shut-off the engine.
                    Turn the fuel primer pump knob clockwise to lock in place.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
