<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 04-47-01 - Bus Lower Rub Rail Corrosion Prevention</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi044701" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>04-47-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2004</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Bus BODY</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Bus Lower Rub Rail Corrosion Prevention</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>RE 200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>RE 300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>FE 300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CE Bus</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3800</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Bus rub rails have designed drainage holes along the bottom to prevent moisture entrapment behind
                    the rail. In certain applications, dirt and salt plug the drain holes, preventing the moisture from
                    escaping and allowing the build up of a "wet" area behind the rail. Although both sides of the rails
                    have been coated to prevent corrosion, under certain conditions, this area of constant moisture is
                    extremely harsh to the paint and will begin to prematurely deteriorate the metal. In the isolated
                    cases seen, this phenomenon has a tendency to occur on the rear left side of the bus (Figure 1) on
                    two lane roads in states using a Calcium Chloride/Fine Sand combination in road de-icing. It is
                    believed the oncoming passing vehicles cause the deicing mixture to be splashed into the underside
                    of the lower rub rails. The sand will block the drainage holes while the trapped road salt
                    contributes to premature signs of corrosion. Easy regular maintenance prevents this issue from
                    occurring.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0447011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0447011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="328px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Area Susceptible to Corrosion Shown by Arrow</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>Maintenance - During winter months, perform a regular inspection of the lower rub rails, especially
                the driver's side of the bus. Check for plugged drain holes. Gently use a small wire or narrow
                screwdriver to remove the sand from the drain hole. Flush rail with fresh water to remove any road
                salts. If required, brush touch up small scratches with a metal prep solution (e.g., Sikkens Autoprep
                Etching Pen - from your local Sikkens Jobber or Henkel's Surface Technology's Touch-N-Prep&#174;Alodine&#174;--1132
                available online at http://www.buyhstna.com/store) followed by urethane based topcoat paint.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
