<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-02-01 - Diagnosis of Chassis Wander Complaints</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi050201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-02-01</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>97-02-02</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>February, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Diagnosis of Chassis Wander Complaints</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>A simple steer axle caster check can be performed to address a chassis wander complaint after the
                    dealer technician has verified the condition, the correct tire inflation and steering
                    linkage/component function. Low or insufficient caster angle is a prime source for chassis wander
                    complaints.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface,
                        set the parking brake, chock the wheels, and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Prior to performing this Service Procedure, ensure that the tire inflation is correct, and the
                steering linkage/ components are operating correctly.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>An alignment rack or pit is not required for this basic check. Required is a level floor and a
                        digital driveline angle measuring device (digital protractor), Part Number ZTSE4329 or
                        equivalent (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9702021">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0502011" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9702021.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Digital Protractor</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position chassis on a level floor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the chassis is so equipped, verify the air suspension bag height is correctly set.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the digital protractor on the spring pads of the front steer axle parallel to the
                    spring assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure and record caster angle.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Positive caster is indicated if the rear of the steer axle spring pad is lower than
                        the front.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Caster which is at or near the lower end of the specification may be increased to
                        the upper end of the specification if the wander complaint persists. Refer to TSI-04-02-01 Steer
                        Axle Alignment Specifications.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">A half degree more caster wedge on the passenger side is desirable to reduce
                        drifting right tendencies due to road crown.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Changing steering gears to correct wander complaints should only be considered as a last
                        resort. A steering gear change is not likely to affect the complaint condition.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
