<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-03-02 - Chassis Lean Correction</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi050302" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-03-02</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>02-03-02</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>September, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Chassis Lean Correction</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Chassis lean may result from manufacturing tolerances; i.e., the frame ladder assembly, leaf
                    spring assemblies, etc. After completing the measurement steps described in the below "Service
                    Procedure", a limited amount of shimming may be acceptable.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Shimming is not an acceptable practice for chassis lean created by the addition of
                            auxiliary equipment or loading practices resulting in vehicle lean. These procedures are
                            intended to assist the service technician in making industry acceptable corrections for
                            nominal lean issues and are not intended to compensate for over/uneven loading or
                            un-repaired vehicle damage - regardless of cause.
                        </para>
                        <para>Shimming is not an acceptable practice for chassis lean on air spring suspension axles.
                            Air spring suspensions incorporate one or two (optional) height control valves and will
                            automatically self level within design limits of the suspension system.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0203021">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="colspec0" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="3.89in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>493720C3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>4 Inch Wide x 1/4 Inch Thick Spacer</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>540069C3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>4 Inch Wide x 3/8 Inch Thick Spacer</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>493721C3</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>4 Inch Wide x 1/2 Inch Thick Spacer</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="colspec0">
                                <para>NPN</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>3 Inch Wide x 1/2 Inch Max. Thick Spacer (See Note)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Make Locally</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Record vehicle weight at all four corners of the chassis as measured at individual wheel
                    positions (tandems on one side in the case of 6 x 4 or 6 x 6) to verify the vehicle is not
                    overloaded or unevenly loaded. Steel spring suspensions will deflect, based upon applied spring
                    loads. Air springs incorporate a height control valve and will automatically self-level within the
                    design limits of the suspension package.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assure that all tires are properly inflated to recommended pressures, based upon the
                    heaviest loads normally carried and park the chassis on a known level surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure the distance from the bottom of the frame rail to the level ground surface on
                    both sides at the steer axle and at the rear suspension. If the difference side to side exceeds 3/8
                    inch (9.5 mm), shimming is an acceptable corrective practice. Exchanging the front springs (right
                    for left and left for right) is also an acceptable corrective practice.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Maximum shim thickness for steer axles shall be no more than 3/8 inch (9.6 mm). Steering and
                        handling performance may be adversely affected if maximum shim thickness for steer axles of 3/8
                        inch (9.6 mm) is exceeded.
                    </para>
                    <para>Maximum shim thickness for drive axles shall be no more than 1/2 inch (12.7 mm). Handling and
                        driveline performance may be adversely affected if shim thickness for drive axles of 1/2 inch
                        (12.7 mm) is exceeded.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When shimming a suspension pack, make sure U-bolts are of sufficient length that when final
                        assembly is accomplished a minimum of 2 threads are showing on the U-bolt legs beyond the nuts.
                        If U-bolts have to be replaced, use only International recommended material.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When shimming a suspension pack, make sure spring locating lug or center bolt head is of
                        sufficient length to properly engage through the shim and into the axle seat to assure proper
                        spring alignment.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Should new front springs be installed as a corrective action, visually compare the springs for
                        even height. If one spring is slightly higher than the other, install the higher (taller) spring
                        on the lower side as stated in Step 3 above.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Re-torque U-bolts per International Owner's Manual / Service Procedure, and at recommended
                        intervals for a new vehicle after completion.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
