<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-08-09 - Headlight Aiming Procedure for CF Model Trucks</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi050809" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-08-09</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Headlight Aiming Procedure for CF Model Trucks</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="yes" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>CF 500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CF 600</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The headlight aim of the CF Models should be checked after the body has been installed and
                    adjusted if necessary. The body and payload weight has an effect on the aiming of the headlights.
                    Should it be necessary to readjust the headlights on CF Models, follow the procedure listed below.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <para>The CF headlights should be properly aimed using the procedure described in
                <exhotlnk document="../S08/S08307.htm" bookname="S08307">S08307</exhotlnk>. When performing the
                headlight adjustment it is important to follow the procedures closely. During the adjustment process
                both the inboard and outboard vertical aim adjustment screws should be turned
                <emph type="bold">the same amount and in the same direction</emph>. Turning the screws in opposite
                directions could result in damage to, and the need to replace, the headlight assembly. Also note that
                <emph type="bold">you should not finish the adjustment procedure while turning the adjusting screws in
                    the counterclockwise direction</emph>. If you are adjusting in the counterclockwise direction, turn
                the adjusting screws one full turn beyond the proper adjustment point and then turn the screws back
                clockwise one full turn so you finish with the proper adjustment while turning the screws in the
                clockwise direction.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
