<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-10-01 - Use of Sikkens Paint for Field Repairs on International Trucks</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051001" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-10-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>GENERAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Use of Sikkens Paint for Field Repairs on International Trucks</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>As a follow up to our recent recommitment to use Akzo-Nobel as our primary OEM source for coatings
                    on our vehicles, I would like to offer the following recommendations.
                </para>
                <para>International selected Sikkens as the Aftermarket Paint Supplier of choice back in the late
                    1980's. The reason for this choice was based on their ability to provide a fully functional field
                    service program for our Basecoat/Clearcoat Technology, 100% color Match Assurance, Technical Service
                    Assistance and Dealer Training.
                </para>
                <para>While other aftermarket paint suppliers can accomplish many of the above benefits, only Akzo Nobel
                    products are designed to be totally compatible with the OEM topcoats from all of our truck assembly
                    plants. It is therefore recommended that all paint repairs to International truck products be
                    performed using Sikkens or Lesonal materials. This will assure technology compatibility while
                    providing our customers with the same level of durability and appearance characteristics found in
                    the OEM topcoat. Akzo Nobel is committed to providing International dealers with the best value and
                    enhanced training on a continuous basis.
                </para>
                <para>In addition, Akzo Nobel is the only aftermarket supplier committed to International in providing
                    color match on newly developed colors. This support is critical in repair work with the newer "Pearl
                    Effect" technology.
                </para>
                <para>In the event it is necessary to use an aftermarket product other than Akzo Nobel, it is highly
                    recommended that a complete system be used. It would not be advisable to mix products from different
                    suppliers as the performance of the combined materials cannot be warranted by either supplier.
                </para>
                <para>In the event you do need technical assistance at any time, please contact the Sikkens Technical
                    Service Line at 1-800-618-1010 or www.akzonobelcarrefinishes.net
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
