<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-12-16 - Fuel Dilution (Fuel in the Oil) Diagnosis with Dye</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051216" year="2005" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>05-12-16</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Fuel Dilution (Fuel in the Oil) Diagnosis with Dye</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>2000001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 570
                    <snrange>2000001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 570
                    <snrange>2000001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Oil contaminated with diesel fuel (fuel dilution) will have a diesel fuel odor and the oil level
                    in the engine will increase. A leaking fuel injector or injector O-ring will cause fuel dilution. A
                    leaking injector sleeve or injector tip could also cause fuel dilution, but would most likely be
                    identified as an engine performance problem. Suspected fuel dilution should be verified by oil
                    analysis.
                </para>
                <para>There are other issues that may also contribute to fuel dilution, beside fuel injectors:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Hard starting</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Running rich (strong fuel odor)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Valve related issue</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>If the engine is mechanically sound and the oil has been changed, diagnose for fuel in the oil
                    with dye.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use only recommended dye, manufactured by Balkamp, Inc., available at local NAPA Auto
                            Parts stores, part number 765-2661.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>Contact Tech Services, (800) 336-4500, open a case, if set (six) of injectors must be replaced.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This procedure is approved for use on I6 engines serial 2000001 and above only. This
                            procedure is an extension of EGES-270 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Diagnostic Manual. This
                            procedure is not approved for use in V8 or V6 engines.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <figure id="f0512161" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/H11033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Fuel Filter Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Water drain valve</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Housing cover assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel filter header</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Drain valve (fuel)</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel primer pump assembly</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Fuel valve assembly air bleed and pressure test port</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify oil contamination.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuel filter housing cover assembly, discard O-ring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add two ounces of dye to fuel filter header.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put replacement O-ring in housing cover assembly. Install housing cover assembly and
                    torque to 33 to 37 Nm (24 to 27 lbf&#183;ft).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The O-ring is available in Fuel Filter Kit, 1842638C91, or individually, 1841394C1.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a rag or suitable container under fuel pressure test valve. Press in on fuel
                    pressure test valve, on fuel rail, while pumping the fuel primer pump. Continue until dyed fuel
                    starts to flow from fuel pressure test valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify there is a yellow/green fluorescent glow to the fuel. Check the fuel with AC Leak
                    Kit (UV Lamp) (ZTSE4618). Dispose of rags, containers, and fuel according to local regulations.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prime the fuel system. See EGES-265 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service ManualSection
                    12.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove valve cover. See EGES-265-1 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service Manual.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start and run engine at idle for three to five minutes.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine running, inspect for yellow/green streams of dye running between valve
                    spring seats at each injector. Use AC Leak Kit (UV Lamp) (ZTSE4618). A small inspection mirror can
                    aid in inspecting hard to reach areas.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Test as indicated in steps 9 and 10 should take no longer than an additional three to five
                            minutes. Because of disbursement of dye in fuel, amount of dye seen is not necessarily
                            indicative of severity of failure, just that failure exists.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To avoid possible engine damage, do not take corrective action if a positive indication is
                        found on whole set of injectors. Check to see if engine oil has been changed. Initial engine oil
                        from the plant has dye in it.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once leak has been found, do steps 12 through 16. If no leak is found, go to step 17.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut down engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure rail. See EGES-265-1 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect failed injector. Failed injector will have a solid yellow/green color around
                    intensifier body area. Use AC Leak Kit (UV Lamp) (ZTSE4618).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open fuel valve assembly air bleed and pressure test port, relieve all pressure in fuel
                    system to avoid further contamination of the oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace leaking fuel injector. See EGES-265 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Shut down engine.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If no dye or leak is found after engine has been running, make sure there is a fuel dilution
                        issue to begin with through oil analysis or watching for an oil level increase.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high pressure rail. See EGES-265-1 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Without removing the fuel injectors, closely inspect areas around each injector and
                    hold-down clamp. Use AC Leak Kit (UV Lamp) (ZTSE4618).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once leak has been found, do steps 21 and 22. If no leak is found go to step 23.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open fuel valve assembly air bleed and pressure test port, relieve all pressure in fuel
                    system to avoid further contamination of the oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace leaking fuel injector. See EGES-265-1 DT 466, DT 570 and HT 570 Service
                    Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open fuel valve assembly air bleed and pressure test port, relieve all pressure in fuel
                    system to avoid further contamination of the oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When removing each fuel injector, hold the fuel injector over the injector opening for several
                        seconds for fuel to drain out of the injector. Place a rag or fuel injector holder cup under the
                        fuel injector to avoid contaminating other injectors during removal. Dispose of rags,
                        containers, and fuel according to local regulations.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no leakage is found and fuel dilution is verified, remove each fuel injector
                    individually. See EGES-265-1 DT 466, DT 570 and HT 570 Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When the fuel injector is in the fuel injector holder cup, do not allow fuel to get above top
                        O-ring and contaminate weep hole.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0512162" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/H11062.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Inspect Weep Hole</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect weep hole, where hold-down clamp indexes on injector body, for each injector.
                    Fuel leaking out of weep hole indicates a failed injector. Use AC Leak Kit (UV Lamp) (ZTSE4618).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace leaking fuel injector. See EGES-265 DT 466, DT 570, and HT 570 Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0512161" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="topbot">
                <title>Fuel Dilution Leak Test Tools</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.28*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.72*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Tool Number</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Pressure Test Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4657</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel/Oil Pressure Test Coupler</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4526</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Pressure Gauge</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4681</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Test Fitting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4692</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>AC Leak Kit (UV Lamp)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4618</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fuel Injector Holding Rack and Cups</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE4299B</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
