<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-12-40 - EPA Emergency Fuel Usage Waiver</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI051240" year="2005" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>05-12-40</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>EPA Emergency Fuel Usage Waiver</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all International&#174; diesel engines. In response to refinery damage caused
                    by Hurricane Katrina, the EPA has issued a temporary fuel usage waiver to eliminate potential fuel
                    shortages.
                </para>
                <para>The distribution of non-road application high-sulfur fuel (2000 ppm sulfur) will be temporarily
                    permitted for highway applications until November 20, 2005. Additionally, the waiver temporarily
                    eliminates the requirement of adding red dye to high-sulfur fuel as an identifier.
                </para>
                <para>Prior to hurricane damage assessment, the EPA initially issued a waiver permitting the
                    distribution of high-sulfur fuel throughout the United States. The waiver currently applies to the
                    District of Columbia and 23 States.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">International Truck and Engine Corporation does not recommend the use of
                        high-sulfur fuel for all International&#174; diesel engines.
                    </emph>
                    The use of high-sulfur fuel can cause corrosive damage to air system components on engines with
                    Exhaust Gas Recirculation (EGR) system and reduce lubrication oil life on all engines.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Use of high-sulfur fuel can result in engine damage. Using high-sulfur fuel will void
                            expressed or implied warranty by International Truck and Engine Corporation on components
                            affected by high-sulfur fuel use.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Current Situation</title>
            <para>Distribution of high-sulfur fuel is allowed by the EPA in the following district and States:</para>
            <table type="simple" frame="none">
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.19*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.81*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Alabama</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>New Hampshire</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Arkansas</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>New Jersey</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Connecticut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>New Mexico</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Delaware</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>New York</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>District of Columbia</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>North Carolina</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Florida</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pennsylvania</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Georgia</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Rhode Island</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Louisiana</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>South Carolina</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Maine</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Texas</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Maryland</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Vermont</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Massachusetts</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Virginia</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Mississippi</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>West Virginia</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>With the widespread introduction of high-sulfur fuel into the marketplace, consumers can be grouped
                into three of the following categories:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Consumers who unknowingly have used high-sulfur fuel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Consumers who have knowingly used high-sulfur fuel</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Consumers who have not used the high-sulfur fuel</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para></para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Corrective Action</title>
            <para>Given these exceptional and temporary circumstances, International Truck and Engine Corporation offers
                the following guidance to ensure your engine continues to perform properly:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ensure you know the exact fuel you are introducing into your fuel system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If you think or know you have used high-sulfur fuel, do the following:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Reduce oil drain and filter (oil and fuel) service intervals by 50%.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drain water separator daily.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Minimize idle time.</para>
                        <para>Applications requiring significant idle time (boom trucks, etc.) should ensure the engine
                            is driven at rated speed for a significant period of time at days end.
                        </para>
                        <para>Bringing the engine to full operating temperature once a day will help reduce the adverse
                            corrosive effects of combined condensation and sulfur. This will additionally ensure the
                            vehicle catalytic converter operates properly.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If your engine has an EGR system, have your engine inspected by technicians for potential
                            corrosive damage to intake manifold.
                        </para>
                        <para>Replace any intake manifolds with signs of corrosion. Failure to replace may result in
                            corrosive flakes being introduced into the air management system and create excessive power
                            cylinder wear.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation will continue to update and advise our customers on future
                EPA waivers as circumstances dictate.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
