<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-12-24 - Turbo Actuator Service Kit (SRA)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051224" year="2005" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>05-12-24</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Turbo Actuator Service Kit (SRA)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 570
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 570
                    <snrange>2,000,001 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <table id="t01" type="simple" frame="topbot">
                    <title>Turbo Actuator Kit 1847620C91</title>
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.33*"/>
                        <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" align="center" colwidth="0.55*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" align="center" colwidth="0.57*"/>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Description</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>Part Number</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>Quantity</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Actuator, 12V I-6</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1847623C1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>1</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Serrated lock nut, M6 x 1.0</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1847622C1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>4</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Nord-lock washer assembly</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1847625C91</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>2</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Fork lever bolt</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1847626C1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>2</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Instruction sheet</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1171855R1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>1</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Kit comes with one extra fork lever bolt and nord-lock washer assembly.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                            sure transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before doing
                            diagnostic or service procedures on engine or vehicle. Read all safety instructions in the
                            "Safety Information" section of the Engine Service Manual for this engine.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, disconnect the main battery negative
                            terminal before disconnecting or connecting electrical components. See "Safety Information"
                            in Engine Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, make sure engine has cooled down
                            before removing components. See "Safety Information" in Engine Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Diagnosis</title>
            <para>This procedure should be used when the turbocharger is suspected to be the cause of low power. This
                procedure will help determine if the cause is the turbocharger actuator, turbocharger assembly,
                electrical power or ground.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition key off. Try moving turbocharger linkage through its full range of motion
                    by hand. Linkage should move smoothly and not chatter or hesitate. Also do bounce test by moving
                    turbocharger linkage all the way out towards frame rail and let it go. Linkage should move towards
                    engine, bounce, and stay there.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If linkage moves smoothly and passes bounce test, do step 2.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If linkage does not move smoothly or fails bounce test, remove turbocharger actuator and
                            retest by moving linkage through its full range of motion.
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="dash">
                            <item>
                                <para>If linkage then moves smoothly, replace turbocharger actuator.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>If linkage does not move smoothly, replace turbocharger assembly.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition key on. Watch turbocharger linkage during pre-cycle movement. Linkage
                    should move all the way out towards frame rail, move all the way back in towards engine, and move
                    back out about half way. Check pre-cycle three times with at least three seconds of key-off time
                    between tests.
                </para>
                <para>Linkage should move through pre-cycle smoothly and not chatter, vibrate, hesitate or slow down
                    during pre-cycle. Each pre-cycle should be completed in less then one second.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When pre-cycle is complete and key-on engine-off; linkage should not move by hand.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If pre-cycle fails, do step 3.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If pre-cycle passes, turbocharger or actuator may not be cause of low power. Verify all
                            performance diagnostic tests on Performance Diagnostic Form EGED-290 do not indicate another
                            cause. If low power complaint is intermittent and Performance Diagnostic Form has been
                            completed without indicating another cause, do step 3.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect turbocharger breakout harness between engine harness and actuator harness.
                    Measure voltage between actuator power and ground terminals with key-on engine-off.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If pre-cycle failed and voltage is 10 volts or more, replace actuator.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If low power complaint is intermittent and voltage is 10 volts or more, inspect
                            turbocharger power and ground wires for corroded or loose connections. If power and ground
                            wires are properly connected, not corroded, and performance diagnostic tests do not indicate
                            another cause of low power, replace actuator.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If voltage is low, repair low voltage problem and retest starting at step 2. (Refer to VGT
                            Actuator section 7 of EGES-270 Engine Diagnostic Manual).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Turbocharger actuator can be retested with a known good power source and ground supplied
                            directly through turbocharger actuator breakout harness.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
