<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-12-11 - New Crankcase-to-Head Tube Assembly and Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Adapter/Plug Kit for
        Diagnostics
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI051211" year="2005" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>05-12-11</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>New Crankcase-to-Head Tube Assembly and Injection Control Pressure (ICP) Adapter/Plug Kit for
                Diagnostics
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 275
                    <snrange>0143815 and Up</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>VT 365
                    <snrange>112360 and Up</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Release new crankcase-to-head tube assembly, part number 1846758C91 (Figure 1) and new ICP
                    Adapter/Plug kit, part number ZTSE4690 used for engine diagnosis.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Crankcase-to-head tube assembly</title>
                <figure id="f0512111" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/J31277.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Old and new crankcase-to-head tube and plug assemblies</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase-to-head tube (short plug)</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase-to-head tube (used with short plug)</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase-to-head tube plug (with check valve)</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase-to-head tube (used with check plug)</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>Original (short plug) crankcase-to-head tube assembly (Figure 1, Items 1 and 2) is no longer
                    available for service. The new (check valve-in-plug type) crankcase-to-head tube assembly (Figure 1,
                    Items 3 and 4) is a direct replacement for the old. The new crankcase-to-head tube assembly consists
                    of a plug (with check valve), tube, and pre-installed D-rings.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0512112" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/J31284.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. New and old crankcase-to-head tube plug</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">New (hex head) check valve-in-plug type crankcase-to-head tube plug
                        </callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Old (square head) short crankcase-to-head tube plug</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>Determine if the crankcase-to-head tube assembly is the old (square head socket) or the new (hex
                    head socket) (Figure 2).
                </para>
                <para>Depending upon build date, serial number, and any previous service, the engine may be configured
                    as follows:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>One short plug crankcase-to-head tube assembly in each cylinder head.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>One short plug crankcase-to-head tube assembly in one cylinder head and one check
                            valve-in-plug type crankcase-to-head tube assembly in the other cylinder head.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>One check valve-in-plug type crankcase-to-head tube assembly in each cylinder head.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To prevent engine damage, it is recommended that the crankcase-to-head tube assembly be
                            replaced each time it is removed. If you reuse the crankcase-to-head tube, you assume the
                            risk for leakage. You must inspect each D-ring carefully for evidence of cutting, abrasion,
                            or twisting. Never reuse a tube exhibiting any of these seal conditions.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>ICP adapter/plug kit</title>
                <figure id="f0512113" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/J31276.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. New ICP adapter/plug kit, ZTSE4690</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ICP sensor adapter (threaded hex head)</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ICP leak test plug (solid hex head)</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0512114" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/J31172.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Old ICP adapter/plug kit, ZTSE 4668</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ICP sensor adapter (threaded hex head)</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">ICP leak test plug (solid hex head)</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>If the new check-in-plug type crankcase-to-head tube assembly is in the engine, you will need to
                    use the new ICP adapter/plug kit (Figure 3) to test the Injector Control Pressure system. However,
                    if an old (short plug) crankcase-to-head tube assembly is in the engine, you will need to use the
                    old ICP adapter/plug kit (Figure 4) to test the Injector Control Pressure system.
                </para>
                <para>Never attempt to use an old adapter/plug kit for testing the new check-in-plug crankcase-to-head
                    tube assembly, or a misdiagnosis will result. Conversely, never attempt to use the new adapter/plug
                    kit for testing the old (short plug) crankcase-to-head tube assembly, or a misdiagnosis will result.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid the possibility of a misdiagnosis or damage to the engine, never use an old
                            adapter/plug kit for testing the new check-in-plug crankcase-to-head tube assembly or a new
                            adapter/plug kit for testing the old (short plug) crankcase-to-head tube assembly.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>T-handle removal tool</title>
                <figure id="f0512115" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/ZTSE4694.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. T-handle, extractor ZTSE4694</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Additionally, there is a tool used to remove the crankcase-to-head tube. If the crankcase-to-head
                    tube proves difficult to remove, use the T-handle extractor (Figure 5).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0512116" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/J31273.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="472px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Removing the crankcase-to-head tube</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">Crankcase-to-head tube</callout1>
                        <callout1 type="arabic">T-handle removal tool ZTSE4694</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>If the crankcase-to-head tube assembly becomes separated, push the T-handle Removal Tool into the
                    tube. Tighten the T-handle until a positive lock can be felt. Pull out tube and discard.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To prevent engine damage, it is recommended that the crankcase-to-head tube assembly be
                            replaced each time it is removed. If you reuse the crankcase-to-head tube, you assume the
                            risk for leakage. You must inspect each D-ring carefully for evidence of cutting, abrasion,
                            or twisting. Never reuse a tube exhibiting any of these seal conditions.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
