<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-12-10 - Valve Cover Electrical Connector Lock</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051210" year="2005" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>05-12-10</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Valve Cover Electrical Connector Lock</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466
                    <snrange>2045790 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 570
                    <snrange>2045790 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>HT 570
                    <snrange>2045790 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury, possible death, or damage to the engine or vehicle, make
                            sure the transmission is in neutral, parking brake is set, and wheels are blocked before
                            doing diagnostic or service procedures on engine or vehicle. Read all safety instructions in
                            the "Safety Information" section of the service manual for this engine.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid engine damage, turn the ignition switch to OFF before unplugging a connector or
                            relay. Failure to turn the switch to OFF will cause a voltage spike and damage to electrical
                            components.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="h09065" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h09065.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Valve cover electrical connector lock</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="h09066" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h09066.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Lock shown flush with electrical connector, indicating it is fully seated
                    </caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The valve cover electrical connector lock
                    <xref refid="h09065"/>
                    ensures that each fuel injector and Injector Control Pressure (ICP) electrical connector is fully
                    seated
                    <xref refid="h09066"/>
                    during assembly at the engine plant.
                </para>
                <para>Each of the six fuel injectors and ICP electrical connectors have connector locks installed during
                    production build at the factory. The Brake Control Pressure (BCP) sensor connector and the engine
                    brake shut-off valve connector do not have the connector locks installed during production.
                </para>
                <para>These locks are not available as service parts since they are only used as a production aid and
                    not intended as a service installation part.
                </para>
                <para>If a connector with a lock needs servicing, remove the lock before attempting to disconnect the
                    connector.
                </para>
                <figure id="h09067" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h09067.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. Arrows indicate where to grab lock with needle nose pliers</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="h09068" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/h09068.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Remove lock with needle nose pliers</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>To remove lock;</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Insert tip of the needle nose pliers in the U-shaped section of the lock while positioning
                            the other tip of the pliers between the lock top and the connector
                            <xref refid="h09067"/>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With the pliers gripping the lock, pull the pliers away from the valve cover to remove the
                            lock
                            <xref refid="h09068"/>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After removing the lock, the electrical connector can be removed from the valve cover
                            gasket, after pressing the release tab for the connector.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Ensure the electrical connector is fully seated and latched when reinstalling it. An
                            improperly installed electrical connector can cause a no-start condition or damage to a
                            component.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Connectors must be properly seated and latched to avoid possible driveability concerns or
                            a no-start condition. Installing connectors on an angle may cause an improper connection and
                            damaged components. Apply light pressure to get the connector into position and then fully
                            seat the connector.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <note>
                        <para>The lock does not need to be re-installed after proper installation of the electrical
                            connector has been completed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
