<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-13-03 - Allison WT Transmission Control Module Relocation</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-13-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Allison WT Transmission Control Module Relocation</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Allison</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>7600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to the 7600 and 8600 models with Caterpillar C10/12 and Cummins ISM engines.
                    Trucks that operate in certain vocations that subject the under cab/chassis area to excessive debris
                    and ice control chemicals may require the relocation of the Transmission Control Module for better
                    environmental protection. The following procedures are required to relocate the Allison Transmission
                    Control Module from inside the right side frame rail to inside the cab on the cab rear sill. For I-6
                    procedures see TSI-05-13-02.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t051303">
                <tgroup cols="2" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.57*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.43*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2590019C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Harness for Caterpillar C10/12 and Cummins ISM</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3565125C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Grommet, Rubber (2 1/4 Inch)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="6">
            <title>service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface,
                        set the parking brake, turn the engine off, and chock the wheels.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Batteries expel explosive gases. Keep sparks, flames, burning cigarettes, or other ignition
                        sources away at all times. Always wear safety glasses and a face shield when working near
                        batteries to avoid property damage, personal injury, or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the positive and negative battery cable from the battery connectors.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate the Transmission Control Module mounted to the inside of the right side frame
                    rail under the cab. See Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0513031" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Locate Control Module</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f0513032" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513032.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Disconnect Harness from Control Module</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the three connectors from the Transmission Control Module and unbolt the
                    module mounting bracket from the frame rail.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the other end of the harness that was disconnected from the control module in
                    step 3. Make note of its position on the connector mounting bracket at the rear of the transmission
                    shown in Figure 2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect and remove the chassis harness from the mounting bracket at the rear of the
                    transmission. Disconnect and note where the other harness breakouts are connected on the right side
                    of the transmission; i.e., the Vehicle speed sensor, the Turbine Speed Sensor, and the Engine Speed
                    Sensor. See Figure 2. The only remaining connector/ harness on the transmission bracket should be
                    the transmission harness feeding the transmission.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To make hookup easier, remove the remaining connector from the transmission bracket and
                    re-install it so it faces rearward in the top mounting hole as shown in Figure 3. On some
                    combinations this connector may already face rearward.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the replacement harness on top of the transmission. Route the engine
                    compartment connectors into the engine compartment, the transmission end to the transmission mounted
                    bracket at the rear of the transmission, and the Transmission Control Module end near the plugged
                    hole in the center of the cab floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At the transmission end, connect the new harness connector to the relocated mating
                    connector that goes into the transmission as shown in Figure 3.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0513033" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Connect New Harness</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the speed sensor leads to the various speed sensors that were disconnected in
                    Step 5.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rubber plug in the center of the cab floor and feed the transmission control
                    module connectors through the floor. Along with the module connectors, make certain that the J1939
                    resistor and connector are also brought into the cab. See Figure 4.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In some applications the predrilled hole may be used by other body builder equipment. If
                        necessary drill an additional 2 1/4" hole in the shifter filler panel near the existing hole and
                        use rubber grommet to seal the cable and hole.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f0513034" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513034.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Connect New Harness Module Connectors and J1939 Resistor in Cab</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">As you remove the old harness from above the transmission, route the new harness leading
                    forward into the engine compartment into the same clipping points as the old.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Figure 5 illustrates the connectors that are now located in the engine compartment which
                    must be connected in place of the old harness that can also be seen in the figure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0513035" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513035.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Connectors in Engine Compartment</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the old harness and replace with the connectors supplied on the new harness.
                    The single connector with the green wire will not be used and should be taped back against the
                    harness. There may also be one or two body builder connectors that will not be used depending on the
                    application of the truck being worked on.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The Transmission Control Module and mounting bracket will be relocated to the rear sill
                    of the cab near the centerline of the cab. See Figure 6 for proper orientation of the bracket/module
                    as it mounts to the floor. Location may vary depending on other equipment located in cab by the body
                    builder.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the module from the bracket. The flange of the bracket to be mounted to the floor
                    will have one of the mounting holes already drilled. Locate another hole on the opposite end of the
                    flange approximately &#190;" in from both edges. Drill a &#188;" hole.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the mounting bracket as a template, locate the two holes to be drilled through the
                    cab floor sill. Drill two holes appropriate for mounting 3/16" self tapping bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the bracket using the newly drilled holes (Figure 6).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f0513036" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0513036.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="432px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Mount Bracket</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the three connectors to the transmission control module. Connect black connector
                    to "Black", the blue connector to "Blue", and the clear connector to "Gray". In addition to being
                    color coded all connectors are keyed to the proper module connector. Don't force the connectors onto
                    the wrong connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remount the module to the bracket using the original hardware.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fit the floor grommet to the cable and re-insert the grommet into the floor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain that the main harness from the transmission to the engine compartment is
                    properly routed and clipped in the same fashion as the original, particularly those areas where the
                    connections are made under the hood.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect battery cables and test for proper operation.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
