<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 05-16-02R - Hoses for Add-On AC Evaporators</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi051602" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>05-16-02R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>03-16-05</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>August, 2005</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Hoses for Add-On AC Evaporators</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="yes" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>In some applications it may be advantageous to add an additional AC evaporator to cool remote
                    areas such as a sleeper compartment. This letter provides the part numbers of the needed hoses and
                    the procedure to accommodate these additions.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Pre 2004 Emission DT 466 and 530 Engines</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6 engine) - 2585758C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6 engine) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Post 2004 Emission DT 466 and 570 Engines, Low Mount Cab</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6 engine) 2588940C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6 engine) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Post 2004 Emission DT 466 and 570 Engines, Mid High Cab</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for I6 engine) - 2588941C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for I6 engine) - 2585759C91</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">For VT 365 Engines</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy accumulator to compressor (for V8 engine) - 2585760C91</para>
            <para>Hose, A/C assy condenser to evaporator (for V8 engine) - 2585761C91</para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death park the vehicle on a level surface, set
                        the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the engine off.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear a face shield or other adequate eye protection when working with refrigerant. The
                        temperature of liquid refrigerant may cause injury or blindness if the refrigerant contacts the
                        eyes.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Wear nonporous gloves when working with refrigerant. Should liquid refrigerant come in contact
                        with skin, remove contaminated clothing, including shoes and treat the injury as though the skin
                        had been frostbitten. See a doctor immediately.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the
                        system are replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause personal
                        injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recover the refrigerant from the AC system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the AC hose from the condenser to the evaporator and install the new hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the AC hose from the accumulator to the compressor and install the new hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the AC hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed
                    hose from the condenser to the evaporator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the AC hose from the new evaporator to the aux. fitting on the newly installed
                    hose from the accumulator to the compressor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate the system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge the system using R-134a refrigerant. The original truck system holds 30 oz. and
                    the new evaporator should require an additional 16 oz. The additional requirement will vary from
                    system to system depending on the length of hoses and the capacity of the new evaporator. The
                    additional capacity will also require an additional 40 cc (1.2 fl. Oz.) of PAG oil in the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Failure to add additional PAG oil to the increased capacity AC system will result in improper
                        lubrication and lead to premature component failure.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate the vehicle to make sure the AC is performing properly and is not leaking.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
