<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-04-03 - Quality Connect Air Fitting Service Information</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi060403" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-04-03</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>94-04-03</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>November, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Quality Connect Air Fitting Service Information</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with air systems.</para>
                <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation has been using Quality Connect air fittings on vehicles
                    with air systems for several years. The Quality Connect fittings are threadless. A collet in the
                    fitting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404031">Figure 1</hotlnk>) bites into the tube to hold it firmly in place. The
                    fitting O-ring (Figure 1) seals the tube to the valve, manifold or tee body to prevent leakage. To
                    aid in service, a kit (part number 991843C91) is available with tools for each port and tube size
                    used by International&#174;.
                </para>
                <para>This letter contains information on how to service Quality Connect air fittings.</para>
                <figure id="f9404031" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9404031.png" type="png"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0604031" tblwidth="pg-wide" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.99in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="2.76in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="1to2"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>991843C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Tool Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="1to2">
                                <para>The Tool Kit contains the following tools.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1698698C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Tube Release Tool</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1698699C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Plug Puller Tool</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1698700C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Collet Service Tool</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1698701C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Tube Cutter Tool</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc id="x9404031" svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>LEAKAGE TEST</title>
            <para>Use Amprobe ultrasonic leak detector (Part Number ZTSE4800) to locate leaks. Use soap bubbles to
                determine severity.
            </para>
            <para>A soap bubble test can be made to determine if the quality connect fitting(s) needs repair. When
                performing a bubble test, leakage should not exceed a soap bubble of 1/2 inch (12 mm) in 3 seconds with
                system air pressure of 100 to 130 psi. If the leakage exceeds these specifications, the quality connect
                fitting(s) should be serviced.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="x9404033" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="11">
            <title>FIELD SERVICE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, completely drain system of air pressure before
                        removing.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a leak has been discovered and service is necessary, drain the air off the system and
                    push the tube into the port to make sure it is fully seated.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pressurize the system. If the leak still exceeds specifications, it will be necessary to
                    disassemble the fitting to determine the cause of the excessive air leak.
                </para>
                <para>Select the appropriate repair tools and parts for the tube size being serviced.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the tube release tool (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404032">Figure 2</hotlnk>) to remove the tube. Do this by placing it around the
                    tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404032" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9404032.png" type="png"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Push the release tool against the fitting, then pull on the tube. Pushing the tool
                    depresses the fitting collet, allowing it to release the tube. Sometimes the brass tube support (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404031">Figure 1</hotlnk>) will be pulled out of the fitting when the tube is
                    removed. Be sure to re-install a tube support when installing the tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the brass tube support remains in the fitting and is undamaged, leave it in place. If
                    it remains in the fitting but looks damaged, remove it with needle nose pliers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404033">Figure 3</hotlnk>). Discard the brass tube support then install a new
                    brass tube support of the same size. (see step 10 ). If fitting is equipped with a black molded tube
                    support, it cannot be removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404033" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404033.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the port for any debris or contaminants. Remove any that are found.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1 id="x9404032">
                <para count="1">Inspect the tube end for external scratches, burrs, or cracks. If it is damaged, trim
                    the damaged portion off at an insertion depth mark (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404034">Figure 4</hotlnk>) or replace the tube. DO NOT re-use a damaged end.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404034" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404034.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Use the tube cutter (supplied in the tool kit) to ensure that the cut is square within 15&#176;
                        to help prevent leakage (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9404035">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Do not use a dull or heavy cutting tool such as
                        side cutters, pocket knife or hack saw which could collapse (flatten) the tube or create O-ring
                        damaging burrs. Do not use the tube cutter to cut anything other than nylon air line tubing.
                        Replace the blade or cutter if the cutting edge becomes dull.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f9404035" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9404035.png" type="png"/>
                <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the forked end of the repair tool to remove the collet (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404036">Figure 6</hotlnk>). Discard the collet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404036" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404036.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the O-ring using the repair tool O-ring remover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404037">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Discard the O-ring. Avoid scratching the O-ring cavity
                    during removal of the O-ring.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404037" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404037.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7.</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the O-ring cavity is scratched even slightly during removal of the O-ring, the scratch may
                        cause the fitting to leak.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the tube support was removed, place it or a new one into a shipping plug (supplied in
                    the parts kit). Press the tube support into the port until it bottoms out (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404038">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Remove the shipping plug with the plug removal tool.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404038" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404038.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use an approved lubricant (preferably liquid detergent in water) and lubricate the new
                    O-ring. Place the O-ring inside the top of the Quality Connect fitting sleeve as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404039">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9404039" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9404039.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new collet. Hand pressure alone is enough. It will click when it is seated
                    properly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403a">Figure 10</hotlnk>). In addition, the collet will push the O-ring into its
                    fully seated position (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9404031">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403a" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403A.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the tubing does not have an insertion depth mark, perform the following: Use the
                    repair tool (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403b">Figure 11</hotlnk>) to identify the correct insertion depth for the size
                    tubing being used. Mark the correct insertion depth on the tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403b" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403B.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the tube end with an approved lubricant (preferably liquid detergent in
                    water)and install it to the correct insertion depth (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403c">Figure 12</hotlnk>). Install the tube by pushing it straight into the
                    fitting. The insertion depth mark should be flush with the face of the fitting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403c">Figure 12</hotlnk>). Gently tug on the tube to make sure it is secured in
                    the fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403c" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403C.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test to make sure the assembly is free from leaks using a soap solution and clean, dry
                    air at system pressure. If a leak exceeding specifications (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9404031">Leakage Test</hotlnk>) is still present, remove and replace the valve,
                    manifold or tee.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="3">
            <title>TUBE INSTALLATION INTO UNUSED PORTS</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To use an unused port, first remove the shipping plug with the plug removal tool. This
                    can be done by depressing the collet, then pulling out the plug (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403d">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403d" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403D.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the repair tool (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403e">Figure 14</hotlnk>) to identify the correct insertion depth for the size
                    tubing being used. Mark the correct insertion depth on the tube. If tubing with insertion depth
                    marks is being used, trim the end of the tubing at an insertion mark using a recommended tube
                    cutter. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9404032">FIELD SERVICE, Step 7</hotlnk>
                    for tube cutting information.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403e" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403E.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 14.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the tube with an approved lubricant (preferably liquid detergent in water)and
                    install it to the correct insertion depth. Install the tube by pushing it straight into the fitting.
                    The insertion depth mark should be flush with the face of the fitting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f940403f">Figure 15</hotlnk>). Gently tug on the tube to make sure it is secured in
                    the fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f940403f" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G940403F.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 15.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test to make sure the assembly is free from leaks using a soap solution and clean, dry
                    air at system pressure. If the fitting leak exceeds specifications (refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9404031">Leakage Test</hotlnk>) perform the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9404033">FIELD SERVICE</hotlnk>
                    procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
