<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-08-05 - High Voltage Circuits (Greater than 50 Volts) on International&#174; Trucks and Buses
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi060805" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-08-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>High Voltage Circuits (Greater than 50 Volts) on International&#174; Trucks and Buses</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="yes" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death refer to the manufacturer's service
                            information before working on any high voltage equipment. By definition high voltage
                            circuits and components contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage, electrical
                            shock and/or electrocution if handled incorrectly.
                        </para>
                        <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work
                            around or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The intent of this document
                            <emph type="boldundersc">IS</emph>
                            to provide some basic guidelines when working on or around International&#174; vehicles that
                            are equipped with high voltage electrical equipment and circuits. For specific instructions,
                            maintenance, or service information on specific equipment or options refer to the service
                            manuals for the specified truck models and component(s). It
                            <emph type="boldundersc">IS NOT</emph>
                            the intent of this document to provide detailed service instructions for high voltage
                            equipment and circuits.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>High voltage systems require the maintainer to be familiar with two types of electrical systems.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">DC (Direct Current)</emph>Most DC systems on today's trucks use 12 Volt
                            negative ground. Some systems can store DC electricity in batteries with operating voltages
                            as high as 600 DC volts.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">AC (Alternating Current)</emph>The main difference between AC and DC
                            systems is that the voltage levels in DC systems remain constant while the voltage levels in
                            AC systems are constantly changing. When measuring an AC system, it is important to know
                            that the average voltage is zero and that is why
                            <emph type="boldundersc">A VOLTMETER SET TO DC WILL NOT INDICATE THE PRESENCE OF AN AC
                                VOLTAGE WHEN CONNECTED TO AN AC CIRCUIT!
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>High Voltage can be lethal. Always refer to the manufacturer of the high voltage component
                            when maintenance or repairs are needed. In most cases, diagnostics and repair are performed
                            after the high voltage circuits are disabled. If you work around or maintain high voltage
                            circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, circuits must be checked using a
                            voltmeter for the presence of both dc and ac voltages. A voltmeter set to dc will not
                            indicate the presence of an ac voltage when connected to an ac circuit! Contacting an
                            unknown ac or dc voltage may cause equipment damage, electrical shock and/or electrocution.
                        </para>
                        <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work
                            around or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">Understanding high voltage equipment and circuits on International&#174;products</emph>
                    </title>
                </para>
                <para>Some examples of high voltage equipment that can be encountered on products include:</para>
                <randlist type="dash">
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Auxiliary Power Units (APUs)</emph>APUs are basically small diesel powered
                            generator units that are integrated into the vehicle electrical system. APUs are utilized in
                            combination with inverters and battery chargers. APUs are often set up to automatically
                            start when the electrical management system deems it necessary to maintain battery charge or
                            electrical demand requires it.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: APU high voltage wiring may</emph>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">NOT</emph>
                            <emph type="bold">be marked for easy identification as high voltage.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Shore Power</emph>Shore power is a connection from a vehicle to an
                            external 120 volt AC power source. The vehicle is equipped with an exterior receptacle that
                            allows connection to an external "shore" power source.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: High voltage shore power wiring may</emph>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">NOT</emph>
                            <emph type="bold">be marked for easy identification as high voltage.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Inverters</emph>Inverters are electronic devices used to change DC (Direct
                            Current) into AC (Alternating Current). Some inverters contain converters that also convert
                            AC to DC for battery charging or running 12V equipment.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: High voltage wiring for Inverters may</emph>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">NOT</emph>
                            <emph type="bold">be marked for easy identification as high voltage.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Hybrid Electric Vehicles (HEVs)</emph>HEVs combine internal combustion
                            engines with high voltage batteries, electric motors, and inverters to offer higher fuel
                            efficiency and lower emissions without compromising power, range, and convenient fueling of
                            conventional vehicles. Regardless of the HEV design, high electrical voltages and currents
                            are present.
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: The industry standard for high voltage cables are for the cables to
                                be covered in
                            </emph>
                            <emph type="boldundersc">ORANGE CONDUIT</emph>
                            <emph type="bold">.</emph>
                            If orange conduit is observed on a vehicle, please review the safety precautions for that
                            system.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <title>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">How to identify high voltage circuits</emph>
                    </title>
                </para>
                <para>High voltage circuits are not always connected with large wires. The best way to identify high
                    voltage equipment or circuits is to be familiar with the equipment and circuit diagrams as well as
                    to look for high voltage warning labels and orange conduit.
                    <emph type="underscr">Inspect the vehicle for any equipment or circuits added after the truck was
                        built
                    </emph>
                    (owner/operators may add high voltage components such as inverters or APUs).
                </para>
                <para>All electrical circuits associated with APUs, shore power, inverters, and HEVs should be
                    considered high voltage. The standard for high voltage cabling on HEVs is orange. APUs, Inverters,
                    shore power, and cabin 110/120V outlet wiring may not indicate high voltage by visual inspection
                    (they may not be marked and are NOT orange in color).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">Servicing International&#174; products</emph>
                    </title>
                </para>
                <para>The following steps outline the appropriate method to follow to identify and address any
                    maintenance or service on International&#174; products with factory installed high voltage
                    equipment.
                </para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Complete related training prior to attempting to identify and service any high voltage
                            system.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Review the line-set ticket provided with the vehicle or from ISIS and identify all high
                            voltage components.
                            <emph type="underscr">Inspect the vehicle for any equipment or circuits added after the
                                truck was built
                            </emph>
                            (owner/operators may add high voltage components such as inverters or APUs that could be
                            live and powering circuits in the vehicle
                            <emph type="underscr">EVEN WITH THE IGNITION OFF AND THE BATTERIES DISCONNECTED</emph>).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refer to manufacturer's service publications for identified high voltage components.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Physically locate high voltage components on the vehicle and disable them according to
                            manufacturer's instructions (some components may require a waiting period or special
                            procedures to discharge the voltage completely).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use Best Work Practices (see below) when performing work on electrical systems.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>
                    <title>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">Best Work Practices</emph>
                    </title>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury or death, permit only trained responsible and capable persons to
                            operate or maintain the equipment. Carelessly operating or neglecting maintenance despite
                            the safe design of any vehicle and its high voltage equipment may result in personal injury
                            or death.
                        </para>
                        <para>The danger of injury through electrical shock is possible whenever electrical power is
                            present. Most fatal injuries result from high-voltage exposure; however, people can sustain
                            severe injuries from low voltage power if it has a high current flow.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Be aware of ALL high voltage equipment on the vehicle; review line-set/build ticket and
                            the owner and service manuals of high voltage equipment
                            <emph type="underscr">BEFORE</emph>
                            starting any work.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When working on this equipment, remain alert at all times. Never work on the equipment
                            when you are physically or mentally fatigued and never work alone near high voltage
                            equipment.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Always stand on an insulated, dry surface when working on any electrical circuit. Do not
                            handle any kind of electrical device while standing in water, while barefoot, or while hands
                            or feet are wet.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Always work in an adequately illuminated area.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Always use appropriate protective equipment: insulated gloves, rubber gloves, goggles/face
                            shield, safety shoes, protective clothing, and insulated tools when working on electrical
                            components/circuits of the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Never wear jewelry when working on this equipment. Jewelry can conduct electricity
                            resulting in electric shock or burns, and may get caught in moving components causing
                            injury.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When working on vehicles that have high voltage devices or equipment, use appropriate
                            alerting techniques in plain view to warn people that may be in the general area and to
                            prevent inadvertent activation of any disabled high voltage circuit(s) during service:
                            safety signs, safety symbols, tags, barricades, cones, etc.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Keep a fire extinguisher close by at all times. Extinguishers rated "ABC" by the National
                            Fire Protection Association are appropriate for use on the electrical system. Make sure the
                            extinguisher is properly charged and be familiar with its use. If you have any question
                            pertaining to fire extinguishers, consult your local fire department.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Ensure that the high voltage power, high voltage power generating equipment, and high
                            voltage storage devices are disconnected, locked out, or otherwise disabled
                            <emph type="underscr">BEFORE</emph>
                            working on or around the vehicle, its electrical circuits, or components. Unless disabled,
                            Auxiliary Power Units (APUs) may start at any time without warning; when this occurs, the
                            circuits associated with the APU become energized with potentially lethal high voltage. Some
                            components may require a waiting period or special procedures to discharge the voltage
                            completely.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use an appropriate electrical tester and procedures to confirm that the power is
                            disconnected
                            <emph type="underscr">BEFORE</emph>
                            performing any work on or near any high voltage components/circuits.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Exercise caution around output circuits even when the input power is off. Parallel power
                            sources and energy storage devices can still be dangerous. Be familiar with the high voltage
                            equipment installed on the vehicle. Some systems contain high voltage condensers that may
                            require time to discharge after power is removed.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After disconnecting or exposing a high-voltage connector or terminal, insulate it
                            immediately using insulation tape.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>After completion of any electrical work,
                            <emph type="underscr">BEFORE</emph>
                            restoring the power, verify that parts and or tools are removed from the work area and that
                            the fasteners are firmly tightened to the specified torque and the connectors are correctly
                            connected.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Voltage can be fatal at levels greater than 60 volts. High voltage can jump a larger air
                            gap than low voltage. If contact is made with high voltage it may not be possible to simply
                            "let go".
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Towing a HEV with its drive wheels on the ground may cause the motor to generate
                            electricity. Consult your operator's/owner's manual for proper towing procedures.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a high voltage fuse or circuit protection device trips, do not re-energize the circuit
                            until it has been determined that the circuit is safe. See manufacturers troubleshooting
                            procedures before servicing a high voltage system.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Reference OSHA Regulations as necessary and applicable.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <title>
                        <emph type="boldundersc">High Voltage Feature Codes</emph>
                    </title>
                </para>
                <para>The following is a listing of High Voltage feature codes released for production
                    <emph type="underscr">at the date of release of this TSI</emph>. This listing does not include
                    feature codes for block heaters, oil pan heaters, and shore power circuits which require connection
                    to a 120V external power source.
                </para>
                <para>08WES - Inverter (PowerPack 1)</para>
                <para>60AAC - Inverter (PowerPack 3)</para>
                <para>12WTK - Auxiliary Power Unit</para>
                <para>10HEV - Hybrid Electric Vehicle ID</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Additional high voltage equipment may be retrofitted or added by body builders or owners
                            and operators after a truck is built.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
