<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-08-07 - Replacement of Grafo Dielectric Grease</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi060807" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-08-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Electrical</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Replacement of Grafo Dielectric Grease</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Electrical connections at components such as starters, alternators, batteries and electrical
                    grounds are currently or were previously protected after assembly using Grafo dielectric grease
                    (part number 472141C2). Grafo grease has been or will be replaced by Fluid Film, part number
                    2593148C1 with the intent that all locations will begin using Fluid Film as soon as possible. There
                    will be a difference in appearance between Grafo grease which is typically dark purple to dark brown
                    versus Fluid Film which is light amber in color.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0608071" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0608071.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0608072" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0608072.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                             scalefitheight="304px"/>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0608071" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.08*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.08*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.86*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">New Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Old Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2593148C1 Fluid Film</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>472141C2 Grafo grease</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>dielectric grease</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to neutral or park , set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, remove ground cable from negative terminal of main battery
                        before disconnecting or connecting electrical components. Always connect ground cable last.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not spray Fluid Film on or around open flames, sparks
                        or hot areas. Fluid Film is Extremely Flammable.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">After completion of an electrical repair, re-apply fluid film or replace Grafo grease
                    with fluid film to protect the electrical connection from the elements. If you are applying Fluid
                    Film to an electrical connection that had Grafo grease on it, all Grafo grease needs to be cleaned
                    from the area before Fluid Film is applied.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTICE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                representations made by the Company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions
                accompanying the product, International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps
                resulting from such errors, or from any misuse of the product.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Please refer to the
                    <exhotlnk document="../tsis/060807.pdf" bookname="TSI">pdf for this TSI</exhotlnk>for more
                    information on Fluid Film&#174;.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
