<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-12-17 - Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel (ULSD) Effects on Seals</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi061217" year="2006" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>06-12-17</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel (ULSD) Effects on Seals</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all International&#174; diesel engines, 2006 model year and older.</para>
                <para>The U.S. EPA has mandated the use of Ultra Low Sulfur Diesel (ULSD) in on-road applications.
                    Replacement of Low Sulfur Diesel (LSD) with ULSD has already begun at most fuel suppliers and will
                    be completed by October 15, 2006.
                </para>
                <para>Depending on the refinery process and crude oil specifics, ULSD may have less aromatic content
                    than LSD. While a lower aromatic level is acceptable according to the ASTM diesel fuel standard, it
                    may cause fuel system seals in older engines to shrink and potentially leak. Older engines are
                    susceptible to shrinkage because their seals may have lost elasticity over time. Engines that have
                    not run for long periods of time with LSD or have been solely run on ULSD, are at minimal risk.
                </para>
                <para>To avoid fuel leaks when changing from LSD to ULSD, consider replacing fuel system seals on
                    engines that have been using LSD for a prolonged period of time. If leakage is experienced when
                    using ULSD, all seals in the fuel system should be replaced, including the fuel lift/transfer pump
                    and the seals in the fuel filter header.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
