<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-12-03 - Increase Crankshaft Vibration Damper Bolt Torque</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI061203" year="2006" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>06-12-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Increase Crankshaft Vibration Damper Bolt Torque</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 570</engfam>
                <engfam>HT 530</engfam>
                <engfam>HT 570</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The vibration damper bolt torque has been increased to 163 N&#183;m (120 lbf&#183;ft). To fully
                    seat the vibration damper against the crankshaft face, the damper bolts must be tightened evenly in
                    sequence, and continue until final torque of 163 N&#183;m (120 lbf&#183;ft) is reached with no
                    movement of any of the three bolts. This will require going around in sequence several times until
                    all three bolts are at final torque with no movement.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid serious personal injury or possible death, the vibration damper must be
                            completely seated on the crankshaft.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid possible engine or vehicle damage, during vibration damper installation, damper
                            bolts must be grade 12.9 and damper retaining plate must be 15.24 mm (0.600 inch) thick.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <note>
                        <para>Grade 12.9 damper bolts have 12 point heads.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>If the vibration damper is removed during service, verify damper bolts are grade 12.9 and damper
                    retaining plate is 15.24 mm (0.600 inch) thick. If they are, the three damper bolts and the damper
                    retainer plate may be reused. During vibration damper installation, tighten the three bolts in
                    sequence to the new torque during vibration damper installation.
                </para>
                <para>If the damper bolts are not grade 12.9, discard the three damper bolts and the damper retainer
                    plate. Install Damper Retainer Kit 1873220C91 during vibration damper installation.
                </para>
                <para>If one or more damper bolts are damaged, discard all three damper bolts. Install three new damper
                    bolts 1850815C1, and tighten the three bolts in sequence to the new torque during vibration damper
                    installation.
                </para>
                <para>If the damper retaining plate is not 15.24 mm (0.600 inch) thick or is damaged, discard the three
                    damper bolts and the damper retainer plate. Install Damper Retainer Kit 1873220C91 during vibration
                    damper installation.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
