<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-12-19 - Air Sensing Viscous Fan Drive Diagnostic Test Procedure</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi061219" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-12-19</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>00-12-05</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>October, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Air Sensing Viscous Fan Drive Diagnostic Test Procedure</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>BorgWarner</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>A correctly operating air sensing viscous fan drive may be misdiagnosed as faulty using the
                    procedures previously available. To reduce the number of misdiagnosed viscous fan drives, perform
                    the updated service procedure that follows.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, read all safety instructions in the
                            <exhotlnk document="../s12/s12002y.htm" bookname="s12002y">S12002Y</exhotlnk>
                            service manual regarding use, application, or modification of a viscous fan drive and/or the
                            fan it carries.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, DO NOT operate a vehicle with a fan
                            drive or fan blades that are malfunctioning or damaged.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, DO NOT attempt to restrict fan blade
                            rotation during engine operation.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, comply with the following before
                            performing tests on the fan drive:
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake, and block wheels.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Wear safety glasses with side shields.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Do not wear loose clothing that can come into contact with the rotating fan
                                    blades.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Avoid contact with hot surfaces.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Protect test leads from contact with rotating components.</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc id="x0012051" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="5">
            <title>For snap action bi-metal or Coil VISCOUS FAN DRIVE TEST PROCEDURE (air sensing viscous DRIVES ONLY)
            </title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This test is most effective at an ambient air temperature of 80&#176;F (26.7&#176;C) or
                            higher.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Diagnostic Procedure</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The engine must be off for Steps 1 through 8.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the torque of fan blade fasteners. Refer to Table 1, Torque Chart.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the torque of fan drive-to-pulley, hub and bracket assembly fasteners.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the torque of pulley, hub and bracket assembly-to-engine fasteners.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check the fan drive, fan blade assembly, shroud, radiator and the immediately
                        adjacent areas for evidence of interference between rotating and non-rotating parts. If damage
                        is present, isolate and repair the problem and replace damaged parts.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the fan, by hand, through at least 360 degrees. It should turn smoothly, but
                        with some internal resistance. Replace fan drive if it binds, jerks, or spins freely. Insure the
                        fan does not contact other objects.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The following step is used to detect looseness in the fan or fan drive mounting; when
                            performing the Step, do not force the blade tip (cause the blade to deflect) because this
                            will distort the resulting measurement.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Grasp one fan blade tip, and apply fore and aft pressure. At 10 inches (254 mm)
                        radius from the center, the blade tip should not move more than 1/16 inch (1.6 mm). If the blade
                        moves more than specified and the excess cannot be attributed to pulley/water pump bearing wear,
                        fan blade deflection, or loose fasteners (fan to fan drive or fan drive to hub/pulley), replace
                        the fan drive.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Check for obstructions in the radiator, charge air cooler, air conditioning
                        condenser, and transmission cooler (if equipped). Remove any dirt, bugs, lint, or debris in the
                        air path through the radiator to the engine. Pressure wash if necessary.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury or death, wear heat protective gloves and safety glasses when
                            working with hot liquids and objects.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid property damage, DO NOT direct high-pressure spray onto the fan drive bi-metal.
                            High-pressure sprays must be directed squarely at the front, or rear, of the radiator and
                            other coolers to prevent fin damage. Bent fin or fin damage will negatively affect air flow
                            and/or cooling capacity of the radiator and other coolers.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Ensure the cooling system is properly filled with the correct coolant mixtures (not
                        to exceed 60% ethylene glycol).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following Step, warming up a cold engine prior to test preparation will shorten the
                            run-time during the test procedure.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If engine is cold, start engine and:</para>
                </step1>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>turn air conditioning OFF,</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>turn heater OFF (NOTE: on buses, turn heater supply valves OFF at the engine),</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>run until thermostat opens; then,
                            <emph type="bold">turn engine OFF</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury or death when working near a hot engine wear protective clothing
                            and heat protective gloves.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following Step, nylon fan blades (yellow in color) may require painting with flat
                            black paint in order to measure fan speed.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply a strip of reflective tape to one (1) blade of the fan and another strip to
                        the fan drive shaft so that fan RPM and fan drive shaft RPM can be measured with the digital
                        photo-tachometer (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0012051">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0012051" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0012051" filename="../tsifigures/G0012051.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="448px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Placement of Reflective Tape</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. Reflective tape on fan blade</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. Reflective tape on fan drive shaft</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Connect EZ-Tech service tool. If testing a non-electronic engine, measure coolant
                        temperature with an accurate thermometer.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Fabricate a cardboard cover that covers the entire frontal area of the radiator. Cut
                        a 5 inch (12.7 cm) hole in the area that aligns directly in front of the fan drive bi-metal
                        switch or coil. Position the cardboard in front of the radiator and tape as necessary to hold in
                        place.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully position the temperature probe so that it measures air temperature within
                        1 inch (2.54 cm) of the fan drive bi-metal or coil. You can safely insert the probe through the
                        A/C condenser, CAC, and radiator core (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0012052">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0012053">Figure 3</hotlnk>) .
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0012052" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0012052" filename="../tsifigures/G0012052.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="448px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Temperature Probe Inserted through Cardboard and Front of Radiator</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. Temperature probe</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f0012053" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0012053" filename="../tsifigures/G0012053.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="448px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3. Positioning of Temperature Probe</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. Temperature probe must be positioned in this area [1 inch (2.54 cm) from
                            bi-metal].
                        </callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Start the engine and:</para>
                </step1>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>recheck to ensure the air conditioning and heater are still OFF (on buses, turn heater
                            supply valves OFF),
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>turn electrical loads ON (lights, etc.).</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the following Step the fan drive shaft speed is not the same as engine speed.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Raise the engine speed until the
                        <emph type="underscr">fan drive shaft</emph>
                        reaches 2500 RPM (measured with digital photo-tach).
                        <emph type="underscr">Do not measure fan speed yet.</emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Bright sunlight may make it difficult to read RPM measurements using the
                            photo-tachometer.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lock the throttle at this RPM (use PTO/cruise switches if available). This
                        establishes the fan drive shaft
                        <emph type="boldundersc">TEST</emph>
                        RPM.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>If engine cannot achieve 2500 RPM fan drive shaft input speed, test at the highest
                                obtainable RPM.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Measure fan blade speed with the digital photo-tachometer (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f0012054">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0012054" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0012054" filename="../tsifigures/G0012054.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="448px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Measuring Fan Blade Speed with Digital Photo-Tachometer</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with shutters, they should open automatically before the fan
                            drive engages.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1 id="x0012052">
                    <para count="1">As the engine is warming up:</para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The fan RPM should stabilize between 700 and 1100 RPM. Some DD-30 and DD-34 fan
                            drives may stabilize at up to 1300 RPM.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">As engine coolant temperature reaches 200-220&#176;F (93.3-104.4&#176;C)
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0012055">(Figure 5)</hotlnk>, fan speed should increase to 85% or more of
                            the fan shaft RPM.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">The air temperature at the bi-metal or coil should be between 165&#176;F (73.9&#176;C)
                            and 195&#176;F (90.6&#176;C) when the fan engages (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f0012055">Figure 5</hotlnk>). Refer to the
                            <exhotlnk document="../tsis/061219.pdf" bookname="TSI">Borg Warner attachment in the pdf for
                                this TSI
                            </exhotlnk>
                            for specific fan drive P/N calibration information.
                        </para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f0012055" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic id="g0012055" filename="../tsifigures/G0012055.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="448px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Measuring the Coolant and Air Temperatures</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">With the fan engaged,
                        <emph type="underscr">record fan RPM, coolant temperature, and air temperature at bi-metal or
                            coil.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Maintain the TESTRPM, with the fan engaged, by keeping the engine speed constant.
                        Remove the cardboard cover from the cooling module. As temperatures decrease, fan speed should
                        begin to decrease. After 2-3 minutes the fan should slow to the initial fan speed (approximately
                        700 to 1100 RPM).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Allow fan to repeat this cycle several times while recording temperatures and fan
                        RPM, utilizing cardboard cooling module cover as required to force fan drive engagement.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Conclusion:</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the fan fails to reach 85% of input speed at 200 - 220&#176;F (93.3-104.4&#176;C)
                        coolant temperature, and the air temperature at the bi-metal exceeds 195&#176;F (90.6&#176;C),
                        replace the viscous fan drive.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the fan fails to reach 85% of fan input speed, and the coolant temperature
                        exceeds 220&#176;F (104.4&#176;C), and the air temperature at the bi-metal or coil does not
                        exceed 195&#176;F (90.6&#176;C); then the fan drive is not faulty. Inspect the vehicle for the
                        following:
                    </para>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Air flow restrictions (through the CAC and radiator)</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Internal radiator plugging</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Faulty thermostat</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Defective water pump</para>
                    </step2>
                    <step2>
                        <para count="1">Refer to TSI-05-12-34 for additional diagnostic information</para>
                    </step2>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">When the fan drive disengages (with the 2500
                        <emph type="bold">TEST</emph>
                        RPM maintained), if the fan speed fails to slow to 700-1100 RPM; replace the fan drive (except
                        DD-30 and DD-34 which could be in the 1300 RPM range).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the air temperature sensing probe from the radiator.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the cardboard from the front of the radiator.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Return the engine to "idle" and allow the engine to cool for two (2) minutes before
                        shutting down.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <para>NOTES:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Engagement air temperatures indicate test cell calibration and may vary in the vehicle.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Bi-metal and coil fan drives will have a gradual engagement speed until the fan is fully
                            in the modulated ON position.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="x0012053" svcproctype="torque chart" graphiccount="0">
            <title>TORQUE CHART</title>
            <table id="t0012052" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Torque Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.50in"/>
                    <colspec colname="2" colwidth="1.28in"/>
                    <colspec colname="3" colwidth="1.36in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Location</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>Ft-Lbs.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>N&#8226;m</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Fan-to-Drive Hardware (5/16 Inch)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>13 - 16</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>18 - 22</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="0">
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Drive-to-Engine Bolt, (5/16 Inch)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>20 - 22</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>27 - 30</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Drive-to-Engine Bolt, (3/8 Inch</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>34 - 38</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>46 - 52</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="1" align="center">
                                <para>Drive-to-Hub Shaft (1 1/4-16 LH Thread)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="2" align="center">
                                <para>120 - 150</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="3" align="center">
                                <para>163 - 203</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The fasteners MUST be S.A.E. Grade #8 or better.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="x0012054" svcproctype="special tools" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SPECIAL TOOLS</title>
            <table id="t0012053" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Tools Required</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC1" colwidth="1.60in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" align="left" colwidth="3.07in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="2.20in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                                <para>Tool Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>Tool Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>Purpose</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>EZ-Tech Electronic Service Tool</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>To measure coolant temperature</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                                <para>ZTSE-4468</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Kit, Viscous Fan Diagnostic (consisting of:)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>(1) ZTSE-4468-1, Digital Photo-Tachometer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>For measuring fan speed</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>(1) ZTSE-4471-1, TK80 Temperature Probe (works with Fluke 88 DMM)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>For measuring air temperature</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC1" align="center">
                                <para></para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>(1) ZTSE-4471-2, Thermo-Couple</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3">
                                <para>For measuring air temperature</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <title>Notice</title>The following information has been furnished by the manufacturer for use with its
                product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on representations
                made to the Company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions accompanying the
                product, International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps resulting from such
                errors, or from any misuse of the product.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
