<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-13-03 - New Synthetic Oil for Eaton and Spicer Transmissions, Starting 04/01/2006</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi061303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-13-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>November, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>New Synthetic Oil for Eaton and Spicer Transmissions, Starting 04/01/2006</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Eaton</vendor>
                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>International Truck and Engine Corporation assembly plants are installing a new synthetic
                    transmission fluid in all Eaton and Spicer manual transmissions. This includes Eaton Autoshift and
                    Ultrashift models. This new synthetic fluid must be used in all above mentioned transmissions built
                    after 04/01/2006. Failure to do so will void Eaton extended warranty. The International part number
                    for this new synthetic fluid is 2645218R1. Please note that this new fluid is amber in color. This
                    new synthetic fluid is completely compatible with the old synthetic fluid (red) and can be used to
                    top off transmissions that are low on fluid even though they have the old synthetic fluid (red) in
                    them. If a transmission built before 4/1/2006 is at or past the recommended drain interval, it is
                    acceptable to use up your old style synthetic fluid (red), but the new style synthetic fluid (amber)
                    should be used as soon as possible.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions
                    accompanying the product, International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps
                    resulting from such errors, or from any misuse of the product.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">*Please read attached Newsletter from COGNIS synlubes technology</emph>
                </para>
                <para>To meet the new Eaton PS-164 Rev.7 Extended Drain Specification, Cognis has developed a new full
                    synthetic transmission lubricant referred to as Emgard 2979 SAE 50. Cognis is completing all major
                    OEM component approvals. This newsletter will provide customers / rebrander with basic information,
                    to prepare your systems and organizations with necessary information.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMGARD&#174; 2979 Synthetic SAE 50 Manual Transmission Lubricant (Roadranger SAE
                        50) intends to meet or exceed all OEM extended drain component performance requirements:
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="asterisk">
                    <item>
                        <para>API MT-1</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Eaton PS 164 rev 7</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>ArvinMeritor O-81 (pending)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>International TMS 6816</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Mack Truck TO-A-PLUS</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>ZF TE-ML 02L (pending)</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">EMGARD&#174; 2979 SAE 50 (Roadranger, SAE 50) provides proven field tested
                        performance benefits such as:
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="asterisk">
                    <item>
                        <para>Maximum drain interval up to 500,000 miles</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Improved gear and bearing protection</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Excellent seal compatibility to insure long life</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Maximum extreme hot and cold temperature performance</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">FAQ - related to the new product roll out: EMGARD&#174; 2979 SAE 50 / Roadranger
                        SAE 50
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Commercialization Date?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Emgard 2979 (Roadranger SAE 50) will be launched in April 2006.</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Why did the Eaton specification Change?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The current Cognis product was designed in the 1970's. Since that time, many changes have occurred
                    with the transmission design, engine horsepower and driver preference. The new product was specially
                    formulated for improved wear performance, all temperature performance and fuel economy.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Was the change absolutely necessary?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The change was necessary to receive Eaton's approval under their new PS-164 Rev. 7 Specification
                    for extended warranty and drain with their transmissions.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Can we continue to use the old Roadranger&#174; approved lubes?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>We are advising customers to use up inventory of the existing lubricant, and begin ordering the
                    new approved lubricant that meets Eaton's PS-164 Rev 7. The existing Roadranger approved lubricant
                    can still be used in currently running trucks, however we recommend that when servicing these
                    vehicles, use the new lubricant, as they are completely compatible.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Why is the new Roadranger&#174; approved gear lubricant a different color? Most
                        transmission lubricants are red, why choose amber?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>A color is not specified in Eaton's PS-164 Rev 7. Cognis chose to maintain the natural color for
                    the new MTF, which is Amber (please refer to color chart below).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0613031" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0613031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                             scalefitheight="328px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Will it stay amber after it has been used in the transmission?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>No, all transmission and axle gear lubricants will turn dark within several thousand miles of
                    service. This is a normal process since one of the tasks of gear lubricants is to keep the gear
                    parts clean. The dark coloration comes from dispersed wear particles and reacted additives, which
                    are typical for automotive power train lubricants.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Will the amber color affect oil analysis?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The same type of oil analysis and laboratory methods may be used for the new products compared to
                    the older Roadranger approved SAE 50 lube. Because the formulation is different, it will have a
                    different "elemental fingerprint" than the older product.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Will the amber color have any affect on the packaging materials?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>All automotive gear lubricants have a color. Some have color from the additives and base stock
                    used. Some have a dye added. All gear lubes will stain light colored (white, clear, tan)
                    polyethylene containers under extended storage conditions (greater than 1 year). Darker colored
                    polyethylene containers (blue, black, gray) do not show any staining. Special coatings for the light
                    colored containers have been investigated to minimize the staining from the amber SAE 50.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Will the amber SAE 50 gear lube stain, or harm, the trucks' finish?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Power train gear lubricants are not recommended for direct contact on painted body panels on cars
                    or trucks. The base stocks utilized can be corrosive to the polymer clear coat used in modern
                    vehicles. The Roadranger SAE 50 is no better or worse than other commercial transmission fluids for
                    this aspect.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Can I mix the new Roadranger&#174; approved lube and the old Roadranger&#174;
                        approved product?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>The new Roadranger lubricant is fully compatible with the current Roadranger product. Because of
                    the color difference, any mixtures will appear as an intermittent color. Any top-off in an
                    in-service transmission will result in a black color due to the strong used oil coloration.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Can I top off with the new product when the old product is still within the drain
                        interval?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>The new product can be used for topping off an older filled transmission. If the recommended drain
                    interval has been exceeded, it is recommended to fully drain the unit prior to refilling with the
                    new product.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Can I mix the Roadranger&#174; approved products with other brands?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Both the new and old Roadranger&#174; approved transmission products are compatible with most
                    competitive synthetic and petroleum based transmission lubricants. Mixing of products is not
                    recommended, but the industry realizes that some mixing will occur and have instituted compatibility
                    testing to minimize any adverse reaction.
                </para>
                <para>Any mix will decrease your performance level depending on the level in which it is mixed.</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Are there any special concerns when handling this product?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>The Roadranger &#174; approved SAE 50 lube is a global commercialized product that contains no
                    detrimental or hazardous components.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">How much of the old products can be left in the transmission without damaging the
                        performance of the new product?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>The new Emgard 2979 SAE-50 lubricant is fully compatible with the old Emgard 2924 SAE-50 at any %
                    or ratio. At the end of the designated drain interval, the older product should be drained well, but
                    no flushing or rinsing is necessary when introducing the new product.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">My trucks are older. Will the new Eaton &#174; approved lube cause the seals to
                        change and leak?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>No, if you are currently using the older Eaton&#174; approved SAE 50 lube. The new Eaton&#174;
                    approved lube will give the same or improved seal performance compared to the older product.
                </para>
                <para>If you are using petroleum SAE 50, under high mileage conditions (greater than 150,000 miles), the
                    introduction of a synthetic gear lubricant can result in fluid leakage. This is because the
                    petroleum based products tend to harden and shrink seals causing them to assume a "set". The
                    introduction of synthetic gear lube can then cause irregular swelling and softening of the elastomer
                    resulting in leakage. A mineral to synthetic change on older / high mileage trucks require a seal /
                    filter change.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Are there any differences I should be aware of in handling, or storing, between
                        the old and the new Roadranger&#174; approved lubricants?
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>The same precautions and handling conditions should be used with the new Roadranger&#174; SAE 50
                    lubes as with the older Roadranger product and other commercial brands of SAE 50 transmission lube.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Question regarding warranty protection?</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Warranty questions should be directed to the component OEM.</para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Further steps:</emph>
                </para>
                <para>We are glad to service and update you as soon we have more information.</para>
                <para>For marketing related questions, please contact:</para>
                <verbatim>
                    <line>Dan Horvath - Sr. Account Specialist</line>
                    <line>Phone#: 419-824-3056</line>
                    <line>E-mail: Dan.Horvath@Cognis.com</line>
                </verbatim>
                <para>For general field related questions, please contact:</para>
                <verbatim>
                    <line>Cognis Technical Service</line>
                    <line>Steve Lakes - R&#38;D</line>
                    <line>Phone#: 513-482-2298</line>
                    <line>E-mail: Steve.Lakes@Cognis.com</line>
                </verbatim>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
