<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-16-08 - Bonded Windshield Glass Replacement Sealant Kit 2592784C91 Requires New Dispenser</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi061608" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-16-08</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>November, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Bonded Windshield Glass Replacement Sealant Kit 2592784C91 Requires New Dispenser</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The 2 part windshield adhesive is being replaced in service with a 1 part adhesive. The 3 primers
                    now have new part numbers assigned.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t0616101" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <tgroup cols="3" align="center">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.20*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">New Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Old Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2592784C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3522505R1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Windshield Sealant Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields, paint and body shop
                        mask and outer clothing when performing windshield replacement and using this sealant.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">** Discontinue use of part #3522505R1 Sealant. Start using part # 2592784C91</emph>
            </para>
            <para>International&#174; offers a dispenser through the ISN tool program, Part number IMLW656024. You can
                also use a Dow, Cox, Milwaukee or 3M dispenser. The dispenser must be able to receive a 10 oz cartridge
                and have enough power to dispense high viscosity adhesives/sealants. A cordless dispenser is highly
                recommended. Make sure the dispenser comes with a 10 oz cartridge holder, battery and charger. The
                dispenser available thru the service parts tool program is Milwaukee 6560-21 12-Volt Caulk and adhesive
                Gun with 10 oz Carriage kit.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="boldital">NEW Windshield Replacement Kit 2592784C91</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The conversion to the new windshield replacement kit was driven by the discontinuation of the 2-part
                urethane adhesive U-216. You will notice a few changes in the new kits.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The new adhesive is Betaseal Express. This is a 1-part moisture curing urethane
                    adhesive.
                </para>
                <para>You will need a pneumatic or electric dispenser for 1-part cartridges.</para>
                <para>There are 2 tubes in the kit to give you the same volume of material as the old kit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">There is no black dynamic mix head in the kit.</para>
                <para>The 1-part adhesive requires no mixing, so there are only tips for the cartridges.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The primers have different numbers. These materials are equivalent to the old kit part
                    numbers. The application process is the same. The numbering changes are:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Clear glass primer 43518 replaces U-401.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Black out glass primer 43520A replaces U-402.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Body primer 43532 replaces U-413.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>These primers are compatible with each other, as long as the priming system includes a "clear
                    glass primer", a "black out glass primer", and a "body primer".
                    <emph type="bold">In some initial critical need kits, you will receive various combinations of this
                        primer system, always with the Betaseal Express 1-part adhesive.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The new windshield replacement kit is ordered under International #2592784C91. This kit includes:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>2 cartridges of Betaseal Express 1-part urethane adhesive</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1 bottle 43518 clear glass primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1 bottle 43520A black out glass primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1 bottle 43532 body primer</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Please Read the Dow Automotive Safety Data Sheets for These Products.</emph>Refer to
                the
                <exhotlnk document="../tsis/061608.pdf" bookname="TSI">pdf for this TSI</exhotlnk>
                for these Data Sheets.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">NOTICE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                with its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                representations made by the Company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions
                accompanying the product, International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps
                resulting from such errors, or from any misuse of the product.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
