<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 06-16-01 - Metal Repair Procedure for Corrosion</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi061601" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>06-16-01</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>03-16-03</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>January, 2006</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Metal Repair Procedure for Corrosion</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Recommended paint repair for International truck body panels when corrosion is present.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, wear safety glasses, paint and body shop mask and outer clothing
                        when performing this paint repair procedure.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash the entire vehicle with warm water/detergent solution. Allow to dry 1 to 2 hours.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all rivets, fasteners, door frames, luggage rings, etc. that exhibit signs of
                    (filiform) corrosion or other damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the substrate is:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Aluminum, sand with #150 to #180 grit paper dry</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Cold roll steel, sand sequentially with #80 then #120 grit paper dry</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Galvanized steel, sand with #120 grit paper dry</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Stainless steel, sand with #150 to #180 grit paper dry</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure all signs of corrosion are removed from the substrate during the sanding
                    process. This includes corrosion that may be present in or around rivet and fastener holes. Feather
                    the edges of areas requiring heavy sanding with sequentially finer grades of sand paper.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, wear safety glasses, paint and body shop mask and outer wear when
                        cleaning with compressed air. Use regulated dry air with a OSHA approved blow gun.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any dust and sanding debris by using compressed air to blow off the surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Degrease the surface with appropriate/compliant Sikkens Surface Cleaner. Use two cloths,
                    the first wet with surface cleaner and the second dry using wipe on / wipe off procedure. Follow the
                    instructions in the Sikkens Technical Manual for Surface Cleaners.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix one part (volume) of Washprimer CR with one part (volume) of Wash Hardener. Stir
                    thoroughly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply the mixed Washprimer CR in one medium coat to the vehicle. Film build target is
                    0.3 to 0.4 mils (8 to 10 microns). Specific application recommendations are provided in the Sikkens
                    Technical Reference Manual for Washprimer CR.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow the paint to flash for 15 minutes at 70&#176;F.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace any rivets, fasteners, door frames or luggage rings removed in Step 2. Use Fusor
                    800 as the sealer between the ring and the door skin.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat Steps 5 to 9 touching up heads of rivets and fasteners.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Steps 13 to 15 must be completed within 8 hours of application of Washprimer CR to assure
                        adhesion.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix appropriate Colorbuild color for topcoats being applied then add 10% of Autocryl
                    Elast-O-Actif (if required). Mix thoroughly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Combine 3 parts (volume) of Colorbuild primer from Step 12, with 1 part (volume)
                    Colorbuild Surface Hardener and 1 part (volume) Colorbuild Surface Activator. Mix thoroughly. If
                    additional flow and leveling is required for large areas or hot weather, add 10% Autocryl Reducer to
                    this ready to spray mixture.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply the mixed Colorbuild in two medium coats to the vehicle. Film build target is 3.0
                    to 4.0 mils (75 to 100 microns). Specific application recommendations are provided in the Sikkens
                    Manual for Colorbuild.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow to dry for a minimum of 30 minutes at 70&#176;F, if longer than one hour, thorough
                    sanding is required to assure topcoat adhesion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If sanding is required, use #360 to #400 grit paper dry or #500 to #600 grit paper wet.
                    After sanding, degrease the surface with appropriate Sikkens Surface Cleaner as indicated in Step 6.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Consult the vehicle lineset to determine the corresponding Nav four digit color number.
                    Topcoat with Sikkens Autobase Plus or Autobase followed by Autobase III, Autoclear HS Plus or
                    Autoclear II LV, following the instructions and recommendations provided in the Sikkens Technical
                    Reference Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If Washprimer CR or Colorbuild is not compliant for your area please contact your local Akzo
                        Nobel Technical Consultant.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>SIKKENS GLOSSARY</title>
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOBASE&#174; PLUS BLENDING ADDITIVE</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autobase Plus Blending Additive is a crystal clear blending additive that allows for easier
                application of Autobase Plus spot repairs. As there is no mixing required, it is very easy to use. Use
                Autobase Plus Blending Additive as a foundation for fade out areas or use it as an additive to Autobase
                Plus colors, solid or metallic, before the application of the fade out coats.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOBASE&#174; PLUS INTERIOR CONVERTER</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When mixed with Autobase Plus basecoat, Autobase Plus Interior Converter Gloss and Mat is a low gloss
                specialty coating designed for application over existing and new interior automotive parts. The gloss
                and mat interior converters provide consistent performance in a wide range of colors. Those colors are
                specifically matched to both the color and gloss of OEM standards.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOBASE&#174; PLUS SPECIAL EFFECT COLORS</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autobase Plus 3 step Special Effect Colors provide unique color and flip/flop effects when viewed from
                different angles. These colors are not available from the mixing system; therefore there are eight
                pre-packaged (ready mixed) colors available. Autobase Plus Special Effect Colors are designed for custom
                finishing and must be used in conjunction with Sikkens clearcoat in order to provide protection from the
                environment.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOBASE&#174; PLUS SOLID, METALLIC AND PEARL COLORS</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autobase Plus provides excellent coverage, metallic control and sprayability when used to duplicate
                OEM solid, metallic, and pearl color effects. Autobase Plus must be used in conjunction with a Sikkens
                clearcoat in order to provide protection from the environment. Autobase Plus is the superior choice to
                achieve optimal color match.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOCRYL&#174; ELAST-O-ACTIF (OE)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Vehicle body parts made of deformable plastics require special flexible paints. Addition of Autocryl
                Elast-O-Actif improves the flexibility to such an extent that the paint can tolerate deformation of the
                plastic parts without cracking or chipping.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOCLEAR&#174; III</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autoclear III is a National Rule compliant acrylic urethane clearcoat for use with Sikkens basecoats.
                The product can be used as a high gloss clearcoat or as an ultra productive clearcoat in both air-dry
                and baking environments with the use of different hardener and activator combinations.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOCLEAR&#174; HS+</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autoclear HS+ is a high solids acrylic urethane clearcoat for use over Autobase Plus. A National Rule
                compliant acrylic urethane clearcoat, Autoclear HS+ offers high gloss and is designed for baking
                conditions. With the choice of activators, can be used for small areas and large areas under different
                temperature environments.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">AUTOCLEAR&#174; MAT</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Autoclear Mat is a two part acrylic urethane clearcoat with mat finish. Higher gloss levels can be
                reached by mixing with any Sikkens urethane clear; i.e., Autoclear III or Autoclear HS+. The main
                application is to achieve a lower gloss level over plastic parts. For VOC recording, Autoclear Mat will
                be listed as a specialty coating under "Elastomeric Refinishing" or "Antiglare Coatings".
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">COLORBUILD&#8482; UNDERCOAT SYSTEM</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The Colorbuild undercoat system consists of six colored primers which, when mixed in proper
                combination with each other, achieve colors closely resembling the most popular topcoat colors.
                Depending on the mixing ratio utilized, Colorbuild can be used as a primer surfacer or wet-on-wet primer
                sealer.
            </para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SURFACE CLEANERS</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Degreasers are solvents especially formulated to remove grease and other contaminants from bare metal,
                existing finishes, plastic, etc. Sikkens has three types of degreasers available to best suit your shop
                and the substrate to be degreased:
            </para>
            <para>1. Sikkens M600 Surface Cleaner</para>
            <para>2. Sikkens Anti-Static Surface Cleaner</para>
            <para>3. Autoclean Surface Cleaner System</para>
            <para></para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">WASHPRIMER CR</emph>
            </para>
            <para>A self-etching washprimer that offers superior corrosion resistance and excellent paint system
                adhesion to steel, galvanized steel, aluminum, and stainless steel. Washprimer CR is used to duplicate
                automotive manufacture corrosion resistance without the use of metal preps and conditioners.
            </para>
            <para></para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
