<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-07-01 - DPF (Diesel Particulate Filter) Regeneration Switches and Regeneration Warning Lights
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi070701" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>07-07-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Exhaust System</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>DPF (Diesel Particulate Filter) Regeneration Switches and Regeneration Warning Lights</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Starting with vehicle models produced for sale within the United States that utilize diesel
                    engines manufactured on or after January 1, 2007, the EPA enacted new requirements for reduced
                    emissions. The EPA requires both reduction in NOx and Particulate Matter (PM) emitted from the
                    engine to the atmosphere. Reductions to the allowable Federal Limits for NOx are achieved through
                    improvements within the engine itself, whereas reductions to the (PM) Particulate Matter are
                    achieved through a combination of improvements to the engine and the addition of a Diesel
                    Particulate Filter (DPF), which captures the PM, and through a process called regeneration, which
                    periodically converts the PM to ash. This ash must be cleaned from the (DPF) periodically.
                </para>
                <para>Following are definitions of the terms used in the process of removing PM (Particular Matter) and
                    NOx.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Regeneration:</emph>
                    The process of converting the trapped particulate matter within the diesel particulate filter into
                    ash.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Passive Regeneration:</emph>
                    The natural process of regeneration where the engine provides sufficient temperature through the
                    exhaust gasses to convert the particulate matter to ash.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Active Regeneration:</emph>
                    The process of regeneration where changes to the engine operation are required and handled through
                    the vehicle and engine software to increase the exhaust temperature so the particulate matter can be
                    converted to ash.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Manual Regeneration:</emph>
                    The process of regeneration where the operator may request that the vehicle and engine change their
                    state to increase the temperature of the exhaust gasses so the regeneration can occur and convert
                    particulate matter to ash.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">DPF Status Lamp:</emph>The lamp will communicate to the operator the level of
                    particulate matter (soot) trapped in the diesel particulate filter and the need to manually begin
                    the regeneration process.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">High Exhaust System Temperature Indicator:</emph>
                    (HEST) The indicator will communicate to the operator the warning that the exhaust gas temperature
                    is elevated due to regeneration.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Parked Regeneration Switch:</emph>
                    The operator enabled switch that, under certain circumstances, can request that the engine and
                    vehicle change their operation so that regeneration can begin while the vehicle is stationary.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Inhibit Regeneration Switch:</emph>
                    The operator enabled switch that requests regeneration will not begin. (This switch is optional on
                    certain models).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Indicator Lamps or Status Indicator Lamps:</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Four indicators are available to assist the operator with understanding the status of the vehicle,
                    engine and DPF. These indicators will communicate when to regenerate the DPF, when the engine is
                    de-rated due to excessive soot load in the DPF and when the temperature of the exhaust gasses are
                    extremely hot.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">DPF Status Lamp:</emph>
                    The DPF Status Lamp provides information regarding the need to regenerate the DPF. Several levels of
                    status will be available. This lamp will progressively change states from off to solid-on to
                    flashing. When Solid-On or Flashing, it indicates the need for the driver to regenerate the DPF.
                    Used in combination with the Check Engine and Stop Engine Lamps, the DPF Status Lamp will provide
                    feedback to the driver on the following regeneration needed levels:
                </para>
                <table id="tstatus" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                    <tgroup cols="6">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.55*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.91*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.92*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.94*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="1.19*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col6" colwidth="1.54*"/>
                        <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col6" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Level</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Indication</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Audible Alarm</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>LCD Text Message (Units Built After June 2007)</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Vehicle Conditions/ Operation</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Action Required</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI1.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>Solid</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>None</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>For Info See Visor</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Exhaust filter regeneration required.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Drive on highway at highway speeds
                                        <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                                        start
                                        <emph type="bold">Parked Regeneration</emph>
                                        to prevent loss of power.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>2</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI1.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>Flashing</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>None</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>For Info See Visor</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Exhaust filter is full.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Pull vehicle safely off roadway and start
                                        <emph type="bold">Parked Regeneration</emph>
                                        to prevent loss of engine power.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>3</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI1.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>Flashing</para>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI2.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>Solid</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>An alarm will beep 5 times every minute while ignition is on.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Warn Engine</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Exhaust filter is full. Engine performance is
                                        <emph type="bold">LIMITED</emph>.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <warning>
                                        <para>Pull vehicle safely off roadway and start Parked Regeneration to prevent
                                            engine stopping.
                                        </para>
                                    </warning>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>4</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI3.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>Solid</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>An alarm will beep continuously while ignition is on.</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Stop Engine</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>A serious engine problem has occurred. Exhaust filter may be overfull. Engine
                                        may
                                        <emph type="bold">SHUT DOWN</emph>
                                        soon.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <warning>
                                        <para>Pull vehicle safely off roadway, turn on flashers, place warning devices,
                                            and STOP ENGINE. DO NOT USE PARKED REGENERATION. Call for service.
                                        </para>
                                    </warning>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry colspan="6" spanname="SPAN1">
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EFSI4.webp" type="webp"/>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">NOTE:</emph>
                                        If this dash indicator is present the exhaust system is HOT and regeneration is
                                        in progress.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Check Engine Lamp: See level 3 above</emph>
                    (yellow Yield Sign). The Check Engine Lamp when lit in conjunction with the DPF Status Lamp
                    indicates that the DPF requires regeneration and that the engine will begin a progressive de-rate to
                    limit the amount of soot contained in the DPF.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Stop Engine Lamp: See level 4 above</emph>
                    (red stop sign). The Stop Engine Lamp when lit may indicate that the DPF is full and that immediate
                    vehicle service is required. The engine will have been de-rated and may be abruptly stopped to
                    prevent damage to the DPF. The vehicle must be immediately serviced by a qualified technician.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">High Exhaust System Temperature Indicator:</emph>
                    The High Exhaust System Temperature Indicator will be lit warning the operator that exhaust gas
                    temperatures are elevated above approximately 400 degrees C. During the time when this indicator is
                    on, the operator must keep the vehicle away from flammable materials and vapors. Indicator only
                    comes on below 5 MPH and when exceeding the 400 degrees C temperature.
                </para>
                <para>Switches:</para>
                <para>
                    <title>Parked Regeneration Switch: HPV 3000, 4000, 7000, and 8000 Models</title>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Failure to perform a Parked Regeneration when exhaust filter Indicator (level 2) is ON
                            will cause the engine to lose power and eventually shut down.
                        </para>
                        <para>When performing Parked Regeneration, make certain vehicle is safely off roadway and away
                            from people, or any flammable materials or structures, as the regeneration process will
                            result in elevated exhaust temperatures.
                        </para>
                        <para>Failure to follow these instructions may result in a loss of engine power, vehicle speed,
                            and may cause an accident or fire resulting in property damage personal injury, or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Perform the following steps to initiate Parked Regeneration (cleaning) of the exhaust DPF:</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Park the vehicle safely off the roadway and away from flammable materials and vapors.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Before initiating parked regeneration (using the ON/PARKD REGEN switch), the following
                            conditions must be in place:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Park brake must be set</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Transmission must be in Neutral (N) or Park (P), if available</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Accelerator, foot brake and clutch (if present) pedals must not be depressed,
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Engine coolant temperature must be 160 degrees F. or above.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>&#9;Press the ON position of the ON/PARKD REGEN switch (Figure 1) to initiate the
                            regeneration cycle.
                        </para>
                        <para>The engine speed will automatically ramp up to a preset RPM and the switch indicator will
                            illuminate when the cycle is started. If the indicator is blinking, check to be sure that
                            all conditions in step 2 have been met. Allow one minute for engine to respond. If indicator
                            cycle switch is still blinking, cycle switch. Once started, the regeneration cycle will last
                            approximately 20 minutes.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: If any of the above conditions are altered during the Parked
                                Regeneration process, regeneration will be halted, and must be restarted.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When the regeneration cycle is complete, the switch indicator will go off, the engine rpm
                            will return to normal idle and all exhaust filter indicators will be off. The vehicle may
                            now be driven normally.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <figure id="f0707012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the event of an emergency situation where the vehicle must be moved after beginning
                            Parked Regeneration, press PARKD REGEN position of the ON/PARKD REGEN switch to cancel
                            Parked Regeneration.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>Parked Regeneration Switch: 5000i, 9000i Models</title>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Failure to perform a Parked Regeneration when exhaust filter Indicator level 2 is ON will
                            cause the engine to lose power and eventually shutdown.
                        </para>
                        <para>When performing Parked Regeneration, make certain vehicle is safely off roadway and away
                            from people, or any flammable materials or structures, as the regeneration process will
                            result in elevated exhaust temperatures.
                        </para>
                        <para>Failure to follow these instructions may result in a loss of engine power, vehicle speed,
                            and may cause an accident or fire resulting in property damage personal injury, or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>Use the PARKD REGEN ON/CANCEL switch to initiate Parked Regeneration (cleaning) of the exhaust
                    DPF. The PARKD REGEN switch is a momentary three position, center stable switch (Figure 2).
                </para>
                <figure id="f0707013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707013.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Park the vehicle safely off the roadway and away from flammable materials and vapors.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Before initiating Parked Regeneration, the following conditions must be in place:</para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Park brake must be set</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Transmission must be in Neutral (N) or Park (P), if available</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Accelerator, foot brake and clutch (if present) pedals must not be depressed,
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Engine coolant temperature must be 160 degrees F. or above.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Momentarily press the ON position of the PARKD REGEN ON/CANCEL switch to initiate the
                            regeneration cycle.
                        </para>
                        <para>The engine speed will automatically ramp up to a preset RPM when the cycle is started.
                            Once started, the regeneration cycle will last approximately 20 minutes.
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: If any of the above conditions are not met, the Regeneration process
                                will not be initiated.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">NOTE: If any of the above conditions are altered during the Parked
                                Regeneration process, regeneration will be halted, and must be restarted.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When the regeneration cycle is complete, the engine rpm will return to normal idle and all
                            exhaust filter indicators will turn off. The vehicle may now be driven normally.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>In the event of an emergency situation where the vehicle must be moved after beginning
                            Parked Regeneration, press the CANCEL position of the PARKD REGEN ON/CANCEL switch to cancel
                            Parked Regeneration.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>Inhibit Regeneration Switch: HPV 3000, 4000, 7000, and 8000 Models (this switch is optional
                        on certain models)
                    </title>
                </para>
                <para>The Regeneration Inhibit switch is used to prevent the Active Regeneration or Parked Regeneration
                    processes.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>There are two versions of the Regeneration Inhibit switch: the two position and the three
                            position switch. Therefore, it's necessary to verify which version is installed in the
                            vehicle. Both versions have the same switch labels.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f0707014" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <title>Two Position Regeneration Inhibit Switch</title>
                </para>
                <para>With the two position switch, pressing the ON position of the ON/INHIBT REGEN switch will inhibit
                    both Active and Parked Regeneration. Regeneration will be inhibited (latched) when in this position
                    and the switch indicator is turned on.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>Three Position Regeneration Inhibit Switch</title>
                </para>
                <para>The three position switch is a momentary switch with a center stable. Pressing the ON position
                    inhibits Active Regeneration while the engine is running, and is reset when the ignition switch is
                    turned Off. The Inhibit function is cancelled when the lower position is pressed, or Parked
                    Regeneration is initiated (PARKD REGEN switch is turned to the ON position).
                </para>
                <para>The switch indicator will be turned on whenever Regeneration Inhibit is enabled.</para>
                <para>
                    <title>Inhibit Regeneration Switch: 5000i, 9000i Models</title>
                </para>
                <para>The Regeneration Inhibit switch is used to prevent the Active Regeneration or Parked Regeneration
                    processes.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>There are two versions of the Regeneration Inhibit switch: the two position INHIBT REGEN
                            ON/OFF switch; and the three position INHIBT REGEN ON/CANCEL switch.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>Two Position Regeneration Inhibit Switch</title>
                </para>
                <figure id="f0707015" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707015.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>With the two position switch, selecting the ON position of the INHIBT REGEN ON/OFF switch will
                    inhibit both Active and Parked Regeneration. Regeneration will be inhibited (latched) until the OFF
                    position is selected.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>Three Position Regeneration Inhibit Switch</title>
                </para>
                <figure id="f0707016" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707016.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The three position switch is a momentary switch with a center stable. Momentarily pressing the ON
                    position inhibits Active Regeneration while the engine is running, and is reset when the ignition
                    switch is turned Off. The Inhibit function is cancelled when the CANCEL position is pressed. With
                    this switch, Parked Regeneration can be initiated whenever the (PARKED REGEN switch is turned to the
                    ON position).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Temperature Effects of Regeneration</emph>: In order to effectively regenerate the
                    DPF, the soot that it stores must be burned at temperatures on the order of 500-600 degrees C. Many
                    operators may not have had experience with exhaust temperatures of this magnitude, especially in a
                    parked vehicle condition. The High Exhaust System Temperature (HEST) indicator is used to notify the
                    operator of the high temperatures. To not pose a threat to the environment, the operator or the
                    vehicle, care should be taken when choosing a location to start a parked regeneration especially
                    when lamp is illuminated. Vehicles must be parked on clean, dry surfaces away from flammable
                    materials and vapors and away from building structures.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Exhaust Cooling Devices and Heat Shields:</emph>
                    Many exhaust configurations have been equipped with heat shields and other special devices used to
                    cool the exhaust gasses as they exit the vehicle. These exhaust cooling devices have been added not
                    only for the safety of the operator, but for pedestrians and any potentially flammable materials
                    that may either come in contact with the exhaust system itself, or that the exhaust gasses may come
                    in contact with. These devices use the cooler air outside of the exhaust to mix with the exhaust
                    gasses before they exit the vehicle to the atmosphere. The result is a cooler stream of gasses
                    exiting than would exist without the device. Care should be taken, even with these devices installed
                    on the vehicle that regenerations are done over surfaces that can withstand high heat, that no
                    flammable debris, materials or vapors are in the area around the exhaust and that no pedestrians or
                    operators come in contact with the exhaust system or exhaust gasses during a regeneration or for a
                    period of ten minutes after the regeneration has completed. The exhaust system will remain hot
                    during regeneration and for a period after the regeneration has completed. Use caution when working
                    around the vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>For safety reasons, it is very important that the complete exhaust system not be modified in any
                    way. See G-Letter G2481 guidelines for modifications allowed for 2007 model exhaust and the CT-471
                    Body Builder book.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The following page shows an actual dash layout with an explanation of the warning lights.
                            This information can also be found in the operators manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The pages after that are a sample of the EPA card that will be put in each vehicle at time of
                    build.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0707017" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G0707017.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                             scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. 2007 Emissions Cluster Layout (HPV 3000, 4000, 7000, and 8000 models)</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
