<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-08-03R - Remote Keyless Entry (RKE) Transmitter Learning</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi070803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>07-08-03R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>02-08-02</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>June, 2008</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Remote Keyless Entry (RKE) Transmitter Learning</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>4100
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>08/01/2005</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>10/01/2005</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/2001</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>ProStar
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/2007</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>16VCN</ucode>
                <ucode>16VCP</ucode>
                <ucode>16WKZ</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The International Keyless Entry System uses electronic door pods in the driver and passenger side
                    doors which also operate the power door locks and the power windows. If equipped with RKE, the
                    memory in the receiver (front passenger door pod) learns the transmitter codes from the key fobs
                    (transmitters) and only recognizes those which it has learned in the programming process. Each
                    vehicle's passenger side door pod has the ability to learn up to six transmitter codes allowing the
                    vehicle to be accessed by six different key fobs. Each key fob has a unique code which can be
                    learned by any number of RKE equipped vehicles.
                </para>
                <para>Please reference SFN 07-89 for a new diagnostic tool, (Remote Entry Pro) part number 500010 to use
                    as a quick aid to check Key Fob function.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Replacement Key Fobs/Transmitters can be obtained from Service Parts by ordering part number
                3544938C2.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Transmitter Learning And Erasing</title>
                <para>Before the transmitter can be used for the first time, it has to be "learned" by the receiver. Up
                    to 6 transmitters with different identification codes can be learned by a single RKE Pod.
                </para>
                <para>These procedures are designed for manual learning/erasing operations on a complete vehicle. They
                    can be used for learning replacement transmitters, for using up to six transmitters for accessing
                    the same vehicle, or for accessing any number of vehicles using the same transmitter. If RKE is
                    being added to the vehicle, additional programming of the Electrical System Controller or Body
                    Controller is required to operate the horn, panic, and dome light functions with RKE.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Procedure For Erasing All Learned Transmitters</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cycle the Ignition from Off to On. Step 2. must be initiated (all four buttons
                        pressed) within 10 seconds of this Ignition event.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">On the
                        <emph type="bold">Driver</emph>
                        Door Pod do the following:
                    </para>
                    <para>While holding down the Driver Window-Up, Driver Window-Down, and Unlock Switches depress and
                        hold the Lock switch. All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is
                        recommended. After the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will erase all learned transmitters and
                        the RKE will be disabled. At this point the erase procedure is finished and a new Ignition cycle
                        must be initiated to perform any transmitter learning.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Procedure For Learning A Transmitter</title>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>This learning procedure cannot be performed during the same Ignition cycle as the "erase
                            all learned transmitters" procedure. If necessary, the erase procedure should be completed
                            before this procedure is started.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Cycle the Ignition from Off to On (leaving the Ignition on will not work, it must be
                        cycled). Step 2. must be initiated (all four buttons pressed) within 10 seconds of this Ignition
                        event.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">On the
                        <emph type="bold">Passenger</emph>
                        Door Pod do the following:
                    </para>
                    <para>While holding down the Window-Up, Window-Down, and Unlock switches, depress and hold the Lock
                        switch. All four switches must be held for at least 5 seconds. 6 or 7 seconds is recommended.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After the 5 seconds the Door Pod RKE unit will enter "Learn Mode" and stay there for
                        10 seconds (or until a transmitter is learned). Once the RKE enters the "Learn Mode", the four
                        buttons can be released. During the ten second "Learn Mode" any function on the new
                        fob/transmitter must be keyed at least twice (See Note 1).
                    </para>
                    <para>Note 1. After the transmitter is learned the next keying of the new transmitter will perform
                        the indicated function. It is recommended that the transmitter be successively keyed until the
                        selected key's function is actually performed; i.e., pressing the Lock Button on the transmitter
                        two times should learn its code, on the third push it should lock the door and momentarily beep
                        the city horn. This is a good way to quickly confirm the success of the learning.
                    </para>
                    <para>Note 2. Steps 1. through 3. of the learning process must be repeated for each transmitter to
                        be learned.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
