<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-08-01RA - New Instrument Panel Cluster Indicators for 2008 Model Year</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi070801" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>07-08-01RA</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Electrical</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>New Instrument Panel Cluster Indicators for 2008 Model Year</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>BE 200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CE Bus</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>ProStar</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>A number of important changes to the instrument cluster have been incorporated for trucks and
                    buses built in 2007, model year 2008.
                </para>
                <para>1. The gauge sweep no longer occurs when the ignition is turned on.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For ProStar trucks equipped with the VID (Vehicle Information Display), the gauge sweep
                            can be requested through the display.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For any vehicle not equipped with the VID, the gauge sweep will occur when the display of
                            on-board diagnostics is requested.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>2. The odometer display button is now used not only to clear resettable values (by pushing), but
                    also to select LCD quadrants (by turning). Refer to the Operator's Manual for specific instructions.
                </para>
                <para>3. The amber Driver Alert symbol has been changed to:</para>
                <figure id="f0708011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g8487084.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="54px"
                             scalefitheight="54px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>It can be turned on not only by the engine but also by other modules/controllers connected to the
                    J1939 data link. This indicator, therefore, no longer represents only an engine alert condition. To
                    correctly identify the actual alert condition, a text message in quadrant 2 of the LCD will be
                    displayed.
                </para>
                <figure id="f0708012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g0708012.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="272px"
                             scalefitheight="152px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. NOTE: Functions of the 4 quadrant LCD are described in the operator's manual.
                    </caption>
                </figure>
                <para>4. The red stop symbol has been changed to:</para>
                <figure id="f0708013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g8487086.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="54px"
                             scalefitheight="54px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>This indicator can also be turned on by multiple modules/controllers, similar to the Amber Driver
                    Alert. Quadrant 2 will display a text message identifying the source.
                </para>
                <para>5. The amber emissions system warning symbol has been changed to:</para>
                <figure id="f0708014" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g8487078.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="54px"
                             scalefitheight="54px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>6. A new indicator for High Exhaust System Temperature (HEST) has been added.</para>
                <figure id="f0708015" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g8487048.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="54px"
                             scalefitheight="54px"/>
                </figure>
                <para>This
                    <emph type="bold">IS NOT</emph>
                    an indication of engine overheat. This indicator warns the driver that the exhaust temperature is
                    high. It will come on because of NORMAL passive or active regeneration or exhaust high temperature
                    duty cycles. The HEST lamp will come on if exhaust temperature is 400&#176;C+ and vehicle speed is
                    less than 5 mph. This condition is NORMAL and is not related to an engine or cooling system overheat
                    condition.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Please refer to the
                            <exhotlnk document="../tsis/070801.pdf" bookname="TSI">pdf for this TSI</exhotlnk>
                            for the explanation of the DPF gauge and symbol readings as the truck goes through
                            preparation for and during regeneration to clear the emissions in the system.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
