<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-12-10 - Revised Cylinder Head Flatness Check</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI071210" year="2007" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>07-12-10</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Revised Cylinder Head Flatness Check</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>VT 275</engfam>
                <engfam>VT 365</engfam>
                <engfam>MaxxForce 7</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>A revised cylinder head flatness check has been developed. The check is used to verify that the
                    cylinder head is within factory specification before installation.
                </para>
                <para>The end-to-end flatness check has been removed from the inspection procedure. The overall
                    end-to-end flatness of the cylinder head is not as critical as the localized flatness checks.
                    Longitudinal measurements are not an accurate indication of cylinder head flatness when installed
                    due to the clamp load of the cylinder head to the crankcase.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Checking Cylinder Head Flatness</title>
            <para>Clean and prepare the cylinder head for inspection by doing the steps in "Cleaning and Inspection"
                found within the Cylinder Head and Valve Train Section of the following Service Manuals:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>EGES 300 - 1, International&#174; VT 275 Diesel Engines, Beginning with 2005 Model Year</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGES 235 - 2, International&#174; VT 365 Diesel Engines, 2002 and 2003 Model Years</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGES 295 - 2, International&#174; VT 365 Diesel Engines, 2004 through 2006 Model Years</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>EGES 345, International&#174; MaxxForce&#8482; 7 Diesel Engines, Beginning with 2007 Model
                        Year
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the cylinder head has been prepared for inspection, do step 1 of the "Cylinder Head
                    Inspection - Valves Installed" procedure. After completing step 1, replace step two with the
                    following:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Inspect points 2, 11, 3, and 12 on the V8 diesel engine first, see Figure 1 (points 2 and 9 on
                        the V6 diesel engine, see Figure 2) as these areas of the cylinder head are the most susceptible
                        to wear.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="fig1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/M08002.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Inspection points for the cylinder head flatness check (V8)</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="fig1" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/M08003.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Inspection points for the cylinder head flatness check (V6 valves not shown)
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, do not machine the cylinder head if it is out of flatness.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not slide the feeler gauge end longitudinally against the straight edge. This action will
                        cause the feeler gauge blade to curl or warp, preventing entry under the straight edge.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To achieve an accurate reading with the straightedge and feeler gauge, do not place
                        straightedge over the lifter opening area of the cylinder head when checking the inspection
                        points for cylinder head flatness.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="fig2" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/M08001.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px" box="no"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Inspection point for cylinder head flatness check</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Straightedge</callout1>
                    <callout1 type="arabic">Feeler gauge</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the cylinder head flatness at the designated points (Figure 1 or 2).</para>
            </step1>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Use the 0.051mm (0.002 inch) blade of the feeler gauge on the point of inspection. Now place
                        the straight edge on top of the leaf. The straight edge is placed transverse or perpendicular on
                        the cylinder head (Figure 3).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the blade of the feeler gauge can not be pulled out from under the straight edge, that
                        point of the cylinder head passes the flatness check. Continue on through all the points. Go to
                        step 3.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the blade of the feeler gauge can be pulled out easily or is loose, the cylinder head could
                        be out of flat. Replace the cylinder head and repeat cylinder head flatness check on a new
                        cylinder head.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Continue with step 3 of the "Cylinder Head Inspection" procedure within the applicable
                    Service Manual for further instructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">See Specifications at the end of the Cylinder Head and Valve Train section and Appendix
                    A - Specifications, Cylinder Heads of the appropriate service manual and mark the following
                    correction to the specifications.
                </para>
                <para>Currently the manual reads:</para>
                <para>Gasket surface flatness Maximum 0.10mm (0.004 inch) per total surface area</para>
                <para>Revise to read:</para>
                <para>Gasket surface flatness Maximum 0.051mm (0.002 inch) per check point</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
