<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-12-07 - Prevention of Objects and Debris from Falling into Intake Ports during Removal and
        Installation of Intake Manifold
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI071207" year="2007" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>07-12-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engine</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Prevention of Objects and Debris from Falling into Intake Ports during Removal and Installation of
                Intake Manifold
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>MaxxForce 5</engfam>
                <engfam>MaxxForce 7</engfam>
                <engfam>VT 275</engfam>
                <engfam>VT 365</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The following procedure is necessary to eliminate hardware, tools, objects, dirt, and debris from
                    falling into intake ports in the cylinder heads, when the intake manifold is removed and installed.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, make sure the engine has cooled before removing
                        components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, wear safety glasses with side shields when doing the
                        following procedure.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>See Engine Service Manual for procedures to remove engine components before removing the
                        intake manifold.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent engine damage, the following steps must be done in sequence and exactly as
                        stated.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove loose hardware, tools, and objects from the area below the intake manifold and
                    from recessed area between the right and left rocker arm carrier and intake manifold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>See Engine Service Manual to remove intake manifold.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Blow out or vacuum dirt and debris from the area below the intake manifold and recessed
                    area between the right and left rocker arm carrier and intake manifold.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove intake manifold.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove dirt and debris from around mating surfaces of intake ports, making
                    sure dirt or debris does not fall into intake ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a borescope to inspect the inside of intake ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove objects and debris from intake ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a magnet to remove metal objects or fragments.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put magnetic cover ZTSE4559 over intake ports in each cylinder head.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After necessary maintenance, follow procedures in the Engine Service Manual to install the
                        intake manifold.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove magnetic cover over intake ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing the intake manifold, use a borescope to make sure intake ports are
                    free of objects and debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a magnet to remove metal objects or fragments.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
