<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 07-17-02 - Conmet Wheel Bearing Preload (Torque)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi071702" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>07-17-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August 2007</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Wheels</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Conmet Wheel Bearing Preload (Torque)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/23/2007</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9900i
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/23/2007</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>ProStar
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>07/23/2007</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to 9000i and ProStar models built in Escobedo and Chatham.</para>
                <para>Tightening or torquing procedure for reinstalling Conmet wheel bearing preload systems.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to neutral or park, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The Conmet home page (http://www.conmet.com) gives specific instructions for removal, inspection and
                installation of their preset bearing load assemblies. Should you elect to discard the bearing adjustment
                spacer and go back to the conventional bearing adjustment procedure, go to their web page, click on
                literature on the left side of the page, and pull up (FAQ) frequently asked questions. This section will
                address what to do if you want to discard the spacer and use standard wheel bearings and conventional
                adjusting procedures.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Notice:</emph>
                The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use with
                its product. International Truck and Engine Corporation reprints this information based on
                representations made to the company. While users are urged to carefully follow the instructions
                accompanying the product, International cannot accept any responsibility for user errors, or mishaps
                resulting from such errors, or from any misuse of the product.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
