<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 08-04-01 - Full Power Brakes SAHR System Troubleshooting</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi080401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>08-04-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May 2008</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Brakes</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Full Power Brakes SAHR System Troubleshooting</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The purpose of this document is to provide detailed troubleshooting information for the Spring
                    Assist Hydraulic Release (SAHR) Parking Brake system used in the Full Power Brakes System. This
                    information is to be used in conjunction with the Full Power Brakes service manual, and the TOOLBOX&#8482;
                    diagnostic program.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is assumed that Vehicle Recall G-06504 has been performed on the vehicle under test, if
                            the vehicle is covered by that recall.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Service procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, shift transmission to neutral or park, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Troubleshooting the Full Power Brakes System begins with reviewing any brake related Diagnostic
                Trouble Codes (DTC's), using the TOOLBOX&#8482; diagnostic program. While the TOOLBOX&#8482; program
                provides adequate repair instructions for most DTC's, the following SAHR related DTC's may require the
                supplemental information provided in this document. The procedures in this document assume that the
                SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is lit and ALL other brake related DTC's have been resolved.
            </para>
            <para>This document covers the following Park Brake DTC's, as displayed in TOOLBOX&#8482;:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>61 3 Travel Switch output implausible, (or could not be applied)</para>
                    <randlist type="asterisk">
                        <item>
                            <para>When the park brake is commanded to apply, the travel switch has indicated to the ECU
                                that the SAHR shaft has remained in the released position. The ECU sends a message to
                                the Gauge Cluster to turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator; and may operate the park
                                brake system in the Backup Mode.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Possible causes:</para>
                            <randlist type="dash">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Travel Switch (or wiring)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>SAHR canister mechanical malfunction</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cut-off valve (SAHR cartridge)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Pressure Supply Valve (PSV)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Driveline park brake components binding or broken</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Park brake cable binding</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>61 4 Park Brake could not be released,</para>
                    <randlist type="asterisk">
                        <item>
                            <para>When the park brake is commanded to release, the travel switch has indicated to the
                                ECU that the SAHR shaft has remained in the applied position. This code may also
                                indicate that after extending to the released position, the SAHR shaft repeatedly
                                retracted enough to require 'replenishment' of the brake fluid in the SAHR canister. In
                                either case, the ECU operates the park brake system in the Backup Mode; and sends a
                                message to the Gauge Cluster to turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Possible causes:</para>
                            <randlist type="dash">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Travel Switch (or wiring)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Electronic Control Unit (ECU)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>SAHR canister mechanical malfunction (binding)</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Cut-off valve (SAHR cartridge). NOTE: Cut-off valve COIL faults are covered by
                                        separate DTC's, which must be resolved before performing these procedures.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>PSV. NOTE: PSV COIL faults are covered by separate DTC's, which must be
                                        resolved before performing these procedures.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>61 13 SAHR shaft overtravel.</para>
                    <randlist type="asterisk">
                        <item>
                            <para>During park brake application, the travel switch has indicated to the ECU that the
                                SAHR shaft has retracted further than the specified limit. The SAHR shaft dimension is
                                [lt ]8.1 inches. The ECU operates the park brake system in the Backup Mode; and sends a
                                message to the Gauge Cluster to turn on the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator. NOTE: This
                                condition generally indicates a worn or broken park brake component, not a SAHR assembly
                                problem.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Possible causes:</para>
                            <randlist type="dash">
                                <item>
                                    <para>park brake cable broken, stretched or misadjusted</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>driveline park brake linings out of adjustment</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>driveline park brake components worn or broken</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent unexpected movement of the vehicle and possible serious personal injury or death,
                        block the wheels to prevent the vehicle from moving in both directions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The full power brake system is a pressurized system that achieves pressures of up to 2320 psi.
                        This pressure IS NOT reduced by switching the ignition off or removing battery power.
                    </para>
                    <para>Prior to removing components from this system, the depressurization procedures in the service
                        manual MUST BE PERFORMED EXACTLY AS PRESENTED. Since it is assumed that a component has failed,
                        you should assume that trapped, pressurized fluid may be present whenever a component is
                        removed. Remove components from the fluid system cautiously.
                    </para>
                    <para>Refer to the appropriate service manual in ISIS before removing any components. Failure to
                        depressurize the system may result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <table id="t08040101" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>SAHR System Troubleshooting Procedure</title>
                <tgroup cols="5">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.61*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.77*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.79*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.90*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="0.97*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col5" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Step</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Procedure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Test Point</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Yes, Meets Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>No, Does Not Meet Spec</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Chock tires, place transmission in a Neutral position, connect EZ-Tech, turn key
                                    to ON.
                                </para>
                                <para>To establish a known condition, attempt to apply the park brake using the dash
                                    Park Brake switch.
                                </para>
                                <para>NOTE: Do not place transmission in a P or PB position, as this may not allow
                                    proper testing of the Park Brake system.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry></entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Using TOOLBOX, verify that only one or more of the following brake related DTC's
                                    have been logged:
                                </para>
                                <para>61 3</para>
                                <para>61 4</para>
                                <para>61 13</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gauge Cluster and TOOLBOX</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If other brake related codes are set, resolve them using TOOLBOX before
                                    troubleshooting the SAHR system with these procedures.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Record the brake related DTC's, then using TOOLBOX, clear all inactive DTC's.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>TOOLBOX</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>4.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Use the COMPONENT TEST menu within TOOLBOX to release the PB (Park Brake), if
                                    possible.
                                </para>
                                <para>Continue procedure regardless of PB status.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>TOOLBOX</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>5.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Inspect PB cables and cable clamps/guides. Verify cables are connected and not
                                    kinked or bound.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>PB cables and cable clamps/ guides</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Make any necessary repairs.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify that there is no indication of brake fluid leakage on the SAHR canister
                                    (near vent hole) and PB line.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister and fittings on PB line.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If a leak is evident, make the necessary repairs.</para>
                                <para>Replace cut-off valve/ cartridge/ manifold, fitting, or brake line. Refer to the
                                    appropriate service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>7.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>While holding the SAHR shaft with a wrench, back the locknut off enough to check
                                    for the indicator stripe on the threaded shaft (Figure 1). The threaded shaft should
                                    be adjusted so that the indicator stripe, 'hash mark', is positioned at the end of
                                    the SAHR shaft. Adjust the threaded shaft, if necessary; then tighten the locknut.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Adjust the threaded shaft, then tighten the locknut.</para>
                                <para>Check PB operation. If adjustment did not correct operation, continue this
                                    procedure.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>8.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>While observing the SAHR canister shaft, have someone use the COMPONENT TEST menu
                                    within TOOLBOX to apply and release the PB several times. Verify that the shaft
                                    extends AND retracts when actuated. The amount of shaft travel is not critical in
                                    this step.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Leave PB released (shaft extended), then go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to step 18.</para>
                                <para>(SAHR canister shaft not responding)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>9.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>With the PB released, verify that the SAHR canister 'release dimension' measures
                                    10.6 inches (Figure 2). This dimension is measured from the end of the shaft (not
                                    including lock nut) to the SAHR canister seam at the vent hole. This dimension is
                                    determined by mechanical stops.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                                <para>NOTE: If shaft extends to proper length, go to next step; even if shaft does not
                                    remain fully extended.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>There is an internal mechanical problem within the SAHR canister and it must be
                                    replaced. Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>10.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Using TOOLBOX apply the PB and verify that the SAHR canister 'apply dimension'
                                    measures 8.1 to 9.8 inches.
                                </para>
                                <para>Like above, this dimension is measured from the end of the shaft to the SAHR
                                    canister seam at the vent hole (Figure 2).
                                </para>
                                <para>In the applied position, this dimension is determined by the following PB system
                                    components: SAHR canister, PB cables, PB shoe linings, and PB drum.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                                <para>NOTE: Preferred 'apply dimension' is 8.7 to 9.8 inches. If shaft dimension is
                                    between 8.1 and 8.7 inches it indicates PB shoes are out of adjustment, or cable is
                                    stretched. Repair as necessary.
                                </para>
                                <para>Normally, the SERVICE PARK BRAKE light will not indicate an overstroke condition
                                    until measurement is [lt ]8.1 inches.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to step 17.</para>
                                <para>(SAHR is UNDER- STROKING or OVERSTROKING during APPLY)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>11.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Using TOOLBOX apply the park brake.</para>
                                <para>Using TOOLBOX clear all brake DTC's.</para>
                                <para>Cycle the IGN key OFF and back ON.</para>
                                <para>Verify that the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is unlit.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is unlit in gauge cluster.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to step 15.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>12.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>IMPORTANT: This step must be performed the first time the PB is released after
                                    clearing the DTC's. The SERVICE PARK BRAKE light must be off. If the light is on,
                                    repeat the previous step.
                                </para>
                                <para>While observing the SAHR canister shaft, have someone use TOOLBOX to release park
                                    brake. Observe the SAHR canister shaft for one minute.
                                </para>
                                <para>The shaft should fully extend and remain extended.</para>
                                <para>If the shaft retracts slightly, then re-extends 2 to 5 times* AND the SERVICE PARK
                                    BRAKE indicator lights (system has entered the 'Backup Mode'); go to step 16.
                                </para>
                                <para>* The number of replenishments allowed before entering the Backup Mode depends on
                                    the ECU software version.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to step 16.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>13.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify that the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is unlit.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace the travel sensor.</para>
                                <para>Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>14.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Using TOOLBOX apply the park brake.</para>
                                <para>Verify that the SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator is unlit.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>System currently operating correctly. Fault is intermittent.</para>
                                <para>Refer to Possible Intermittent Problems and their Causes (after table).</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace the travel sensor.</para>
                                <para>Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>15.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1.&#9;Disconnect the travel sensor electrical connector near the SAHR canister.
                                </para>
                                <para>2.&#9;Verify key is ON. Do not start engine.</para>
                                <para>3.&#9;With a multimeter check the pins on the connector from the chassis harness
                                    (Figure 3).
                                </para>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Pin A - 12 to 14 Vdc</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Pin B - Continuity to Chassis Ground</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Pin C - 12 to 14 Vdc</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                                <para>NOTE: Verify that pins of both connectors are tight and free of corrosion. If not,
                                    repair or clean connection, then retest.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Chassis harness connector for travel sensor.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify that pins of the ECU 31 pin connector are tight and free of corrosion. If
                                    not, repair or clean connection, then retest.
                                </para>
                                <para>If ECU connector is ok, replace the travel sensor.</para>
                                <para>If problem still exists, replace ECU.</para>
                                <para>Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Isolate faulty circuit between harness connector and ECU, using the appropriate
                                    circuit diagram manual, or electrical troubleshooting guide, on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>16.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Disconnect the electrical connector from the cut-off valve coil. Using a
                                    multimeter, measure the resistance of the cut-off valve coil at the pins on the coil
                                    connector.
                                </para>
                                <para>Resistance of the originally installed coils varies by vehicle build date.
                                    Replacement parts may also have a different value. Inspect the coil body for a
                                    printed resistance value. Typically, the following values can be used:
                                </para>
                                <para>Vehicles built prior to April 2008: 8.37 to 10.23 Ohms.</para>
                                <para>Vehicles built April 2008 and after: 6.38 to 8.14 Ohms.</para>
                                <para>NOTE: Verify that pins of both connectors are tight and free of corrosion. If not,
                                    repair or clean connection, then retest.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Cut-off valve electrical connector</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cut-off valve/ cartridge/ manifold. Refer to the appropriate service
                                    manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace cut-off valve electrical coil. Refer to the appropriate service manual on
                                    ISIS.
                                </para>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">CAUTION -The maximum torque on the coil retaining nut is
                                        CRITICAL.</emph>Torque value is 4 to 5 lbf-ft (44 to 60 lbf-in) maximum.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>17.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Verify that the SAHR canister 'apply dimension' is [lt ]8.1 inches (Overstroke
                                    condition).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister shaft</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Overstroke.</para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;Adjust park brake shoes (Refer to service manual s04044).</para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;If problem still exists, check for broken driveline park brake
                                    components or stretched park brake cable(s).
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Understroke</para>
                                <para>Possible causes, correct as necessary:</para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;Park brake shoes adjusted too tight to drum. (Refer to service manual
                                    s04044).
                                </para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;Binding cable.</para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;Binding or broken driveline park brake components (shoes, etc.). Refer
                                    to service manual s04044
                                </para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;SAHR canister malfunctioning (springs, binding, etc.). Replace SAHR
                                    canister. Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <caution>
                                    <para>During some of the following steps, the presence of brake fluid under extreme
                                        pressure will be checked. When loosening the bleeder fitting always assume that
                                        the brake fluid is pressurized, until proven otherwise. Open the bleeder fitting
                                        slowly, and only enough to determine if pressure is present.
                                    </para>
                                    <para>During these steps, insure that the hose is securely fastened onto the bleeder
                                        fitting and that the entire hose is controlled to prevent 'whipping'.
                                    </para>
                                </caution>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>18.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SECURELY connect a hose to the SAHR canister bleeder fitting. Regardless of shaft
                                    position, attempt to apply the park brake using TOOLBOX.
                                </para>
                                <para>Carefully, open the bleeder screw just enough to determine that the brake fluid in
                                    the line is NOT PRESSURIZED at this time. Tighten the fitting.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister bleeder fitting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If pressurized fluid was present, replace the Pressure Supply Valve Core. Refer to
                                    the appropriate service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>19.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Read this entire step before proceeding.</para>
                                <para>NOTE: The TOOLBOX selection used in this step will only energize the PSV for a
                                    brief period of time, then de-energize it.
                                </para>
                                <para>With a hose SECURELY connected to the SAHR canister bleeder fitting, carefully,
                                    open the SAHR bleeder screw just enough to monitor the brake fluid pressure in the
                                    line.
                                </para>
                                <para>While monitoring the brake fluid pressure at the bleeder hose, have someone use
                                    the following TOOLBOX menus to energize the PSV (Supply Valve): COMPONENT TESTS/
                                    MISCELLANEOUS OUTPUTS.
                                </para>
                                <para>Verify that the fluid IS PRESSURIZED while the PSV is energized.</para>
                                <para>Tighten the bleeder fitting, and apply the PB to insure that pressure is released
                                    from the brake line.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister bleeder fitting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>SAHR canister is inoperable.</para>
                                <para>Possible causes:</para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;Cut-Off valve is stuck closed, preventing fluid from entering or
                                    leaving the SAHR canister. Replace the cut-off valve/ cartridge/ manifold assembly.
                                </para>
                                <para>&#8226;&#9;A broken or binding component in the SAHR canister is preventing any
                                    movement of the shaft. Replace SAHR canister.
                                </para>
                                <para>Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.</para>
                                <para>CAUTION: It may be necessary to disassemble the canister to determine the faulty
                                    component. Remove components slowly to prevent injury from trapped pressurized
                                    fluid, if present.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>If pressurized fluid is NOT present, go to next step.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>20.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Disconnect the electrical connector from the Pressure Supply Valve coil.</para>
                                <para>Using a multimeter, measure the resistance of the Pressure Supply Valve coil at
                                    the pins on the coil connector.
                                </para>
                                <para>Coil resistance must be 10.8 to 13.2 Ohms.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pressure Supply Valve electrical connector</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace Pressure Supply Valve. Refer to the appropriate service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                                <para>CAUTION: Do not over-tighten the coil retaining nut.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Replace Pressure Supply Valve electrical coil only. Refer to the appropriate
                                    service manual on ISIS.
                                </para>
                                <para>CAUTION: Do not over-tighten the coil retaining nut.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Possible Intermittent Problems and Probable Causes</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent failure to release. (SAHR shaft has difficulty extending or occasionally will not
                        extend.) Possible Cause(s):
                    </para>
                    <seqlist style="alphalc">
                        <item>
                            <para>Binding in SAHR canister (Test while SAHR is working correctly.)</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Vehicle in Neutral. Key ON. PB applied.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Pull FPB motor fuses (see service manual).</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Monitor accumulator pressure with TOOLBOX.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Pump pedal until pressure drops to 1540-1550 psi.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Using TOOLBOX, attempt to release PB.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>If PB does not release, SAHR canister is binding internally. Replace SAHR
                                        canister.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>If PB does release, SAHR canister is most likely not the problem.</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cut-off valve or Pressure Supply Valve (PSV) sticking</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Can only be isolated when occurring, or by substitution.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>When problem is occurring, isolate with steps 18 - 20 of procedure.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Sticking valves are typically caused by improper installation of valve (wrong
                                        tool or excessive torque, see service manual).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent failure to apply. (Shaft extends but, intermittently will not retract.) Possible
                        Cause(s):
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cut-off valve or Pressure Supply Valve (PSV) sticking</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Can only be isolated when occurring, or by substitution.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>&#9;When problem is occurring, isolate with steps 18 - 20 of procedure.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>&#9;Sticking valves are typically caused by improper installation of valve
                                        (wrong tool or excessive torque, see service manual).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intermittent SERVICE PARK BRAKE indicator with normal park brake operation. Possible
                        Cause(s):
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Normal Replenishment - Travel sensor indicating need for replenishment.</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Normal operation - a software update will prevent this on future vehicles
                                        >5/2008.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Intermittent OPEN electrical circuit from travel sensor to ECU.</para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>Attempt to recreate problem by driving on rough surface, or wriggling
                                        harness.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Check for corroded or loose connections (travel sensor and 31-pin ECU
                                        connector).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Intermittent travel sensor</para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f08040101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g08040101.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. SAHR Shaft Connection</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Locknut</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Flats on SAHR Shaft</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Indicator Stripe 'Hash Mark'</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. Flats on Threaded Shaft</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f08040102" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g08040102.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Reference Points for Measuring SAHR Dimensions</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f08040103" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g08040103.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Chassis Harness Connector to Travel Sensor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
