<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 08-05-01 - ProStar Power Steering Cooler Hoses</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi080501" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>08-05-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July 2008</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>ProStar Power Steering Cooler Hoses</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>ProStar
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>06/02/2008</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>ProStar Tractors built after June 2, 2008 will now have type 6 Power Steering cooler hoses P/N
                    2644104R1 with type 6 hose clamp P/N 2022867C1.
                </para>
                <para>ProStar tractors built before June 2, 2008 that operate in extreme cold climates with type 1 hose
                    P/N 2643655R1 with type 1 clamps P/N 3576742C1 may experience fluid weepage at the hose to cooler
                    location. To correct, please replace the type 1 hose and clamp with the type 6 hose and clamp. Type
                    6 hose is cloth covered and the part number 2644104R1 is stamped on it every few feet.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not use the type 1 hose clamp with the type 6 hose.</emph>
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">GOVERNMENT REGULATION: Engine fluids (oil, fuel, and coolant) may be a hazard to human
                    health and the environment. Handle all fluids and other contaminated materials (e.g. filters, rags)
                    in accordance with applicable regulations. Recycle or dispose of engine fluids, filters, and other
                    contaminated materials according to applicable regulations.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, read all safety instructions in the "Safety Information"
                        section of EGES 415 Engine Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake,
                        and block wheels before doing diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, allow engine to cool before working with components.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury or death, do not let engine fluids stay on your skin. Clean skin
                        and nails using hand cleaner and wash with soap and water. Wash or discard clothing and rags
                        contaminated with engine fluids.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Replace hoses and clamps in the figure below with type 6 hose P/N 2644104R1 and clamps P/N
                2022867C1.
            </para>
            <figure id="f08050101" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G08050101.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
