<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 08-16-02 - Improved Calibration Procedure for Optional Instrument Cluster Compass</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi081602" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>08-16-02</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>07-16-02</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>May 2008</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Cab</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Improved Calibration Procedure for Optional Instrument Cluster Compass</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <distribution dealer="yes" fleet="yes" bodybuilder="no" isis_cd="yes"/>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>7700</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8500</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>DuraStar</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>LoneStar</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>ProStar</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>TranStar</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>WorkStar</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>BE Bus</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>CE Bus</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>HC Bus</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>16HBZ</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This calibration procedure for the optional instrument cluster compass has been improved and
                    replaces the old procedure printed in Operator's Manuals published prior to January 2008. The
                    following procedure should be followed for compass calibration.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc>
            <title>Improved Instrument Cluster Compass Calibration Procedure</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To avoid personal injury or death, pull vehicle off roadway and away from all other
                            traffic before performing the following procedure.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>All new vehicles with an optional compass must have an initial compass calibration performed. A
                    compass calibration may or may not have been completed at the vehicle assembly plant. If the compass
                    headings are noticeably incorrect, or become noticeably incorrect, or the NO CAL message is
                    displayed, the Declination Zone may need to be reset to agree with the current geographic location,
                    or the Compass Directional Calibration will need to be recalibrated.
                </para>
                <para>The compass direction is displayed in the lower left quadrant of the Instrument Cluster Display
                    just below the outdoor temperature reading. Text messages necessary to calibrate the compass can be
                    found in the Instrument Cluster Display in the lower right quadrant (quadrant 2) of the display.
                    Twist the Instrument Cluster Display Knob until the curser is flashing in the lower right quadrant.
                    Press the Instrument Cluster Display Knob until the desired text message is displayed. Compass
                    Calibration related text messages include "Calibrate Compass", "Compass Declination", "Declination
                    Zone #", and "End Calibration".
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The Declination Zone for the location where the Compass Calibration procedure is being
                            performed must be set
                            <emph type="bold">first</emph>, and thereafter the Compass Directional Calibration procedure
                            can be performed. Both procedures are listed on the following pages and must be followed
                            <emph type="bold">exactly</emph>
                            to ensure proper calibration of the compass.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Compass Declination Zone Set Procedure</title>
                <para>The Declination Zone number is used to account for the errors between magnetic North and true
                    North in the vehicle's geographic operating area, and must be set correctly for the compass to
                    display accurate headings.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>When calibrating/recalibrating the compass, you must select the Declination Zone which
                            corresponds to the location where the compass calibration is being performed. It can be
                            reset later to match the Declination zone where the vehicle will be operating.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>For vehicles that regularly operate coast-to-coast or in several different Declination Zones,
                    either choose a Declination Zone in the geographic center of the vehicle's operating area, or change
                    the Declination Zone daily to match the present Declination Zone.
                </para>
                <para>To begin the Declination Zone set procedure, the vehicle must be stopped with ignition key ON.
                    Refer to Zone Map for determining the proper Declination Zone number.
                </para>
                <figure id="f8487224" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g8487224.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Zone Map</caption>
                </figure>
                <table tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple">
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.49*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.65*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.86*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Step</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Procedure</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Displayed Message</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Select Quadrant 2 (lower right) on the display by turning the display control
                                        knob either clockwise or counter-clockwise.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817049.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>2</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Select the Compass Declination message by pressing and releasing the display
                                        control knob until this message appears.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817053.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>3</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Press and hold the display control knob until any Declination Zone number (0 -
                                        10) is displayed.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817054.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>4</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Turn the display control knob clockwise or counter-clockwise until the desired
                                        Declination Zone number is displayed. Refer to Zone Map 1 to determine the
                                        proper number for the current geographic location.
                                    </para>
                                    <note>
                                        <para>If no Declination Zone number is selected within 15 seconds, the display
                                            will return to the Compass Declination message.
                                        </para>
                                    </note>
                                    <note>
                                        <para>If the compass is being calibrated/recalibrated the Declination Zone must
                                            be set to the Zone number for the location where the compass
                                            calibration/recalibration is being performed regardless of the location
                                            where the vehicle will eventually operate.
                                        </para>
                                    </note>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817055.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>5</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Press and
                                        <emph type="bold">HOLD</emph>
                                        the display control knob until the Compass Declination message appears (this
                                        indicates that the new Declination Zone number has been programmed into the
                                        compass).
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817053.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Compass Directional Calibration Procedure</title>
                <para>To begin the Compass Directional Calibration Procedure, stop the vehicle in an area large enough
                    to permit driving in complete circles and perform the following steps:
                </para>
                <table tblwidth="pg-wide" type="simple">
                    <tgroup cols="3">
                        <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.48*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.67*"/>
                        <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="0.85*"/>
                        <thead>
                            <row>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Step</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Procedure</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry align="center">
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Displayed Message</emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </thead>
                        <tbody>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>1</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Select Quadrant 2 (lower right) on the instrument cluster display by turning
                                        the display control knob either clockwise or counter-clockwise.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817049.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>2</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Select the Calibrate Compass message by pressing and releasing the display
                                        control knob until this message appears.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817050.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>3</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Press and hold the display control knob (3 to 5 seconds) until the End
                                        Calibration command is displayed.
                                    </para>
                                    <note>
                                        <para>IF the End Calibration command will not show up, turn OFF the vehicle,
                                            restart it, and return to Step 1.
                                        </para>
                                    </note>
                                    <note>
                                        <para>The following steps (4 through 6) must be completed within 3 minutes to
                                            lock-in the new calibration.
                                            <emph type="bold">Do not press the display control knob or turn the key OFF
                                                until these steps are completed or the calibration process will be
                                                cancelled.
                                            </emph>
                                        </para>
                                    </note>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817051.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>4</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Immediately following the End Calibration command being displayed, drive the
                                        vehicle in 3 complete circles (during this time the compass display will go
                                        blank or have dashed lines present).
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817052.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>5</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Stop the vehicle and wait shortly. The End Calibration message should reappear
                                        on the display.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817051.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>6</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Push and HOLD the display control knob until the End Calibration command
                                        disappears. The calibration should now be complete.
                                        <emph type="bold">IMPORTANT! Just pressing and failing to hold the display
                                            control knob inward until the End Calibration command disappears will cancel
                                            the calibration procedure and you must start over at Step 1.
                                        </emph>
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>&#160;</para>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                            <row>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>7</para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <para>Test the compass calibration. Turn the vehicle ignition key OFF and then
                                        restart the vehicle. Wait 10 seconds to for the compass to complete its self
                                        test. Drive the vehicle in a circle and note the compass readings. If the lower
                                        left quadrant of the Instrument Panel Display shows the correct compass/vehicle
                                        heading, the compass calibration is now complete. If the compass readings are
                                        incorrect, inspect for correct Declination Zone number, turn OFF the vehicle,
                                        restart the vehicle, wait 10 seconds, and perform another circle while
                                        periodically noting the compass readings. If readings are still incorrect
                                        restart the compass calibration procedure.
                                    </para>
                                </entry>
                                <entry>
                                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g3817056.webp" type="webp"/>
                                </entry>
                            </row>
                        </tbody>
                    </tgroup>
                </table>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
