<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 90-16-07 - Installation, Roof Air Deflector and Roof Air Deflector Extension</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi901607" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>90-16-07</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>89-16-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>October, 1990</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Installation, Roof Air Deflector and Roof Air Deflector Extension</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI replaces the 9300/9400 Series information in TSI-89-16-1 dated August, 1989. Discard
                    TSI-89-16-1.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not attempt installation while muffler and tail pipe are hot. Contact with hot surfaces
                            can cause serious personal injuries. This installation requires personnel to work on roof of
                            vehicle or on ladders. Extra care must be taken. Falling from heights can cause serious
                            personal injuries.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Slings dangling from lifting device can snag air deflector or side deflector extension
                            while vehicle is being driven away after assembly has been completed, and can cause
                            extensive vehicle damage.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Bolts forced into misaligned holes will induce stress in material and can cause extensive
                            material damage. Redrill any set of misaligned holes before inserting bolt.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not overtighten fasteners. Overtightening will cause damage to fiberglass panels.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Two people are needed to complete this installation. Air deflector extensions are
                            assembled to air deflector before placing on vehicle. To avoid distorting deflector and
                            extension panels, install each bolt with washers and nut as each hole is drilled. Install
                            bolts that will be visible so that heads are on finished side of deflector or extensions.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>
                <title>SPECIAL TOOLS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Roof protection must be available. It can be made from a remnant of indoor-outdoor carpeting, or
                Saf-Tred stair tread material or other material that will protect paint from damage and provide non-slip
                surface. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9016071">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9016071" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016061.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Proper Use Of Roof Protective Covering</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>A special air deflector lifting sling can be made from lightweight chain, rubber hose, bolts and nuts,
                plus small angle stock. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9016072">Figure 2</hotlnk>for details.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9016072" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016062.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Special Lifting Sling Detail</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. BEND BOLT 90 DEGREES (APPLY HEAT)</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. WELD TOGETHER</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. FLEXIBLE HOSE (FOUR 4 FT. LENGTHS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 1/4 INCH CHAIN (TWO 12 FT. LENGTHS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 5/16-18 X 2 1/2 INCH BOLT WITH NUT (FOUR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SPECIAL ANGLE BRACKET (TWO)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 1/4 INCH X 2 INCH STEEL STOCK</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <title>STANDARD TOOLS</title>
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Lifting device to hold 300 pounds (Accolift&#174; hand chain hoist, #1320010, 1/20-ton maximum
                        capacity, or equivalent) located so as to allow vehicle and deflector to pass underneath.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Two Visegrip&#174; pliers, VP11SP, or equivalent.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Two ten-foot stepladders.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>One three-foot stepladder with padded top edge.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Two 1/2 inch hex wrenches.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Two 9/16 inch hex wrenches.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Screwdriver.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>11/32 inch diameter drill bit.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Portable electric hand drill.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Saw for cutting fiberglass.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Padded frame stand. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9016073">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Torque wrench, 50 ft. lbs. capacity.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f9016073" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016065.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Frame Stand</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. PROTECTIVE COVER (CLOTH AND TAPE, FOR EXAMPLE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. POST AND REST</callout1>
                    <callout1>C. PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>D. STAND BASE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
            <title>INSTALLATION: CAB ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR ASSEMBLY - ALL MODELS</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9016074">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses unless otherwise stated.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air horns from roof brackets on left and right sides if equipped.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put cab roof air deflector (Item 1) on blocks high enough to permit attachment of
                    lifting sling to bottom. Attach lifting sling to air deflector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle is equipped with aerodynamic panels but does not have sleeper box cut
                    slots in the upper corners of the roof air deflector, refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9016071">Cab Roof Air Deflector Assembly - Models Without Sleeper Box.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With help from another person, guide air deflector into position on cab roof.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align pre-drilled holes in air deflector with front roof mounting brackets (Item 2) and
                    rear mounting brackets (Item 4). Brackets must be inside deflector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using roof brackets (Item 2 and 4) as templates and a 11/32 inch diameter bit,
                    back-drill 3 holes in air deflector at centers of slots in roof brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The cab or sleeper roof may be damaged if excessive weight is placed on it. To avoid causing
                        damage, minimize body contact with the roof and do not stand on it. Use a ladder resting on the
                        deck plate and against the back panel to gain access. Always protect cab paint from damage and
                        make sure another person holds the ladder secure while in use.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach air deflector to brackets (Items 2 and 4) with fasteners. Use ladders to gain
                    access to bolts from outside. Do not tighten nuts until all fasteners for the brackets are
                    assembled.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align air deflector with roof, then with the help of another person, tighten all nuts
                    until snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If equipped, position air horns through openings in deflector and re-install.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9016074" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016074.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Cab Roof Air Deflector Installation (42 Inch Shown, 60 Inch Similar)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AIR DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FRONT MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 INCH BOLT W/FLAT WASHERS, SPECIAL FLAT WASHER AND LOCKNUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. REAR MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. COVER PLATE (9400 ONLY)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="x9016071" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
            <title>INSTALLATION: CAB ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR EXTENSION ASSEMBLY - MODELS WITHOUT SLEEPER BOX</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unpack roof deflector extensions and hardware. Paint the extensions following directions
                    in PAINT and REFINISHING section of the Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The roof air deflector must have two slots cut out of each upper corner to allow for
                        attachment of the extension angles.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the following procedure to cut slots in corners:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make two templates using the pattern in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9016075">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align the templates at each corner with the top of each template positioned 27-1/2
                        inches from the deflector center line (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9016076">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Cut out slots in the air deflector with a suitable saw, then file and paint rough
                        edges.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9016075" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Pattern For Template To Cut Slots Into Air Deflector</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9016076" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016076.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Positioning The Template Onto The Air Deflector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AIR DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. TEMPLATE IN POSITION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mark hole locations on the air deflector as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016076">Figure 6</hotlnk>. Using a 11/32 inch diameter drill bit, backdrill four
                    holes in the air deflector for attachment of extension angles (Item 24,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016076">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using clamping tools, attach each extension angle to the air deflector. Fasten the
                    angles to the deflector with four 5/16-18 x 1.0 inch hex head bolts, flat washers, and locknuts.
                    Tighten all fasteners until snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten nuts. Overtightening will cause damage to fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rear most fastener from each cab roof rear mounting bracket (Item 4,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016074">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using clamping tools, attach the left and right roof air deflector side extensions (Item
                    25,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016077">Figure 7</hotlnk>) to the extension angles (Item 24) and cab side
                    extension channels (Item 26).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9016077" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016077.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Attachment Of Side Extensions To Air Deflector</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>24. SIDE EXTENSION ANGLES</callout1>
                    <callout1>25. SIDE EXTENSIONS</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. CAB SIDE EXTENSIONS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the deflector extensions as templates and a 11/32 inch drill bit drill three holes
                    into each side of the roof air deflector. Using the extension angles as templates and the same drill
                    bit, drill two holes in each side extension. Fasten the side extensions to the extension angles and
                    air deflector with 5/16-18 x 1.0 inch hex head bolts, flat washers, and locknuts (two washers for
                    each bolt). Fasten the bottom of each side extension to the roof deflector using the rear mounting
                    bracket fasteners removed in Step 5. DO NOT TIGHTEN.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fasten the roof air deflector extensions to the cab side extension channels (Item 27)
                    with 5/16-18 x 1.0 inch bolts, flat washers and locknuts (two washers for each bolt). DO NOT
                    TIGHTEN.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all fasteners from Steps 7 and 8 until snug.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten nuts. Overtightening will cause damage to fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all clamping tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide extension moldings (Item 28,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016078">Figure 8</hotlnk>) into the molding brackets at the rear of the deflector
                    extensions. Lubricate if necessary using foamy glass cleaner or a similar product.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and mark points on molding brackets at 8 inches from the bottom for the lower
                    hole and 34 inches from the bottom for the upper hole. Fasten with self drilling screws (Item 29).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9016078" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016078.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Attachment Of Extension Moldings To Side Extension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>25. FLEXIBLE MOULDING</callout1>
                    <callout1>26. ROOF DEFLECTOR SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>29. SELF DRILLING SCREW</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="9">
            <title>INSTALLATION: CAB ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR EXTENSION ASSEMBLY - MODELS WITH 42 OR 60 INCH SLEEPER BOX
            </title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unpack side and center extensions (Items 7 and 16,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016079">Figure 9</hotlnk>). Also unpack extension extenders (Item 9) if working on
                    9400 with 60 inch sleeper model. Paint all panels following directions in PAINT and REFINISHING
                    section of the Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9016079" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9016079.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="592px" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Sleeper Box Extension Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. 2 INCH MAXIMUM GAPS</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. AIR DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HOSE CLAMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. REAR BRACE MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SIDE EXTENSION EXTENDER (9400 ONLY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. REAR BRACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. EXTENSION MOLDING</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. MOLDING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. REAR (60 INCH BBC) MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. REAR (42 INCH BBC) OR INTERMEDIATE (60 INCH BBC) MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. FRONT MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. CENTER EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. EXTENDER BRACE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using Visegrip&#174; pliers or similar tool, assemble by overlapping side and center
                    extensions with center extension underneath, and clamp together temporarily. Panels may require
                    trimming to fit correctly. Align uniformly with gap of 1/4 inch or less. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607a">Figure 10.</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607a" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Fastener Detail - Center Extension To Side Extension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. 1/4 INCH MAXIMUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. REAR BRACE MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. CENTER EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 INCH CAP SCREWS, FLAT WASHERS, LOCKNUTS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put assembly on blocks high enough (approximately 8 inches) to permit attachment of
                    lifting sling at bottom.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using side extensions (Item 7,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9016079">Figure 9</hotlnk>) as templates and 11/32 inch diameter bit, drill 18
                    holes in center extension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Portion 7 screws (Item 17,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607a">Figure 10</hotlnk>) in holes on each side of center extension, counting
                    from the rear. Place two other screws in front hole on each side of center extension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach rear brace mounting brackets (Item 8,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607a">Figure 10</hotlnk>) on second and third screws, counting from the rear on
                    each side. Secure with locknuts and tighten until snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure remaining screws with locknuts and tighten until snug.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten nuts. Overtightening can cause damage to fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove clamping tools.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">9400 with 60 inch BBC models only: Attach extension extenders to side extensions.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Align extension extenders (Item 9,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9016079">Figure 9</hotlnk>) to side extensions (Item 7) and clamp temporarily
                        using Visegrip&#174; pliers or similar tool. Using extender as a template and a 11/32 inch
                        diameter bit, drill 6 holes in each side extension.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach extension extenders (Item 9,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9016079">Figure 9</hotlnk>) with fasteners.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide extension moldings (Item 11,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607b">Figure 11</hotlnk>) into molding brackets (Item 12) at rear of side
                    extensions (Item 7 - 42 inch BBC) or extension extenders (Item 9 - 9400 W/60 inch BBC). Molding
                    flares to outside. Lubricate with foamy glass cleaner or similar product if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607b" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607b.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Dimensions</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION (42 INCH BBC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SIDE EXTENSION EXTENDER (9400 WITH 60 INCH BBC ONLY)</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. EXTENSION MOLDING</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. MOLDING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. 10-16 X 1 1/4 INCH SELF DRILLING PAN HEAD SCREW</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate and mark points on molding brackets 2 inches and 40 inches above inside bottom
                    surface of extension (Item 7,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607b">Figure 11</hotlnk>) or extender (Item 9). Install screws (Item 19) through
                    molding bracket into extension molding.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach lifting sling to air deflector extension assembly. With help of another person,
                    guide assembly into position on sleeper box.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align pre-drilled holes in deflector, extension assembly with roof mounting brackets
                    (Item 15 and 14 only - 42 inch BBC or Items 15, 14 and 13 - 60 inch BBC,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607c">Figure 12</hotlnk>). Brackets must be inside extension assembly. Align air
                    deflector extension assembly with air deflector. Maintain uniform gap of 2 inches minimum between
                    them.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607c" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607c.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Fastener Detail - Mounting Brackets To Side Extension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>3. 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 BOLT, FLAT WASHERS, SPECIAL FLAT WASHER, LOCKNUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENDERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. REAR MOUNTING BRACKET (60 INCH BBC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. REAR (42 INCH BBC) OR INTERMEDIATE (60 INCH BBC) MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. FRONT MOUNTING BRACKET (ALL)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using brackets (Items 15 and 14 or 15, 14 and 13,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607c">Figure 12</hotlnk>) as templates and a 13/32 inch diameter bit, backdrill
                    4 holes in each side extension (Item 7) at centers of slots on roof brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach side extensions to brackets as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607c">Figure 12</hotlnk>. Do not tighten nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach front braces (Item 20,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607d">Figure 13</hotlnk>) to each side of center-side extension assembly
                    (inside). The bolts must be in the second hole on vertical surfaces of assembly, counting from the
                    front. Do not tighten nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise both front braces to cross each other at their mid-points. Secure together with a
                    6 inch hose clamp at their mid-point . Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607d" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607d.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Fastener Detail - Front Cross Brace To Center Extension And Side Extension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>6. HOSE CLAMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. CENTER EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 INCH CAP SCREW, FLAT WASHERS, LOCKNUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. 5/16-18 X 1 /14 INCH BOLT, EXTERNAL/INTERNAL TOOTH LOCK WASHER, FLAT WASHERS,
                        LOCKNUT
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>20. FRONT BRACE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach rear braces (Item 10,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607e">Figure 14</hotlnk>) to rear brace mounting brackets (Item 8) with
                    fasteners. Raise both rear braces to cross each other at the mid-points. Secure with a 6 inch hose
                    clamp at their mid-point. Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607e" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607e.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Fastener Detail - Rear Cross Brace To Deflector Bracket</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. 1/4 INCH MAXIMUM</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. REAR BRACE MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. REAR BRACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. CENTER EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 INCH CAP SCREWS, FLAT WASHERS, LOCKNUTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. 5/16-18 X 1 /14 INCH BOLT, EXTERNAL/INTERNAL TOOTH LOCK WASHER, FLAT WASHERS,
                        LOCKNUT
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach front braces (Item 20,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607f">Figure 15)</hotlnk>
                    to front mounting brackets (Item 15) with fasteners (Item 18). Do not tighten nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach rear braces (Item 10,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607f">Figure 15</hotlnk>) to the rear (42 inch BBC) or intermediate (60 inch
                    BBC) mounting brackets (Item 14). Do not tighten nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607f" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607f.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Fastener Detail - Roof Mounting Brackets To Front Or Rear Cross Braces</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>10. REAR BRACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. REAR (42 INCH BBC) OR INTERMEDIATE (60 INCH BBC) MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. FRONT MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>18 5/16-18 X 1 1/4 INCH BOLT EXTERNAL/INTERNAL TOOTH LOCK WASHER, FLAT WASHERS, LOCKNUT
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>20. FRONT BRACE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten nuts. Overtightening will cause damage to fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With help from another person, align deflector extension assembly with cab roof air
                    deflector and with sleeper box roof. Maintain 2 inches minimum gap between deflector and extension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten nuts on front braces at center extension snug. Tighten hose clamps on front and
                    rear braces until snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all nuts on roof mounting brackets on left and right sides to 30 ft-lbs. (46
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect all other nuts for tightness. Tighten all that are loose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using Visegrip&#174; pliers or similar tool, clamp left side extension extender (Item 9,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607g">Figure 16)</hotlnk>
                    to sleeper side extension (Item 22).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attach extender to sleeper side extension with fasteners (Item 32,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f901607g">Figure 16</hotlnk>). Tighten until snug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove clamping tool</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607g" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607g.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. Fastener Detail - Sleeper Roof Side Extension Extender To Sleeper Side Extension
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>7. SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. SIDE EXTENSION EXTENDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>21. 5/16-18 X 1.0 INCH BOLT FLAT WASHER, LOCKNUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>22. SLEEPER SIDE EXTENSION</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">For 9400 with 60 inch BBC only:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Attach extender race (Item 23,
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f901607h">Figure 17</hotlnk>) to extension extender (Item 9) with bolt, flat
                        washers and locknut.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Position loose end in place at side extension (Item 9) and using the end as a
                        template, backdrill a hole in the extension with an 11/32 inch drill bit.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Fasten loose end and tighten. Repeat on the other extender.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clear slings, remove roof platform from roof and move ladders away from vehicle before
                    driving away.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f901607h" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g901607h.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Location Of Extender Brace</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>9. SIDE EXTENSION EXTENDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>23. EXTENDER BRACE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
