<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-04-03 - Brake Air Pressure Distribution Valve (Automatic Front Wheel Limiting Valve) (Code 04567)
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi910403" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-04-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Brake Air Pressure Distribution Valve (Automatic Front Wheel Limiting Valve) (Code 04567)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>04567</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI affects all vehicles with FMVSS-121 Air Brake System.</para>
                <para>Automatic front wheel limiting valves alter the brake balance designed into Navistar vehicles by
                    reducing pressure to the front brakes under all but full or near full pressure stops. This adversely
                    affects brake life and vehicle control; consequently, Navistar continues to discourage the use of
                    automatic front wheel limiting valves.
                </para>
                <para>Some customers and drivers feel that the vehicle should not have front wheel brakes at all; others
                    believe they will have better vehicle control if there is reduced front braking through the use of
                    an automatic front wheel limiting valves. Navistar is convinced that full use of the front brakes is
                    in the best interest of vehicle handling and brake performance. The only reason that automatic front
                    wheel limiting valves are available is because of customer demand. Engineering does not recommend
                    them.
                </para>
                <para>International brake systems are designed for balanced braking between steer and drive axles. It is
                    necessary to brake evenly on all wheel positions to assure stopping in the shortest possible
                    distance. Use of the automatic front wheel limiting valve will not provide optimum balanced braking.
                    Customers should be made aware of the potential problems that can result from the use of the
                    automatic front wheel limiting valve. For example:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Increased Rear Axle Brake Wear</emph>
                            - During normal brake stops, the automatic front wheel limiting valve decreases pressure to
                            the front brakes to approximately half the pressure applied to the rear brakes. The results
                            will be more wear and braking by the rear brakes. Existing designs attempt to balance wear
                            between the front and rear axles without the automatic front wheel limiting valve. Use of
                            the automatic front wheel limiting valve will shorten lining life on the drive axles.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Glazing and Noise</emph>-A brake needs to be worked to assure proper
                            burnishing and effectiveness. The use of an automatic front wheel limiting valve will reduce
                            front brake work and lower its operating temperature, which can cause glazing of the lining
                            and brake noise.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">Vehicle Control</emph>- A vehicle needs to have brake torque applied to
                            the axles experiencing vehicle load (static and dynamic) for balanced braking. Front wheel
                            limiting valves alter this balance.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Navistar does not recommend the use of the automatic front wheel limiting valve.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
