<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-04-02 - False Hydraulic Brake Warning Indication</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi910402" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-04-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>False Hydraulic Brake Warning Indication</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI describes false hydraulic brake warning indication on all vehicles with hydraulic brakes,
                    Model Year 1988 to present with Hydro-max Monitor Module.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The hydraulic brake monitor module monitors several functions of the hydraulic brake system. If the
                monitor module detects an abnormal condition, it illuminates the brake warning light and sounds a
                beeper. Two areas to check when there is a warning indication but no apparent defect are as follows:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>False indications when turning on the parking or headlights is usually the result of poor stop
                        and tail light grounds. Check and clean all stop and tail light grounds and then coat with Grafo
                        grease (part number 472141C1). In instances where stop and tail lights have been relocated to a
                        truck or bus body by a body builder, it is necessary that the body be well grounded to the
                        chassis.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>False indication can also result from non-synchronized brake light and backup motor switches
                        (brake pedal activated). Adjust switches so they activate simultaneously. To reduce the need for
                        frequent adjustment of these switches, a revised brake monitor module with increased timing is
                        available under part number 1658510C3. The color of the new module has been changed from gray to
                        black to make it easily identifiable. The new module was incorporated into production vehicles
                        effective approximately April 20, 1991.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
