<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-05-03 - On Vehicle TAS Power Steering Gear Input Shaft Seal Replacement</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi910503" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-05-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>On Vehicle TAS Power Steering Gear Input Shaft Seal Replacement</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>TRW</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>If you have determined that an external power steering gear leak is caused by the gear input shaft
                    seal, use this improved procedure to replace the input shaft seal on the vehicle.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="15">
            <stitle>TSI 91-05-03 - On Vehicle TAS Power Steering Gear Input Shaft Seal Replacement</stitle>
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect and plug the return line from the steering gear. Also cap the return port of
                    the steering gear with a high pressure fitting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105031">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105031" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105031.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Disconnect Return Line</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the steering column from the gear input shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105032">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105032" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105032.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Disconnect Steering Column</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the dirt and water seal from the steering gear (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105033">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105033" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105033.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Remove Dirt And Water Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wipe out the grease and remove the spiral retaining ring. Use a screwdriver inserted
                    into the notch formed in the end of the ring (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105034">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105034" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105034.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Remove Retaining Ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slip the steering column back onto the input shaft with the pinch bolt installed, but
                    not tightened (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105035">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105035" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105035.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Replace Column</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tie or wrap a shop towel around the input shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105036">Figure 6</hotlnk>) and place a drip pan under the vehicle to catch oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105036" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105036.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Wrap Exposed Area</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add fluid as necessary to fill the power steering reservoir to the fill line on the dip
                    stick (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105037">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105037" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105037.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Fill The Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not mix oil types. Refer to GROUP 10, LUBRICATION in the Service Manual for the proper type
                        of oil to use.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the vehicle in neutral, the wheels blocked to prevent vehicle movement, momentarily
                    turn the starter (quickly turn off the engine if it starts).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the shop towel from around the input shaft. Disconnect the steering column and
                    remove the input shaft seal (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105038">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105038" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105038.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Remove Input Shaft Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the seal area of the valve housing for seal fragments. Remove any that are found (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9105039">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9105039" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9105039.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Inspect Seal Area</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the removed input shaft seal for heat damage. If the seal is stiff and brittle,
                    and not pliable it is probably heat damaged (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503a">Figure 10</hotlnk>). Determine and fix the cause of excessive heat in the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503a" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503A.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Inspect Old Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Put clean grease on the new input shaft seal and place over the input shaft, garter
                    spring side toward the gear. Use a seal installer tool to install the seal. Put the seal installer
                    over the input shaft and against the seal. Tap the seal installer until the tool shoulder is square
                    against the valve housing. Remove any seal material that may have sheared off in the seal bore
                    retaining ring groove (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503b">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503b" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503B.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Install New Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert new retaining ring into the retaining ring groove (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503c">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503c" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503C.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 12. Install Retaining Ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pack the end of the valve housing bore around the input shaft with clean high
                    temperature industrial grease. Apply more grease to a new dirt and water seal and install it over
                    the input shaft seal. Seat it in the groove behind the shaft serrations and against the valve
                    housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503d">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503d" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503D.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 13. Install The Dirt And Water Seal</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the steering column onto the input shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503e">Figure 14</hotlnk>) and tighten to 70 to 75 lb. ft. (95 to 102 Nm). A
                    7/16-20 prevailing torque fastener assembly is required. If original fastener is lost or damaged,
                    replace with Navistar service part number 586263C1 Bolt, 273896 Bolt.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503e" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503E.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. Install Steering Column</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reconnect the return line to the steering gear return port (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f910503f">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f910503f" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G910503F.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Reconnect Return Line</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the reservoir nearly full. Start and run the engine for 10 seconds. Shut the engine
                    off and check and refill the power steering reservoir. Repeat this operation at least three times,
                    each time check and refill the power steering reservoir.
                </para>
                <para>Start the engine and let idle for two minutes. Shut the engine off and check the fluid level in
                    the power steering reservoir.
                </para>
                <para>Start the engine and steer the vehicle from full left to full right turn several times. Add fluid
                    as necessary to the full line on the power steering reservoir dip stick.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air from a gear mounted in an inverted position and equipped with a manual bleed
                    screw by first following step 17.
                </para>
                <para>With the engine idling and no steering action, loosen the manual bleed screw about one turn
                    allowing air and aerated fluid to bleed out around the bleed screw until only clear (non-aerated)
                    fluid is observed. Close the bleed screw and check and fill the power steering reservoir.
                </para>
                <para>Repeat this procedure 3 or 4 times until only clear (non-aerated) fluid is discharged when the
                    screw is loosened. Tighten the manual bleed screw to 27 to 33 in. lbs. (3.1 to 3.7 Nm). Check and
                    refill the power steering reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not steer the vehicle while the bleed screw is loose.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
