<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-08-03 - Installation Guidelines For High Output Radio Transmitters</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi910803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Installation Guidelines For High Output Radio Transmitters</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>International vehicles are using more and more electronic devices such as electronic engines,
                    instrument clusters, entertainment radios, intermittent wiper switches, hydromax monitor modules,
                    antilock brakes and soon electronic transmissions. The following guidelines should be followed to
                    reduce the possibility of radio frequency interference (RFI) affecting these components.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>GUIDELINES</title>
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmitters of this type usually have a control module mounted on the dashboard with the
                            power unit mounted elsewhere. The power unit should be mounted on the back wall or floor of
                            the cab. Any excess cable between the control module and the power unit should be secured at
                            the power unit. Keep cable from the control module to the power unit away from vehicle
                            harnesses.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The positive and negative supply cables to the power unit should exit through the rear
                            floor of the cab and connect directly to the batteries (or as close as possible). Use
                            suitable circuit protection for the positive cable (fuse or circuit breaker). Route cables
                            along and close to the crossmember and frame rails. Power cables should be twisted together
                            if possible.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Antennas should be roof mounted for best performance. Antenna leads should enter from the
                            rear of the cab. It is especially important that the antenna leads be protected from
                            possible damage and that they have good end connections to avoid "leakage" of RFI.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The SWR (standing wave ratio) of the antenna should be measured to be sure it is in the
                            range of 1.0 to 1.5. SWR's above 1.5 may indicate an installation problem.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Good grounds between the cab, frame, engine and hood (if metal) are essential. Add
                            suitable flat braided ground strap between these components when needed. The ends of the
                            ground straps should be secured to clean bare metal and then coated with Grafo grease (part
                            number 472141C1).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Professional installation of these types of radios is recommended.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
