<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-08-04 - Alternator Turn On Speeds</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi910804" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-08-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Alternator Turn On Speeds</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Many alternators used in International vehicles are self-energizing and may require that the
                    engine be revved before they will begin charging. They will then charge at idle. If the vehicle is
                    going to be warmed up prior to beginning operation, the driver should observe the voltmeter or
                    ammeter for charging indication before leaving the vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>INTERNATIONAL 7.3 AND DT ENGINES WITH DELCO 21-SI ALTERNATORS</title>
                </para>
                <para>These engines should be briefly revved to a minimum of 850 rpm when used with the Delco 21SI 65
                    and 100 amp alternators. For the 115 and 145 amp alternators, the engine should be briefly revved to
                    a minimum of 1000 rpm. Alternator output at idle will vary greatly depending on idle speed. Idle
                    speed should be checked periodically to be sure it is within specifications. Idle speed for the
                    International 7.3 diesel engine is 675 rpm. Idle speed for the International DT diesel engines is
                    650 rpm, plus or minus 50 rpm. Setting the idle speed at the upper limit will significantly increase
                    the alternator output at idle. On vehicles with Allison automatic transmissions, idle speed must be
                    set with the transmission in the normal forward drive gear.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
