<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-12-01 - Engine Idle Shutdown Feature On Electronic Engines</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi911201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Engine Idle Shutdown Feature On Electronic Engines</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The function of an engine idle shutdown feature on all electronic engines is to limit excessive
                    idle time by shutting down the engine after a specified time. This is NOT a turbo cool down feature,
                    so the ignition key must remain in the RUN position.
                </para>
                <para>The idle shutdown time is programmable and can be specified by the customer when ordering the
                    vehicle, or by an authorized dealer.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The engine idle shutdown feature shuts down ONLY THE ENGINE, not the power to the rest of
                            the vehicle, which can result in run down batteries if the vehicle is left unattended for an
                            extended period of time.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following information explains how the engine idle shutdown feature functions on Caterpillar
                    3176, 3406B PEEC, Cummins Celect and Detroit Diesel Series 60 electronically controlled engines.
                    (See
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9112011">Figure 1</hotlnk>.)
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CATERPILLAR 3176, 3406B PEEC</title>
            <para>Property Code 812WBD must be ordered to obtain the parking brake switch, plumbing and jumper wires for
                this feature.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Navistar's default value is zero minutes which means it is still disabled.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The idle shutdown timer may be programmed for three (3) to sixty (60) minutes in one (1) minute
                increments. Zero minutes means the feature is turned off.
            </para>
            <para>The following conditions must be met to activate the idle shutdown timer:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Parking brake must be set.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission must be in neutral</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine must be at operating temperature.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle speed must be at "0" mph.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>When the above conditions are met, the engine will shut down after the programmed time. Ninety (90)
                seconds before the programmed idle shutdown time is reached, the "diagnostic lamp" will start to flash
                at a rapid rate. This will allow the driver to reset the timer before engine shutdown.
                <emph type="bold">If the clutch or brake is depressed anytime during the last 90 seconds (while the
                    light is flashing), the timer will be disabled.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Reset The Timer</title>
            </para>
            <para>To reset the idle shutdown timer, re-apply the parking brake.</para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Restart</title>
            </para>
            <para>To restart the engine after idle shutdown, turn the ignition key off, then restart the engine.</para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CUMMINS CELECT</title>
            <para>The engine idle shutdown timer can be set for three (3) to sixty (60) minutes in one (1) minute
                increments, and the feature must be enabled by programming the Idle Shutdown to "Yes". The CELECT system
                does not use any switches on the parking brake.
            </para>
            <para>The following conditions must be met to activate the engine idle shutdown feature:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Engine must be at idle rpm.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle speed must be "0" mph.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No PTO, throttle or clutch activity.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The engine idle shutdown feature will automatically shut the engine off after a preset period of
                engine idling time if there is no clutch, brake or throttle activity.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Reset The Timer</title>
            </para>
            <para>Depressing the clutch, brake or throttle will reset the timer.</para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Restart</title>
            </para>
            <para>To restart the engine after idle shutdown, turn ignition key off, then restart the engine.</para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
            <title>DETROIT DIESEL SERIES 60</title>
            <para>The engine idle shutdown timer may be programmed from three (3) to one hundred (100) minutes in one
                (1) minute increments. The idle shutdown timer must also be programmed to "Yes". Series 60 vehicles may
                be programmed so that this feature does, or does not work during PTO operation. All Series 60 vehicles
                have two (2) switches on the parking brake, one for the idle shutdown timer, and one to determine
                whether to use cruise control or PTO logic.
            </para>
            <para>The following conditions must be met to activate the idle shutdown timer.</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Parking brake must be set.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Transmission must be in neutral.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Vehicle must be at "0" mph.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The engine must be at idle rpm.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <title>Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>The engine idle shutdown timer will automatically shut the engine off after a preset period of time.
                Ninety (90) seconds before the programmed idle shutdown time is reached, the "check engine" lamp will
                start to flash. If the accelerator pedal is depressed during this interval (check engine lamp flashing),
                the timer will be disabled.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Reset The Timer</title>
            </para>
            <para>The idle shutdown timer may be reset by reapplying the parking brake. The timer may also be reset by
                depressing the accelerator pedal PRIOR to the last 90 seconds (flashing light).
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Engine Restart</title>
            </para>
            <para>To restart the engine after idle shutdown, turn the ignition key off, then restart the engine.</para>
            <figure id="f9112011" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9112011.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Engine Idle Shutdown Functions For Engines Used In International Vehicles</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
