<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 91-16-03 - Instructions For Painting Lower Skirting On Navistar Vehicles</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi911603" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>91-16-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1991</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Instructions For Painting Lower Skirting On Navistar Vehicles</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar dealers often get requests to paint the gray lower skirting on Navistar vehicles the same
                    color as the top coat on the vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>Many of these parts are made of a special TPO plastic. This special plastic is resistant to
                    breaking in cold weather and is also very difficult to make paint adhere to.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="prime" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PAINTING PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>RECOMMENDED SYSTEM</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Sikkens Primer</emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean the part with M600 degreasing solvent or with hot water and soap. Be sure to
                        rinse the part thoroughly.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Thoroughly dry the part.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Scuff vigorously with Red Scotchbrite.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Clean again with M600, turning the rag often.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply two coats of Plastoflex Adhesion Primer, allowing each coat to thoroughly
                        dry.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Top coat with Sikkens Autocryl or Autobase with 30% Elast-O-Actif additive.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If Autobase is applied, follow with Autoclear.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Keep paint away from heat, sparks and flame. Vapor may cause flash fire. Use with adequate
                            ventilation. Do not breathe vapors or spray mist. Wear an appropriate, properly fitted
                            respirator (NIOSH/MSHA approved) during and after application, unless air monitoring
                            demonstrates vapor/mist levels are below applicable limits. Follow respirator manufacturer's
                            direction for respirator use. Avoid contact with eyes, skin and clothing. Wash thoroughly
                            after handling. May contain lead. Do not use on toys, furniture or surfaces or other
                            articles that might be chewed by children.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent the possibility of damage to property or personal injury you must follow all
                            warnings given by the paint supplier.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>ALTERNATE SYSTEM</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Oceans Primer</emph>
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Scuff vigorously with Red Scotchbrite.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Wash the part with 50/50 Isopropanol Alcohol/MEK solution.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply one coat of Oceans TY-Coat #1 Adhesive Primer. Allow TY-Coat #1 to dry to
                        touch.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Top coat with Sikkens Autocryl or Autobase with 30% Elast-O-Actif additive.</para>
                    <para>If Autocryl is applied, follow with Autoclear.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>TY-Coat #1 can be purchased through Sherwin Williams stores. If the Sherwin Williams
                            jobber does not stock TY-Coat #1, the jobber should call 1-800-343-1496 for 24 to 48 hour
                            delivery of Oceans Coatings.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
