<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-03-03 - Wear Limits For Rear Suspension Torque Leaf Bushings</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-03-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Wear Limits For Rear Suspension Torque Leaf Bushings</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all vehicles equipped with Vari-Rate rear suspension.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The following procedures may be used to determine when Vari-Rate rear suspension torque leaf bushing
                service is required.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following bushing wear check should be made PRIOR to lubrication.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert a 12 inch to 16 inch bar between the spring bracket rebound pin and the torque
                    leaf spring eye. Observe movement of the torque leaf spring eye while pushing up and down on the
                    outer end of the bar. If movement of the torque leaf spring eye at the shackle pin appears to be
                    more than 1/8 inch, go to step 2.
                </para>
                <para>It should be noted that a bar of greater length than 16 inches could possibly exert undue force
                    causing the spring, spring bracket and/or spring shackle pin to be deformed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The only accurate measurement of bushing wear requires removing the spring shackle pin (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9203031">Figure 1</hotlnk>), measuring the outside diameter of the pin and the
                    inside diameter of the spring eye bushing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9203031">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The difference between the two measurements is the
                    amount of clearance between the spring eye bushing and the spring shackle pin. If a measurement of
                    .007 to .012 is noted, the bushing is new. A measurement of .080 to .090 indicates that the bushing
                    should be replaced during the next vehicle service interval; if the measurement is .120 or more, the
                    bushing should be replaced immediately.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9203031" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9203031.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Vari-Rate Spring Suspension</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SPRING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. SPRING</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TORQUE LEAF</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SPRING EYE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SPRING EYE BUSHING</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. SHACKLE PIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. REBOUND PIN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
