<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-04-02 - Location of Seals in Pressure Differential Valve</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920402" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-04-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Location of Seals in Pressure Differential Valve</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all vehicles with hydraulic brakes.</para>
                <para>The Hydro-Max Brake Booster with Split Hydraulic Brake System (CTS-5018, Chapter IV) Service
                    Manual Section has an error in Figure 13 on page 11. The "O" ring seal next to the centering ring
                    (sleeve) is shown in the wrong position on the spool. The following illustration shows the seal in
                    the proper position on the spool. The illustration in CTS-5018 shows the "O" ring seal on the right
                    side of the centering ring instead of as illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9204021">Figure 1</hotlnk>. If the "O" ring seal is installed on the right side of
                    the centering ring, the valve will leak brake fluid from the sensor opening and will not center
                    properly.
                </para>
                <para>Instruction number 17 on page 13 of CTS-5018, Chapter IV, explains how to install the "O" ring
                    seals as illustrated in Figure 13. Disregard instruction number 17 and install the "O" ring seals as
                    illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9204021">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9204021" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9204021.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Proper "O" Ring Seal Installation On The Pressure Differential Valve Spool
                    </caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. "O" RING SEAL</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. CENTERING RING</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. VALVE SPOOL</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. MASTER CYLINDER</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. SENSOR OPENING</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>This error in CTS-5018, Chapter IV, will be corrected at the next revision. it is suggested that a
                    copy of this TSI be placed on page 13, in CTS-5018, Chapter IV.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
