<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-04-03 - Brake Fluid Contamination</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920403" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-04-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Brake Fluid Contamination</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all vehicles with hydraulic brakes.</para>
                <para>Vehicles with hydraulic brakes have two completely separate hydraulic systems that consist of:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Hydraulic pump (power steering) that provides fluid to the Hydro-max portion of the
                            braking system to give power assist to the master cylinder that pressurizes the brakes.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The hydraulic brake system that includes the master cylinder and wheel end cylinders.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>The hydraulic pump and hydro-max booster operate on a fluid that is totally different from the
                    fluid used in the hydraulic brake system.
                    <emph type="bold">THE FLUIDS ARE NOT COMPATIBLE.</emph>
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The hydraulic pump and hydro-max booster operate on
                            <emph type="bold">POWER STEERING FLUID</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The hydraulic brake system operates on
                            <emph type="bold">BRAKE FLUID</emph>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Introduction of fluids other than brake fluid in the master cylinder will result in the swelling and
                deterioration of rubber parts, leading to reduced brake performance and eventual failure of the brake
                system. Brake failure might result in personal injury.
            </para>
            <para>A Caution label has been added to the master cylinder (in addition to embossed wording in the master
                cylinder reservoir cover) noting that the brake system uses only brake fluid.
            </para>
            <para>To avoid putting the wrong fluid in the master cylinder (contaminating the system), the following
                precautions should be followed:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Use only fluids specified for each system. Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION in CTS-5000 Master
                        Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Make sure that fluids are properly identified. Store only in the original containers and
                        carefully check the label before using.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Add fluids only as follows:</para>
                    <para>Power steering fluid only to the hydraulic pump reservoir.
                        <emph type="bold">NOT THE MASTER CYLINDER.</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>Brake fluid
                        <emph type="bold">ONLY</emph>
                        to the master cylinder reservoir.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">DISCARD</emph>
                        - do not attempt to reuse - any fluid drained from either system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>If the master cylinder is found to have non-compatible fluid, as indicated by swollen rubber
                components (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9204031">Figure 1</hotlnk>), perform the following:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove master cylinder and brake calipers.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Flush all brake lines thoroughly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean and rebuild master cylinder using new parts per International service
                    instructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace all rubber brake line hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean and rebuild brake calipers using new parts per International service
                    instructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Optional: Replace all rubber brake line hoses, master cylinder and brake calipers with
                    new units.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9204031" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9204031.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Rubber Brake Parts</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Failure to completely purge the system of contaminated fluid and replace all contaminated
                        rubber components will impair brake performance and possibly lead to brake failure resulting in
                        personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Contaminated brake fluid is a maintenance error and is not covered by warranty.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
