<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-05-02 - On-Vehicle Poppet Readjustment for TRW TAS Power Steering Gears</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920502" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-05-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>STEERING</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>On-Vehicle Poppet Readjustment for TRW TAS Power Steering Gears</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>TRW</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all vehicles with power steering.</para>
                <para>Poppets are pressure unloading valves set to trip just before a full turn is reached in each
                    direction. When this procedure is operating correctly, system pressure will be reduced before the
                    axle stop contacts the axle stop screw in both directions.
                </para>
                <para>Why poppets need to be adjusted:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Changed to larger tires.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Reduced vehicle wheelcut.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Pitman arm mistimed, condition corrected.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering gear being installed on a different truck.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steering axle stop bolt(s) were bent or broken.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Steer axle U-bolt(s) were bent or broken.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>To determine if the poppets require readjustment or if they are performing properly, install a
                    Power Steering System Analyzer between the power steering pump and the steering gear. If poppet
                    readjustment is required, you can leave the Analyzer in the system to verify that the following
                    procedure is completed properly.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9205021" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.60in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.57in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.33in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1670596C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Adjusting Screw and Nut</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="11">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This procedure will work in most cases with at least 1-3/4 steering wheel turns from each side
                        of center. If you're making a large reduction in wheelcut and this procedure does not work,
                        refer to GROUP 05 - STEERING for detailed information to internally set the poppets.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set axle stops to Navistar's specifications. Refer to GROUP 02 - FRONT AXLE.</para>
                <para>Start the engine and allow the vehicle to idle for 5 to 10 minutes to warm the hydraulic fluid.
                    Shut off the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a new poppet adjusting screw and nut are being used, turn the screw into the
                    non-sealing end of the jam nut until the device end of the screw is flush with the nut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205021">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>Your steering gear will have either a fixed stop bolt or an adjusting screw. If the adjusting
                    screw is already part of the steering gear, back the nut off the adjusting screw until it is flush
                    with the end of the adjusting screw.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205021" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205021.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Assemble Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the engine is off and the front wheels of the vehicle are straight ahead.
                    Remove and discard the poppet fixed stop bolt (if equipped) and washer from the lower end of the
                    housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205022">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>If the unit has a poppet adjusting screw and sealing nut that need to be replaced, remove and
                    discard them.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205022" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205022.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Remove Poppet Stop Screw</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a 7/32 inch Allen wrench, turn the adjusting screw and sealing nut assembly without
                    rotating the nut on the screw into the housing until the nut is firmly against the housing. Tighten
                    the sealing nut against the housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205023">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205023" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205023.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Turn Adjusting Screw Assembly Into Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Refill the system reservoir with approved hydraulic fluid (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205024">Figure 4</hotlnk>). Refer to GROUP 10 - LUBRICATION for the proper
                    hydraulic fluid.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not mix fluid types. Mixing of transmission fluid, motor oil, or other hydraulic fluids
                            will cause seals to deteriorate faster.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205024" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205024.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Check and Fill Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block the rear wheels and set the parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place a jack under the center of the front axle and jack up the front end of the vehicle
                    so the steer axle tires are off the ground (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205025">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205025" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205025.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Jack Up Vehicle</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and run at idle speed. Note which output shaft timing mark is nearest
                    the housing piston bore. Turn the steering wheel in the direction that makes this timing mark move
                    toward the adjusting screw just installed. Turn in this direction until axle stop contact is made.
                    Pull hard on the steering wheel (put 30 lbs. rim pull on a 20-inch-diameter steering wheel) after
                    the axle stop is contacted. This will prepare the upper poppet for setting (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205026">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205026" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205026.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Push Upper Poppet Out To Prepare It For Setting</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To set the poppet, turn the steering wheel in the opposite direction (end of timing mark
                    away from adjusting screw) until the other axle stop is contacted. Pull hard on the steering wheel
                    (put 30 lbs. rim pull on a 20-inch-diameter steering wheel). Release the steering wheel and shut off
                    the engine (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205027">Figure 7</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not hold the steering wheel at full turn more than 10 seconds at a time; the heat build-up
                        at pump relief pressure may damage steering components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f9205027" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205027.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Set Upper Poppet</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen the sealing nut and back off the adjusting screw until 1 inch past the nut.
                    Tighten the sealing nut against the housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205028">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205028" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205028.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Back Out Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and let idle. Turn the steering wheel in the original direction (end of
                    timing mark toward adjusting screw) until axle stop contact is made. Hold the steering wheel in this
                    position (30 lbs. rim pull) for 10 seconds, then release (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9205029">Figure 9</hotlnk>). Repeat this hold and release process as many times as
                    necessary while completing step 12.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9205029" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9205029.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Set Lower Poppet</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With steering wheel held at full turn, loosen the jam nut and hold it in place with a
                    wrench. Turn the adjusting screw in (clockwise)
                    <emph type="underscr">using finger-pressure only - don't use a ratchet</emph>
                    - until the Allen wrench comes to a stop.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not attempt to turn it in further.</emph>Stop the turn-in process each time the
                    driver releases the steering wheel; continue turning only while the steering wheel is being held at
                    a full turn. Back off the adjusting screw 3-1/4 turns and tighten sealing nut to 33-37 ft. lbs.
                    torque (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f920502a">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f920502a" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G920502A.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Position Adjusting Screw</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not hold the steering wheel at full turn more than 10 seconds at a time; the heat build-up
                        at pump relief pressure may damage steering components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>The length of the adjusting screw beyond the nut must be
                        <emph type="underscr">no more than</emph>
                        1-1/16 inch for proper thread engagement.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>The length of the adjusting screw beyond the sealing nut may vary for each vehicle.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The poppets have now been completely set. Check the power steering reservoir fluid level and fill if
                required (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f920502b">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f920502b" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G920502B.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 11. Check And Fill Reservoir</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
