<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-08-11 - Removing and Replacing Factory Installed Panasonic, Alpine and Technics Radios</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920811" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-08-11</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Removing and Replacing Factory Installed Panasonic, Alpine and Technics Radios</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI describes the removing and replacing of radios in certain model vehicles.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Radios installed in 2000, 4000 and 8000 models use a "DIN" mount and can be removed by
                    using the removal tools provided in the radio instruction package.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Radios installed in 5000 and 9000 models are mounted in brackets which are secured with
                    theft protective screws. Tools to remove the theft protective screws are available from your local
                    Snap-On, Mac, Matco, etc. tool distributors.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The radio removal tools used for 2000, 4000 and 8000 models will not work on 5000 and
                    9000 models. Attempts to do so can damage the radio. Also, never pry on radio face plates - they are
                    not removable. Attempts to do so will damage the radio.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Radios from 5000 and 9000 models returned under warranty must include the mounting
                    bracket. Do not remove radio from mounting bracket. Replacement radios will include a new mounting
                    bracket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Radios from 2000, 4000 and 8000 models returned under warranty must include the rubber
                    bumper mounted on the back side. Replacement radios will include a new bumper.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Panasonic and Technics radios include a removable radio harness. If these radios are
                    returned under warranty, the harness must also be returned. Replacement radios will include a new
                    harness.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Warranty on radios whose harnesses have been cut into or spliced will not be honored.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Radios returned under warranty should be returned using the same box the replacement
                    radio arrived in.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
