<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-08-09 - Creation of False 412 Fault Code With Cummins Echek Service Tool</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920809" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-08-09</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Creation of False 412 Fault Code With Cummins Echek Service Tool</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Cummins</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all vehicle models with Cummins CELECT Engines.</para>
                <para>Recent field tests have revealed a fault code condition with the Cummins Echek electronic service
                    tool. The cause of the condition is that the Echek service tool can induce a fault code 412 (same as
                    SID 250 + FMI 3) as the Echek does its power-up self check. The Echek's power-up sequence creates a
                    situation that the CELECT control module sees as lasting too long, so a fault code is logged. If the
                    Echek is powered up
                    <emph type="bold">before</emph>the CELECT system (through the cigarette lighter or direct battery
                    feed), this condition will not be encountered.
                </para>
                <para>To correct this condition, Cummins will lengthen the time constant in the software that triggers
                    this fault code. New "Software Calibrations" for CELECT will be released upon resolution
                    verification. For the new software, the vehicle must be updated through the Cummins' ESDN system.
                </para>
                <para>In the meantime, do not be alarmed by 412 codes, but do not ignore them either. There are still
                    other legitimate potential causes for a 412 code as shown in the Cummins L10 and N14 Troubleshooting
                    Manual. The Pro-link and Cummins Compulink service tools will not cause this condition.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
