<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-08-12 - Programming Information for Medium and Heavy Duty Truck Instrument Clusters</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920812" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-08-12</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Programming Information for Medium and Heavy Duty Truck Instrument Clusters</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>06/01/1991</startdate>
                        <enddate>01/01/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>03/01/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1991</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>All speedometers and tachometers are programmed electronically at the factory via the cluster data
                    link. All dip switches are set to "0". Factory programming for both speedometer and tachometer will
                    be deactivated if any dip switch is moved to the "1" position. Factory programming will be
                    reactivated if all dip switches are returned to "0".
                </para>
                <para>Dip switches will have to be manually set if tire size or axle ratio is changed, or if a
                    replacement cluster is installed. The dip switch settings that were electronically programmed are
                    shown on the linesetting ticket, and on a label attached to the cluster (1000-4000 and 8000 only).
                </para>
                <para>When manually programming 1000-4000 and 8000 models, dip switch "7" on the right (tachometer) bank
                    must always be set to "0". Failure to set switch "7" to "0" will result in erroneous tachometer
                    readings. Switch "8" on the right (tachometer) bank controls the odometer and must be set to "0" for
                    miles and "1" for kilometers.
                </para>
                <para>When manually programming on 5000 and 9000 models, dip switch "9" on the right (tachometer) bank
                    must always be set to "0". Switch "10" on the right (tachometer) bank controls the odometer and must
                    be set to "0" for miles and "1" for kilometers. Note that dip switches "9" and "10" now function
                    differently as compared to the earlier stand-alone tachometer unit.
                </para>
                <para>The correct service manual section to use for the 5000 and 9000 models is CTS-5048. For the
                    1000-4000 and 8000 models, use service manual section CTS-5088. Both of these sections are located
                    in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. Do not use prior service manual sections for these new
                    instrument clusters.
                </para>
                <para>A cartridge is being developed for the Pro-Link service tool so that instrument clusters can be
                    electronically programmed in the field. It is planned that the future generation of clusters will
                    not have dip switches.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
