<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-08-03 - Vehicle Jump-Starting Information</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi920803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Vehicle Jump-Starting Information</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar recently became aware of several instances where a portable welder was used to jump-start
                    several vehicles. Due to excessive voltage being applied to the vehicles, engine control modules
                    were destroyed, resulting in repair costs of over $2000.00 per vehicle
                </para>
                <para>Navistar vehicles are currently equipped with various electronic components including, but not
                    limited to:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Instrumentation</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>ABS Modules</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Brake Warning Module</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Engine Control Modules</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Transmission Control Modules</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Glow Plug Module</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Panel Light Dimmer</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Windshield Wiper Control (intermittent)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Radio</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>Excessive voltage or current applied to electronic components may damage or destroy them,
                    resulting in expensive repairs.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>To avoid damage to vehicle electronic components, voltage supplied to a vehicle's
                            electronic system must never exceed 16.0 volts. This voltage must not be exceeded when the
                            ignition switch is in the "off" "acc" or "ign" position, or during engine cranking.
                            <emph type="bold">The most reliable means for jump-starting a vehicle is to use batteries
                                connected so as to provide 12 volts.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>Auxiliary vehicle jump-starting equipment, such as Goodall "Start-All" units, are acceptable only
                    if they are equipped with optional voltage control units. If you currently have such equipment,
                    contact the manufacturer of the equipment for information on retro-fitting a voltage control unit.
                </para>
                <para>Electric welders must never be used for vehicle jump starting as such devices are commonly current
                    controlled, not voltage controlled.
                </para>
                <para>Electronic component failures caused by excessive voltage or current will be denied warranty
                    reimbursement.
                </para>
                <para>Further important information on jump-starting procedures and precautions are contained in Service
                    Manual section CTS-5021 - Maintenance Free Batteries.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
