<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-10-01 - Application of Special Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi921001" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-10-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>GENERAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Application of Special Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</subject>
            <subject>Questions and Answers About Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Application of Special Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</title>
                <para>In a continuing effort to keep service personnel informed of the latest service procedures,
                    Navistar has provided a listing of various applications for adhesives, sealants, and cleaning
                    compounds. This listing comes complete with the sizes available for each product and Fleetrite part
                    numbers.
                </para>
                <para>Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9210011">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9210012">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                    for applications of special adhesives, sealants and cleaning components. Only the material with
                    assigned service part numbers approved by Fleetrite are listed. It is important to note that there
                    are different types of material for different applications.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9210011" figsize="full-pg">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Special Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9210012" figsize="full-pg">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210012.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Special Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds (Cont.)</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Questions and Answers About Adhesives, Sealants and Cleaning Compounds</title>
                <lev1>
                    <title>BASIC PRINCIPLES OF ADHESIVES</title>
                    <para>We have included a helpful information, questions and answers portion of this letter prepared
                        by Loctite Corporation. This information is to assist Service Technicians in the selection of
                        appropriate adhesives and sealants.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: What can Fleetrite Adhesive/Sealants do for me?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Just a few examples. They can:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Prevent fasteners from loosening - Lock N' Seal</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Seal leaky threaded fittings - Pipe Sealant with Teflon</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Keep bearings from spinning out - Sleeve N' Bearing Mount</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Restore fit between worn bearings, sleeves, gears, pulleys - Sleeve N' Bearing Mount
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Seal flanged assemblies - Gasket Eliminator&#174; 515, Ultra Blue TM, Form-A-Gasket&#174;</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do these adhesive/sealants work?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210013">Figure 3</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Applied as a liquid or a paste, they automatically harden into a tough resin between
                        threads or close fitting parts. They lock and seal after assembly.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210013" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210013.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Can I get the parts apart?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Yes. Use a little extra elbow grease and ordinary tools on fasteners. Use a bearing puller
                        or a press for bearings or sleeves. Heat at 550&#176;F (288&#176;C) will help loosen parts. Take
                        apart while hot.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Can I re-use the parts?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210014">Figure 4</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Yes. Knock or blow off the loose particles and re-apply the adhesive/sealant. Material can
                        be removed by wire brush if necessary.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210014" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210014.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do I clean the parts?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210015">Figure 5</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Clean with Clean N' Cure Primer or Cleaner Parts Solvent, if available. Or use ordinary
                        shop solvent, or wipe off with clean shop towel.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210015" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210015.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: What happens if I apply adhesive/sealant and it doesn't work?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210016">Figure 6</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Three things could have happened.</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Sufficient material was not applied to fill the joint.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Insufficient time was allowed for cure.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Parts were excessively oily, dirty or greasy, which may prevent the adhesive/sealant
                                from curing.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                    <figure id="f9210016" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210016.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: What should I do then?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Clean all parts thoroughly, using a wire wheel or putty knife and a solvent. When all parts
                        are clean and dry, apply Clean N' Cure Primer. Let it dry, then apply adhesive sealant. Allow
                        sufficient time to cure.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How much temperature will the adhesive/sealant stand?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210017">Figure 7</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: -65&#176;F (-54&#176;C) to 300&#176;F (149&#176;C) for both Lock N' Seal products, Pipe
                        Sealant with Teflon, Sleeve N' Bearing Mount and Gasket Eliminator 515.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210017" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210017.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Will hydraulic oil, motor oil, fuel or water dissolve the
                            adhesive/sealant?
                        </emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210018">Figure 8</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: No. These adhesive/sealants are solvent resistant to all the ordinary liquids and gases.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210018" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210018.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do I apply adhesive/sealant?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9210019">Figure 9</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Simply apply from bottle nozzle to one part. Apply sufficient amount to fill the gap
                        between parts. Adhesive/sealant will not harden while in contact with air - hardens only
                        <emph type="bold">in the joint after assembly</emph>.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9210019" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9210019.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: What happens if I leave the cap off a bottle or tube?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Nothing. It won't harden in the tube or bottle or evaporate.</para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SHAFT MOUNTING</title>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Can I use Sleeve N' Bearing Mount to fill the clearance between a bearing
                            and a worn housing or shaft?
                        </emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001a">Figure 10</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Yes. It will fill a clearance up to .005 inch (.13 mm). Holding power is equal to a press
                        fit.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001a" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001a.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do I use Sleeve N' Bearing Mount?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Spray parts with Clean N' Cure Primer. Apply compound to shaft or bore. Assemble in normal
                        way.
                    </para>
                    <para>How to use Sleeve N' Bearing Mount (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001b">Figure 11</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Spray with Clean N' Cure Primer. Let dry 2 or 3 minutes.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Apply Sleeve N' Bearing Mount.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Assemble in normal way.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Cure two hours at room temperature.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Press fits can be used at once. On slip fits, allow 2 hours for full cure.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <figure id="f921001b" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001b.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>PRIMING AND PREPARATION</title>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: In general, how fast will adhesive/sealant cure?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001c">Figure 12</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Usually fixtures in 1 hour. Fully cured in 4 hours.</para>
                    <figure id="f921001c" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001c.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How can I speed up the cure if I have to go right back into service?
                        </emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001d">Figure 13</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Apply Clean N' Cure Primer on parts before applying sealant. Cuts cure time in half, or
                        apply heat to 300&#176;F (149&#176;C); this will cure material in 15 minutes.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001d" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001d.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>PIPE SEALING</title>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: We use Teflon tape to seal threaded fittings. Why should I use Pipe
                            Sealant with Teflon?
                        </emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001e">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001f">Figure 15</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Teflon tape can shred and get into systems which may block orifices and valves. Pipe
                        Sealant with Teflon is easier to apply, locks and seals fittings at any angle. Won't vibrate
                        loose. Forms a solid seal. Withstands high pressures.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001e" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001e.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f921001f" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001f.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GASKETING</title>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How does Gasket Eliminator 515 work?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001g">Figure 16</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Gasket Eliminator forms the gasket
                        <emph type="bold">in place</emph>. When confined between the assembled flanges, the gel-like
                        material automatically converts into a tough sealing gasket. It resists heat to 300&#176;F (177&#176;C).
                        Also resists water, oil and solvents. One tube makes many sizes and shapes of gaskets.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001g" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001g.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do I apply Gasket Eliminator 515?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001h">Figure 17</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Apply directly from the nozzle applicator on the tube. No mixing. No heat cure. For most
                        joints, apply a 1/16 inch (1.59 mm) diameter bead around the bolt holes and between the bolt
                        holes centered on the flanges. Material does not cure until flanges are mated together. Be sure
                        that the material will be in contact with both flanges when parts are assembled.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001h" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001h.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Can I get the flanges apart?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Yes. Tap on flanges to loosen.</para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: How do I clean off the cured material?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001i">Figure 18</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001j">Figure 19</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: For most flanged joints, it is not necessary to remove the cured material. Wipe off surface
                        with a clean shop towel and apply a new bead. If it is a very critical dimension joint, remove
                        all residue by applying Gasket Remover or by scraping with a putty knife or wire wheel. Then
                        clean up with Clean N' Cure Primer before re-assembly.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001i" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001i.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f921001j" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001j.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Where can I use Gasket Eliminator 515?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001k">Figure 20</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Rigid flanges such as axle shaft flanges, flywheel housing and other rigid covers, plates.
                        Use only where the change in joint thickness will not affect internal clearances.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001k" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001k.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Where do I use Make-a-Gasket #2?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Use to dress cut paper and cork gaskets such as on oil pans, transmissions and timing
                        covers. Use also to seal hose connections.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Where do I use Ultra Blue RTV Silicone Gasket?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001l">Figure 21</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: A formed-in-place gasketing material three times more oil resistant than other RTV
                        silicones; use on valve covers, oil pans or other applications requiring a flexible gasket. For
                        Navistar applications, the non-corrosive to electrical contacts components, such as two speed
                        shift motor, are most important.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001l" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001l.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: What is good use for Superflex&#8482; Clear RTV Silicone?</emph>
                        (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f921001m">Figure 22</hotlnk>)
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Use where cosmetic appearance is important. Dries clear and flexible. Maximum temperature
                        400&#176;F (204&#176;C). Use for caulking of windshields, windshield frames, lights and
                        weatherstripping. Adheres to glass, metal, wood and rubber.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f921001m" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g921001m.webp" type="webp"/>
                    </figure>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="italic">Q: Where do I use Form-a-Gasket Black RTV Silicone?</emph>
                    </para>
                    <para>A: Use on flexible flanges to make form-in-place gaskets, where oil resistance is required. Or
                        use for same application as Superflex Clear RTV when black color is desired.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
