<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-11-02 - Clutch Operation</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi921102" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-11-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CLUTCH</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Clutch Operation</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Difficulty in shifting transmissions into first and reverse gear (first and reverse gear are NOT
                    always synchronized) is been reported. The following information as outlined in the OWNER'S MANUAL
                    under
                    <emph type="bold">Clutch Operation</emph>should help clear up this situation
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">CLUTCH BRAKE (VEHICLES WITH NON-SYNCHRONIZED TRANSMISSION)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>A clutch brake is used to stop transmission input shaft rotation so that the initial first or reverse
                gear selection can be accomplished when the vehicle is at a standstill and the engine running at
                <emph type="bold">IDLE</emph>speed. Clutch brake application occurs in the last approximate 1 inch
                (25mm) of pedal travel.
            </para>
            <para>Fully depress the clutch pedal when using the clutch brake and shift the transmission into either
                first or reverse gear. If tooth-butting occurs between the clutch teeth, re-engage the clutch while
                slightly applying light pressure to the shift lever. This will provide for a smooth shift into either
                first or reverse gear.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">SHIFTING WITH SYNCHRONIZED TRANSMISSION</emph>
            </para>
            <para>With the clutch released (pedal depressed) and engine at idle, if low gear is not synchronized,
                <emph type="bold">use second speed gear synchronizer to stop clutch disc rotation</emph>. This will
                allow smooth engagement of first or reverse gear selection. If the transmission
                <emph type="bold">IS</emph>
                synchronized in low/1st gear then either low or 1st gear synchronizer can be used to stop rotation. It
                may be necessary to start engagement (slipping) of the clutch with light pressure on the shift lever to
                complete gear engagement. It takes one or two seconds to match gear speeds. Steady pressure on the shift
                lever will help the synchronizer perform its job quicker. If the transmission is forced into gear, it is
                possible to override a blocker and defeat the purpose of the synchronizer, causing gear clash.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
