<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-12-05 - Inspection Procedure For Verification Of Oil Or Coolant Leakage From Cylinder Head Gasket
        (7.3L Diesel Engine)
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi921205" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-12-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Inspection Procedure For Verification Of Oil Or Coolant Leakage From Cylinder Head Gasket (7.3L
                Diesel Engine)
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>7.3L Diesel Engine</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI describes a systematic inspection procedure that is to be performed to alleviate
                    unnecessary replacement of the cylinder head gasket due to misdiagnosed causes such as external oil,
                    coolant or combustion gas leakage.
                </para>
                <para>Any fluids that are leaked or spilled on the front or top of the engine have a tendency to collect
                    in the crankcase/cylinder head gasket joint area and subsequently result in no-fault cylinder head
                    gasket replacement.
                </para>
                <para>Typically fluids light enough in viscosity run freely and appear to be leaking from the front or
                    rear corners of the crankcase/cylinder head joint area.
                </para>
                <para>Fluids of heavier viscosity sometimes remain in the crankcase/cylinder head joint area and either
                    type of fluid can saturate the head gasket body material. These fluids during normal engine
                    operation/vibration and thermal induced motion cause small bubbles to form which expand and collapse
                    at varying frequency depending on engine speed. (Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="x9212051">
                        <emph type="bold">BLOWING BUBBLES BETWEEN HEAD AND BLOCK</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    of this bulletin for description of causes.)
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="6">
            <title>INSPECTION PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Visually inspect engine for leaks at coolant hoses, power steering hoses, injection pump, high/low
                pressure fuel lines and all cover/gasket areas that seal fluids or coolant.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect drain pan plug at rear of intake manifold valley pan to verify it is open. A clogged plug
                allows fluids to accumulate in vee of engine and eventually spill over at the rear of the engine.
            </para>
            <para>Closely inspect the following areas that contribute to coolant leaks on the engine: (Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212051">Figure 1</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212052">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212053">Figure 3</hotlnk>.)
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Upper radiator hose at thermostat housing and top tank</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Thermostat housing mounting gasket</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Heater supply hose at right front cylinder head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Heater return hose at water pump housing</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Coolant fill line hose at coolant inlet</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Deaeration tank</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Deaeration hose of air compressor coolant supply line left front of crankcase</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>At coolant sensors mounted in cylinder head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Water pump</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Any unused pipe plug locations on cylinder heads and water pump housing</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cup plugs in ends of cylinder heads.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f9212051" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212051.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Areas That Contribute to Coolant Leaks on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9212052" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212052.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Areas That Contribute to Coolant Leaks on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9212053" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212053.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Areas That Contribute to Coolant Leaks on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Closely inspect the following areas that contribute to oil seepage/leakage on engine: (Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212054">Figure 4</hotlnk>,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212055">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212056">Figure 6.</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Valve cover gaskets</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Oil pressure gauge supply line and/or sender</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspection pump drive gear/access cover</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low oil pressure warning switch and piping</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Intake manifold valley pan to crankcase mounting front and rear</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Power steering pump reservoir and/or hoses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air compressor mounting gasket</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air compressor oil drain quad seal ring on cylinder head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air compressor oil supply line</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>1/8 inch Allen head pipe plugs that intersect with oil drain holes in cylinder heads</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>C.D.R. valve and/or hoses</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Clogged/restricted valley pan drain plug</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Spillage of oil, fuel and other fluids during normal service intervals.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f9212054" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212054.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Areas That Contribute to Oil Seepage/Leakage on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9212055" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212055.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Areas That Contribute to Oil Seepage/Leakage on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9212056" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212056.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Areas That Contribute to Oil Seepage/Leakage on Engine</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Returned material analysis as well as on-site investigations has indicated that head gaskets
                        are being inadvertently replaced due to leaks at the aforementioned locations.
                    </para>
                    <para>Since the head gasket is very seldom the cause of leak concerns, it is recommended that a
                        thorough cleaning of the engine and/or suspected area should be performed in order to ascertain
                        the location and/or cause of the concern prior to any head gasket replacement.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="x9212051" svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="1">
            <title>BLOWING BUBBLES BETWEEN HEAD AND BLOCK</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9212057">Figure 7</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>The cause of these bubbles has been identified as engine oil, diesel fuel, power steering fluid and
                glycol/antifreeze. Any spillage or leakage of these fluids on the engine will drain along the head
                gasket joint and will be trapped at the edge of the gasket material. On a cold engine, the bubbles may
                not be evident. During engine operation small soap-like bubbles develop and burst due to heat and joint
                motion. The higher the engine speed the more rapid this bubbling occurs.
            </para>
            <para>This phenomenon is caused by joint motion between cylinder head and crankcase and requires an external
                source of fluids.
            </para>
            <para>Engineering testing and examination of these gaskets reveals that no combustion gases have escaped the
                combustion seals of these gaskets.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9212057" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9212057.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Bubbles Between Head and Block</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
