<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 92-14-01 - Checking Power Divider Input Shaft End Play, Forward Rear Axle</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi921401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>92-14-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1992</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>REAR AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Checking Power Divider Input Shaft End Play, Forward Rear Axle</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>14GDA</ucode>
                <ucode>14GDC</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to Models with Codes 14GDA and 14GDC Tandem Single Reduction Rear Axles.</para>
                <para>Spicer Heavy Axle and Brake Division of Dana Corporation is recommending that checking the end
                    play of the power divider input shaft be made part of the standard maintenance procedures for Codes
                    14GDA and 14GDC rear axles. Whenever the vehicle is serviced, the axle input shaft should be
                    visually checked for excessive end play. A leaking input shaft may be the first indication of
                    excessive end play. Input shaft end play should be measured every 100,000 miles.
                </para>
                <para>Power dividers are assembled with 1 to 5 thousandths (.001 to .005) inch of end play when new. If
                    the input shaft end play measures 25 thousandths (.025) inch at 100,000 miles, it will be necessary
                    to reshim the unit. Refer to TSI-89-14-02, dated June, 1989 for the proper end play measuring and
                    shimming procedures.
                </para>
                <para>The 14GDA and 14GDC rear axle design used the side gears and pinion mates of the inter-axle
                    differential to establish input shaft end play. As these components wear under normal usage, the end
                    play will increase slightly. This increase in end play is not detrimental to vehicle operation,
                    unless it is excessive.
                </para>
                <para>If the end play exceeds 25 thousandths (.025) inch in less than 100,000 miles, it is possible the
                    inter-axle differential components are wearing excessively, and inspection is recommended. If
                    necessary to replace the inter-axle differential, use kit part number 1665307C91.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The inter-axle differential can be removed and replaced without removing the intermediate
                            differential housing.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following procedures should be used to remove and install the inter-axle differential. For
                    more detailed instructions for repairing the rear axle assembly, refer to GROUP 14-REAR AXLE in
                    CTS-4001 or CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the driveshaft at the forward axle input yoke.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>It is not necessary to remove the input yoke or drain the gear lube at this time.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove bolts attaching input bearing retainer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove input shaft, yoke and front cover as a unit. Slots are provided for ease of
                    removal.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If axle is equipped with a lube pump, it must be removed to access removal slots.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove inter-axle differential shift cylinder, snap ring and spring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a 10-inch pipe wrench to remove shift shaft from shift fork.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove shift fork, clutch collar and helical drive gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a suitable pry bar, remove metal lube retainer plate (slinger) and discard.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove inter-axle differential assembly and inspect for excessive wear. If excessive
                    wear is indicated, replace inter-axle differential. If no wear is indicated thoroughly clean and
                    inspect for reassembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove any wear particles from inter-axle differential cavity in the power divider case.
                    Clean RTV sealastic from mating surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean all components for reassembly.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 10-LUBRICATION in CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for lubrication information.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prelube and install inter-axle differential assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the proper installation tool to install a new metal lube retainer plate.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate and install the helical drive gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply grease to the machined surface on the drive gear that contacts the large thrust
                    washer. Install thrust washer with chamfer forward.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide shift fork into clutch collar groove with the raised section of fork forward.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fork and collar assembly into position with lugs engaged into the mating lugs on
                    the drive gear.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thread the shift shaft into the fork. Use a 10-inch pipe wrench to tighten the shaft to
                    approximately 35 ft. lbs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install spring, snap ring and shift cylinder.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a 1/8-inch bead of RTV gasket material to the input bearing retainer mating
                    surface.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install input shaft, bearing retainer and end yoke assembly into the power divider.
                    Rotate the end yoke slowly while installing to help align input shaft splines with the mating
                    splines in the inter-axle differential.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Bolt bearing retainer to the inter-axle differential housing. Evenly tighten the bolts
                    to 70 ft. lbs. torque.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check input shaft end play. Refer to TSI-89-14-02 for the proper procedure.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the end play is within .001 to .005 inch, it will not be necessary to reshim the
                    input shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the input shaft end play is over .005 inch, the input shaft must be shimmed. Refer to
                    TSI-89-14-02 for the proper procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install driveshaft, air line to the air shift cylinder. Check and fill axle to proper
                    lube level if necessary. Refer to GROUP 10-LUBRICATION.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the end yoke is removed to install a new seal, re-install the end yoke washer and nut.
                        Tighten the nut to 900 to 1200 ft. lbs.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
