<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-02-01R - Tie Rod and Drag Link End Inspection Information</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi930201R" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-02-01R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>93-02-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>November, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Tie Rod and Drag Link End Inspection Information</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The tie rod and drag link end inspection information that is in CTS-5027K in GROUP 02 STEERING
                    GENERAL SERVICE INFORMATION AND WHEEL ALIGNMENT section in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual is
                    being modified. It is suggested that you modify page 6 of CTS-5027K Service Manual Section in your
                    Master Service Manual as follows:
                </para>
                <figure id="f9302011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9302011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Check Tie Rod and Drag Link End Movement</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>A. MOVEMENT IN AXIAL DIRECTION</callout1>
                        <callout1>B. TORQUE TO ROTATE SOCKET</callout1>
                        <callout1>1. TIE ROD/DRAG LINK END</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. STEERING ARM OR PITMAN ARM</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Replacement Criteria - Tie rod and drag link ends must be free to rotate within
                        the ball socket. Replace the tie rod or drag link end if there is movement as described below in
                        the axial direction when checking BY HAND on the vehicle.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>If axial movement of 1/8 inch (3.175 mm) or less is found
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9302011">Figure 1</hotlnk>, the tie rod or drag link end(s) should be replaced at
                    the next service interval.
                </para>
                <para>If 1/8 inch (3.175 mm) or more axial movement is found, the vehicle should not be driven (taken
                    out of service) until after replacement of the tie rod and/or drag link end(s) is completed.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not pry on the steering linkage with a bar as damage to the steering linkage may
                            result.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>An alternate method of evaluating the tie rod and drag link ends is by rotating the ball stud with
                    the stud removed from the steering and pitman arms. The torque (force) required to rotate the stud
                    in the end cap should be at least 5.0 to 250.0 in-lbs (depending on ball joint design/manufacturer).
                </para>
                <para>If the tie rod/drag link taper joint is loose or the cotter pin is missing, remove, inspect and
                    replace the components if the contact surface is worn.
                </para>
                <para>For additional information, view the video titled CHECK IT OUT (#TCN-90355) that is available from
                    Westmont.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
