<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-04-02 - Information Concerning Fluoroelastomers (FKM) - VITON, FLUOREL, AFLAS</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi930402" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-04-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Information Concerning Fluoroelastomers (FKM) - VITON, FLUOREL, AFLAS</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar is using Fluoroelastomers (FKM) in O-rings, gaskets and seals in power train and air
                    brake applications requiring high-temperature performance and fluid resistance. More applications
                    are being added everyday as customers' requirements are demanding longer life parts with lower
                    service requirements. Navistar recently released a new heavy duty wheel seal utilizing FKM that will
                    far outlast any existing wheel seal.
                </para>
                <para>FKM is a premium material both in performance and cost. Component design requirements are
                    carefully studied to assure that the correct material is specified for a given application. When
                    used under design conditions, FKM is safe and justified. However, if exposed to temperatures of 600&#176;F
                    (316&#176;C) or greater, FKM may decompose and the formation of hydrofluoric acid (HF) may occur. HF
                    can be highly corrosive to human tissue if not handled properly. Navistar application of
                    fluoroelastomers do not result in exposure to temperatures of 600&#176;F (316&#176;C) or higher in
                    operation or service.
                </para>
                <para>FKM is often a brown rubber in O-rings and seals to differentiate it from other materials, but it
                    can be any color, including black.
                    <emph type="bold">HF WILL APPEAR AS A CLEAR LIQUID ON OR ADJACENT TO THE RUBBER MATERIAL.</emph>The
                    following precautions should be followed when handling FKM parts suspected of being contaminated
                    with HF.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>WARNING WHEN HANDLING FKM PARTS EXPOSED TO EXCESSIVELY HIGH TEMPERATURES</para>
                        <para>DO NOT TOUCH EITHER THE SEAL OR SURROUNDING EQUIPMENT WITHOUT WEARING NEOPRENE OR PVC
                            GLOVES IF DECOMPOSITION OR THE PRESENCE OF HF IS SUSPECTED. A decomposed seal may appear as
                            charred or a black sticky mass. HF may condense as a clear liquid on the part or equipment.
                            ALLOW THE EQUIPMENT TO COOL. Then wear neoprene or heavy PVC gloves to safely handle parts
                            or equipment. Wash parts and equipment well with 10 percent limewater (calcium hydroxide
                            solution) to neutralize any hydrogen fluoride. Discard gloves after handling decomposed FKM
                            parts.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">FIRST AID:</emph>Wash affected areas of the skin
                    <emph type="bold">IMMEDIATELY</emph>with plenty of water. Then rub a 2.5% calcium gluconate gel into
                    skin until there is no further irritation.
                    <emph type="bold">SEEK PROMPT MEDICAL ATTENTION.</emph>Tell the doctor that a hydrogen fluoride (HF
                    or hydrofluoric acid) burn is suspected.
                </para>
                <para>FKM's used in Navistar products are safe in the normal service environment.</para>
                <para>To obtain additional information, the following vendor technical services may be contacted.</para>
                <verbatim>
                    <line>Dupont Emergency Medical Service: 1-800-441-3637</line>
                    <line>3M Technical Service: 612-733-5353</line>
                </verbatim>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
