<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-04-04 - Hydraulic Disc Brake Caliper Piston Condition</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi930404" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-04-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Hydraulic Disc Brake Caliper Piston Condition</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with Hydraulic Brakes.</para>
                <para>Disc brake pad wear should be checked as part of the preventative maintenance service and
                    inspection or at least every 10,000 miles under normal operating conditions; more frequently under
                    severe service conditions.
                </para>
                <para>During disc pad replacement, all wheel end brake components and mountings should be thoroughly
                    inspected and all needed repairs performed before new disc pads are installed.
                </para>
                <para>Calipers should be rebuilt if the piston shows extensive damage (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9304043">Figure 3</hotlnk>), the seal boot has failed or is damaged, or if the
                    piston is sticking in the bore. If the boot has failed, the piston seal surface may become pitted or
                    corroded.
                </para>
                <para></para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="3">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <para>Some vehicles have phenolic (dark colored nonmetallic material) caliper pistons. It is important that
                these pistons be inspected for cracks, chips or gouges in the area that passes through the piston seal
                whenever the brake pads are replaced.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9304041">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                illustrates a phenolic piston that is in good condition and may be re-used.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9304041" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9304041.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Phenolic Piston</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>No cracks, chips, gouges or any other damage which would contact the seal is allowed on the piston
                O.D.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9304042">Figure 2</hotlnk>illustrates mechanical damage to the face of the piston. The
                metal insert is intact.
            </para>
            <para>Cracks, chips and gouges may not extend into the piston seal area. The piston seal area is the area
                below the metal heat shield.
            </para>
            <para>This piston can be re-used.</para>
            <figure id="f9304042" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9304042.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Mechanical Damaged Piston</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The phenolic piston in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9304043">Figure 3</hotlnk>shows excessive heat damage to the end of the piston that is
                in contact with the brake pad. The metal insert on the open end of the piston is also missing.
            </para>
            <para>A piston in this condition should not be re-used.</para>
            <figure id="f9304043" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9304043.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Heat Damaged Piston</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PISTON INSTALLATION</title>
            <para>Use a wire brush to remove any rust from the exposed end of the piston. Lubricate piston, seal and
                caliper bore with clean brake fluid. Assure that the seal is fully seated. Position dust boot and insert
                piston in bore. Apply firm steady pressure to piston, and guide it through the piston seal until
                bottomed in the caliper housing. Avoid using a C-clamp or pliers to compress piston. If strong
                resistance is felt, remove the piston and inspect the piston seal installation.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>NOISE SUPPRESSION</title>
            <para>A common complaint of disc brakes is brake "squeal". Metal to metal contact along with vibration are
                the most common causes. No rotor is perfectly true; so as the rotor turns, the brake pads vibrate.
                Contact between the metal backing plate of the brake pad against the piston creates a high pitched
                squeal.
            </para>
            <para>Before installing the brake pads, coat the backside of the pad plates with a 1/16-inch coat of liquid
                Disc Brake Quiet, Part # ZDEM6-04. Allow 20-30 minutes curing time if room temperature is above 72
                degrees. Allow longer curing time for temperatures below 72 degrees.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
