<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-08-03 - Troubleshooting Procedures for On-Off Engine Fan Control Circuits</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi930803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Troubleshooting Procedures for On-Off Engine Fan Control Circuits</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>This service letter applies only to "normally closed" circuit designs.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <para>Many engine fan control circuits used on International vehicles incorporate a solid state
                        electronic fan temperature control switch which provides excellent temperature control.
                        International uses a "normally closed" circuit design to assure that failure in this circuit
                        will cause the fan to come on, thus protecting the engine from overheating.
                        <emph type="bold">Because the switch is electronic, it cannot be continuity tested in the normal
                            manner. In fact, depending on the method used, such testing could cause a good switch to
                            fail.
                        </emph>
                        Attached are step-by-step procedures a technician should use to determine the root cause of a
                        fan control program. The circuit shown is for 9200 through 9400 models. Circuits for other
                        models are similar.
                    </para>
                    <para>Please note that International recently changed to a 3-wire fan temperature control switch
                        which replaces the former 2-wire switch. The third wire is a ground wire which replaces the case
                        ground of the former 2-wire switch. If replacing a 2-wire switch with a 3-wire switch, connect
                        the eyelet on the new ground wire under a suitable bolt, making sure the surfaces have been
                        cleaned of paint, corrosion, etc. to provide a good ground. The part number of the new 3-wire
                        switch is 1684560C92. It is a 205&#176;F switch and can be used in all former 200&#176;F and 195&#176;F
                        applications.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <title>NORMAL CONDITIONS</title>
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fan engages when engine temperature reaches approximately 205&#176;F and remains on
                                until coolant temperature has been reduced about 10&#176;F.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Fan engages whenever the air conditioning refrigerant pressure exceeds 300 psi and
                                remains on until pressure drops below 210 psi.
                                <emph type="bold">NOTE: This function is controlled by a mechanical pressure switch
                                    installed in the high pressure refrigerant line near the refrigerant compressor.
                                </emph>
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>In moderately hot weather, the fan will cycle on and off about three to four times per
                                minute if the vehicle is idling with the air conditioning ON.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>In very hot weather, the fan will run continuously if the air conditioning is ON.
                            </para>
                            <para>Consult the Troubleshooting Chart (
                                <hotlnk xrefid="t9308031">Table 1</hotlnk>) for other conditions.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <table id="t9308031" frame="all">
                        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING CHART</title>
                        <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                            <colspec colwidth="2.17in"/>
                            <colspec colwidth="2.08in"/>
                            <colspec colwidth="2.38in"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                        <para>
                                            <emph type="bold">Condition</emph>
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                        <para>
                                            <emph type="bold">Possible Cause</emph>
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                        <para>
                                            <emph type="bold">Solution</emph>
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>1. Fan runs all the time with the air conditioning off and the engine
                                            coolant temperature below 195&#176;F to 205&#176;F.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Possible electrical control system fault.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Refer to troubleshooting flow chart and repair or replace as necessary.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>2. Fan won't cycle when vehicle is idling with the air conditioning ON.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Outside air temperature is too low, there is a low refrigerant charge, or
                                            the refrigerant pressure switch is faulty.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Check air conditioning system; replace pressure switch if required.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>3. Engine overheating; fan doesn't engage when the engine temperature
                                            exceeds 205&#176;F.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Fan drive, air solenoid valve, or related air lines may be faulty.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Repair or replace as necessary.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry morerows="2" valign="top">
                                        <para>4. Fan runs all the time with the air conditioning ON.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>This is normal in extremely hot weather.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Spraying water on the condenser should temporarily turn off the fan.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>-</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Air conditioning system may be overcharged or the condenser is covered
                                            with debris.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Check air conditioning system.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>
                                        <para>-</para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Pressure switch may have drifted out of calibration. Use service gauge to
                                            verify that the fan engages when pressure is approximately 300 psi and turns
                                            off when the pressure drops below 210 psi.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Replace pressure switch.</para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>5. Fan cycles frequently when vehicle is stationary with the air
                                            conditioning ON.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para>Up to 4 fan cycles per minute is a normal condition in moderately hot
                                            weather. Turning off the air conditioning system should cause the cycling to
                                            stop.
                                        </para>
                                    </entry>
                                    <entry valign="top">
                                        <para></para>
                                    </entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
                    <para>DIAGNOSTIC FLOW CHART FOR FAN CONTROL CIRCUITS.</para>
                    <para>See
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9308031">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9308032">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9308031" figsize="full-pg">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9308031.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Diagnostic Flow Chart For Fan Control Circuits</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f9308032" figsize="full-pg">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9308032.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Diagnostic Flow Chart For Fan Control Circuits (Cont.)</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9308033">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9308034">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                for the following steps.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Ignition key off. Disconnect connector 227 at the fan solenoid (part number 1689785C91).
                    Measure the resistance of the solenoid, connecting the ohmmeter "common" lead to the black wire of
                    the solenoid and the "positive" lead to the red wire (with some ohmmeters, measuring backwards will
                    result in a false reading due to the internal solenoid diode). Replace solenoid if coil resistance
                    is greater than 30 ohms or less than 10 ohms. Also measure resistance between each wire and the
                    metal housing of the solenoid. Replace solenoid if resistance to housing is less than 10,000 ohms.
                    If any reading is less than 8 ohms, also replace fan temperature control switch. AVOID USING 12
                    VOLTS TO TEST THE SOLENOID TO PREVENT POSSIBLE DAMAGE TO THE INTERNAL DIODE. Also check to be sure
                    the red wire of the solenoid is connected to circuit 23D. CONNECTING THE SOLENOID WIRES BACKWARDS
                    WILL CAUSE THE TEMPERATURE SWITCH TO FAIL AND POSSIBLY THE SOLENOID AS WELL.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Perform the following steps with the ignition key ON, the engine OFF, and connector
                    227 disconnected. Engine coolant temperature must be below 190&#176;F.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for 12 volts in circuit 23 at connector 237. If not present, check circuit 23 for
                    open or short. Check fuse/circuit breaker and check for 12 volts to the fuse/circuit breaker from
                    key switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for 12 volts in circuit 23C at connector 228. If not present, check circuit 23C
                    for open or short. If circuit 23C is okay, replace fan temperature switch.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for 12 volts in circuit 23D at connector 227. If not present, check circuit 23D
                    for open or short. If circuit 23D is okay, replace refrigerant pressure switch.
                </para>
                <para>Vehicles equipped with a 460 HP, 3406 Cat. PEEC III will have a Normally Closed (NC) Intake
                    Temperature Switch located between the refrigerant switch and the fan solenoid (circuit 23D in and
                    23E out).
                </para>
                <para>This switch opens at 149&#176;F (65&#176;C) and closes at 138&#176;F (57&#176;C).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Measure resistance in circuit 23GB between connector 227 and ground. If greater than 1
                    ohm, repair ground circuit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn ignition off. Re-connect connector 227. Cycle ignition switch on and off and listen
                    for proper operation of solenoid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no electrical problems are found, perform the following:</para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Check air lines to fan drive for proper orientation and assure there are no
                            restrictions.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Check fan clutch for proper operation.</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9308033" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9308033.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9308034" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9308034.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
