<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-12-02 - The Use of Propylene Glycol Antifreeze</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931202" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-12-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>The Use of Propylene Glycol Antifreeze</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI describes the use of Propylene Glycol Antifreeze in all vehicle engines (except Detroit
                    Diesel).
                </para>
                <para>There has been some interest in and questions asked about the use of propylene glycol antifreeze
                    (PG) in Navistar vehicles, especially the mixing of PG with ethylene glycol (EG), the antifreeze put
                    in the cooling system of Navistar vehicles during production. There is no detrimental effect on the
                    cooling system or system performance if PG is put in the cooling system or if EG and PG are mixed.
                    However, the following information shows why it is not recommended that PG antifreeze be mixed with
                    EG antifreeze.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>The freeze protection measuring devices will not give the right answers if the two types
                            of antifreeze are mixed. The bubble tube measuring device is not suitable. If a dual scale
                            refractometer is used, the average of the PG and EG readings will give a measurement of the
                            protection level of the antifreeze mixture that may be as much as 7 degrees off.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The freeze protection of PG is slightly inferior to EG, but should not be a problem except
                            in borderline conditions.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Adding EG to PG will increase toxicity. However,
                            <emph type="bold">USED ANTIFREEZE OF ANY TYPE SHOULD BE DISPOSED OF IN ACCORDANCE WITH
                                APPLICABLE FEDERAL AND LOCAL REGULATIONS.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>Corrosion protection additives are similar for both EG and PG antifreezes; therefore, test
                            kits suitable for EG will work with PG. The test kit should be matched to the type of
                            supplemental coolant additive used: Fleetrite kit with Fleetrite filters and Liquid SCA,
                            etc.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>During the first two years after the vehicle is manufactured, the coolant system will most likely
                    be filled with EG and it is recommended that EG be added to the system when required, as a mixture
                    of EG and PG will create the above conditions.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
