<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-13-08 - Allison Automatic Transmission Operation With Viscous Fan Drive</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931308" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-13-08</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>November, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Allison Automatic Transmission Operation With Viscous Fan Drive</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Allison</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with Allison transmissions.</para>
                <para>All International medium duty vehicle engines are equipped with viscous fan drives. The operating
                    principle of this drive is to sense air temperature via a bi-metal sensor to activate an internal
                    valve that allows the viscous fluid to engage the clutch mechanism. This causes the fan speed to
                    increase as coolant temperature rises and decreases as it lowers. This speed increase/decrease can
                    be quite abrupt.
                </para>
                <para>Therefore, it is possible, under certain operating conditions (load/grade demand), for the
                    transmission to downshift as the fan engages. This condition is normal and should not be confused
                    with a transmission shifting complaint/concern.
                </para>
                <para>The fan noise resulting from the full engagement of the fan in combination with the increase of
                    engine speed when the engine downshifts has tricked some drivers into thinking that the transmission
                    has shifted into neutral or is slipping excessively.
                </para>
                <para>Please be aware of this possibility and explain this operating principle to the customer. Major
                    transmission disassembly and/or replacement work or fan drive replacement will not change the
                    vehicle operation.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
