<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-16-02 - Process To Remove Tiny Rust Spots From Painted Surfaces</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931602" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-16-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Process To Remove Tiny Rust Spots From Painted Surfaces</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>In today's environment, it's not unusual for vehicles to develop tiny rust spots (see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316021">Figure 1</hotlnk>)on the horizontal surfaces. These usually come from
                    microscopic metallic particles that can come from numerous sources of industrial fallout. Typically
                    this is surface rust and has come from particles lying on the painted surface and may appear on
                    either the cab or the fiberglass hood. This results in oxidation which can stain the surface of the
                    clearcoat. Upon close examination, a small black dot often appears in the center of the spot. This
                    is the offending material that is causing the oxidation.
                </para>
                <para>Navistar has tested and approved the following procedure that can effectively remove this
                    unsightly spotting.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9316021" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9316021.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Rust Spots</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PROCESS</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury, wear eye protection, rubber gloves and protective clothing. Follow
                        manufacturer's recommended application.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the vehicle to remove unwanted dirt and dust, then proceed as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mix Finish Kare #1119 Soil and Coating Remover, 1 part #1119 to 4 parts of
                        <emph type="bold">COLD</emph>water.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Use a clean wash mitt and apply the mixture to areas where rust spots have occurred.
                        Keep the surface wet for 5 to 10 minutes.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>DO NOT allow the mixture to dry or streak down the side of the vehicle.</para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rinse with cold water.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make sure the vehicle is clean and dry.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using a dry wash mitt or sponge, apply Finish Kare #833 Rust Remover directly to the
                        surface, one panel at a time.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Keep the area wet for up to 5 minutes.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the surface with a strong jet of water to completely remove the particles.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the particles are not completely removed, repeat steps 1 and 2.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the iron particles are removed, apply Finish Kare #118SC Liquid Neutralizer
                    Concentrate Shampoo or equivalent. This is required to neutralize the removal action.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mix the concentrate as 1 part concentrate to 100 parts water.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Apply the neutralizer shampoo with a mitt or sponge.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rinse with clean water.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The neutralizer concentrate is a heavy duty shampoo.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If fine scratches appear on the surface, use an available aftermarket light "finishing"
                    compound with a foam pad to remove scratches.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Polish as necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>FINISH KARE PRODUCTS</title>
            </para>
            <para>Finish Kare products are marketed by mobile distributors which will deliver the products directly to
                your dealership. If a Finish Kare distributor is not located in your area, Finish Kare can be contacted
                at the address and phone number below for direct shipment from their national office. In case of direct
                shipment, a product training video and manual will be provided with the shipment.
            </para>
            <verbatim>
                <line>Finish Kare Products, Inc.</line>
                <line>1726 Floradale Ave</line>
                <line>El Monte, CA 91733</line>
                <line>Phone: (213) 686-0462</line>
            </verbatim>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
