<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-16-05 - Shrader Valves and Standard SAE Metric Charging Ports on Air Conditioning Systems Charged
        With HFC-134a
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931605" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-16-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Shrader Valves and Standard SAE Metric Charging Ports on Air Conditioning Systems Charged With
                HFC-134a
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with air conditioning charged with HFC-134a.</para>
                <para>The shrader valve ports located near the compressor on the high pressure side of air conditioning
                    systems charged with HFC-134a (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316051">Figure 1</hotlnk>) are for switch installation, NOT FOR CHARGING OR
                    DISCHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM. International has continued to use shrader fittings for
                    installation of switches on air conditioning compressor to allow the use of the same switches for
                    air conditioning systems charged with HFC-134a and R-12. This was done to help standardize air
                    conditioning components and keep from having additional part numbers.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9316051" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9316051.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Typical Fan Drive and/or Radiator Shutter Override Switch Installation on
                        Vehicles Built with HFC-134a
                    </caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. FAN DRIVE OR SHUTTER OVERRIDE SWITCH</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. SAE-METRIC QUICK DISCONNECT SERVICE PORTS ON THE COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. AC COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. SHRADER VALVE - OPTIONAL SWITCH LOCATION</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
                <para>The service ports on air conditioning systems charged with HFC-134a are STANDARD SAE METRIC QUICK
                    DISCONNECT fittings located on the compressor (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316051">Figure 1</hotlnk>), on the receiver/dryer, under the right side of the
                    dash panel on 2000, 4000 and 8000 models and under the right side cab floor on 5000 and 9000 Series
                    vehicles. These are the only fittings that are to be used to charge or discharge the air
                    conditioning system.
                </para>
                <para>The manifold gauge set hose ends are different for each type of refrigerant (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316052">Figure 2)</hotlnk>. The hose ends on manifold gauge hoses for R-12 have
                    internal threads to fit shrader fittings (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316052">Figure 2</hotlnk>). They will not work on HFC-134a charged systems because
                    the manifold gauge hose ends have metric quick disconnect fittings, along with a valve (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316052">Figure 2</hotlnk>), that will work only on systems charged with HFC-134a.
                </para>
                <para>Also, it is important that R-12 and HFC-134a refrigerants not be mixed when discharging to a
                    recycling station or charging either type system. Each type of refrigerant must have its own
                    dedicated recycling and charging station. That is one of the reasons for the different types of hose
                    fittings on manifold gauge sets for the two refrigerants.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9316052" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9316052.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Manifold Service Hose Set</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If there is a shrader fitting on the compressor of an HFC-134a charged air conditioning
                            system that is not being used and is capped off, it is not suitable for servicing the system
                            because it is on the high pressure side. There is no low pressure side shrader valve to use
                            to set up a manifold gauge set.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">It is very important</emph>
                    that service personnel who service air conditioning systems on International vehicles become
                    familiar with the latest service manual sections pertaining to air conditioning. The latest version
                    of these sections include information on servicing HFC-134a. They are:
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>CTS-5062J - Air Conditioning Basic Theory and Service</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>CTS-5068J - Air Conditioning - Compressor and Clutch (2cyl)</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>CTS-5069 - Air Conditioning System - 2000, 4000, 8000</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>CTS-5070 - Air Conditioning system - 5000, 9000</para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
                <para>TSI-92-16-07, circulated in October 1992, contains information related to the differences between
                    air conditioning systems that use R-12 and HFC-134a refrigerant. Precautions and changes in service
                    procedures and tools are also covered.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
