<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-16-04 - Air Conditioning Drip Tray</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931604" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-16-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Air Conditioning Drip Tray</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to 2000, 4000, and 8000 Series vehicles with air conditioning.</para>
                <para>The air conditioning drip tray in some 2000, 4000 and 8000 Models may be mounted incorrectly,
                    causing the tray to become twisted, allowing water to drip onto the floor of the cab. If this
                    condition exists, the following procedure will correct the condition.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the screws that hold the lower right instrument panel in place, and remove the
                    panel along with the drip tray. On the backside of the panel are two pins molded into the panel.
                    These two pins go into two holes on the edge of the air conditioning drip tray. The tray is held in
                    place by a tinnerman clip on each pin. The reason the drip tray twists out of shape which allows
                    water to drip on the cab floor is because the two holes in the edge of the drip pan are located
                    incorrectly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a pair of side cutter pliers to cut the tinnerman clip on each pin at its narrowest
                    part. Carefully remove the tinnerman clips from the pins because rough handling may cause the pins
                    to break off.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the tray and drill a new 1/4 inch hole, 1/2 inch to the left of each hole in the
                    edge of the tray. (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316041">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Handle the instrument panel with care while positioning the two pins in the new holes in
                    the tray because rough handling may cause the pin(s) to break off. Carefully secure the tray on the
                    pins with new tinnerman clips, Pt# 146327R1
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the drain end of the tray through the hole in the dash. Secure the instrument
                    panel with the screws removed in step 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>If after removal, the drip tray is badly deformed, it may be necessary to replace it. Order a new
                tray, Pt# 581673C3, from Service Parts. The holes in the edge of the new tray will not have to be
                relocated.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9316041" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9316041.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Relocate Holes In Tray</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
