<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-16-09 - Repair Water Leaks on Second Generation Bentz Sleeper Boxes</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931609" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-16-09</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Repair Water Leaks on Second Generation Bentz Sleeper Boxes</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bentz</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/04/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/04/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/04/1993</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar began building 9200, 9300 and 9400 models equipped with the "2nd Generation Bentz"
                    sleeper boxes starting on 01/04/93. This new family of sleeper boxes includes 48 inch flat roof
                    (codes 16SBE, 16SBG or 16SBH), 60 inch flat roof (codes 16SBJ, 16SBK or 16SBL), and 60 inch
                    Cantilever (code 16SBM).
                </para>
                <para>Complaints of water leaking into the sleeper box, received on the initial production of these
                    boxes, has prompted Navistar to initiate a program of inspection, repair and water testing intended
                    to minimize customer dissatisfaction.
                </para>
                <para>When a sleeper box water leak complaint is received, the following items and areas need to be
                    inspected and repaired as needed: Repair instructions are furnished under SERVICE PROCEDURES.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
            <title>INSPECTION</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Presence of polyurethane foam in the six corners of the bottom of the sleeper box. Some boxes
                        may have gray sealer in these areas which is acceptable and does not require foam.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Visible gaps or voids in the sealer between the box skin and the tool box door and between the
                        box skin and the exit door frames.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Visible gaps or voids in the sealer at the perimeter of the top of the box both above and
                        below the drip rail and at the top and bottom of the back panel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Visible gaps or voids in the sealer at the perimeter of the top of the box both above and
                        below the drip rail and at the top and bottom of the back panel.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Presence of the 8 or 10 plastic plugs (under the rubber mat) in the floor of the box.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Proper sealing of the tool box and exit doors.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Sealer between the plastic 7-way electrical socket and the rear of the sleeper box.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Sealer between the 5th wheel lights and the rear of the sleeper box.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>MATERIAL REQUIRED</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Clear sealer to be used is a non-silicone latex sealer.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>GEOCEL "PRO-FLEX" or "WATER SHIELD". Part Number 2643819R1 is available through PDC. It is
                        also available at Ace or True Value Hardware Stores.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>12 oz. container foam fill insulation. Fomo Products "Handi Foam" or equivalent polyurethane
                        foam which can be obtained from local hardware/lumber yards, or call 1-216-753-4585.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>3/16 inch diameter aluminum blind head rivet, Part Number 403061-C1, Quantity 6.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Upholstery tack dry type glue or contact cement.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for the presence of polyurethane foam in all six corners of the underbody of the
                    sleeper box. Some boxes may have gray sealer in these areas which is acceptable and does not require
                    foam. If the foam is not present repair as follows:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for visible gaps or voids in the sealer between the box skin and the frame of
                    both the tool box and exit door (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316091">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9316091" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9316091.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Applying Foam To Underbody</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. SEAL FRONT RADIUS OF UNDERBODY WITH CLEAR SEALER-SKIN TO FLOOR AT RADIUS AND 3 HOLES,
                        BOTH SIDES.
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>FOAM UNDERBODY - USE "HANDI FOAM" (POLYURETHANE) OR EQUIVALENT.
                        <callout2>FOAM 6 INDIVIDUAL CORNER IN SIDE POSTS - 3 EACH SIDE</callout2>
                        <callout2>FOAM BOTH FRONT ROUNDED CORNERS. INSERT FOAM NOZZLE IN 1/2 INCH HOLE AT UNDERBODY -
                            BOTH SIDES OF BOX (SEE NOTE BELOW)
                        </callout2>
                        <callout2>FOAM CUTOUTS BELOW EACH DOOR - BOTH SIDES</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>KNIFE CUT EXCESS FOAM EXTENDING BELOW BOTTOM OF BOX.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When completed, foam may extend from inboard of rear corner post along each side, around front
                        corner and inboard of front center corner post.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for visible gaps or voids in the sealer at the top of the box above and below
                    drip rail and at the top and bottom of the back pane (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9316092">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9316092" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9316092.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Applying Sealer To Top Of Box And Back Panel</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>*1. SEAL OUTSIDE PERIMETER OF TOP OF BOX ABOVE AND BELOW DRIP RAIL WITH CLEAR SEALER.
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>*2. SEAL GAPS AT BACK PANEL JOINTS - TOP AND BOTTOM OF BOX WITH CLEAR SEALER.</callout1>
                    <callout1>*3. SEAL AROUND PERIMETER OF BOTH DOOR FRAMES WITH CLEAR SEALER.</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SMOOTH/REMOVE EXCESS SEALER FOR COSMETIC APPEARANCE.</callout1>
                    <callout1>*Preferred method is to push the sealer gun along the joint to be sealed vs. pulling the
                        gun along the joint.
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for the proper installation of the 8 or 10 plastic filler plugs under the floor
                    mat in the box. Missing plugs must be replaced. If you do not have the proper size plugs in
                    inventory, duct tape can be used to cover the hole from the inside.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">(6) Plugs along rear sill.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">(2) Plugs - 1 at each front corner (may not be present on some boxes)</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">(2) Plugs under center of bunk.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for the proper sealing of both the tool box and exit rubber door seals for no
                    visible light between door and seal. Adjust the door (at the hinge), seal or bend the seal fence to
                    insure proper contact between the seal and the perimeter of the door. The seal should not contact
                    the door trim panel - particularly along the top edge of the door. If seal contacts the trim, water
                    may leak inside between the door and the trim panel. To repair:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">With the door closed, mark face of trim panel along bottom edge of seal with a
                        pencil to determine the amount of material to be removed to shorten the trim board.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the trim panel and measure area under the seal - from pencil mark to top of
                        trim panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Pull trim loose from back side of door trim and fold under.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Mark area to be removed from panel backing board and cut area being careful not to
                        damage face trim
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Spray Tack Dry Upholstery Glue or Contact Cement to back side of panel and restretch
                        trim material and stick edges to back side of panel.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Re-install door trim panel and check for interference to seal.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <para>The seal may need to be pulled away from the fence to insure contact with the door. The seal flange
                may also need to be straightened to eliminate the step in the flange.
            </para>
            <para>If the door seal is kinked in the corners the seal should be removed from the fence and re-installed
                in a different position so the same part of the seal is not in the corner.
            </para>
            <para>Clear sealer should be applied if there is a visible gap on the door frame seal fence at the butt
                joint. Remove the seal and apply sealer on the inside of the seal flange at the butt joint.
            </para>
            <para>The final fit and adjustment must insure that no light enters the sleeper box through the door to seal
                joint due to contact between the seal and the interior trim panel on the exit door.
            </para>
            <para>If the above items do not correct the door seal leaks, new seals may be required. Order from PDC. Part
                numbers are listed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="t9316091">Table 1</hotlnk>as follows:
            </para>
            <table id="t9316091" frame="all">
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Seals</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Access Door Seal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1516850C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Luggage Door Seal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1516851C1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The plastic 7-way socket should be removed and clear sealer applied on all sleeper boxes
                    on trucks built before June 1, 1993. Remove the seal around the large diameter of the connector body
                    and re-install with the original gasket. Also, apply sealer on the backside of the connector where
                    the ends of the cover springs protrude through the face of the connector. Apply sealer to the
                    threads of the bolts when re-installing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Both 5th wheel lights should be removed and clear sealer applied between the light
                    housing and the back panel of the sleeper box on all trucks built before February 22, 1993.
                </para>
                <para>Drill out the three mounting rivets and apply a wide bead of clear sealer to the backside of the
                    light where the mounting flange and the housing meet.
                </para>
                <para>The bead of sealer should be within the inside diameter of the paper mounting gasket and should
                    result in a solid bead between the light housing and the back panel on the inside of the sleeper
                    box. Re-install the light using 3/16 inch blind head rivets.
                </para>
                <para>Sealer should also be installed between light lens and the light housing.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>WATER TESTING</title>
            <para>High pressure washing is recommended in order to assure that all the potential sources of water leaks
                have been corrected. After steps 1 thru 7 have been completed and any sealer which had been added has
                been allowed to cure (see instructions on sealer for cure time), the sleeper box must be tested for
                water leaks by high pressure washing.
            </para>
            <para>The interior of the sleeper box and tool box should then be thoroughly inspected for the presence of
                water. If water is found, the source of the leak must be identified and corrected. Additional high
                pressure washing should be performed to verify that the source of the leak has been corrected.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
