<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 93-17-01 - Hubcap for Oil Lubricated Wheel Bearing on Non-Driving Front Axles</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi931701" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>93-17-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 1993</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>WHEELS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Hubcap for Oil Lubricated Wheel Bearing on Non-Driving Front Axles</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models equipped with I-Beam Front Axles of 9,000 to 20,000 pounds
                    capacity.
                </para>
                <para>This letter contains information on the operation and maintenance International's hubcap (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9317011">Figure 1</hotlnk>) used with oil lubricated front wheel bearings on 9,000
                    to 20,000 pound non-driving front axles.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9317011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9317011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Front Hubcap</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <para>During normal vehicle duty cycle, the lube and air inside the hub/wheel cavity expands, and if not
                vented causes pressure build up in the wheel cavity, resulting in accelerated seal wear. The rubber plug
                in the center of the hubcap face has a slit in it to allow the pressure in the hub/wheel cavity to be
                maintained in an operating range that is not detrimental to seal life. Navistar uses the slit type of
                venting as it allows less contamination (moisture, dust, etc.) to get into the hub/wheel cavity during
                normal duty cycle, including chassis cleaning operations. As the air and oil expand, an oil/air mist is
                expelled through the vent. It is normal for a slight film of oil to be present on the outside of the
                hubcap around the vent slit (or hole in the case of non-standard Navistar hubcaps.)
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc id="clean" svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>MAINTENANCE</title>
            <para>Over a period of time, if the hubcap is not routinely cleaned, a slight film of oil can collect dirt
                around the rubber fill plug and face which could be perceived as a leak. Furthermore, routine cleaning
                ensures that the lube level can be easily observed through the clear window as intended.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use caution when cleaning the hubcap with a high pressure cleaner as cleaning fluid, water
                        and/or steam may be forced through the vent and contaminate the oil.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>In a case where the window is clear on the outside but discolored on the inside from the type of
                lubricant used, the lube level may be checked by removing the rubber check valve vent plug and inserting
                a finger through the hole in the face plate.
            </para>
            <para>The specified lube level for clear window type hubcaps on International vehicles is from the minimum
                line to 5/16 inch above the minimum line.
            </para>
            <para>If the lube level should suddenly drop below the minimum line between face wiping and lube level
                inspection intervals, it may serve as an indication of a leak somewhere in the system. If this should
                happen, take the following steps:
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the area around the gasket to determine if the gasket is leaking. A dry hubcap
                    and a wet area around the gasket indicates the gasket could be leaking or the hubcap mounting bolts
                    may be loose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check to be sure the mounting bolts are tight. Torque should be 16 to 20 ft. lbs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect for a leaking wheel seal.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the rubber vent for nicks or other damage that could cause leakage between the
                    rubber plug and the outer edge of the plug opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace defective parts as required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is no apparent leakage, add same lube used in hub to raise level to minimum
                    line
                    <emph type="bold">Do not exceed 5/16 inch above the minimum line.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If these steps do not reveal leakage, the hubcap can be pressure checked to determine if
                    it is leaking between the clear window and the aluminum body.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>LEAKAGE TEST PROCEDURES</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hubcap from vehicle and mount securely to a flat plate with silicone or
                    similar sealer between the hubcap mounting surface and the plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It is best to remove the hubcap from the vehicle before pressure checking. Air pressure inside
                        the hub could cause some wheel seals to move thus cause premature seal wear.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Thoroughly clean the hubcap and the area around the mounting surface with a hot
                    water/soap solution.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the threaded fill plug in the side of the hubcap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Screw an air line adapter into the fill plug hole. The standard International hubcap is
                    tapped with 3/8-18 NPTF threads.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a pressure regulator (1-10 PSI) and control valve to the adapter.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a soap and water solution to entire hubcap body and around mounting flange.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold finger or thumb over slit in rubber check valve or hole in clear face.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">SLOWLY open air valve and raise pressure to 10 PSI.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for air leaking between face and body or around rubber check vent and face. There
                    should be no air escaping from these two potential leak paths.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air escapes between face and body, discard the hubcap.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If air escapes between rubber check vent and face/body, inspect for damage to rubber
                    check vent and/or face/body interface area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace rubber check vent or hubcap if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
