<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-04-02 - Master Cylinder Silicone Assembly Fluid</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi940402" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-04-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Master Cylinder Silicone Assembly Fluid</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL</title>
                    <para>This TSI applies to all vehicles with hydraulic brakes.</para>
                    <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for
                        use with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information
                        based on representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not
                        responsible for any errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any
                        misuse of the product. Every user is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany
                        the product.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>MINI MASTER CYLINDER SILICONE ASSEMBLY FLUID</title>
                    <para>Bendix (Allied Signal) Bulletin No. PRO-20-08 with Effective Date of 10/01/93.</para>
                    <para>During manufacture of the Mini Master Cylinder, Bendix lubricates the piston bore with a
                        silicone fluid to facilitate component installation and testing. THIS SILICONE MATERIAL has the
                        consistency of a light grease. It is inert and is compatible with brake fluid. This silicone
                        material often migrates to the master cylinder reservoir. Since the silicone is lighter than the
                        brake fluid, it floats on the surface of the brake fluid and is often mistaken as "foreign
                        matter" or contamination. The silicone fluid appears as either a relatively thin film on top of
                        the brake fluid or globules floating in the brake fluid. While the possibility of contamination
                        should not be discounted, material floating in the reservoir is most likely the silicone
                        assembly fluid used during manufacture.
                    </para>
                    <para>When the brake fluid and silicone mixture in the reservoir is penetrated with the tip of a
                        clean screwdriver, the silicone will tend to gather and adhere to the screwdriver tip. When the
                        screwdriver is slowly removed the silicone will "string" away, similar to a heavy oil.
                    </para>
                    <para>True oil contamination in the brake fluid is most easily identified by examining the rubber
                        components in the reservoir caps. When brought into contact with oil, rubber components intended
                        for use in brake fluid will exhibit substantial swelling (often exceeding 125% of their original
                        size).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
