<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-08-04 - Speedometer and Tachometer Ground Clip Installation</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi940804" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-08-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Speedometer and Tachometer Ground Clip Installation</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI describes the adding of ground clips to ground the speedometer and tachometer gauges.
                </para>
                <para>When static electricity results in false movement (sweeping) of the speedometer and tachometer,
                    ground clips can be added to ground the speedometer and tachometer gauges to the housing. All 9000
                    vehicles built after January 1, 1994 will have the ground clips installed.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove speedometer/tachometer gauge unit from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place unit in a clean work area. Clothing that is likely to cause static electricity
                    should not be worn for this procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the front faceplate from the unit by removing the six screws located on the sides
                    of the housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be careful not to bend the gauge assembly during removal. To remove the gauge assemblies
                    from the circuit board, place fingers under each gauge and while applying light straight up
                    pressure, gently rock the gauge from side to side to over come the friction fit of the connector to
                    the circuit board pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place grounding clips (2 required) as illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408041">Figure 1</hotlnk>, (part number 1696371C1) at both ends of the housing so
                    the holes in the clips are lined up with the holes that secure the faceplate to the housing. The
                    grounding clip should be positioned so that it will make contact with the gauge when re-installed (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408042">Figure 2</hotlnk>and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408043">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use steel wool to remove white paint on the back of the speedometer and tachometer gauge
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408044">Figure 4</hotlnk>) when the slips will contact them when re-installed in
                    the housing (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408043">Figure 3</hotlnk>). Remove all steel wool debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install speedometer and tachometer gauge into housing. Position the gauge over the
                    pins in the circuit board and push the gauge straight down on the pins. Be careful not to bend.
                    Insure that the clips are making good contact.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install faceplate onto housing. Before installing the screws that secure the
                    faceplate to the ends of the housing, be sure the holes in the ground clips are lined up with the
                    screw holes in the housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install speedometer/tachometer unit in the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9408041" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9408041.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Clip Part No 1696371C1</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9408042" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9408042.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Ground Clip Installed On End Of Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9408043" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9408043.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Ground Clip Installed On End Of Housing</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9408044" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9408044.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Paint Removed From Underside of Faceplate</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
