<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-08-07 - 3+1 Battery System (Code 08MCB)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi940807" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-08-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>3+1 Battery System (Code 08MCB)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>08MCB</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>In October 1991, International introduced the Fleetrite 3+1 Battery System (Code 08MCB) on its
                    9000 Conventional and Cabover models. Over the last three years, this option has enjoyed widespread
                    use.
                </para>
                <para>But even though the 3+1 system has been popular among fleets and owner operators, there are still
                    some misconceptions about what this system is capable of doing. The system's primary function is to
                    provide three batteries for engine cranking. This ensures that a fully charged battery system is
                    available to crank the engine even when it has been shut down with the accessories, including
                    lights, left on.
                </para>
                <para>Unlike some battery systems that were offered in the past, the three batteries used in the 3+1
                    system are NOT used to power electrical accessories. Rather, the accessories get their power from
                    ONE deep cycle battery (with engine shut off) which has a capacity of about 100 amp. hours. This is
                    roughly 1/3 less power than the standard three-battery system can provide.
                </para>
                <para>The question that many operators ask is "How long does it take to recharge the accessory battery
                    when it has been run down?" Recharge time depends on several factors, including what state of
                    discharge the battery is in and ambient air temperature. A basic rule is that the colder the
                    weather, the longer it will take to recharge the battery.
                </para>
                <para>A graph (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408071">Figure 1</hotlnk>) has been provided which approximates the driving time
                    required to recharge the accessory battery to an 80% state of charge from various levels of
                    discharge and temperature.
                </para>
                <para>The cycle life rating on the deep cycle battery is established at 50% of total discharge. As an
                    example: A 300 cycle life rated battery will last 300 cycles if discharged 50% each discharge cycle.
                    A 300 cycle life rated battery discharged 100% during each cycle will last approximately 1/4 of the
                    cycle life rating.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9408071" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9408071.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Driving Time Required To Recharge a Deep-Cycle Battery</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
