<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-08-08 - K7N Integrated Fan Drive Control System Kit</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi940808" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-08-08</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>K7N Integrated Fan Drive Control System Kit</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Excessive fan cycling when an engine is idling with the air conditioning running causes premature
                    fan drive failure and stresses the air conditioning system. Navistar now has available a kit (Part
                    Number 1697071C91) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9408081">Figure 1</hotlnk>) that will reduce fan cycling when the engine is idling.
                </para>
                <para>The K7N fan drive control system kit is designed to reduce fan cycling for longer fan drive life
                    and improved air conditioning component reliability. A special three minute timer in the temp./timer
                    controller prevents the fan from cycling by keeping the fan on for a minimum of three minutes
                    whenever the fan is activated by the air conditioning system. The three minute fan cycle lowers
                    refrigerant compressor discharge pressure and temperatures which increases the life of air
                    conditioning components such as the compressor, clutch and hoses.
                </para>
                <para>The K7N fan control kit can be used with any combination of engine and air actuated fan drive. The
                    kit contains all necessary parts including interconnecting cables, a dashboard mounted manual
                    override switch and snap together connectors, all of which make the K7N kit easy to install.
                </para>
                <para>The K7N kit is not required on 1994 Caterpillar and Detroit electronic engines because the three
                    minute time delay for the fan is built into the ECM.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9408081" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9408081.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. K7N Integrated Fan Drive Control System Kit (Part No. 1697071C91)</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
