<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-08-02 - Data Link Driven Speedometer and Tachometer</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi940802" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-08-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Data Link Driven Speedometer and Tachometer</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>GENERAL</title>
                    <para>Navistar has changed the way the speedometer and tachometer are wired for all 1994 vehicles
                        equipped with electronic engines. Prior to 1994, the tachometer was fed from the flywheel sensor
                        and the speedometer was fed from one of the outputs of a dual sensor on the rear of the
                        transmission. With 1994 electronic engines, the speedometer and tachometer are fed from the
                        engine Electronic Control Module (ECM) by way of the SAE J1708 data link. A single speed sensor
                        at the rear of the transmission now feeds the ECM and a flywheel sensor is no longer required.
                        The ECM reads its own speedometer and tachometer data, calibrates the input frequency and
                        transmits the information, via the data link, to the speedometer and tachometer gauges.
                    </para>
                    <para>Field calibration of the speedometer and tachometer is now done in the ECM and not at the
                        cluster. The cluster is merely programmed to accept speedometer and tachometer information from
                        the data link and the only calibration required is setting the dip switches for miles or
                        kilometers.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>HEAVY DUTY VEHICLES</title>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Speedometers and tachometers are used in the data link mode for all electronic
                                Caterpillar, Cummins and Detroit engines after January 1, 1994.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Changing tire size or axle ratio in the field will require reprogramming the engine
                                ECM and not the cluster.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Heavy duty vehicles WITHOUT electronically controlled engines are programmed, as
                                before, to operate from standard sensor inputs.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>EXAMPLE of dip switch setting for heavy duty vehicle speedometer and tachometer to
                                operate in the data link mode:
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <verbatim>
                        <line>Speedometer Dip Switches: 1111111111</line>
                        <line>Tachometer Dip Switch: 11111111#*</line>
                        <line># - Bit 9 of Tach: not used, set to a 0</line>
                        <line>* - Bit 10 of Tach: Odometer Miles/kilo Switch</line>
                        <line>1= Kilometer</line>
                        <line>0 = Miles</line>
                    </verbatim>
                    <seqlist></seqlist>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>MEDIUM DUTY VEHICLES</title>
                    <para>ECM driven speedometer and tachometer also apply to medium duty vehicles equipped with the
                        NAVISTAR T 444E V-8 electronic engine.
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>T 444E electronic engines use buffered speedometer and tachometer signals from the
                                Vehicle Personality Module (VPM). These signals are calibrated to 12 pulses/rev for the
                                tachometer and 30000 pulses per mile for the speedometer.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>The dip switch settings for the T 444E electronic engine are also predefined settings.
                                Changes in tire size or axle ratio will require reprogramming the engine ECM.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Medium duty vehicles WITHOUT electronic engines are programmed, as before, to operate
                                from standard sensor outputs.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>EXAMPLE of dip switch setting for medium duty vehicle speedometer and tachometer, with
                                T 444E electronic engine, to operate in the data link mode.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <verbatim>
                        <line>Dip Switch 1: 01011111</line>
                        <line>Dip Switch 2: 00*000#@</line>
                        <line>* - Bit 3 of DIP Switch 2: 2 spd. axle ratio 1 = 1.39, 0 = 1.36</line>
                        <line># - Bit 7 of DIP Switch 2: Tachometer Scale; always 0 for 3500 RPM</line>
                        <line>@ - Bit 8 of DIP Switch 2: Odometer switch; 1 = Kilometers, 0 = Miles</line>
                    </verbatim>
                </lev1>
                <lev1></lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
