<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-12-05 - Method to Clean Oil From A Chassis Mounted Charge Air Coolant</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941205" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-12-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>April, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Method to Clean Oil From A Chassis Mounted Charge Air Coolant</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with a charge air cooler.</para>
                <para>If a turbocharger failure occurs which allows oil to enter the chassis mounted charge air cooler,
                    the contaminated cooler must be removed from the vehicle and cleaned. The following procedure should
                    be used to clean a charge air cooler after it has been removed from the vehicle.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CLEAN CHARGE AIR COOLER</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove charge air cooler from vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain as much oil as possible by gravity through either or both openings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a detergent soap such as a no suds dishwasher soap mixed with hot water. Fill,
                    agitate and flush the charge air cooler until all oil is removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>This step may need to be repeated more than once to completely remove all oil from the
                        cooler.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse with hot water until all soap solution is removed and the water used to rinse is
                    clear after it has circulated completely through the cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Circulate compressed air through the cooler to remove most of the remaining rinse
                    water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Over pressure from compressed air can cause damage to the charge air cooler and/or injury to
                        people near by.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be sure to wear eye protection while blowing water out of the charge air cooler with
                        compressed air. Failure to wear eye protection may cause serious damage or loss of the use of
                        one or both eyes.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install charge air cooler in vehicle leaving the outlet disconnected from the intake
                    piping (cold side).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and run at low RPM observing the charge air cooler outlet. Precautions
                    should be taken to prevent foreign material from being drawn into the engine through the cold side
                    intake pipe while performing this step. When outlet air becomes completely free of water residue,
                    stop engine and re-install the engine intake side piping to the charge air cooler.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check leakage integrity of the complete intake system described in Step 2, Air Induction
                    Pressure Test in CTS-5087, CHARGE AIR SYSTEM in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Road test and check intake manifold pressure as described on engine diagnostic form
                    CGED-115, step 10 "Intake Manifold Pressure".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para></para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
