<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-12-07 - Maintenance and Replacement Information For V-Ribbed Belts (Dayco Poly Rib&#174;)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941207" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-12-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Maintenance and Replacement Information For V-Ribbed Belts (Dayco Poly Rib&#174;)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Dayco</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>NOTICE</title>
                    <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for
                        use with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information
                        based on representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not
                        responsible for any errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any
                        misuse of the product. Every user is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany
                        the product.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>DAYCO SALES INFORMATION PRODUCT BULLETIN</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>INTRODUCTION</title>
                        <para>This bulletin is being issued in order to provide a general assistance guide to those in
                            the field that are faced with the day-to-day responsibility of maintaining and replacing
                            v-ribbed belts (Dayco Poly Rib&#174;) used in the heavy vehicle industry today. Since the
                            somewhat recent introduction of serpentine as well as single v-ribbed belt drives for heavy
                            duty vehicles a few years ago, there may be some confusion as to when to replace the
                            v-ribbed belt and what is causing the need for possible replacement. This bulletin has been
                            designed to assist those who may have such concerns.
                        </para>
                        <para>The normal cause for v-ribbed belt replacement is caused by rib rubber fatigue, which is a
                            natural occurrence and is known as "rib cracking". Beyond "rib cracking" there exists
                            several other reasons to replace the drive belt.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>WARNING SIGNS FOR BELT REPLACEMENT ARE:</title>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>RIB CRACKING:</title>
                            <para>As a v-ribbed belt goes through its natural life it passes through several phases of
                                cracking.
                            </para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>After an extended time in service, minor rib cracks may appear, usually one or
                                        two cracks per inch of belt.
                                        <emph type="bold">This is Normal</emph>
                                        (see
                                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9412071">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>A replacement concern should occur when the belt ribs exhibit severe multiple
                                        cracking which will lead to rib chunking (see
                                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9412072">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>When severe cracking or rib chunking appears, it is time to replace the belt
                                        (see
                                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9412073">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                            <figure id="f9412071" figsize="col-wide">
                                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9412071.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="100"/>
                                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                            </figure>
                            <figure id="f9412072" figsize="col-wide">
                                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9412072.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="100"/>
                                <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                            </figure>
                            <figure id="f9412073" figsize="col-wide">
                                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9412073.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="100"/>
                                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                            </figure>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>RIB SIDEWALL GLAZING:</title>
                            <para>When the ribs appear to have a shiny surface that is hard and brittle, it is usually
                                an indication of belt slippage. This is attributed to inadequate tension and/or extreme
                                temperature. Both characteristics will lead to severe cracking and failure often with
                                little advance warning. If this happens, locate the cause and correct before installing
                                a new belt.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>BELT WEAR:</title>
                            <para>Accelerated wear on any part of the belt; fabric backing, tensile cord, or rib rubber
                                is a concern and should be investigated for cause and corrected before installing a new
                                belt.
                            </para>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Some Causes:</emph>
                            </para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Drive Misalignment</emph>
                                        - Belt performance will begin to be adversely affected when misalignment exceeds
                                        1/16 inch for each 12.0 inch of belt span (1/3 of 1&#176;).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Belt Length</emph>
                                        - Must be correct.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Environmental Conditions</emph>
                                        - Temperature, exposure to engine fluids, etc.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>
                                        <emph type="bold">Abrasive Materials</emph>
                                        - Such as small stones, sand, metal shavings, etc. (see
                                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9412074">Figure 4</hotlnk>).
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                            <figure id="f9412074" figsize="col-wide">
                                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9412074.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="100"/>
                                <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                            </figure>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>FOREIGN OBJECTS:</title>
                            <para>V-Ribbed belts, like most engine components, can tolerate only so much abuse before
                                failure.
                            </para>
                            <para>Any object protruding in the path of the belt drive and contacting the belt will cause
                                damage and failure of the belt. Locate the object and remove before installing a new
                                belt (see
                                <hotlnk xrefid="f9412075">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                            </para>
                            <figure id="f9412075" figsize="col-wide">
                                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9412075.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="100"/>
                                <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
                            </figure>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>NOISE/ VIBRATION/ HARSHNESS (NVH)</title>
                            <para>Much effort has gone into the design of each v-ribbed belt drive in order to prevent
                                NVH problems by the end user. However field problems occasionally occur which may be
                                related to NVH causes.
                            </para>
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Some causes:</emph>
                            </para>
                            <para>Insufficient belt tension may create a high- pitched howl (squeal) or rasping sound
                                during engine acceleration or deceleration.
                            </para>
                            <para>Misalignment may cause a chirping noise, especially at or near idle speed. Rigid
                                bracketing of accessories is a must for reasonably vibration-free belt spans ... some
                                span vibration is to be expected during the range of engine speed and accessory loading.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
