<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-12-01 - Supplemental Coolant Additives (SCA'S)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Supplemental Coolant Additives (SCA'S)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Supplemental coolant additives (SCA'S) are important to insure long diesel engine life. Their
                    primary function is to protect the cylinder wall from cavitation erosion (pitting). Secondarily,
                    they bolster the anti-corrosion additives in antifreeze.
                </para>
                <para>In order to insure a uniform concentration level of SCA at time of vehicle delivery, Navistar has
                    recently started to incorporate the SCA in factory fill antifreeze. A combination of quality water,
                    proper percentage of antifreeze and the correct amount of SCA is called FULLY FORMULATED COOLANT.
                </para>
                <para>On or about January 1, 1994, the coolant filter element will be standardized as a four unit
                    service filter for all engines, in lieu of the 12 or 15 unit precharge filters that were previously
                    used.
                </para>
                <para>Navistar's "Fleetrite" filters for OEM and service utilize the "DCA4" formulation of SCA. When
                    using the "DCA4" additives, concentration should be maintained at 1.5 to 3.0 units per gallon when
                    tested with the "DCA4" test kit.
                </para>
                <para>Navistar realizes that some customers prefer "Nalcool" coolant additive. "Nalcool" is completely
                    compatible with "DCA4". When using "Nalcool" as the coolant additive, concentration should be
                    maintained at 800 to 2400 ppm of nitrite, when tested with the "Nalcool" test kit.
                </para>
                <para>SCA LEVELS SHOULD BE MAINTAINED BY REGULAR COOLANT FILTER CHANGES AND/OR LIQUID SCA ADDITIONS TO
                    PROPERLY MAINTAIN THE SCA LEVEL. COOLANT SHOULD BE TESTED A MINIMUM OF TWICE A YEAR. WHEN EXCESSIVE
                    COOLANT LOSS OCCURS AND COOLANT IS REPLACED, DILUTION OF THE SCA RESULTS. IF EXCESSIVE COOLANT LOSS
                    IS SUSPECTED, COOLANT SHOULD BE TESTED, AND ADEQUATE SCA ADDED TO MAKE UP FOR CHEMICAL LOST DUE TO
                    DILUTION.
                    <emph type="bold">LOW LEVELS OF SCA'S WILL RESULT IN ENGINE CYLINDER OR CYLINDER WALL CAVITATION
                        EROSION.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
