<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-14-03 - Procedures for Welding a Transverse Torque Rod Bracket to a Rear Axle</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941403" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-14-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>REAR AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Procedures for Welding a Transverse Torque Rod Bracket to a Rear Axle</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>To provide satisfactory service life, the procedure for welding transverse torque rods to rear
                        axle housings must be followed. The following welding information will aid a welder in providing
                        a commercial quality weld for truck applications.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELDER CERTIFICATION</title>
                    <para>All welding on axle housings must be done by welders certified by an independent testing
                        laboratory to meet the requirements of AWS D1.1 Structural Welding Code.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>Invisible ultraviolet and infrared rays emitted in welding can injure unprotected eyes
                                and skin. Protection such as welder's helmet with dark colored filter lenses of the
                                proper density must be used. GTAW or TIG welding will produce intense radiation,
                                therefore, filter plate lenses of the deepest shade providing adequate visibility are
                                recommended. It is strongly recommended that persons working in the weld area wear flash
                                safety goggles. Also wear protective clothing.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SURFACE PREPARATION</title>
                    <para>Weld joints must be free from contamination, such as moisture, lubricants and rust. Paint must
                        be removed since it will adversely affect the weld quality.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELD JOINT FIT-UP</title>
                    <para>A slight grind to fit condition may exist between the housing and bracket due to axle housing
                        and bracket tolerances. Grind the bracket to fit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9414031">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The bracket should fit-up as close as possible to
                        avoid excessive welding.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9414031" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9414031" filename="../tsifigures/g9414031.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Fit to Contour</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELD LENGTHS</title>
                    <para>The effective weld length shall not include skips, off location welds and/or other conditions
                        defined in the WELD QUALITY section of this letter.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELD LOCATION</title>
                    <para>All welds should be centered laterally in the joint in a manner to insure fusion between the
                        parts being joined. Portions of the weld which are undersize, or do not meet the minimum
                        requirements for weld quality (undercut, porosity, craters) shall be considered as skips and are
                        not considered in the weld length.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELD LEG SIZE</title>
                    <para>The minimum weld leg has to be at least as thick as the minimum thickness of the thinnest
                        member of the bracket.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>THROAT THICKNESS</title>
                    <para>The minimum throat thickness of fillet welds are to be equal to 60% of the shortest weld leg
                        size. Maximum throat thickness is to be limited to 100% of the longest leg size (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9414032">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9414032" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9414032" filename="../tsifigures/g9414032.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Throat Thickness</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>DEFINITIONS</title>
                    <para>The welding terms shall be interpreted in accordance with the definitions given in AWS - Weld
                        (ANSI/AWS A2.4 latest issue).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SYMBOLS</title>
                    <para>Welding symbols shall be interpreted in accordance with AWS Standard Welding Symbols (ANSI/AWS
                        A2.4 latest issue).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELD QUALITY</title>
                    <para>Unless otherwise specified, the following characteristics shall be permitted. No more than one
                        of these characteristics shall be permitted in the weld if the any other characteristic is at
                        the maximum limit.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Undercut</title>
                        <para>Shall not exceed .030 inch (0.8 mm).</para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Craters</title>
                        <para>Unfilled craters are not considered part of the effective weld length, and are therefore
                            limited by the length of the weld tolerance for gaps. They can be properly filled and
                            counted in the weld length.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Cracks and Burn-through</title>
                        <para>Cracks in the weld and holes burned through the base stock will not be permitted.</para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Visible Porosity</title>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Frequency</title>
                            <para>No more than four (4) significant pores shall be permitted in any 1 inch (25 mm) of
                                weld length with the average limited to one (1) per 1 inch (25 mm) of weld length.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                        <lev3>
                            <title>Severity</title>
                            <para>The maximum diameter of the pores shall be 1/16 inch (1.6 mm) and shall be spaced at
                                least 1/16 inch (1.6 mm) apart.
                            </para>
                            <para>Pores must be larger than 1/64 inch (0.4 mm) in diameter to be considered significant.
                                Porosity shall not be permitted in any weld specified as oil tight.
                            </para>
                        </lev3>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Inclusions</title>
                        <para>Non-metallic inclusions shall be considered and judged as a gap.</para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WELDING RECOMMENDATIONS</title>
                    <para>The welding rod used shall produce a minimum tensile strength of 70,000 psi using an
                        all-weld-metal test sample tested in accordance with AWS B4.0. Typical processes and electrodes
                        which meet this requirement are as follows:
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Electrode</title>
                        <verbatim>
                            <line>A.W.S. (American Welding Society)</line>
                            <line>E70XX (Ref. AWS-A5.1-91)</line>
                        </verbatim>
                        <verbatim>
                            <line>A.W.S. E-70X-X</line>
                            <line>(Ref. AWS-A5.18-93)</line>
                        </verbatim>
                        <verbatim>
                            <line>A.W.S. F-72-XXXXX</line>
                            <line>(Ref. AWS-A5.17-89)</line>
                        </verbatim>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Process</title>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Shielded metal-arc welding of carbon low alloy steels.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Gas metal-arc welding of carbon and low alloy steels.</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Submerged arc welding of mild and low alloy steels.</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>Use the voltage and amperage recommended by the electrode manufacturer. This will provide
                            the best fusion and strongest weld.
                        </para>
                        <para>Do not "test the arc" on the housing. Deposit the required amount of metal with the least
                            number of passes - one pass is preferred. Where a second pass is required, thoroughly remove
                            the slag from the weld between passes.
                        </para>
                        <para>On brackets that require welding all around, distortion and stress can be further
                            controlled by welding on opposite sides of the bracket alternately.
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9414033">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                            shows the tack welding sequence. Tack welds must be cleaned prior to final welding.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f9414033" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g9414033" filename="../tsifigures/g9414033.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 3. Tack Weld Sequence</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9414034">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                            shows the sequence and direction of the final weld. Start weld at each end of bracket and
                            work toward middle of bracket. Remove the slag from the weld. Cover the tack welds with the
                            final welds.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f9414034" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g9414034" filename="../tsifigures/g9414034.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 4. Weld Sequence and Direction</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <para>There is a notch in the end of the transverse torque rod bracket for use as a moisture
                            drain. Do not weld in the area of the notch (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9414035">Figure 5</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f9414035" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g9414035" filename="../tsifigures/g9414035.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 5. No Weld Area</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <para>If information on welding locations of transverse rods is required, call 1-800-44TRUCK.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
