<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-14-04 - Proper Identification and Gear Pattern for the New Spicer "Continuous Index" Cut Gear Sets
        Supplied for the W230-S (Code 14057) and W460-S (Code 14474) Rear Axles
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941404" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-14-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>REAR AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Proper Identification and Gear Pattern for the New Spicer "Continuous Index" Cut Gear Sets Supplied
                for the W230-S (Code 14057) and W460-S (Code 14474) Rear Axles
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
                <vendcodegroup/>

                <vendcode>W230-S</vendcode>
                <vendcode>W460-S</vendcode>
            </configure>
            <configure>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>14057</ucode>
                <ucode>14474</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="0">
            <title>NOTICE</title>
            <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information based on
                representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for any
                errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user
                is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="2">
            <title>PROPER IDENTIFICATION AND GEAR PATTERN FOR THE NEW SPICER "CONTINUOUS INDEX" CUT GEAR SETS FOR W230-S
                (CODE 14057) AND W460-S (CODE 14474) REAR AXLES
            </title>
            <para>Spicer Bulletin No. 62, dated 10-25-1994</para>
            <para>Due to today's production requirements, Spicer Heavy Axle has phased in ring and pinion gear sets that
                use different manufacturing methods than the conventional gear sets.
            </para>
            <para>The new sets are called
                <emph type="bold">"Continuous Index Cut Gears."</emph>
                The new gear sets are a direct replacement for the conventional cut gears, therefore it was not
                necessary to assign new part numbers for the matched sets. The "Continuous Index" gear sets do, however,
                require building with a different tooth contact pattern than the conventional gear sets, so positive
                identification was necessary to distinguish continuous index gear sets from the conventional.
            </para>
            <para>The individual Continuous gears were assigned new part numbers that will be used to properly identify
                them. The first 5 digits of the pinion gear part number are 057GP, followed by a 3 number suffix to
                indicate ration. The first 5 digits of the ring gear part number are 057GR. The illustration (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9414041">Figure 1</hotlnk>) shows location of individual part numbers.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9414041" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9414041.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>GEAR FAILURE WILL OCCUR TO BOTH CONTINUOUS INDEX OR CONVENTIONAL GEAR SETS IF PROPER TOOTH
                        CONTACT PATTERN IS NOT ESTABLISHED FOR EITHER SET.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following procedures are to be used to establish proper gear tooth pattern after assembly of the
                carrier is complete.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If matched sets are being reused, measure and record backlash before disassembly, and
                        reassemble to the same backlash. This will match ring and pinion gears to the established wear
                        patterns. Hand rolled patterns of pre-used gear sets will cover less area than the wear pattern
                        established by previous service.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Paint ring gear with marking compound on both the drive and coast side. (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9414042">Figure 2</hotlnk>)
                </para>
                <figure id="f9414042" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9414042.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate ring gear at least one complete revolution in both directions while load is being
                    applied.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="1">
            <title>RING GEAR TOOTH INTERPRETATION</title>
            <para>The illustration (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9414043">Figure 3</hotlnk>) compares correct and incorrect patterns of both "Continuous
                Index" and conventional gear sets.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9414043" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9414043.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
