<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-16-01 - Modification Of The Short Filler To Roof Fairing Extender and Sleeper Box Extender
        Installation
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941601" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-16-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Modification Of The Short Filler To Roof Fairing Extender and Sleeper Box Extender Installation
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>9200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>To prevent damage from occurring to the roof fairing extender, the short filler panel and/or the
                    sleeper box extender on 9200, 9300 and 9400 model vehicles built after January 4, 1993, the
                    following modification should be made to the short filler to roof airing extender and sleeper box
                    extender installation.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>The following procedure is for one side of the vehicle, repeat on the opposite side of the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9416011">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                for all items in parentheses unless otherwise stated.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9416011" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g9416011" filename="../tsifigures/G9416011.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Modification To Short Filler</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ROOF FAIRING SIDE EXTENDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ROOF FAIRING EXTENDER BRACE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. AIR DEFLECTOR MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. AIR DEFLECTOR MOUNTING SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SMALL FILLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. 5/16 INCH BOLT, FLAT WASHER, NUT</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. SLEEPER BOX EXTENDER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two 5/16 inch nuts, flat washers and bolts (Item 6) that secure the short
                    filler (Item 5) to the sleeper box extender (Item 7).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 5/16 inch nut, flat washer and bolt that secure the roof fairing extender
                    brace (Item 2) to the roof fairing side extender (Item 1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 5/16 inch nut and flat washer that secure the roof fairing extender brace
                    (Item 2) to the air deflector mounting bracket (Item 3). Remove the second 5/16 inch nut and flat
                    washer from the air deflector mounting bracket (Item 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Manufacture a 1/4 inch thick spacer to fit between the air deflector mounting bracket
                    (Item 3) and the air deflector mounting support (Item 4). Make the spacer large enough to include
                    the full width and length of the air deflector mounting bracket base.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut two slots in the spacer to allow it to fit around the two studs that protrude upward
                    from the air deflector mounting support (Item 4) through the air deflector mounting bracket (Item
                    3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Raise the air deflector mounting bracket (Item 3) high enough to insert the spacer
                    between it and the air deflector mounting support (Figure 1). Install 5/16 inch lock nuts on the two
                    studs protruding through the air deflector mounting bracket. Tighten both nuts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The studs protruding through the air deflector mounting bracket are not long enough to
                    remount the roof fairing extender brace to. Position the roof fairing extender brace (Item 2) on the
                    air deflector mounting bracket (Item 3) and the roof fairing side extender (Item 2) as illustrated
                    in Figure 1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the end of the roof fairing extender brace (Item 2) on the roof deflector side
                    extender as illustrated in Figure 1 in the hole it was removed from with the 5/16 inch bolt, flat
                    washer and nut removed in step 2. It may be necessary to elongate the hole in the brace and grind
                    off the corner to make it fit. Hand tighten the nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Place a piece of wood or metal between the air deflector mounting support and the cab when
                        drilling the following hole to prevent drilling through the top of the cab.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the roof fairing extender brace hole as a template and drill a hole (the size of the
                    hole in the brace) through the air deflector mounting bracket, the 1/4 inch spacer and the air
                    deflector mounting support at this location. Secure the brace in this location with 5/16 inch X
                    1-1/2 inch bolt, flat washer and nut. Tighten the nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure all fasteners are tight.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut a piece of 1 inch X 1 inch X .100 inch aluminum angle stock 10 inches long. Measure
                    5 inches from one end of the angle stock and place a pencil mark at this location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill two equally spaced 3/16 inch holes on each side of the center mark on the angle
                    stock (four holes total).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the angle stock so that the center mark on the angle stock is at the gap
                    between the roof fairing side extender (Item 1,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9416012">Figure 2</hotlnk>) and the small filler (Item 3,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9416012">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Hold the angle stock in position with a clamp.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9416012" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9416012.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Roof Fairing Side Extender</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. ROOF FAIRING SIDE EXTENDER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. 1 INCH X 1 INCH X 10 INCH X .100 INCH ALUMINUM STOCK</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SMALL FILLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. 3/16 INCH POP RIVETS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill a 3/16 inch hole into the extender and filler in each hole location on the 1 inch
                    angle stock.
                    <emph type="bold">Care should be taken not to drill completely through the extender and filler.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the 1 inch angle stock to the extender and fill with 3/16 inch pop rivets
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9416012">(Figure 2).</hotlnk>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Repeat this procedure on the opposite side of vehicle.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
