<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 94-16-05 - Instructions To Repair Paint On Prop Shafts and Other Unprimed Metal Parts</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi941605" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>94-16-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 1994</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Instructions To Repair Paint On Prop Shafts and Other Unprimed Metal Parts</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar recommends the following procedure be followed in the field to repair paint on prop
                    shafts, springs and other unprimed metal parts that are peeling due to the lack of primer.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PAINT PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Keep paint away from heat, sparks and flame. Vapor may cause flash fire. Use with adequate
                        ventilation. Do not breathe vapors or spray mist. Wear appropriate, properly filled respirator
                        (NIOSH/MSHA approved) during and after paint application, unless air monitoring demonstrates
                        vapor/mist levels are below applicable limits. Follow respirator manufacturer's directions for
                        respirator use. Avoid contact with eyes, skin and clothing. Wash thoroughly after handling.
                        Paint may contain lead. Do not use on toys, furniture or surfaces or other articles that might
                        be chewed by children.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FIRST AID:</emph>In case of eye contact, flush immediately with plenty of water for at
                least 15 minutes and get medical attention. For skin, wash thoroughly with soap and water. If affected
                by inhalation of vapor or spray mist, move to fresh air. If a hazardous substance has been swallowed,
                get immediate medical attention.
            </para>
            <para>Before opening the products used in this procedure, read all
                <emph type="bold">WARNING</emph>labels. Follow all precautions. Keep container closed when not in use.
                In case of spillage, absorb with inert material and dispose of in accordance with applicable
                regulations.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Reports have associated repeated and prolonged occupational overexposure to solvents with
                        permanent brain and nervous system damage. Intentional misuse by deliberately concentrating or
                        inhaling the contents may be harmful to your health or fatal.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use high pressure water to remove the existing paint on the surface to be repaired. The
                    remaining paint can be removed with steel wool and/or a wire brush depending on severity until all
                    waterborne black paint is removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the surface with either a 50/50 mixture of alcohol and water, or Sikkens Aquaprep
                    degreaser. Follow with a clean cloth to wipe the surface dry.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply an even coat, 1-1.5 mil. of Ashland Chemical's Techtyl 300G waterborne primer, and
                    allow 3 - 5 minutes to dry.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply an even coat, 1-1.5 mil. of Akzo waterborne black chassis paint. Allow 3-5 minutes
                    to dry.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
