<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-02-02 - Spicer Tie Rod End Replacement Criteria</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi950202" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-02-02</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Spicer Tie Rod End Replacement Criteria</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Notice</title>
                    <para>This information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier
                        for use with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information
                        based on representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not
                        responsible for any errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any
                        misuse of the product. Every user is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany
                        the product.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>SPICER TIE ROD END REPLACEMENT CRITERIA (Spicer Heavy Axle uses only full ball type tie rod ends.)
            </title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Spicer Service Bulletin No. 65</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">4-1-95</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">This Service Bulletin contains information and instructions to check tie rod end
                        conditions.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Inspection:</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Carefully wipe seal clean and examine for splits or tears that allow contaminants
                        into the socket.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If seal is acceptable, shake tie rod assembly by hand only.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <caution>
                            <para>Prying on steering linkage can result in damage. False indication of looseness can be
                                created.
                            </para>
                        </caution>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If looseness is detected, set up a dial indicator as shown in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9502021">Figure 1.</hotlnk>
                        Jack up that side of the axle and measure movement at the tie rod end. Move the tire in and out
                        as illustrated in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9502021">Figure 1.</hotlnk>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>C-clamp setup is recommended for testing the tie rod end for looseness.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The tie rod end should be replaced if a
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9502022">reading of .030"</hotlnk>
                        or more is taken. Replace tie rod end at the next service interval.
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>We no longer recommend removal of the tapered stud from the arm to check rotating
                                torque. This may damage the seal or socket assembly. The full boot clamped seal that is
                                popular in today's product can give false rotating torque readings.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9502021" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9502021.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9502022" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9502022.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
