<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-02-01 - Rockwell Tie Rod and Steering Arm Change</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi950201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-02-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Rockwell Tie Rod and Steering Arm Change</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Rockwell</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>This information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for
                    use with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product.
                    Every user is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Rockwell Product Information Letter #228</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">February, 1995</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Tie Rod And Steering Arm Change</emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">All Non-Driving Front Axles</emph>
                </para>
                <para>Dear Customer,</para>
                <para>Due to increased market demand, tie rod and steering arms are being resourced. In addition,
                    Rockwell has taken advantage of this resourcing to improve the product by changing the key design in
                    the taper joint of all non-driving front axle tie rod and steering arms.
                </para>
                <para>The new key and key seat are a Woodruff shape as opposed to the old square key design. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9502011">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9502011" figsize="full-pg">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9502011.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Tie Rod and Steering Arm Key Change</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The new Woodruff design is easier to assemble because it does not slide up or down the slot.
                </para>
                <para>Top level specifications will not change. Tie rod and steering arm part numbers will not change.
                    Key part numbers will change. As this will be a running change, the Bill of Material will indicate
                    Woodruff or square key design.
                </para>
                <para>Square key part number: 16-X-202</para>
                <para>Woodruff key part number: 16-X-1035</para>
                <para>This change will be implemented on a running change basis beginning in April 1995. FF and FG
                    series axle tie rod arms will be changed first.
                </para>
                <para>Rockwell recommends the appropriate key be assembled into the appropriate arm. Rockwell recommends
                    arms with Woodruff seat be assembled exclusively with Woodruff keys. Conversely, arms with square
                    seat are to be assembled only with square keys.
                </para>
                <para>Rockwell does not recommend assembly of Woodruff keys into square arm seats. Square keys are not
                    to be assembled into arms with the Woodruff key seat.
                </para>
                <para>Loose arm shipments for production assembly with Woodruff keys will be shipped with appropriate
                    keys.
                </para>
                <para>This tie rod and steering arm change does not affect the steering knuckle.</para>
                <para>Service replacement square and Woodruff keys will be available individually. Tie rod and steering
                    arms will be sold as a kit that includes the appropriate key. All components will be available
                    through Rockwell Aftermarket Service channels at Florence, KY and Brampton, Ontario.
                </para>
                <para>If you have any questions. please contact your Rockwell account representative.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
