<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-12-06 - Service Manual Correction For Proper Cylinder Sleeve Installation Procedure</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi951206" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>95-12-06</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Service Manual Correction For Proper Cylinder Sleeve Installation Procedure</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 408</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>An incorrect procedure has been identified in Service Manuals EGES 105 and EGES 105-1 for the DT-408,
                DT-466 and the International&#174; 530 diesel engines. Section 6, pages 26 and 27 specify the use of
                lubriplate for lubricating the cylinder sleeve O-Rings and crankcase lower counterbore prior to sleeve
                installation. This practice could lead to problems described below. Refer to the next sections for
                service manual corrections. Replace these corrected sections in your service manuals and advise all
                service technicians of the correct procedure.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">THE USE OF LUBRIPLATE OR ANY OTHER TYPE OF GREASE IN THE SLEEVE O-RING AREA IS NOT
                    RECOMMENDED.
                </emph>
                Lubriplate and grease have thick consistencies and are
                <emph type="underscr">NOT</emph>
                able to escape from between the O-Rings during sleeve installation. Use of lubriplate or grease can
                result in a grease bound condition between the O-Rings thereby causing the sleeve to distort and lead to
                cylinder scoring.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>USE CLEAN ENGINE OIL ONLY FOR LUBRICATING THE SLEEVE O-RINGS AND LOWER COUNTERBORE AREAS.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Difficult sleeve insertion into the lower counterbore is an indication of incorrect size, twisted, out
                of position or lubrication bound O-Rings. The sleeves should install by hand without extreme effort. If
                difficult sleeve insertion is encountered or there is any question of distortion at the lower
                counterbore area, inspection of the sleeve bore with a dial bore indicator is recommended. Out of round
                or tapered condition beyond specified limits is not acceptable and can cause cylinder scoring. If any of
                these conditions are encountered the sleeve must be removed and the cause of distortion corrected.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">THIS PROCEDURE APPLIES TO ALL INTERNATIONAL WET SLEEVED ENGINES.</emph>
            </para>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CONNECTING RODS, PISTONS &#38; RINGS - Continued</title>
            <para>2. Assemble the piston and connecting rod as follows: Refer to
                <emph type="bold">
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9512061">Figure 6.41.</hotlnk>
                </emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f9512061" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9512061.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <seqlist style="alphalc">
                <item>
                    <para>Lubricate the connecting rod piston pin bushing with clean engine oil.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the retaining ring at one end of the piston pin bore.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Insert the connecting rod into the piston aligning bored holes of the rod and piston (the
                        short side of the split on the crank end of the rod is to be toward the side of the piston
                        marked
                        <emph type="bold">"CAMSIDE"</emph>).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Align the pin bores and insert the piston pin.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install the second retaining ring.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Connecting rod and cap matching numbers must be opposite the camside of the piston.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="2">
            <title>CYLINDER SLEEVES</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate the O-Rings with clean engine oil and install one into each cylinder
                        sleeve groove (without twist). Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9512062">Figure 6.42.</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Lightly lubricate O-Ring area of sleeve and lower counterbore of crankcase with clean
                                engine oil to ease installation and avoid O-Ring twist or pinch.
                                <emph type="underscr">DO NOT USE GREASE OR LUBRIPLATE.</emph>
                            </para>
                            <para>Each cylinder sleeve uses two (2) O-Rings.</para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                    <figure id="f9512062" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9512062.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If required, assure the proper shim(s) is installed, in the crankcase counterbore,
                        so cylinder sleeve protrusion is within specifications. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">"CYLINDER SLEEVE FITTING PROCEDURE", (Figure 6.4).</emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Be sure the O-Rings are properly aligned in the groove.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Apply clean engine oil to the lower crankcase counterbore, then carefully install
                        cylinder sleeve. If reusing sleeve, rotate 90&#176; from its original position and install in
                        the same bore from which it was removed. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9512063">Figure 6.43.</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9512063" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9512063.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The sleeve should be installed by hand with no resistance felt. If a resistance is
                                felt or if there is any question of distortion at the lower counterbore area, inspect
                                the sleeve bore with a dial bore indicator. Any distortion, out-of-round or tapered
                                condition is not acceptable and can cause cylinder scoring.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">After installation, check cylinder sleeve protrusion. Refer to
                        <emph type="bold">"Reconditioning".</emph>
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="1">
            <title>PISTON &#38; CONNECTING ROD</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Assembly</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate the piston rings with clean engine oil and stagger the ring gaps 120&#176;
                        apart.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Install the piston ring compressor
                        <emph type="bold">ZTSE4395</emph>
                        (DT-408/466) or
                        <emph type="bold">ZTSE4396</emph>
                        (International&#174; 530) over the piston rings.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Lubricate cylinder sleeve with clean engine oil.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The piston and rod assemblies can be installed by turning the crankshaft three (3)
                                times. Position the Nos.1 and 6 crankpins at BTDC. Install Nos.1 and 6 piston
                                assemblies. Repeat this procedure for the Nos. 2 and 5 and Nos. 3 and 4 piston and rod
                                assemblies.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Insert piston and connecting rod assembly into sleeve. The numbers on connecting rod
                        must face away from camshaft while markings on top of piston faces toward the camshaft side of
                        the engine.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Push piston and connecting rod into the cylinder sleeve with a wooden or plastic
                        handle
                        <emph type="bold">
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9512064">(Figure 6.44)</hotlnk>
                        </emph>
                        .
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9512064" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9512064.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Guide the connecting rod into place on the crankshaft.</para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
