<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-12-04 - Service Procedure Changes For Model GT 40 Turbochargers Used On All DT 408/466 and the
        International&#174; 530 Engines
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi951204" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>95-12-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Service Procedure Changes For Model GT 40 Turbochargers Used On All DT 408/466 and the
                International&#174; 530 Engines
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 408</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>The center housing and rotating assembly used on Model GT 40 turbochargers for all 408, 466 and The
                International&#174; 530 engines is serviced as a complete assembly only. Component parts for the center
                housing/rotating assembly previously released for service will not be available except, the backplate
                o-ring.
            </para>
            <para>The engine service manual (Form Nos. EGES-105 &#38; 105-1) addresses servicing turbocharger center
                housing/rotating assembly components. This procedure should be disregarded until the service manual is
                revised to reflect that these parts should not be serviced individually.
            </para>
            <para>Service parts for the turbocharger center housing/rotating assembly are listed in the following
                catalogs: Form Nos. PC-4000, PC-8000, MT-512A &#38; 1 171 657 R2. These parts should not be ordered. The
                part numbers will be omitted in the next revision.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>OTHER COMPONENT SERVICE PARTS THAT ARE NOT PART OF THE CENTER HOUSING/ROTATING ASSEMBLY FOR
                        MODEL GT 40 TURBOCHARGERS AS SHOWN IN THE PARTS CATALOGS ARE AVAILABLE FOR SERVICE.
                    </para>
                    <para>KEEP A COPY OF THIS SERVICE LETTER WITH THE SERVICE MANUAL AND CATALOG, AS A REMINDER, WHEN
                        SERVICING THE TURBOCHARGER
                        <emph type="underscr">DO NOT</emph>
                        DISASSEMBLE THE CENTER HOUSING AND ROTATING ASSEMBLY.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
