<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-12-01 - Engine Fan Continuously Runs</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi951201" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Engine Fan Continuously Runs</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Horton</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The Horton engine fan may continuously run on vehicles with a Detroit Diesel Series 60 or
                    Caterpillar electronic engine, with air conditioning, built before July 1, 1994, at Springfield and
                    July 27, 1994, at Chatham.
                </para>
                <para>This condition can be caused by the refrigerant high pressure switch staying open. The original
                    refrigerant switch was designed to be actuated with 12 volts. The 1994 engines use the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9512011">Electronic Control Module</hotlnk>
                    (ECM) to control the fan solenoid and the switch is operated at 5 volts instead of 12 volts. The
                    switch contacts can become dirty, due to the low voltage not cleaning the switch contact surfaces,
                    which causes the switch to provide an open circuit signal to the ECM. This causes the engine fan to
                    run continuously.
                </para>
                <para>Before replacing the refrigerant high pressure switch, part number 1697119C1 (green housing), the
                    wiring should be checked for shorts and/or opens. Disconnect wire no. (228) from the refrigerant
                    switch and check that wire no. 97-G/23-GB is connected to ground. Wire no. 23C/16BK connects back to
                    the ECM connector. If the wiring is okay, replace the refrigerant high pressure switch, part number
                    2035274C1 (red housing).
                </para>
                <para>Because of the possible detrimental effects of the fan drive being continuously engaged, it is
                    advisable to rebuild the fan clutch with a Horton Super Kit. The Horton kit part number is ZBH994273
                    and can be ordered through the Navistar parts distribution system.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9512011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9512011.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
