<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-13-01 - Spicer Production and Service Transmission Input Shaft 10 Tooth Spline Manufacturing Design
        Change
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi951301" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-13-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>TRANSMISSION</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Spicer Production and Service Transmission Input Shaft 10 Tooth Spline Manufacturing Design
                Change
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Spicer Service Topics Number 69</title>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the
                                supplier for use with its product. Navistar International Corp. reprints this
                                information based on representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or
                                supplier and is not responsible for any errors or untoward consequences resulting from
                                such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is urged to carefully follow
                                the instructions which accompany the product.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Objective</title>
                    <para>Call attention to change in appearance of subject 10 tooth spline created by elimination of
                        grinding the spline O.D.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Transmission Models Affected</title>
                    <para>All Spicer Current Production Transmission Assemblies and all Future Transmission Input Shaft
                        Service replacements.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Customer Concerns</title>
                    <para>Is the transmission input shaft 10 tooth spline O.D. machined correctly, because it is not
                        smooth and shiny as it was in previous years?
                    </para>
                    <para>What is the reason for the change in appearance of the transmission input shaft 10 tooth
                        spline O.D. compared to Spicer transmission input shafts manufactured in the past?
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Reasons For Change</title>
                    <para>All known clutch designs do not require that the transmission input shaft 10 tooth spline O.D.
                        have a ground smooth finish.
                    </para>
                    <para>Transmission input shaft 10 tooth spline O.D. grind operation is not necessary for the part or
                        the clutch to function properly.
                    </para>
                    <para>Grinding the transmission input shaft 10 tooth spline eliminated to facilitate
                        manufacturing.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Spline Design Change Location</title>
                    <para>See
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9513011">Figure 1</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9513011" figsize="full-pg">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9513011.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                    </figure>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>Subject manufacturing design change applies to all Spicer Transmission Input Shafts manufactured after
                approximately 5-1-95.
            </para>
        </partsinfo>
    </tsi>
</isis>
