<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-16-04 - Intermittent Air Conditioning Operation</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI951604" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-16-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>September, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Intermittent Air Conditioning Operation</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/05/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/05/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>12/05/1994</startdate>
                        <enddate>07/21/1995</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>2000, 4000 and 8000 Model vehicles built from December 5, 1994, through July 21, 1995, may have
                    intermittent Air Conditioning system operation between temperatures of 70 to 80 degrees F., and have
                    an operational A/C system when the vehicle is brought into the service center. Under these low
                    temperature conditions, the low side pressure may momentarily fall below the A/C low pressure switch
                    setting thereby disengaging the A/C compressor clutch. This automatically latches or holds the A/C
                    relay in the open position until the operator turns the ignition key off and on, or until the A/C
                    control switch is cycled. This condition does not exist on all vehicles. If a customer encounters
                    this condition, perform the following procedure to correct it.
                </para>
                <para>All vehicles built after July 21, 1995, will not exhibit this condition and will not require this
                    repair.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc id="S951604" svcproctype="proctype" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Refer to TSI-95-16-02 for information to service components in the Heater-A/C system on the above
                listed vehicles built after December 4, 1994.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the lower right instrument panel cover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516041">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9516041" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516041.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the lower relay panel mounting screws from the instrument panel (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516042">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9516042" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516042.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the air conditioning relay from the electrical harness plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the screw that fastens the relay harness plug to the relay panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a plug lock tool to remove the electrical harness plug lock tab. Pull the lock out
                    from the electrical harness plug.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Locate wire number 77L, which will be in plug position no. 4. Use tool to unlock
                    terminal tab and pull wire no. 77L and terminal out of the relay plug (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516043">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f9516043" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516043.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install electrical harness plug lock.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use electrical tape and tape wire 77L terminal that was removed from the harness plug.
                    Bend the wire back 180 degrees onto the harness and tape the wire to the harness assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install relay electrical harness plug on relay panel.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install relay in electrical harness plug.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install relay panel assembly on instrument panel (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516042">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install lower right side instrument panel cover (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516041">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate A/C system to confirm system operates properly.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>International Technical Letters are intended for professional technicians, NOT a "do-it-yourselfer."
                They are written to inform these technicians of conditions that may occur on some vehicles, or to
                provide information that could assist in the proper service of a vehicle. Properly trained technicians
                have the equipment, tools, safety instructions, and know-how to do a job properly and safely. DO NOT
                assume that the letter applies to your vehicle, or that your vehicle will have that condition. See your
                International dealer for information on whether your vehicle may benefit from the information. WE
                SUPPORT VOLUNTARY TECHNICIAN CERTIFICATION
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
