<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 95-16-01 - Changes to Air Conditioning Systems Using HFC-134a Refrigerant</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi951601" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>95-16-01</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>TSI-92-16-07</tsinumber>
            <tsinumber>TSI-92-16-07R</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>January, 1995</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Changes to Air Conditioning Systems Using HFC-134a Refrigerant</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/30/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/30/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/30/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/30/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">This TSI letter replaces TSI-92-16-07R dated August, 1992. Discard 92-16-07R.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">The purpose for the update to this TSI letter is to notify the field that Navistar
                        has changed the type of oil used in the air conditioning compressor. Effective approximately
                        February 1, 1995, the identification label on the compressor will list the new type of oil.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>The Federal Government has legislated a scheduled phase-out of the production of CFC-12 (R-12),
                    the refrigerant used in automotive and truck air conditioning systems. This action is in response to
                    discovery of the depleting effect of CFC-12 on the ozone layer, which allows increased ultraviolet
                    radiation to reach the earth's surface, causing a deterioration of ecological and health conditions.
                    In addition, CFC's are known to be one of the "greenhouse gases," a group of gases which are alleged
                    to be causing global warming.
                </para>
                <para>The automotive and truck industry has selected HFC-134a as the refrigerant to replace CFC-12
                    (R-12). The in-effect date for the use of HFC-134a in all vehicles produced by Navistar with air
                    conditioning is as follows for vehicles built at:
                </para>
                <para>Chatham - November 30, 1992</para>
                <para>Springfield - January 1, 1993.</para>
                <para>Converting to the new 134A refrigerant will require system and hardware changes. This letter
                    explains the differences between the current air conditioning system that uses R-12 refrigerant and
                    the new system that uses HFC-134a refrigerant. Precautions and changes in service procedures and
                    tools are also covered.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
            <title>VEHICLE CHANGES</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>The outward appearance of the air conditioning system that uses HFC-134a refrigerant has not
                    changed much, but the internal make-up is quite different from the current air conditioning system
                    that uses R-12 as the refrigerant. The changes are:
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>REFRIGERANT</title>
                <para>The new refrigerant (HFC-134a) has many of the same properties as R-12 and is similar in form and
                    function. However, HFC-134a is a hydrofluorocarbon (HFC) based refrigerant while R-12 is a
                    chlorofluorocarbon (CFC) based refrigerant. Because of the absence of chlorine in the molecular
                    structure of HFC-134a, the use of HFC-134a refrigerant will not have any harmful effects on the
                    ozone layer of the atmosphere. Because there is not enough evidence to determine the "greenhouse"
                    effect of HFC-134a, recycling of HFC-134a will be required.
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Due to the difference in density of HFC-134a, the amount of refrigerant required to charge
                            a typical air conditioning system has been reduced from 4.5 lbs. to 3.5 lbs.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Extensive testing by Navistar has determined that the performance of air conditioning
                            systems using HFC-134a is equal to or better than systems using R-12.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</title>
                <figure id="f9516011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516011.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The compressor for systems requiring the use of HFC-134a refrigerant is the same as is used with
                    systems requiring the use of R-12 except as follows:
                </para>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9516011">pressure relief valve</hotlnk>
                        that was on the receiver-dryer has been moved to the compressor. This will offer better
                        protection to the compressor in extreme high pressure.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The service port connections are a new type SAE standard metric quick-connect
                        fitting. This will require the use of a gauge set dedicated to the service of HFC-134a.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The compressor will be equipped with a tag that shows:</para>
                    <seqlist style="alphauc">
                        <item>
                            <para>Type of refrigerant to be used.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Quantity of refrigerant to be used.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Type of oil to be used.</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>REFRIGERANT OIL</title>
                <para>On vehicles built between November 30, 1992 and February 1, 1995, at Chatham and January 1, 1993,
                    and February 1, 1995, at Springfield, the refrigerant compressor was filled with PAG oil. Effective
                    approximately February 1, 1995, all refrigerant compressors will be filled with Lubrizol LZ2916
                    Ester Oil (Part# WTJ6914). If adding oil is necessary when servicing the air conditioning system, we
                    recommend that the PAG oil be drained from the compressor and refill it with Lubrizol LZ2916 Ester
                    Oil.
                </para>
                <para>Ester oil is compatible with mineral and PAG oil. When changing from mineral or PAG oil to Ester
                    oil, it is not necessary to flush the system unless it is contaminated.
                </para>
                <para>Be sure to observe the following:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>PAG oil can never be mixed with mineral oil and can only be used in HFC-134a systems.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Mineral oil can never be mixed with PAG oil and can only be used in R-12 systems.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Lubrizol LZ2816 Ester oil can be mixed with either mineral or PAG oil. It is permissible
                            to add Ester oil in small amounts to systems filled with either PAG or mineral oil.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Keep spare refrigerant oil in a sealed container. The oil draws moisture and will become
                            moisture contaminated if exposed to the atmosphere for any period of time.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>SYSTEM HOSES</title>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Hoses used with the HFC-134a type refrigerant air conditioning system are smaller in
                            diameter and are nylon lined.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Smaller size clips are used.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>When servicing air conditioning systems charged with HFC-134a refrigerant, be sure to
                            replace hoses with the type recommended for HFC-134a systems.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <para>
                    <title>Condenser</title>The condenser used in the new HFC-134a air conditioning system requires more
                    condensing capacity. To accomplish this, more fins have been added to the condenser. This will
                    require that closer attention be paid to keeping fins clean and straight.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>RECEIVER-DRYER</title>
                <figure id="f9516012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516012.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>The
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9516012">receiver-dryer</hotlnk>
                            used on the HFC-134a air conditioning system has a different desiccant material.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>On receiver-dryers used in production, the pressure relief valve has been removed and
                            moved to the compressor. Replacement receiver-dryers will have a relief valve.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The receiver-dryer used in production will be equipped with a service port. Replacement
                            receiver-dryers will not have the service port.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>DO NOT use a receiver-dryer designed for use on an R-12 air conditioning system on an
                            HFC-134a air conditioning system. The desiccant material will break down and plug the
                            system.
                            <emph type="underscr">The receiver-dryer designed for use on an HFC-134a air conditioning
                                system CAN be used on an R-12 system.
                            </emph>
                            The receiver-dryer provided by Navistar Service Parts will service both old and new systems.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>EXPANSION VALVE</title>
                <para>The expansion valve is different than the one used on R-12 air conditioning systems. The capillary
                    tube and sensing bulb are filled with HFC-134a.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>DO NOT use an expansion valve designed for an R-12 air conditioning system on an HFC-134a
                            system. Do not use an expansion valve designed for use on an HFC-134a air conditioning
                            system on an R-12 system.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>PRESSURE SWITCHES</title>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">Low Pressure Switch</emph>
                    function is the same as for R-12 Air Conditioning systems.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">High Pressure Safety Switch</emph>
                    has been added for HFC-134a air conditioning systems. 2000, 4000 and 8000 Models have this switch up
                    under the instrument panel near the unit assembly, next to the low pressure switch. 5000 and all
                    9000 Models have both the low pressure and high pressure switches in the heater/air conditioner box
                    under the passenger seat. The high pressure switch will disengage the A/C clutch when abnormally
                    high pressures (375 psi &#177; 20 psi) are reached.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>SHUTTER AND FAN ACTUATOR</title>
                <para>Both switches function the same for R-12 and HFC-134a air conditioning systems.</para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>EVAPORATOR</title>
                <para>The evaporator functions the same in both the R-12 and HFC-134a air conditioning systems.</para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>KEY COMPONENT IDENTIFICATION</title>
                <para>Navistar service parts: compressors, expansion valves and receiver-dryers will be clearly labeled
                    for use with HFC-134a systems.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATION</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>Operation of the R-12 and HFC-134a systems are the same. Pressures of both systems are the same.
                    Service information in GROUP 16 - CAB in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual applies to both systems,
                    <emph type="bold">EXCEPT AS STATED IN THIS LETTER.</emph>
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>SYSTEM FLUSHING</title>
                <para>At the present time, there is no flushing solution available for HFC-134a air conditioning
                    systems. R-11 and any other flushing solutions that are currently used to flush R-12 systems cannot
                    be used to flush HFC-134a systems.
                </para>
                <para>The residue left by these flushing products after flushing will destroy the lubrication properties
                    of the oil used in HFC-134a systems.
                </para>
                <para>The only procedure presently available to flush an HFC-134a air conditioning system is to pressure
                    flush with HFC-134a using a recycling system to capture the 134A flushed through the system.
                    Navistar will advise when acceptable flushing material has been developed and is available.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
            <title>SERVICE EQUIPMENT</title>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>MANIFOLD GAUGE SET AND SERVICE HOSES</title>
                <figure id="f9516013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516013.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                </figure>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>The
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9516013">manifold gauge set</hotlnk>
                            and service hoses
                            <emph type="bold">MUST BE DEDICATED</emph>
                            to and used only on air conditioning systems charged with HFC-134a refrigerant. If the oil
                            that is in the hoses and gauges used to service R-12 charged air conditioning systems is
                            introduced into the HFC-134a charged air conditioning system, the oil from the R-12 manifold
                            gauge set will cause the HFC-134a system to function poorly and eventually may cause
                            compressor failure.
                            <emph type="bold">DO NOT USE THE SAME MANIFOLD GAUGE SET ON BOTH SYSTEMS.</emph>
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>The fittings on the service hoses for HFC-134a air conditioning systems are standard SAE
                            Metric quick-connect fittings that will work only on HFC-134a air conditioning systems.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>RECYCLING AND CHARGING EQUIPMENT</title>
                <figure id="f9516014" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516014.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516014">recycling and charging equipment</hotlnk>
                    for HFC-134a charged air conditioning systems
                    <emph type="bold">MUST BE DEDICATED</emph>
                    to HFC-134a air conditioning systems.
                </para>
                <para>The oil and refrigerant are different for HFC-134a and R-12 systems and
                    <emph type="bold">CANNOT</emph>
                    be interchanged. If the same recycling and charging equipment is used for both HFC-134a and R-12
                    systems, both systems will experience failures which will be expensive to repair.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>VACUUM PUMP</title>
                <para>Vacuum pumps can be used on both the R-12 and HFC-134a air conditioning systems. The mineral oil
                    in the pump should not affect the HFC-134a refrigerant system.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>LEAK DETECTOR</title>
                <figure id="f9516015" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9516015.webp" type="webp" resolution="100"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Navistar has a
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9516015">leak detector</hotlnk>
                    listed in its Service Tool Catalog for HFC-134a refrigerant. It is recommended that this one be used
                    to detect leaks in HFC-134a air conditioning systems. A number of leak detector manufacturers
                    advertise leak detectors for HFC-134a air conditioning systems. Due to the broad variance in
                    performance, it is recommended that you request a demonstration of the detector before you make a
                    purchase.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
