<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-04-01 - Replacing a Bendix M-21 Antilock Modulator Assembly With An M-22 Antilock Modulator
        Assembly
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI960401" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-04-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>June, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Replacing a Bendix M-21 Antilock Modulator Assembly With An M-22 Antilock Modulator Assembly
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with ABS brakes built before September, 1995.</para>
                <para>All vehicles with Bendix ABS brakes built before September, 1995 were supplied with an M-21
                    Antilock Modulator Assembly. In September 1995, Navistar changed from the Bendix M-21 to the Bendix
                    M-22 Antilock Modulator Assembly. They differ in that the supply and delivery ports are on opposite
                    sides and the timing of the two assemblies is different. The exhaust ports on both modulators must
                    be directed toward the road surface when mounted on the vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>PHYSICAL DIFFERENCE</title>
                </para>
                <para>The physical difference between the two valves is the M-21 has the electrical connector on the
                    delivery port side of the assembly, and the M-22 has it on the supply port side of the assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9604011">Figure 1</hotlnk>). On the M-21 assembly, the delivery and supply ports
                    are in the lower half of the assembly.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9604011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9604011.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>On the M-22 assembly, the two ports are located in the upper half of the assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9604011">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The I.D. label is on the side of the M-21 and it's
                    located on the bottom of the M-22 assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9604011">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>OPERATIONAL DIFFERENCE</title>
                </para>
                <para>Both assemblies function basically the same. The only difference between the two assemblies is
                    they are timed differently.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When one M-21 assembly needs to be replaced on an axle, it will be necessary to replace
                            both assemblies ON THE SAME AXLE with new M-22 assemblies because of the difference in
                            timing between the M-21 and the M-22.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>MOUNTING DIFFERENCE</title>
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The wire harness must not be STRAINED. A two inch radius must be maintained in the harness
                            to assure it will not pull out of the connector or allow water to enter the connector. Early
                            faults can be expected if the wire harness does not have adequate strain relief.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The position of the supply port, delivery port, and exhaust port determine how the
                            modulator must be mounted, NOT THE ELECTRICAL CONNECTOR.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>
                    <title>Rear Axles</title>
                </para>
                <para>It will be possible to mount the M-22 assemblies in place of the M-21 assemblies without any
                    modification to the M-21 mounting brackets. When mounting the M-22, be sure the exhaust port is
                    facing down. The electrical connector will need to be routed around to the opposite side to connect
                    to the M-22 assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9604011">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>Front Axle</title>
                </para>
                <para>Because the Quick Release Valves are connected to the Modulator Assemblies, it will be necessary
                    to drill out or file the mounting holes in the old M-21 mounting brackets to mount the new M-22
                    assemblies. When mounting the M-22, be sure the exhaust port is facing down. The electrical
                    connector will need to be routed around to the opposite side to connect to the M-22 assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9604011">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <para>For a detailed Description, Operation, Maintenance and Service Procedure for both Modulator
                    Assemblies, refer to CTS-5247 in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
