<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-06-01 - Spicer Life Series SPL-170 and SPL-250 Propeller Shafts</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi960601" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-06-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>PROPELLER SHAFT</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Spicer Life Series SPL-170 and SPL-250 Propeller Shafts</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Effective October 1996, the Spicer Life Series SPL-170 and SPL-250 propeller shafts will become
                    available on 2000, 8000 and 9000 Models. Features include permanently lubricated slip joint and
                    extended lubrication cycle for the U-joint (100,000 miles in line-haul applications). U-Joint Kit
                    bearing and seal designs have been improved for extended service life.
                </para>
                <para>During scheduled maintenance, it is important to recognize the SPL series from greaseable
                    propeller shafts to prevent premature failure due to lack of lubrication.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>SPICER LIFE SERIES</title>
                </para>
                <para>SPL-170 and SPL-250 propeller shafts have a boot over the slip spline and no grease zerk (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9606011">Figure 1</hotlnk>). The factory grease fill is permanent and does not need
                    to be replenished. The U-joint has a zerk fitting and is to be lubricated at 100,000 mile intervals
                    for line-haul applications and 25,000 miles for off-highway and city service, following the
                    recommendations in Group 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual. Additionally, the
                    stamped bearing straps have been replaced with machined bearing straps for increased durability (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9606012">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Strap mounting bolts are tightened to 100 to 120
                    ft-lbs. (135 to 160 Nm) of torque. The spring straps on tube yokes are tightened to 25 to 30 ft-lbs.
                    (35 to 40 Nm) of torque (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9606013">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9606011" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9606011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9606012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9606012.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9606013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9606013.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>
                    <title>GREASABLE SERIES</title>
                </para>
                <para>All greaseable propeller shafts follow the lubrication intervals and recommendations listed in
                    Group 10 - LUBRICATION in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
