<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-08-04 - Operation of the Hall Effect Stop Light and Brake Booster Pump Switch</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI960804" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-08-04</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Operation of the Hall Effect Stop Light and Brake Booster Pump Switch</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to the 3000RE bus with hydraulic brakes.</para>
                <para>As a result of the release of the new 3000RE bus with hydraulic brakes, Navistar has incorporated
                    a Hall Effect stop light and brake booster pump switch. The Hall Effect switch is an electronic
                    device which generates a voltage signal controlled by the presence, absence or strength of a
                    magnetic field (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9608041">Figure 1</hotlnk>). This switch is located under the floor at the brake
                    pedal.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9608041" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9608041.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>When the pedal mounted magnet is moved away from the switch, the switch closes and the switched
                    circuit goes to ground. When the Hall Effect switch goes to ground, both stop light relays are then
                    grounded and the relays close. Refer to the circuit diagram (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9608042">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f9608042" figsize="full-pg">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9608042.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PROPER HYDRAULIC BRAKE SYSTEM ELECTRICAL OPERATION</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>With Ignition OFF and Brake Pedal Not Applied</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake lights must be OFF</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake booster pump must be OFF</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With Ignition OFF and Brake Pedal Applied (Light Pressure)</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake light must go ON</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake booster pump must RUN</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With Ignition ON - Engine Not Running - Brake Pedal Not Applied</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake lights must NOT BE ON</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake booster pump must RUN with warning lamp and buzzer ON</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With Engine Running and Pedal Not Applied</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake lights must NOT BE ON</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake booster pump, warning lamp and buzzer must NOT BE ON</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With Engine Running and Brake Pedal Applied</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake light must come ON</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Brake booster pump, warning lamp and buzzer must NOT BE ON unless there is a fault in
                                the brake or power steering hydraulic system.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DIAGNOSTICS</title>
            <para>If the brake system does not operate as described above, the Hall Effect switch may be out of
                adjustment. With the brake pedal released, the air gap between the end of the switch and the magnet
                should be .100 to .200 inch. Adjustment may be made by backing off the lock nut and screwing the switch
                in or out as required to get the proper air gap. With key OFF, brake booster pump motor must come on
                with light foot pressure; make appropriate adjustment.
            </para>
            <para>To determine if the Hall Effect switch is defective, do the following: Refer to circuit diagram (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9608042">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Disconnect connector 209 and check voltage at terminal "A"
                of harness side of connector. If there is no voltage at terminal "A," check wiring and fuse. At pin "C,"
                insure that the circuit goes to ground. Check "B" to insure that there is voltage present; if not, check
                relays, wiring and fuses. Ground "B," pump must come on. If pump does not come on, check relay, wiring
                and pump.
            </para>
            <para>Reconnect connector 209. With magnet away from switch face (more than .200 inch), pump must be on.
                With magnet brought close to Hall Effect switch (.100 inch or less), pump must not be on. If the above
                does not occur, replace Hall Effect switch.
            </para>
            <para>For complete electrical diagnostic procedures for the hydraulic brake system, refer to CTS-5190 in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
