<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-08-03 - Diagnostic Table Change</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi960803" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-08-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>February, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Diagnostic Table Change</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Navistar has changed from diagnostic flow charts to diagnostic tables in the CTS-5000 Master
                    Service Manual. The introduction of diagnostic tables is another way that Navistar is improving
                    service publications to further assist technicians. These tables follow a logical diagnostic
                    strategy which helps you to diagnose correctly and quickly.
                </para>
                <para>These tests are designed in a way that will lead to an accurate diagnosis of the problem in as few
                    steps as possible.
                </para>
                <para>The diagnostic charts are set up to be used in a sequential step by step manner. Starting at step
                    one and following the steps in sequence ensures a valid test. Do not skip steps unless instructed to
                    do so by the YES-IN SPEC., or NO-OUT OF SPEC. column.
                </para>
                <para>To use the table, go to step one in the left hand column. Continue to the second column and
                    observe whether the ignition key should be ON or OFF. Turn the ignition key to the position
                    indicated in the table. Perform the operation asked for in the ACTION column at the points listed in
                    the TEST POINTS column.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Use the Circuit Diagram Manual listed on the front of the Electrical Troubleshooting
                            Manual you are using for the diagnoses. The test points are shown on the circuit diagram for
                            the condition being tested. Circuit diagrams are no longer duplicated in the Electrical
                            Troubleshooting Manuals.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The results of the test are then compared against the specification in the SPEC. column, and the
                    appropriate action is taken based on whether the test results fall within the YES-IN SPEC., or
                    NO-OUT OF SPEC. column.
                </para>
                <para>When comparing measurements (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9608031">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9608032">Figure 2</hotlnk>) to the SPEC. column, the ">" symbol means that the
                    measurement or reading should be greater than the value listed. The "&#60;" symbol means that the
                    measurement or reading should be less than the value listed.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9608031" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9608031.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Sample</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9608032" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9608032.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2. Sample</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
