<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-08-08 - Operation and Adjustment of the New Design Stop Light/Brake Booster Switch</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi960808" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-08-08</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Operation and Adjustment of the New Design Stop Light/Brake Booster Switch</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to 3600, 3800, 4700 and 4900 models with hydraulic brakes.</para>
                <para>Effective May 15, 1995, 4700 and 4900 Models and effective August 5, 1996, 3600 and 3800 Models
                    use a new design switch to control the stop light and brake booster function. The new switch design
                    replaced the individual stop light and brake booster switches.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>BRAKE SYSTEM ELECTRICAL OPERATION</title>
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>With Ignition Off and Brake Pedal Not Applied</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Stop lights must be Off</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake booster pump must be Off</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With Ignition Off and Brake Pedal Applied (light pressure)</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Stop lights must be On</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake booster pump must Run</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With Ignition On, Engine Not Running and Brake Pedal Not Applied</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Stop lights must Not be On</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake booster pump must Run with warning lamp and buzzer On</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With Engine Running and Brake Pedal Not Applied</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Stop lights must Not be On</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake booster pump, warning lamp and buzzer must Not be On</para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>With Engine Running and Brake Pedal Applied</para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>Stop lights must come On</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Brake booster pump, warning lamp and buzzer must Not be On unless there is a fault
                                    in the brake or power steering hydraulic system
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>If the brake system does not operate as described, the stop light/brake booster switch may be out of
                adjustment.
            </para>
            <para>To adjust the switch, push down on the brake pedal and hold the pedal down. With the pedal down, pull
                the plunger out of the switch about 1 inch toward the brake pedal (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9608081">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Slowly release the brake pedal and the switch will self
                adjust. Make sure that the switch cannot rotate and is held in place by the tab on the switch bracket.
                If the switch rotates, bend the tab as required to lock the switch in position.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9608081" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9608081.webp" type="webp" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not pull the brake pedal up by hand. Doing so could misadjust the switch.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Also check to see if brake pedal moves down slightly when the engine is started. If it does, there is
                a problem with the power steering fluid flow system. Refer to the appropriate power steering manual for
                diagnostic information. If this condition exists, the stop switch cannot be properly adjusted until the
                power steering system is repaired.
            </para>
            <para>When adjusting the stop light switch by pulling out the plunger, the plunger should take 7 to 20
                pounds of force to pull the plunger out. If the force to pull out the plunger is below 7 pounds, replace
                the switch.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
