<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-12-10 - Removal and Installation of Molded Glass-Filled Tanks on Modine Radiators</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi961210" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-12-10</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Removal and Installation of Molded Glass-Filled Tanks on Modine Radiators</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Modine</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>
                    <title>NOTICE</title>
                </para>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or untoward consequences resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product.
                    Every user is urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
            <title>AD-TECH RADIATOR SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR NAVISTAR INTERNATIONAL TRUCKS</title>
            <para>
                <title>MODINE TANK TO HEADER SYSTEM</title>
            </para>
            <para>The radiator tanks are molded glass-filled nylon and are secured to the core header by Side-lock
                latching strips.
            </para>
            <para>(See
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9612101">Figure 1</hotlnk>)
            </para>
            <figure id="f9612101" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612101.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
            <title>TANK REMOVAL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble header support frame around core and position five L clamps along the tank and
                    header support frame as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612102">Figure 2</hotlnk>. If so desired the header support frame can be
                    constructed as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f961210a">Figure 10</hotlnk>
                    or purchased from Johnson Manufacturing Company. See "special service tools and equipment" section.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hand tighten L clamps evenly until the Side-lock latching strips become loose enough to
                    be removed by hand or with the aid of a small screwdriver. Excessive torque is not required.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>To prevent header distortion it is very important that the header be completely supported
                            on all four sides (See
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9612102">Figure 2</hotlnk>). For cores smaller than 28.56" one end of the
                            header support frame must be positioned up to the core support under the header. The other
                            end of the header is supported by sliding the adjustable header end support (See
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f961210a">Figure 10</hotlnk>) up to the core support under the header.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f9612102" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612102.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 2.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The radiator is equipped with Side-lock latching strips (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612103">Figure 3</hotlnk>) and retainers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612107">Figure 7</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612108">Figure 8</hotlnk>). To remove the retainer, pry outward on the bottom to
                    disengage the retainer teeth from the header slot, then pull the retainer upward as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612108">Figure 8</hotlnk>. After the retainers are removed, the Side-lock latching
                    strips are removed by tapping the strip lo the left with a screw driver and hammer until the tabs of
                    the strip can easily be pulled out of the header slots. (6 strips and 4 retainers per header).
                    Discard the old strips and retainers
                </para>
                <figure id="f9612103" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612103.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 3.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen and remove header clamps and header support frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift tank from the core header.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the O-ring seal from the header. Discard the old O-ring seal.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="tsiproc" graphiccount="7">
            <title>TANK INSTALLATION</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the sealing surface of the radiator core header to be sure it is clean and free
                    of foreign material or damage.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dip the new O-ring in fresh glycol and place the gasket in the header groove.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the tank to the header using caret not to scratch the tank sealing surfaces. Be
                    sure the top and bottom of the tank is positioned properly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clamp the tank in position on the header with five (5) L clamps and header support frame
                    as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612102">Figure 2</hotlnk>. Tighten the header clamps to compress the O-ring gasket
                    until the Side-lock latching strips can be inserted by hand.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>There are four different length Side lock latching strips, see
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f9612104">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>For a 26.5" header each side requires assembly with one 16 tab strip and one 21 tab strip. The 3
                    tab strips are for assembly at header ends. For a 29.2" header a 20 tab strip is required instead of
                    a 16 tab strip.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9612104" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612104.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert Side-lock latching strips, making sure all tabs are positioned into header slots.
                    Tap strips to the right using a screw driver and hammer as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612105">Figure 5</hotlnk>. This tapping locks the new strip Into place. When fully
                    engaged there will be an opening in the left hand edge of the header slot, see
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612106">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9612105" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612105.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9612106" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612106.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the header clamps and header support from the header core.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lock the Side-lock latching strips in place with retainers. Install (1) retainer between
                    the 21-tab strip and the 16-tab (or 20-tab) strip (2 per header), and (1) retainer at each 3-tab
                    strip (2 per header) as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612107">Figure 7</hotlnk>. When installing the retainers, hook the top of the
                    retainer over the header flange, then pull down as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612108">Figure 8</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9612107" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612107.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7.</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f9612108" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612108.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8.</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>The teeth of the retainer must be fully engaged into the header slot at the opening to the left of
                    the latching strip tab as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9612109">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9612109" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9612109.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9.</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>At the center of the header, (1) retainer is used to lock (2) latching strips.</para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f961210a" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g961210a.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10.</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DRAINCOCK/VENT FITTING REMOVAL AND INSTALLATION</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>The draincock and vent fitting are in the plastic tank and can be replaced without disassembling
                    the radiator.
                </para>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Removal</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Turn the stern counter/clockwise to unscrew the stem. When the stem is unscrewed to
                        the end of the threads, pull the stem from the radiator tank and body.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the retainer body from the radiator tank by squeezing the sides together with
                        a pair of needlenose pliers. Then, pull the retainer body from the tank.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Installation</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove retainer body from draincock or vent fitting stem.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Snap retainer body into radiator tank.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Snap draincock or vent fitting into retainer body.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Tighten draincock or vent fitting by turning clockwise. Tighten to 2.0 - 7.7 N&#8226;m
                        (18 - 25 in - lb.).
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>RADIATOR CORE REPAIR</title>
            <para>The Ad Tech radiator core is of copper-brass construction and can be repaired by using the usual good
                radiator shop repair procedures for this type of radiator core. Note, however, that heat must be kept
                from the header/gasket/tank area, unless the plastic tank is first removed from the radiator core.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not attempt to dean an Ad Tech radiator core using caustic cleaning solutions unless the
                        plastic tanks are first removed. Immersing the plastic tanks in a caustic cleaning solution can
                        damage the tanks and O-ring gaskets.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SPECIAL SERVICE TOOLS AND EQUIPMENT</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>No. 421-CS: Support frame and clamp kit, Complete. (Includes 5 clamps).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No. 421-03: L-Clamp, single with flat and curved pressure pad.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>No. 421-01: Header support frame. U-Channel style.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Above can be ordered from:</para>
                    <para>Johnson Manufacturing Company</para>
                    <para>P.O. Box 96</para>
                    <para>Princeton, IA 52768</para>
                    <para>(319) 289-5123</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
