<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-12-25 - Charge Air Cooler Leak Testing</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi961225" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-12-25</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>October, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Charge Air Cooler Leak Testing</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>When a low engine power complaint is encountered and a leak in the charge air cooler is suspected,
                    you must leak test the Charge Air Cooler (CAC).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Charge air coolers are not designed to be 100% air tight and leak free. The charge air
                            cooler is not defective if it leaks less than 5 psi in 15 seconds, from a start of 30 psi.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>If testing indicates the Charge Air Cooler is leaking beyond the allowable specification, replace
                    the CAC. Do not attempt to repair the CAC, because field repair is difficult and will void the CAC
                    warranty.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>Charge Air Cooler units returned for warranty will be tested 100%. Any units which meet
                            leak rate will be rejected for warranty reimbursement!
                        </para>
                        <para>To test the CAC, it is not usually necessary to remove it from the chassis, but you will
                            need compressed air and a Charge Air Cooler Test Kit.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>If your shop does not have a Charge Air Cooler Test Kit (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9612251">Figure 1</hotlnk>), it is possible to fabricate one, or you may purchase a
                Test Kit through the Navistar tool program.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9612251" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9612251.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="432px" resolution="150"/>
                <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HOSE CLAMP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. EXHAUST (HOT SIDE) HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INTAKE (COLD SIDE) HOSE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. GAUGE COUPLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. SAFETY CHAIN</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. GAUGE - REGULATOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. QUICK DISCONNECT FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. BLEED-OFF COUPLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. QUICK DISCONNECT FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. AIR VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. AIR GAUGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. BLEED-OFF VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. CHARGE AIR COOLER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <table id="t9612251">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>ZTSE-4341</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Charge Air Cooler Test Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
            <title>CAC PRESSURE DECAY TEST</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove piping, hump hoses and clamps from the charge air cooler system. The charge air
                    cooler can remain in the chassis for this test. Existing hump hoses and clamps on the Charge Air
                    Cooler itself will be used for this test. Double clamp all hump hose connections and tighten all
                    constant torque hose clamps to 100 in-lbs.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>To prevent possible injury from test adapters blowing off, secure safety chains on test
                            adapters to any convenient bolt. Always remain out of line with the test adapters while
                            performing the test and when the system is pressurized.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Doublecheck all connections to verify that all joints are tight. Close air pressure
                    regulator and drain valve before beginning test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Begin test by slowly opening air pressure regulator until test pressure reaches 30 psi.
                    When 30 psi test pressure has been reached, close the air pressure regulator.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not exceed 40 psi air pressure at any time, as excessive pressure can cause adapters to
                            blow off which may result in injury or damage the cooler.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Monitor pressure gauge and determine rate of pressure decay with a stopwatch. System
                    pressure should not drop more than 5 psi in 15 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After testing, open the drain valve to release pressure. If pressure drop exceeds 5 psi
                    in 15 seconds, re-check all connections.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a leaky connection is found, tighten the connection and repeat the test. If the leak
                    is within the charge air cooler, repeat the test as many times as necessary to verify the reading.
                    Similar pressure decay readings should be obtained on at least three consecutive tests to verify the
                    reading.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">
                    <emph type="bold">If pressure decay does not exceed 5 psi in 15 seconds, the charge air cooler is
                        within acceptable performance limits and should not be replaced.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>For more detailed service information, refer to CTS -5087.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
