<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-12-14 - Instructions to Install a T 444E Engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi961214" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-12-14</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Instructions to Install a T 444E Engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to 1000, 3000, and 4000 Series models with standard torque T 444E engines.</para>
                <para>As recently announced, the engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device became standard equipment on all
                    standard torque T 444E engines effective 7/15/96. This device will provide faster engine warm-up and
                    will allow the engine to maintain higher engine temperatures during extended idling conditions in
                    cold weather. It is also recommended that engine rpm be set at 1250 rpm using the Electronic Hand
                    Throttle during extended idling conditions in cold weather. The engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device
                    can be retrofitted to any standard torque T 444E engine (engine codes 12NHW, 12NHZ, 12NHX, 12NJA,
                    12NDX, and 12NHS). The engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device cannot be used on T 444E High Torque
                    engines. Procedures for retrofitting an Electronic Hand Throttle can be found in TSI-96-12-15.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <para>The following parts are required for equipping the T 444E engine with an exhaust back pressure device.
                This feature requires use of an ambient temperature sensor. An ambient temperature sensor already exists
                in vehicles built September 29, 1994 and later.
            </para>
            <table id="t9612141">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="2in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1.5in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1699804C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>EBP Kit</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1814320C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Sensor IAT - Trucks Built Prior to 9/29/94</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2000848C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Harness, EBP Engine - Trucks Built Prior to 9/29/94</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>2035252C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Harness, EBP Engine - Trucks Built After 9/29/94</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <para>Trucks built prior to 9/29/94 need a new air intake pipe unless the truck is equipped with an air
                compressor. If your truck is equipped with an air compressor, use a "T" fitting for sensor installation.
            </para>
            <table id="t9612142">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="1.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="2in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="1.5in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Number</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Part Description</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Quantity</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3505038C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 4000</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>2037170C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 4000 LPX</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3505038C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 3800</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3505041C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 3600</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3505043C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 1652 UPS</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3505041C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pipe, Air Intake - 1652</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>0444150</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>"T" Fitting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
            <stitle>TSI 96-12-14 - Instructions to Install a T 444E Engine Exhaust Back Pressure Device</stitle>
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Refer to TSI-94-08-05 for reprogramming procedures to turn on the Exhaust Back Pressure Device
                feature. If Tech Central assistance is required, call 1-800-336-4500.
            </para>
            <para>Installation of the Exhaust Back Pressure Device (EBPD) can be performed on all engines except high
                torque ratings. Refer to the parts lists for required parts needed for installation of EBPD on your
                specific model and build date.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of the turbocharger - Refer to EGES 120 Section 2 page 5.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Removal of the turbo pedestal and exhaust outlet - Refer to EGES 120 Section 2 page
                    11.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Installation of the EBPD control valve and pedestal - Refer to EGES 120 Section 2 page
                    17.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Installation of the turbocharger - Refer to EGES 120 Section 2 page 18.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If required, install the new air intake pipe from the air cleaner to the turbo inlet. If
                    the truck has an air compressor, remove the air compressor intake hose fitting from the air intake
                    pipe and install T-fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If required, install the new air temperature sensor in the air intake pipe.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the plug on the front of the right exhaust manifold and install fitting
                    1822713C1.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install EBP sensor bracket onto the top of the front cover high pressure reservoir.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the EBP sensor into the sensor bracket.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the EBP tube between the sensor bracket and the right hand exhaust manifold
                    fitting.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the IDM dash harness on the outside of the cab routing to the IDM, ECM, and the
                    engine connector locate the EBPD harness breakout (6 pin connector 410) located below the "T" in the
                    harness. Connect the EBPD overlay harness to this connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Route the EBPD overlay harness down inboard side of the left cylinder head and connect
                    connector (411) to the EBP solenoid valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If required, connect connector (390) to the air temperature sensor located in the air
                    intake pipe.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Routing the EBPD overlay harness on the left cylinder head, remove one of the glow plug
                    controller mounting bolts and remove all paint from this surface and install eyelet for ground.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Route the overlay harness over the front cover high pressure reservoir and connect
                    connector (409) to the EBPD sensor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure harness in place and inspect routing to insure it is free of abrasions and
                    obstructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a service tool (Pro-Link) turn the exhaust back pressure feature ON by one of the
                    following steps that applies to the vintage of your vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>Using the Pro-Link, scroll to the end of the data stream and determine your VPM Ver. #. This will
                    indicate 2.000 or 2.001 and greater.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">VPM Ver. 2000</emph>
                    will need a new password from Tech Central. Before calling, you will need to find the following
                    information for Tech Central to give you a new password. 1. VPM s/n (This can be found at the end of
                    the data stream) 2. ID # (This can be found at the end of the data stream) 3. Total tattle tales
                    (This can be found in the password and audit menu).
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">VPM Ver. 2.001 and greater</emph>
                    use four zeros (0000) for password. If this does not work, the password may have been reset by
                    dealer or customer. Call Tech Central for VPM reprogramming if password cannot be found.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the operation of the exhaust back pressure device by performing the engine running
                    diagnostic test.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check and clear all codes when complete.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
