<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-12-29 - Cold Weather Operation of International Engines</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi961229" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-12-29</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Cold Weather Operation of International Engines</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>1000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies 1000, 2000, 3000, 4000, 5000, and 8000 with International engines.</para>
                <para>Service personnel should be aware that the following language will be incorporated into the next
                    revision of the Operators Manual for the above models.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <title>COLD WEATHER OPERATION for International Engines</title>
                </para>
                <para>Diesel engines are highly efficient. Very little fuel is used at idle and prolonged low rpm idling
                    in cold weather can cause a diesel engine not to reach normal operating temperature. This in turn
                    can cause a build-up of heavy deposits of carbon and varnish on valve stems, which can cause valves
                    to stick, resulting in substantial valve train damage. When operating in extremely cold ambient
                    temperatures, these conditions become increasingly worse.
                </para>
                <para>The following cold weather idling guidelines must be followed:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Avoid extended idling (beyond 10 minutes) whenever possible.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Use a minimum 45 Cetane diesel fuel or utilize Cetane index improvers from a reputable
                            manufacturer.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Maintain a minimum of 1250 idle rpm by use of the Hand Throttle.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Maintain engine cooling system.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>For school buses: Shut off rear heater fans until bus is being driven.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Do not shut engine down after extended idling but rather drive the vehicle under load for
                            several miles at normal operating temperature to burn off any accumulated varnish and
                            carbon.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Consider use of engine block heaters, approved winterfronts and/or radiator shutters where
                            conditions warrant.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
