<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 96-16-01 - Air Conditioning Compressor Clutch Coil Mounting Bolts</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi961601" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>96-16-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1996</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CAB</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Air Conditioning Compressor Clutch Coil Mounting Bolts</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>To improve the air conditioning clutch coil mounting on all vehicles with air conditioning built
                    before December 30, 1995, Navistar has released a service kit that contains clutch coil mounting
                    bolts that have an improved self-locking device. The kit also contains two clutch pulley mounting
                    bolts and a hardened flat washer to be used with the pulley mounting bolt. If the clutch coil
                    mounting bolts are loose, Navistar recommends that they be replaced with the bolts in this service
                    kit.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9616011">
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="sqcolumn1" colwidth="2.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="sqcolumn2" colwidth="2.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="sqcolumn3" colwidth="2in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>1699459C91</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Kit, Clutch Coil Mounting</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove air conditioning compressor belt.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove compressor clutch pulley.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It will not be possible to remove and install the clutch coil mounting bolts without removing
                        the pulley because there is not enough clearance between the back of the pulley and the coil
                        mounting plate.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clutch coil mounting bolts.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Inspect the clutch coil mounting bolt holes to make sure the threads are not damaged or the
                        holes elongated. If the clutch coil mounting bolt hole threads are damaged, the air conditioning
                        compressor will have to be replaced. If the clutch coil mounting plate is bent or the mounting
                        holes are elongated, the clutch coil will have to be replaced.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mount the clutch coil to the air conditioning compressor with the four self-locking
                    bolts in the service kit. Tighten to 15 to 17 ft-lbs. (180 to 204 in-lbs.) (20 to 23 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the clutch pulley with one of the new pulley mounting bolts and the hardened
                    flat washer from the service kit. Tighten to 20 to 25 ft-lbs. (27 to 34 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The 1-1/2 inch bolt should be used with a V belt pulley and the 1-3/4 inch bolt should be used
                        with a serpentine belt pulley.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the belt and tension to 130 lbs. initially. Run the engine with the air
                    conditioning system engaged. Retension the belt to 100 lbs. after initial belt wear in.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
