<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-02-01R - Rockwell Front Steer Axles With Unitized Wheel Hub Assemblies, Navistar Code 02ARK and
        02ARL
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi970201r" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-02-01R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>97-02-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>May, 2000</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>FRONT AXLE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Rockwell Front Steer Axles With Unitized Wheel Hub Assemblies, Navistar Code 02ARK and 02ARL
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Rockwell</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>02ARK</ucode>
                <ucode>02ARL</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The subject axles are equipped with unitized wheel hubs that are lubricated (greased) for life.
                    They should not be inspected at pre-delivery for lubricant or bearing end play.
                </para>
                <para>The Rockwell unitized wheel hub can be identified by the threaded grease cap.</para>
                <para>The bearings and seals in the unitized wheel hub are not serviceable. The unitized wheel hub must
                    be replaced as an assembly.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="1">
            <title>INSPECT UNITIZED WHEEL HUB</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>Inspect the unitized wheel hub for end play every 200,000 miles or 24 months.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Do not work under a vehicle supported by a jack. Jacks can slip or fall over causing
                            personal injury. Always use safety stands.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Periodic Inspection Procedure</title>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Set parking brake. Place wheel blocks in front and behind each rear wheel. Place
                        safety stands under the front axle. Raise the front end so that the front wheel is off the
                        ground. Remove the wheel and tire.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Remove the hub cap.</para>
                </step1>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>As the unitized wheel hub warms up during operation, a small amount of grease will purge
                            out the outboard dust seal as pressure is released from inside the hub unit. This is normal.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Attach a dial indicator with magnetic base to the end of the axle spindle. Place the
                        indicator stem in contact with the wheel pilot on the unitized wheel hub.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Set the dial indicator to zero ("0").</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Rotate the wheel in both directions while pushing inward until the dial indicator
                        reading remains constant. Record the reading.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">Repeat Step 5 while pulling outward. Record the reading.</para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">The difference between the two readings is end play and should be .003 to .009
                        inch.
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If the end play is out of specification, verify the torque on the inner wheel
                        bearing nut. The tightening specification is 500 to 700 ft-lbs. (678 to 949 Nm) of torque (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9702011">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </step1>
                <figure id="f9702011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9702011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Verify Torque</caption>
                </figure>
                <step1>
                    <para count="1">If correct end play cannot be achieved, the unitized wheel hub must be replaced.
                    </para>
                </step1>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
