<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-03-03 - Hendrickson HN Suspension Rebound Control Adjustment</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi970303" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-03-03</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>July, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>SPRINGS</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Hendrickson HN Suspension Rebound Control Adjustment</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Hendrickson</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>2000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>5000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer for use with its product.
                    Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information based on representations made
                    to the Company by the manufacturer and is not responsible for any errors or mishaps resulting from
                    such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is urged to carefully follow the
                    instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
            <title>Hendrickson Technical Publication</title>
            <para>HN Series</para>
            <para>No: 17730-223</para>
            <para>SUBJECT: HN Rebound Control Adjustment</para>
            <para>DATE: May 1995 Revision: B</para>
            <para>The following procedure is to acquaint and assist maintenance personnel when adjustment to the rebound
                control assembly is required.
            </para>
            <para>For proper suspension performance, the rebound control assembly as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9703031">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                should be adjusted so that the threaded washer contacts the rebound spring when the vehicle is empty.
                The adjustment must be made after the body is installed, and during an empty vehicle condition. If the
                vehicle is equipped with lift axle(s), they must be in the raised position during this procedure. After
                the adjustment is complete tighten the jam nut to 17-23 foot pounds torque.
            </para>
            <para>The adjustable rebound bumper assembly prevents the overextension of the bolster springs during empty
                vehicle operation.
            </para>
            <para>If it is required to replace the rebound control assembly the following procedure is recommended.
                Remove the rebound spring control rod jam nut, threaded washer, and rebound control spring. Remove the
                rebound bumper control rod clevis locknut and bolt, and remove the control rod and clevis assembly.
            </para>
            <para>Install the rebound spring control rod and clevis through the saddle bracket and position the clevis
                on the equalizing beam mounting tab.
                <emph type="bold">Install the clevis bolt and locknut. Tighten the locknut but do not pinch clevis up
                    tight. The clevis must be free to rotate.</emph>Install the new rebound spring, threaded washer, and
                jam nut on control rod above the saddle bracket. Tighten the jam nut to 17 to 23 foot pounds torque.
            </para>
            <figure id="f9703031" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9703031.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Hendrickson Rebound Control Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The threaded washer must contact the rebound spring when the vehicle is empty. The adjustment must be
                made after the body is installed, and during an empty vehicle condition. After the adjustment is made,
                tighten the jam nut to 17-23 ft-lbs. torque.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
