<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-08-07 - Wabco and New Allied Signal (Bendix) ABS Controllers</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi970807" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-08-07</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Wabco and New Allied Signal (Bendix) ABS Controllers</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
                <vendor>Wabco</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>This TSI applies to all models with air ABS.</para>
                    <para>Effective February 17, 1997, Navistar will implement a change to a new Bendix and Wabco ABS
                        controller. The new Bendix and Wabco ABS controller is interchangeable with current Bendix and
                        Wabco ABS controllers for service.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>BENDIX</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>ABS Dash Warning Light</title>
                        <para>The ABS warning light will be illuminated at engine start-up for approximately two seconds
                            and then extinguish after a successful self test of the electrical system. If an error is
                            detected at any time, the dash light will stay illuminated.
                        </para>
                        <para>Prior to the new Bendix ABS controller, the dash light would blink and then stay on until
                            the vehicle was driven to a speed of approximately 7 mph and then go out. If a system fault
                            was detected, the ABS warning light would stay illuminated.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Autocalibration</title>
                        <para>The new Bendix ABS controller has an autocalibration feature which will compensate for
                            rolling radius differences that are commonly encountered between front and rear tires. Many
                            fleets specify tires that have significant differences between the front and rear tires. The
                            dealer/ user will not have to perform any activity for the autocalibration to occur. This
                            eliminates the need for a dealer to stock different ABS controllers for different rolling
                            radiuses.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>WABCO</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>ABS Dash Warning Light</title>
                        <para>When the Wabco controller is initially put into service, or each time the controller is
                            serviced (fault codes cleared using the Prolink electronic tool or the blink light switch),
                            the vehicle must be driven above 4 mph to extinguish the ABS dash warning light. Once the
                            ABS dash warning light is extinguished, the ABS dash warning light will function in the same
                            manner as the Bendix ABS dash warning light previously mentioned.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Autocalibration</title>
                        <para>The autocalibration feature has always been available with the Wabco controller, therefore
                            there is no change with the current system.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
