<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-08-05 - False ABS Warning Lamp Illumination</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi970805" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-08-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>False ABS Warning Lamp Illumination</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8100</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8200</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8300</truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>The Bendix ABS controller continuously monitors vehicle system voltage and checks the modulator
                    circuit integrity. If the voltage is not stable within tolerance, the ABS warning lamp will
                    illuminate. The fault indicated by the diagnostic LEDs will generally be a right front modulator.
                    Conditions which can cause voltage fluctuations sufficient to cause the ABS controller to indicate a
                    fault are an alternator problem or loose connections.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>Check and repair the following conditions:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>An alternator with a shorted rectifier diode or phase winding will produce erratic output
                        which may result in ABS warning lamp illumination and low alternator output. Replace or repair
                        the alternator. Do not replace the ABS controller or modulator.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>An alternator with loose stator turns will short out under certain vibration conditions. Loose
                        stator turns may short out when the engine is under specific load and RPM and may not be
                        duplicated during test drive exercises. Loose stator turns can be seen by removing the
                        alternator, removing the fan, and inspecting the stator turns. If any of the stator turns can be
                        moved with light pressure using a pencil, or if some of the stator turns have a different color
                        resulting from high heat, the alternator must be replaced or repaired. Do not replace the ABS
                        controller or modulator.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Loose electrical connections at the alternator or major feed points may cause erratic
                        voltages. Verify all connections are tight.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
