<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-12-11R - Supplemental Cooling Additive (SCA) Factory Fill and Maintenance Level of Concentration for
        International Engines
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi971211r" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-12-11R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>97-12-11</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>September, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Supplemental Cooling Additive (SCA) Factory Fill and Maintenance Level of Concentration for
                International Engines
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SUPPLEMENTAL COOLANT ADDITIVE</title>
                    <para>This TSI applies to all models with International diesel engines.</para>
                    <para>Water filters on International diesel engines are now pre-charged with 4.0 units of DCA4
                        supplemental coolant additive (SCA). This replaces a plain coolant filter without any SCA
                        pre-charge. This ensures a factory level of 1.9 units per gallon (UPG). Immediately after
                        filling, SCA will begin coating the coolant system, initializing engine and coolant system
                        protection. The coating process will deplete a small amount of the factory installed SCA. The
                        current specification for SCA is 1.5 to 3.0 UPG while the optimum level is 1.5 to 2.0 UPG. The
                        pre-charged filter will provide a cushion to assure that each vehicle is delivered with the SCA
                        level in the optimum range.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>PRODUCTION IN-EFFECT DATES:</title>
                    <para>T 444E Engines 3/11/97 (engine serial number 503178)</para>
                    <para>DT 466 and 530 Engines 12/3/96 (engine serial number 1026427)</para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="1">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <svcprocinfo>
                <para>It is recommended that SCA concentration level be checked at regular PM service intervals. SCA
                    levels should not exceed 3.0 UPG. During coolant system SCA maintenance, the upper level should be
                    based on depletion rates experienced with the PM intervals utilized. Again, the optimum level is
                    1.5-2.0 UPG to both prevent cavitation erosion and to realize maximum cooling system component life
                    and cooling system efficiency.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Ethylene glycol antifreeze is installed at the assembly plants. The DCA4 test kit will
                            accurately measure DCA4 or Pencool SCA level in either ethylene glycol or propylene glycol
                            coolant mixtures or combinations of both. Navistar does not recommend mixing ethylene glycol
                            and propylene glycol coolants.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </svcprocinfo>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Pre-Delivery</title>
                <para>It is not necessary or recommended to check SCA level at Pre-delivery. The only exception is if
                    the coolant level is low from a system leak. In this case only, the SCA level should be checked and
                    if the concentration level is found to be below 1.5 UPG, SCA should be added to bring it up to 1.9
                    UPG, equivalent to factory fill level.
                </para>
                <para>Bus body companies and others who open and connect into International chassis cooling systems are
                    responsible to ensure that all coolant added to the system is no less than 1.9 UPG.
                </para>
            </svcsubproc>
            <svcsubproc>
                <title>Summary</title>
                <para>Navistar now ships all International engines with a 4.0 unit pre-charge filter. The optimum level
                    is 1.5-2.0 UPG. Factory fills will be a minimum of 1.9 to accommodate normal initial depletion. Only
                    vehicles that have experienced cooling system leaks require checks at Pre-delivery inspection.
                </para>
                <para>A worksheet (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9712111">Figure 1</hotlnk>) is included to determine the amount of SCA that needs
                    to be added to the coolant system to reach the desired level of concentration.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9712111" figsize="full-pg">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/g9712111.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Worksheet For SCA Level Determination</caption>
                </figure>
            </svcsubproc>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
