<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-12-01 - Cold Starting And Warm Up Aid Kit For DT 408/466 and the International&#174; 530 Engines
        Equipped W/Model P-3000 or 7100 Fuel Injection Pump
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi971201" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>97-12-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>January, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Cold Starting And Warm Up Aid Kit For DT 408/466 and the International&#174; 530 Engines Equipped
                W/Model P-3000 or 7100 Fuel Injection Pump
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 408</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>530</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <svcproc svcproctype="TSI" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
            <para>A cold starting and warm up aid kit, package,
                <emph type="bold">(P/N 1826410C92)</emph>
                is released. This kit will improve cold starting and drive-away performance. It also prevents the
                development of excessive white smoke during and immediately after the engine has started.
            </para>
            <para>The cold start system consists of the following components:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Flame Start Controller</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flame Glow Plugs (2)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel Solenoid Valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Temperature Sensor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Indicator Lamp</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fuel Lines (3)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>(Note, a complete list of all parts included in the kit is given in the installation instructions
                furnished with the kit.)
            </para>
            <para>The cold start system operates with two flame glow plugs (FGP's), installed in the engine's intake
                manifold. The FGP's are activated electrically to start the preheat cycle. Once the required temperature
                at the FGP is reached the dash mounted indicator light blinks and the engine can be cranked to start.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE</emph>
                        - If the coolant temperature is above 25&#176;C (77&#176;F) the indicator light blinks
                        immediately after turning ignition switch on whereby, the cold start system is not activated and
                        is not required.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>During engine cranking mode, a fuel solenoid valve directs diesel fuel to the FGP nozzle. The nozzle
                meters diesel fuel onto the FGP where it mixes with air and ignites. The air is now heated before
                entering the intake manifold. By maintaining the flame for a predetermined duration after the engine
                starts, the engine can warm up much more quickly and the white smoke, that normally occurs during and
                immediately after engine starting, is reduced to a minimum. The entire temperature dependent engine
                starting process is preprogrammed and automatically controlled by the cold start controller
                microprocessor.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>DO NOT USE VOLATILE STARTING AIDS SUCH AS ETHER, PROPANE OR GASOLINE IN THE ENGINE AIR INTAKE
                        SYSTEM. GLOW PLUGS WILL IGNITE VAPORS. FIRE MAY CAUSE SERIOUS INJURY, DEATH OR PROPERTY DAMAGE.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>At very cold temperatures (-20&#176;C, -4&#176;F) the cold start system reset time will be
                        longer due to engine oil pressure build up.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>During the installation of the flame glow plugs a new emission label will be required. The label will
                be replaced free of charge. A replacement form is included with the instructions furnished in the kit.
            </para>
            <para>A system wiring diagram and troubleshooting guide are also included with the instructions.</para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
