<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-12-26 - Navistar's New Engine Control Module For All International&#174; Electronically Controlled
        Engines Built October, 1997 and Later (T 444E Engine Serial Number 634234 and Above) (DT 466E and 530E Engine
        Serial Number 1075289 and Above)
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi971226" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>97-12-26</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Navistar's New Engine Control Module For All International&#174; Electronically Controlled Engines
                Built October, 1997 and Later (T 444E Engine Serial Number 634234 and Above) (DT 466E and 530E Engine
                Serial Number 1075289 and Above)
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E
                    <snrange>634234 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E
                    <snrange>1075289 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
                <engfam>530E
                    <snrange>1075289 and above</snrange>
                </engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>General Information</title>
                    <para>An engine mounted electronic control module
                        <emph type="bold">(ECM)</emph>(
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9712261">Figure 1</hotlnk>
                        and
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9712262">Figure 2</hotlnk>), is released for Navistar's full line of
                        Electronically Controlled diesels, the T 444E, DT 466E and 530E International&#174; brand
                        engines. The new "Navistar ECM" consolidates the current three modules used for monitoring and
                        controlling engine and vehicle performance. The previous electronic modules were chassis
                        mounted. Production began October 27, 1997 for the DT 466E and 530E engines with serial number
                        1075289 and above; and November 3, 1997 for the T 444E engines with serial number 634234 and
                        above.
                    </para>
                    <para>The three modules replaced by the new ECM are:</para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>ECM - Electronic Control Module</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>IDM - Injection Driver Module</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>VPM - Vehicle Personality Module</para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                    <figure id="f9712261" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712261.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. T 444E Engine Equipped With Navistar ECM (Engine Control Module)</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <figure id="f9712262" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712262.webp" type="webp"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. DT 466E Engine (530E Similar) Equipped With Navistar ECM (Engine Control
                            Module)
                        </caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>Strategies of operation are very similar between the two systems. The functions of the three
                        modules used in the prior system are consolidated into a single controller. By combining the
                        three modules to one it enhances engine and vehicle operating and control features, also
                        electrical harnesses are reduced to only two. One is the engine harness, containing wiring to
                        engine mounted components. The other harness is the chassis harness, containing wiring to
                        chassis mounted components including battery and ignition power supply.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Features</title>
                    <para>A new Change Oil Lamp
                        <emph type="bold">(COL)</emph>standard feature is added to the dash panel. This feature can be
                        programmed for the amber lamp to illuminate when it is time to change the engine oil. The COL
                        can be programmed in terms of vehicle miles, hours or calculated fuel consumption. These service
                        interval limits may be adjusted or the COL feature may be turned off.
                    </para>
                    <para>New engine protection systems are optional features and controlled by the ECM. The red Oil and
                        Water Lamp
                        <emph type="bold">(OWL)</emph>
                        and the Engine Alarm Buzzer are intended to be turned on when conditions are present that will
                        cause impending damage to the engine. The level of protection is dependent upon which
                        <emph type="bold">Engine Warning and Protection System</emph>
                        is turned on in the ECM. When ignition switch is in the "On" position power is available at the
                        OWL lamp and alarm. The lamp and the alarm are turned "On" when the ECM provides a path to
                        ground. A momentary bulb check can be visually observed each time the ignition switch is turned
                        on by the operator.
                    </para>
                    <para>Hydraulic pressure governing
                        <emph type="bold">(HPG)</emph>; this is a new optional feature used for closed loop control of
                        hydraulic pressure based on an external hydraulic pressure input and a programmable desired
                        hydraulic pressure. Controls will be wired to the ECM to enable the operation and a sensor is
                        used to signal operational pressure. This feature is mainly for fluid delivery pumps, especially
                        fire truck applications.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Sensors</title>
                    <para>The following engine and chassis mounted sensors are changed to accommodate the Navistar
                        Engine Control Module.
                    </para>
                    <para>The manifold absolute pressure
                        <emph type="bold">(MAP) sensor</emph>
                        is changed. The prior sensor that was mounted on the cowl is replaced by an analog sensor
                        mounted directly in the intake air stream; in the top of the valve cover. With this sensor the
                        signal voltage increases as the boost pressure increases. Note, this is the same sensor as the
                        prior sensor used for engine oil pressure.
                    </para>
                    <para>The engine oil pressure
                        <emph type="bold">(EOP) sensor</emph>
                        is changed. The EOP sensor is now required on all engines equipped with the Navistar ECM, unless
                        the customer prefers their own sensing system. The new sensor will now read up to 100 psi. It is
                        an analog sensor with which the signal voltage increases with an increase in pressure. As
                        previously mentioned in this letter an Engine Warning and Protection feature is available and
                        should be used in conjunction with the EOP sensor. It will warn driver of low engine oil
                        pressure condition and can be programmed to shut the engine down.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Clutch pedal switch (sensor)</emph>
                        is replaced by a single pole double throw switch. Operation will be similar, however, the switch
                        will now be wired in series with the engine crank inhibit relay (standard relay) controlled by
                        the ECM.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Cruise on/off switch (sensor)</emph>
                        is now a continuous switch and no longer will it be wired in series with a resistor block, but
                        will send a digital signal directly to the controller.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Brake switches (sensors);</emph>
                        hydraulic brakes will use a double pole single throw switch with two separate circuits to the
                        controller. Straight truck air brakes will use two air pressure switches, each with a signal to
                        the controller. Tractor air brakes will use a single switch with parallel circuits to the
                        controller. Both of the brake inputs to the controller will be normally open.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Actuators</title>
                    <para>The ECM will control fan clutch and shutter operation determined by engine temperature. The
                        engine temperature is monitored by an
                        <emph type="bold">Engine Fan Control</emph>
                        which provides the proper logic to determine when the fan should be turned on or off by
                        energizing/de-energizing the fan drive solenoid.
                    </para>
                    <para>The
                        <emph type="bold">engine crank inhibit relay</emph>
                        is replaced with a standard relay controlled by the ECM. The relay receives signals from the
                        ignition switch and ECM to close the relay. Current to the relay is supplied from the neutral
                        safety switch with automatic transmission or clutch with manual transmission.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Starter relay</emph>
                        is now mounted on the center of the cowl next to the power relay. The starter relay is used to
                        switch battery power to the cranking motor solenoid when the crank inhibit relay (standard
                        relay) is energized. With thermal overcrank protection, the relay is also controlled by the
                        overcrank thermocouple.
                    </para>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">Battery power</emph>
                        to the ECM will pass through a single power relay. The electronic control module requires a 12
                        volt source of power in order to perform its functions. It receives this operating power
                        directly from the vehicle batteries via the ECM relay-contacts each time the ignition key switch
                        is turned to the "On" position. Turning the ignition switch "On" causes the ECM to provide an
                        internal ground to the coil side of the ECM relay. This causes the relay to close its contacts
                        and provide the ECM with the power necessary to perform its various functions.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
