<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-12-16 - Loss of Power and Engine Knock on International&#8482; T 444E Engines Built January, 1997 and
        Later With Split Shot Fuel Injectors
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi971216" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>97-12-16</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>August, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Loss of Power and Engine Knock on International&#8482; T 444E Engines Built January, 1997 and Later
                With Split Shot Fuel Injectors
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>T 444E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>All T 444E 1997 Model Year engines using split shot fuel injectors ID No. 1822803C1 or 1825125C1
                    and a dead head fuel system (effective on engines with serial number 460195 and up; also, engines
                    with serial number 432842 and up on United Parcel Service applications).
                </para>
                <para>The fuel system now referred to as a dead head system, means the left and right bank fuel rails no
                    longer have the ability to return fuel. All return fuel comes from the pressure regulator located
                    ahead of the fuel rail check valves (See Dead Head Fuel System Diagram,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f9712161">Figure 1</hotlnk>). A full description of split shot injectors is
                    explained in Service Letter TSI 97-12-09.
                </para>
                <figure id="f9712161" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712161.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 1. Dead Head Fuel Supply System Flow Diagram</caption>
                </figure>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <para>A loss of power sometimes accompanied by a knocking sound can be caused by fuel restriction to the
                cylinder head on subject engines. The fuel supply fitting in the cylinder heads (right rear and left
                front) has an orifice that can become restricted, usually debris from the supply line rubber seal (see
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9712162">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Diagnosing the engine for this condition may generate
                multiple cylinder contribution codes on one bank.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not replace the fuel injectors!</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f9712162" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712162.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Fuel Supply fitting (Check Valve) At Cylinder Head</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Remove the suspected fuel supply line to the cylinder head (left front or right rear) and inspect the
                fitting for debris. Inspect the supply line rubber seal and replace if necessary (P/N 1812348C1). When
                installing a new seal the metal tube should be bottomed in the fitting in its normal position while the
                tube retainer nuts are tightened.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure to install the connector fitting as described here to ensure the rubber seal is seated
                        evenly. If fitting is not installed properly the seal can be cut.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Removing the debris from the fuel inlet fitting to the cylinder head should restore proper engine
                operation.
            </para>
            <para>An engine knocking sound, "cackle" sometimes described as a fuel knock or connecting rod knock, can be
                caused by the fuel regulator valve sticking or debris caught in the seat. Fuel transfer pump pressure
                that drops below 35 psi at idle can aggravate the "cackle" concern. Disassembly the regulator (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9712163">Figure 3</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9712164">Figure 4</hotlnk>) and inspect for sticking, debris or broken spring, replace
                if necessary with regulator valve package (P/N 1823641C91). Remove the fuel supply line from the 3-way
                fitting at the fuel supply pump (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f9712165">Figure 5</hotlnk>) and inspect the supply line rubber seal, replace if
                necessary (P/N 1812348C1). When installing a new seal the metal tube should be bottomed in the fitting
                in its normal position while the tube retainer nuts are tightened.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be sure to install the connector fitting as described here to ensure the rubber seal is seated
                        evenly. If fitting is not installed properly the seal can be cut.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the conditions described in this letter still exist after performing these procedures,
                        refer to the engine diagnostic manual for further diagnosing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f9712163" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712163.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Fuel Regulator Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9712164" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712164.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Fuel Regulator Valve</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f9712165" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/G9712165.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Regulator Valve Fuel Supply Fitting At Three-Way Fitting</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
