<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 97-12-05 - Replacement of Vibration Damper</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI971205" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>97-12-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>March, 1997</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engines</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Replacement of Vibration Damper</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530E</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>Rubber streaking of vibration damper and replacement criteria.</para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="3">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>A condition called 'rubber streaking' is commonly observed on the vibration damper, refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f97120501">Vibration Damper Rubber Streaking
                    <xref refid="f97120501"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f97120501" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EG6962.webp" type="webp" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. Vibration Damper Rubber Streaking</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Rubber streaking becomes evident as the rubber, found between the inertia ring and damper pulley,
                begins its normal life cycle process, refer to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="f97120502">Cutaway View Of Vibration Damper Rubber Compound And Inertia Ring
                    <xref refid="f97120502"/>
                </hotlnk>
                . This process occurs due to high temperatures generated from the energy absorbed by the damper over a
                period of time. The time required to generate this condition varies greatly between engine rating and
                vehicle application.
            </para>
            <figure id="f97120502" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EG6961.webp" type="webp" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Cutaway View Of Vibration Damper Rubber Compound And Inertia Ring</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The streaking condition described, occurs on both the front and rear surfaces of the vibration damper.
                A vibration damper with rubber streaking
                <emph type="boldundersc">SHOULD NOT</emph>
                be replaced immediately and can remain in operation for some time. Due to the confusion of when to
                replace the vibration damper, the following is recommended. Replace the vibration damper when the rubber
                has recessed more than; 10 mm (3/8 inch) in depth across a 51 mm (2 inch) radius of the rubber compound
                on both sides of the vibration damper or if rubber member 'chunking' occurs (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f97120503">Vibration Damper Replacement Condition
                    <xref refid="f97120503"/>
                </hotlnk>
                ).
            </para>
            <figure id="f97120503" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/EG6963.webp" type="webp" box="yes"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Vibration Damper Replacement Condition</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>In
                <hotlnk xrefid="f97120503">Vibration Damper Replacement Condition
                    <xref refid="f97120503"/>
                </hotlnk>
                , the damper on the left needs to be replaced while the damper on the right is still in good working
                condition.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>NOTICE THE DEPTH OF THE GROOVE BETWEEN THE VIBRATION DAMPER PULLEY AND INERTIA RING. THE
                        GROOVE IS MUCH DEEPER AND LONGER IN LENGTH ON THE DAMPER WHICH NEEDS TO BE REPLACED.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A copy of this service bulletin should be filed with the engine service manual (Form No. EGES
                        105 or EGES 160) until the manual has been updated to include this change.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
