<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 98-04-02R - Elimination of Key and Keyway in Air Compressor Drive Gear for Bendix Tu-Flo 550 and 750 Air
        Compressors
    </stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi980402R" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>98-04-02R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>98-04-02</tsinumber>
            <tsinumber>97-12-22</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>March, 1999</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Elimination of Key and Keyway in Air Compressor Drive Gear for Bendix Tu-Flo 550 and 750 Air
                Compressors
            </subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all models with International DT 466/DT 466E and 530/530E engines built after
                    March 1, 1998.
                </para>
                <para>Bendix has implemented changes to the Tu-Flo 550 and 750 air compressor drive gear and crankshaft.
                    The key and keyway have been eliminated in air compressor drive gear and crankshaft. The drive gear
                    retainer nut, tightened to 110 ft-lbs. (149 Nm) of torque, is sufficient to prevent the gear from
                    turning on the shaft and eliminates the need for the key and keyway.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not mix non-keyed components with old material (keyed components). Mixing of non-keyed
                            components with keyed components may fail the crankshaft.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <para>Effective with Engine Serial Number 1050304 for the Bendix 550, and Engine Serial Number 1055789
                    for the Bendix 750, Tu-Flo compressors have the new style forged crankshaft. The drive gear retainer
                    nut should be tightened to 110 ft-lbs. (149 Nm).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not use an air impact tool to tighten the drive gear retainer nut to prevent possible
                            damage to the crankshaft.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Using a Bendix Tu-Flo 750 compressor with a DT 466 rated at 2400 RPM will result in
                            compressor failure. The Bendix Tu-Flo 750 compressor is rated for a maximum of 2000 RPM.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9804021" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information (New Part Numbers for Service)</title>
                <tgroup cols="2" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1694005C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Bendix 550 Tu-Flo Air Compressor</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1696864C92</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Bendix 750 Tu-Flo Air Compressor</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1830070C1</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>Drive Gear W/O Keyway (Do Not Substitute)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
    </tsi>
</isis>
