<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 98-04-01R - Next Generation ECU for Anti-Lock Brake Systems (ABS)</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI980401R" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>98-04-01R</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>98-04-01</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>April, 1998</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>BRAKES</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Next Generation ECU for Anti-Lock Brake Systems (ABS)</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Bendix</vendor>
                <vendor>Wabco</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>General</title>
                    <para>This TSI applies to all models manufactured with Wabco ABS effective February 2, 1998, and
                        Bendix ABS effective March 1, 1998.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Allied Signal (Bendix)</title>
                    <para>Effective March 1, 1998, all vehicles built with Bendix ABS will use the new Bendix EC-17 ECU
                        in place of the EC-16 ECU. The new Bendix EC-17 ECU is 33% smaller and 44% lighter than the
                        EC-16 ECU and has serial communications for J1939 engine control.
                    </para>
                    <para>On 91/92/93/9400 Models, the ECU has been relocated to the right frame rail behind the cab (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9804011">Figure 1</hotlnk>). On all other models the ECU location remains the
                        same.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9804011" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9804011" filename="../tsifigures/G9804011.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Bendix ECU and Harness Routing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Diagnostics</title>
                        <para>The Bendix EC-17 ECU is not available with diagnostic LED's or the magnetic switch used to
                            reset and self configure the ECU. This change was driven by the fact that most ECU's are
                            mounted in locations where the diagnostic LED's cannot be viewed.
                        </para>
                        <para>There are two options available for Bendix service diagnostics, the EZ Tech&#8482; laptop
                            service tool with ACom diagnostic software or the Diagnostic Communications Interface (DCI).
                            Navistar worked jointly with Bendix to develop the DCI and ACom diagnostic software.
                        </para>
                        <para>One option is the
                            <emph type="bold">EZ Tech Laptop:</emph>
                            The EZ Tech service tool is a rugged laptop computer based diagnostic service tool that has
                            been developed to provide efficient and accurate information to service International
                            vehicles. The EZ Tech laptop connects to the J1587 Data Link through the computer serial
                            port connector on the DCI unit. A technician using the ABS ACom diagnostic software can
                            perform the following tasks:
                        </para>
                        <seqlist>
                            <item>
                                <para>Locate and diagnose current faults</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Test individual components for proper operation</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Obtain, view and store a history of specific fault occurrences</para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>Record performance of components during actual vehicle operation</para>
                            </item>
                        </seqlist>
                        <para>The second option is
                            <emph type="bold">DCI:</emph>
                            The DCI service tool is a hand held unit that plugs into the vehicle diagnostic connector
                            (J1587 Data Link) located on the dash panel in the cab. The DCI service tool has the same
                            LED diagnostic display as on the previous EC-16 ECU for locating anti-lock system faults and
                            a reset button to replace the magnet switch on the EC-16. Refer to Group 04, ABS/Traction
                            Control, in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual to interpret fault codes. The DCI service
                            tool, part number ZTSE-4453, can be ordered from Kent Moore at 1-800-520-2584.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>Wabco</title>
                    <para>Effective February 2, 1998, all vehicles built with Wabco ABS will have Wabco's "D" version
                        ECU in place of the "C" version. The enhanced Wabco "D" version ECU has the capability of serial
                        communications for J1939 engine control without cost penalty. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f9804012">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                        for ECU location on the frame.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f9804012" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g9804012" filename="../tsifigures/G9804012.webp" type="webp" resolution="300"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Wabco ECU and Harness Routing</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <para>If the vehicle has the "D" version ECU with automatic traction control (ATC), the system will
                        use one ATC valve instead of two ATC valves used with the "C" version ECU.
                    </para>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>Diagnostics</title>
                        <para>There are two options available for Wabco service diagnostics, the EZ Tech laptop service
                            tool or the blink code switch.
                        </para>
                        <para>One option is the
                            <emph type="bold">EZ Tech Laptop:</emph>
                            Windows based diagnostic software for the Wabco "D" version ECU will be available mid 1998.
                        </para>
                        <para>The other option is
                            <emph type="bold">Blink Code Switch:</emph>
                            The Wabco "D" version ECU has a momentary blink code switch instead of the off/on toggle
                            switch used on the "C" version ECU. To display fault codes, press and hold the blink code
                            switch for one second and release. To interpret the fault codes refer to CTS-5253, Rockwell
                            Wabco 4 Channel Anti-Lock/Traction Brake System, located in Group 4 in the CTS-5000 Master
                            Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
