<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 98-08-05 - Year 2000 Compliance with International&#174; Trucks</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi980805" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>98-08-05</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1998</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ELECTRICAL</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Year 2000 Compliance with International&#174; Trucks</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to all International models with electronic control modules.</para>
                <para>This statement is a Year 2000 Readiness Disclosure pursuant to the Year 2000 Information and
                    Readiness Disclosure Act (105 P.L. 271).
                </para>
                <para>The engine control modules used in International trucks use an electronic clock system to keep
                    track of time interval information, but without reference to calendar date of occurrence. Since the
                    dating function is not incorporated into the operating strategy, the engine control modules are
                    <emph type="bold">Year 2000 Compliant</emph>. This applies to International engines used in medium
                    duty vehicles as well as heavy duty engines supplied by Caterpillar (3406E, 3406P, 3176, 3176B, C10
                    and C12), Cummins (PACE, PT-PACER, ECI and CELECT), and Detroit Diesel (DDEC II, and DDEC III).
                </para>
                <para>Similarly, the following components/systems are
                    <emph type="bold">Year 2000 Compliant</emph>: alternators; brakes; collision avoidance systems; HVAC
                    monitors; instrument clusters; monitoring systems from Caterpillar, Cummins, Detroit Diesel, Eaton,
                    Pollack, and XATA Corporation; radios (if equipped with a clock function); special equipment
                    communication systems; tachograph from Argo Instruments and Veeder-Root; transmissions.
                </para>
                <para>The Navistar EZ-Tech&#8482; and ProLink service tools are
                    <emph type="bold">Year 2000 Compliant</emph>.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </tsi>
</isis>
