<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 98-11-01 - Clutch Engagement Noise with Eaton Spicer Angle-Ring 350 MM Clutches</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi981101" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>98-11-01</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>December, 1998</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>CLUTCH</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Clutch Engagement Noise with Eaton Spicer Angle-Ring 350 MM Clutches</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <vendorgroup/>

                <vendor>Eaton</vendor>
                <vendor>Spicer</vendor>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Notice</title>
                <para>The information supplied herein has been furnished by the manufacturer and/or the supplier for use
                    with its product. Navistar International Transportation Corp. reprints this information based on
                    representations made to the Company by the manufacturer and/or supplier and is not responsible for
                    any errors or mishaps resulting from such errors or from any misuse of the product. Every user is
                    urged to carefully follow the instructions which accompany the product.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>Eaton Customer Bulletin</title>
            <para>Date: 10/6/98</para>
            <para>
                <title>Squawk with Eaton Spicer Angle-Ring 350 mm Clutches</title>
            </para>
            <para>There is a potential for "squawk," i.e., clutch noise, with the Eaton Spicer Angle-Ring 350 mm clutch.
                Some "squawk" or "chirp" is sometimes heard at clutch engagement, when the ceramic facing material
                contacts the flywheel. This noise is especially noticeable when starting in second or third gear, or in
                vehicles with poor startability, causing the clutch to slip for a longer period of time before complete
                engagement.
            </para>
            <para>This "squawk" is inherent to the product, and causes NO problems to the life of the clutch or to the
                vehicle. This characteristic is considered normal, and is NOT covered under vehicle warranty.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
