<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 98-12-18 - In Chassis Cleaning Procedure for Vehicle Cooling Package</stitle>
    <tsi id="tsi981218" tsitype="truck">
        <tsinumber>98-12-18</tsinumber>
        <replace>
            <tsinumber>97-12-18</tsinumber>
        </replace>
        <tsidate>November, 1998</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>ENGINE</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>In Chassis Cleaning Procedure for Vehicle Cooling Package</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>3000</truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <para>This TSI applies to AmTran 3000RE bus.</para>
                <para>Charge air cooler fin clogging can cause low power as the engine reduces fuel delivery to
                    compensate for above normal coolant temperatures. This has mainly been noticed on units with T 444E
                    engines utilizing the exhaust back pressure device in colder climates.
                </para>
                <para>A 24 inch crankcase breather tube extension was added in production on April 28, 1998 to minimize
                    oily crankcase vapors from being drawn into the engine compartment and forced into the charge air
                    cooler. Additionally, any fluid leaks greater than seepage can cause CAC clogging.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Engine compartment fluid leaks should be repaired as soon as possible to prevent CAC
                            clogging.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <para>The following procedure is recommended as an annual maintenance program to ensure road salts and
                    debris are removed from the cooling package to insure optimum performance and reliability.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Air management flip up panels should be closed and latched when the bus is in service to
                            prevent excessive contaminants from entering the engine compartment.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <partsinfo>
            <table id="t9812181" frame="all">
                <title>Parts Information</title>
                <tgroup cols="3" colsep="1" rowsep="1">
                    <colspec colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="2.75in"/>
                    <colspec colwidth="1.01in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Number</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part Description</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Quantity</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>SG13005</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Simple Green Cleaner</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1 Gal.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Deck Sprayer with Flexible Extension Wand and Fan Tip</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Pressure Washer or Steam Cleaner</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Garden Hose with Pistol Grip Nozzle</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Extendable Technicians Mirror</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>npn</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top">
                                <para>Flashlight</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry valign="top" align="center">
                                <para>1</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </partsinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="clean" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICE PROCEDURE</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix Simple Green cleaner in a 50/50 mixture with water in the sprayer tank.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Spray charge air cooler from engine side with Simple Green cleaning solution. Use the
                    technicians mirror and flashlight to insure full and even coverage with the cleaning solution. Allow
                    the cleaning solution to soak 20 to 30 minutes. Additional cleaning solution may be applied to
                    heavily plugged areas.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rear grille assembly.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the engine oil drain plug cover from the air management panel to open a path for
                    water to drain out.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply cleaning solution to the radiator from the rear of the bus.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not spray charge air cooler or radiator fins at an angle as fin damage may occur and reduce
                        cooling efficiency.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not attempt to clean the charge air cooler from the engine side with a pressure washer as
                        damage to the charge air cooler fins will reduce cooling efficiency.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the soak period, pressure wash or steam clean the cooling package from the rear of
                    the bus. Thoroughly clean each row of fins slowly vertically then horizontally. This process should
                    take approximately 10 minutes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the charge air cooler with the garden hose and nozzle from the engine side. Spray
                    water at a 45 degree angle or less to dislodge and rinse debris from the charge air cooler. Inspect
                    the fins with the technicians mirror and the flashlight to insure adequate cleaning.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Return to the radiator side and pressure wash following Step 6 for approximately 5
                    minutes to remove any remaining debris.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rinse the cooling package and engine compartment with clean water to remove any cleaning
                    solution residue.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform a final inspection of the cooling package using the technicians mirror and
                    flashlight. If areas were missed, spot clean those areas following the above procedure Steps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the grille and engine oil drain plug cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the fan clutch wiring harness and run the engine at high idle for
                    approximately 3 minutes to dry the cooling package.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off the engine and reconnect the fan clutch wiring harness.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
