<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>TSI 99-12-08 - Coolant Filter Header Assembly</stitle>
    <tsi id="tSI991208" tsitype="engine">
        <tsinumber>99-12-08</tsinumber>
        <tsidate>May, 1999</tsidate>
        <subjectfile>Engines</subjectfile>
        <subjectgroup>
            <subject>Coolant Filter Header Assembly</subject>
        </subjectgroup>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <engfamgroup/>

                <engfam>DT 408</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466 High Torque</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E</engfam>
                <engfam>DT 466E High Torque</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530E</engfam>
                <engfam>International&#174; 530E High Torque</engfam>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>Coolant Filter Header Assembly</title>
                <para>A new coolant filter header featuring a manual shut off valve will replace the existing filter
                    header that utilizes check valves to contain engine coolant whenever the filter is removed. This is
                    designed to minimize any potential loss of coolant when servicing the filter.
                </para>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
        <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="2">
            <title>Service Procedure</title>
            <para>
                <title>Redesigned Coolant Filter Header Assembly</title>
            </para>
            <para>The redesigned coolant filter header assembly has been released for use in all NGD I-6 diesel engines,
                replacing the existing coolant filter header assembly. The redesigned header assembly, located on the
                right side of the engine behind the front cover, will incorporate a manual shut off valve instead of the
                current filter header utilizing (2) check valves. This will aid service technicians by minimizing the
                possibility that the check valves may not seat properly, resulting in lost engine coolant.
            </para>
            <para>The new coolant filter header assembly (P/N 1827689C91) will replace the discontinued coolant filter
                header assembly (P/N 1820381C93, discontinued in both production and service parts). There will be no
                changes made to any existing related components such as bolts, gaskets, or the filter itself. This
                production change will occur with 1999 Model Year engines, bearing serial number 117199 and higher.
            </para>
            <figure id="f981801" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8043.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. New Coolant Filter Header Assembly With Valve Lever In The Off Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Manual Filter Shut Off Valve Lever (OFF Position, Filter Bypassed)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>TO AVOID PERSONAL INJURY USE ONLY THE FOLLOWING PROCEDURE TO REMOVE THE PRESSURE TYPE CAP FROM
                        THE COOLING SYSTEM. ALWAYS ALLOW THE ENGINE TO COOL FIRST. WRAP A THICK, HEAVY CLOTH AROUND THE
                        CAP. PUSH DOWN, LOOSEN CAP SLOWLY TO ITS FIRST NOTCH POSITION; THEN PAUSE A MOMENT. THIS WILL
                        AVOID POSSIBLE SCALDING BY HOT WATER OR STEAM. CONTINUE TO TURN CAP TO THE LEFT AND REMOVE.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">To Replace The Coolant Filter:</emph>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn the manual shut off valve lever to the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f981801">"OFF" position
                        <xref refid="f981801"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the deaeration tank pressure cap and then remove the coolant filter using a
                    filter wrench/strap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a thin coat of coolant to the filter gasket and install onto the filter header.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten until the gasket touches the coolant filter header. Tighten by hand one (1)
                    additional full turn.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the servicing operation is complete, check coolant level and replace the pressure
                    cap. Be certain to turn the manual filter shut off valve back to the "ON" position, so that the
                    filter will once again be operational, extending the service life of the coolant as well as the
                    engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f981802">New Coolant Filter Header Assembly (Valve In The On Position)
                    <xref refid="f981802"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <figure id="f981802" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../tsifigures/eg8044.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. New Coolant Filter Header Assembly With Valve Lever In The On Position</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Manual Filter Shut Off Valve Lever (ON Position, Filter Operational)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A copy of this service bulletin should be filed with the following publications until they
                        have been updated to include this change:
                    </para>
                    <para>ENGINE SERVICE MANUAL (Form No. EGES 105-1)</para>
                    <para>ENGINE SERVICE MANUAL (Form No. EGES 160-1)</para>
                    <para>ENGINE OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE MANUAL, DT-466 (Form No. 1171667R4)</para>
                    <para>ENGINE OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE MANUAL, DT-466E, (equipped with International Diamond Logic&#8482;
                        Electronic Control Module) (Form No. 1171734R1)
                    </para>
                    <para>ENGINE OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE MANUAL, THE INTERNATIONAL 530 (Form No. 1171668R4)</para>
                    <para>ENGINE OPERATION AND MAINTENANCE MANUAL, THE INTERNATIONAL 530E (equipped with International
                        Diamond Logic&#8482; Electronic Control Module) (Form No. 1171735R1)
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </tsi>
</isis>
