<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AERODYNAMIC PANELS - AERO SIDE SKIRT PANELS - INSTALL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position deep channel bracket to frame and determine which crossmember bolts to remove.
                Remove only those crossmember bolts necessary to mount the deep channel to the frame.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position deep channel bracket and replace crossmember bolts by bolting through the deep
                channel bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position angle brackets as required and mount to frame rail using bolts, washers, and
                nuts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert step support arms into deep channel bracket and cross bolt arms to bracket using
                bolts, washers, and nuts. Finger tighten nuts at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Bolt aero side panel support arms to angle brackets. Finger tighten nuts at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position battery box/tool box bracket and mount using bolts, washers, and nuts. Finger
                tighten nuts at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With an assistant, position aero side panels and attach them to the support arms using
                capscrews and washers. Lightly tighten at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When all aero side panels are hung on a side, align them as required. Tighten all support
                arm mountings and all panel face capscrews.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not drive a 9400 at road speed unless all aero side panel mountings are secure. Check all
                        aero side panel support arm bolts and all panel face capscrews.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
