<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - PAINT REFINISHING - SPOT REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SPOT REPAIR</title>
        <para>This procedure is for fiberglass and metal.</para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>This procedure is intended for the "minor" or non-panel replacement type of repairs such as dents,
                    dings, and deep scratches on metal or plastic substrates. Prior to starting, all brackets and other
                    components should be removed from the area to be repaired.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wash panel with lacquer thinner.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Degrease the panel with Sikkens M600 Wax and Grease Remover. Use two cloths: the first with
                M600, the second dry, as a wipe on and wipe off process. Follow the direction listed in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_27.xml" xrefid="hl1600201">Sikkens Degreasers &#38; Cleaners</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Sand area to be repaired with #60 - #80 grit paper Remove all old paint down to base
                material over an area approximately twice the size of the defect to be repaired. Wear an approved dust
                mask.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Feather the edges of the sanded area with sequentially finer grades of sand paper starting
                with #120 - #150. Wear an approved dust mask.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use Sikkens Polykit, Polystop LP according to the instructions in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_31.xml" xrefid="hl1600205">Sikkens Polystop LP</hotlnk>, to fill in the area to
                be repaired. Avoid overfilling the area and spread the material evenly out to the edges. Allow Polystop
                to cure completely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Sand the filled area flat using a sander or sanding block by sequentially sanding with #60 -
                #80 grit paper dry to #180 - #220 grit paper dry until the area is smooth and level with the surrounding
                panel. Wear an approved dust mask.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If there are irregularities in the surface, repeat steps 5 and 6.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a random orbital sander or sanding block with #220 - #280 grit paper dry and sand the
                entire area. Wear an approved dust mask.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Degrease the panel with Sikkens M600 Wax and Grease Remover. Use two cloths: the first with
                M600, the second dry, as a wipe on and wipe off process. Follow the direction listed in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_27.xml" xrefid="hl1600201">Sikkens Degreasers &#38; Cleaners</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mix 1 part Wash Primer EM with 1 part Wash Hardener.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply mixed Wash Primer EM in one medium coat at 1 mil film thickness. Specific application
                guidelines for spray gun tip and pressures can be found in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_28.xml" xrefid="hl1600206">Sikkens Washprimer EM</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow paint to flash off at ambient conditions for 1 hour at 70 degrees F.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the topcoat is Autonova or Autobase/Autonova Clear, the Wash Primer EM must first be
                        recoated with Autonova Filler or Autonova Non-Sanding filler.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Mix 100 parts Autocryl Filler Off-White with 50 parts of Autocryl 1.2.3 Hardener and 40
                parts Sikkens 1.2.3 Reducer according to the directions in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_30.xml" xrefid="hl1600203">Sikkens Autocryl Filler Off-White</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply mixed Autocryl Filler Off-White following the instructions in the technical data
                sheet.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow to dry a minimum of 15 minutes at 70 degrees F. If longer than one hour, sanding is
                required to assure topcoat adhesion.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If sanding is required, use #360 - #410 grit paper dry or #500 - #600 grit wet. After
                sanding, degrease the surface with M600 wax and grease remover. Wear an approved dust mask.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Topcoat with Sikkens Autobase/Clearcoat System following the instructions in
                <hotlnk document="s16002_32.xml" xrefid="hl1600204">Sikkens Autobase Metallic-AutoClear System</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
