<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - BASIC
        PRINCIPLES - HOW THE SYSTEM WORKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>HOW THE SYSTEM WORKS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Basic Review</title>
            <para>When liquid refrigerant absorbs heat from the surrounding area, it changes to a vapor. This action is
                referred to as the latent heat of vaporization.
            </para>
            <para>Liquid refrigerant, like most liquids, boils and changes to a vapor when pressure is reduced (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601904">Figure 4</hotlnk>). When pressure is applied to the refrigerant vapor, it is
                condensed to a liquid (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601905">Figure 5</hotlnk>). During the process of converting a vapor to a liquid,
                latent heat of condensation is dissipated to the outside air (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601906">Figure 6</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601904" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601904" filename="../figg16/g1601904.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Refrigerant Boils and Changes to a Vapor</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1601905" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601905" filename="../figg16/g1601905.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Refrigerant Vapor Condenses to a Liquid</caption>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1601906" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601906" filename="../figg16/g1601906.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Latent Heat of Condensation Dissipates</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Basic Refrigerant Cycle</title>
            <para>The refrigerant cycle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601907">Figure 7</hotlnk>), consists of four phases: compression, condensation,
                expansion, and evaporation of refrigerant. Consider the starting point at the receiver-dryer. At this
                point, the refrigerant is a hot liquid under high pressure. The liquid refrigerant flows to the
                expansion valve under high pressure. The expansion valve meters the flow of refrigerant, thus reducing
                its pressure to a low-pressure liquid. The low-pressure liquid moves into the evaporator where it
                expands and changes to low pressure, low temperature vapor. During the change of state, large quantities
                of heat are absorbed from the cab by the refrigerant.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601907" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601907" filename="../figg16/g1601907e.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="622px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. The Refrigerant Cycle</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The heat-laden, low pressure vapor is drawn to the compressor. The compressor changes the low
                pressure, low temperature vapor to a high pressure, high temperature vapor. The high temperature, high
                pressure vapor is pumped to the condenser. The cooler outside air passing over the condenser fins
                removes heat from the refrigerant that was picked up in the cab of the vehicle and condenses the high
                temperature, high pressure vapor back to a high temperature, high pressure liquid. The high temperature,
                high pressure liquid is then pumped to the receiver-dryer. The cycle is then repeated.
            </para>
            <para>As a means of better understanding the overall system, consider the following description of the
                components used in an International truck air conditioning system. The system has the following
                components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Compressor and Clutch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Condenser</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Receiver-dryer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Expansion Valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Evaporator</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Thermostatic Control Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Refrigerant Low Pressure Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High Pressure Safety Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fan Drive Override Switch (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Shutter Override Switch (optional)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Air Blower</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Blower Speed Control Resistors.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
