<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - DESCRIPTION
        OF SYSTEM COMPONENTS - CONDENSER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONDENSER</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601911">Figure 11</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1601911" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1601911" filename="../figg16/G1601911a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"/>
            <caption>Figure 11. Typical Condensers</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. OUTLET FITTING</callout1>
                <callout1>2. INLET FITTING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The air conditioning condenser is located at the front of the vehicle between the engine radiator and the
            grille. It consists of a series of coils, with inlet and outlet fittings, surrounded by thin cooling fins.
            High pressure/high temperature refrigerant vapor from the compressor enters at the top of the condenser,
            circulates down through the coils and exits at the bottom of the condenser as high pressure/high temperature
            refrigerant liquid. As the vapor condenses (changes state), heat is released to the outside air which passes
            over the fin external surfaces to carry the heat away.
        </para>
        <para>The efficiency of the condenser operation is affected by ram air flowing across the condenser. For this
            reason, it is important that the condenser cooling fins remain free of airborne contamination (leaves,
            insects, dirt, etc.) which can block the fins and cause system temperatures to run higher than normal.
        </para>
        <para>When operating properly, the condenser acts as an efficient heat exchanger, containing refrigerant vapor
            in approximately two-thirds of the upper portion of its coils and condensed refrigerant liquid in the lower
            one-third portion. The condenser passes high temperature/high pressure liquid refrigerant to the
            receiver-dryer.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
