<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - REMOVE - CAB</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
        <title>CAB</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>General Procedures for Cab Removal</title>
            <para>The removal of the cab from chassis can be performed providing an overhead crane and cab lifting
                fixture are available. Removal procedures may vary for various models depending on the type of equipment
                and accessories.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>When working on, or near a vehicle, the following general precautions should be observed.
                    </para>
                    <seqlist>
                        <item>
                            <para>Park the vehicle on a level surface, apply the parking brakes, and always block the
                                wheels.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Stop the engine when working around the vehicle.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Drain the air pressure from all reservoirs before beginning any work on the vehicle.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Never connect or disconnect a hose or line containing pressure; it may whip. Never
                                remove a component or plug, unless you are certain all system pressure has been
                                released.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Never exceed recommended pressures and always wear safety glasses.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Do not attempt to install, remove, disassemble or assemble a component until you have
                                read and thoroughly understand the recommended procedures. Use only the proper tools and
                                observe all precautions pertaining to use of those tools.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Prior to returning the vehicle to service, make certain all components and systems are
                                restored to their proper operating condition.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Always turn the ignition key to the off position before disconnecting any of the
                                antilock wiring or connectors. If the key is not off, the EC-15 controller will record
                                the power interruption as a static fault.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </seqlist>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to the correct sections in the Master Service Manual for the component being removed and
                        replaced.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The following steps may be used as a guide.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Block wheels of truck and engage parking brake.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt or remove hood.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always disconnect power source before working on electrical equipment.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect battery ground cable.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the pressure cap from the deaeration tank.
                        Always insulate the cap by wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent possible injury from scalding water or steam, do not pull the pressure cap off
                        immediately when it has been loosened to the first "notch." Pause momentarily to allow time for
                        excess pressure to release through the overflow tube.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drain cooling system and disconnect heater hose.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect steering shaft at gear.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect accelerator linkage and cruise control, if so equipped.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect electrical connections and ground wire.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect clutch linkage.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or possible death , whenever any component is serviced or removed
                        from the air system, be sure the air system is drained.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect brake system (air or hydraulic).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the
                        system are removed or replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system may cause
                        personal injury or possibly death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not vent refrigerant into the atmosphere. The use of R-12 is a worldwide environmental
                        concern. Because of the absence of chlorine in the molecular structure of R-134a, the use of
                        R-134a refrigerant will not have any harmful effects on the ozone layer of the atmosphere.
                        Because there is not enough evidence to determine the " greenhouse " effect of R-134a, recycling
                        of R-134a is recommended. Effective November 1995, recovery and recycling of R-134a is required
                        by law.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always use approved refrigerant recycling equipment when working with R-134a. Federal and
                        state laws require that refrigerant be recovered and recycled to help protect the environment.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect air conditioning lines (if so equipped). Refer to
                    <emph type="bold">GROUP 16 - CAB</emph>
                    in the
                    <emph type="bold">Master Service Manual</emph>
                    for the proper procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove shift lever from transmission.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Detach exhaust system from cab if system is vertical type.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Detach any other connections between the cab and frame, if required.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cab lifting fixture. Make sure fixture is padded to prevent damage to cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use an overhead crane and cab lifting fixture when removing the cab from the chassis. Pad the
                        lifting fixture to prevent damage to the cab assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Partially lift cab so cab weight will be supported on lifting fixture.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Cab on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove daycabs, remove cab to frame mounting bolts and nuts at front and rear
                    mounting locations. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1603397"/>
                    for
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Daycab Front Cab Mounting</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Daycab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove short sleeper cabs, remove cab to frame mounting bolts and nuts at front and
                    rear mounting locations. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603398">Figure 98</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1603398"/>
                    for
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Short Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Short Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove long sleeper cabs, remove cab to frame mounting bolts and nuts at front and
                    rear mounting locations. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603399">Figure 99</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1603399"/>
                    for
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Long Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Long Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Daycab Front Cab Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex nuts (Item 1) with two flat washers (Item 2) from two square head bolts
                    (Item 3) under lower chassis front cab mount support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save hex nuts and
                    flat washers for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mount cap (Item 5) from two square head bolts (Item 3) under front cab
                    mounting insulator (Item 6), driver side shown. Save front cab mount cap for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull two square head bolts (Item 3) out of upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7),
                    driver side shown. Save square head bolts for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side cab mounting hardware.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603397" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603398.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 97. Daycab Front Cab Mounting and Daycab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEX NUT (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLAT WASHER (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SQUARE HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER CHASSIS FRONT CAB MOUNT SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. FRONT CAB MOUNT CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT CAB MOUNTING INSULATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. UPPER FRONT CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. HEX FLANGED NUT (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CARRIAGE BOLT (12 MM X 110)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. REAR CAB AIR SUSPENSION ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. CAB UNDERBODY SILL</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. CAB MOUNT RETAINING CLIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. HEX FLANGED NUT (M 16)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 16 X 120)</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 12 X 37)</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Daycab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex flanged nuts (Item 8) from the two carriage bolts (Item 9) under the top
                    plate of the rear cab air suspension assembly (Item 10).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The two carriage bolts (Item 9) are secured to the cab underbody sill (Item 11) with cab
                    mount retaining clips (Item 12). The carriage bolts will remain with cab underbody sill when cab is
                    lifted off the rear cab air suspension assembly (Item 10).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Inspect all cab to frame attaching points to be sure they are disconnected or damage can
                        result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using an overhead crane and cab lifting fixture, carefully lift cab from chassis. If
                    removing cab from overhead crane, set it on a suitable surface to protect painted surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Front Cab Mounting Insulator on Daycab and Sleeper Cab with Cab Lifted off Chassis</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603397"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to replace the front cab mounting insulator (Item 6), driver side
                    shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hex flanged nut (Item 13) from hex flanged bolt (Item 14) and remove hex flanged
                    bolt. Save hex flanged nut and hex flanged bolt for installation, unless damaged and being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mounting insulator (Item 6) from lower chassis front cab mounting
                    support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save front cab mounting insulator for installation, unless
                    damaged and being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side front cab mounting insulator.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Front Cab Mounting Insulator on Daycab and Sleeper Cab with Cab Mounted to Chassis</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603397"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to replace the front cab mounting insulator (Item 6), use a bottle
                    jack between bottom of cab and frame rail to support cab, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex nuts (Item 1) with two flat washers (Item 2) from two square head bolts
                    (Item 3) under lower chassis front cab mount support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save hex nuts and
                    flat washers for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mount cap (Item 5) from two square head bolts (Item 3) under front cab
                    mounting insulator (Item 6), driver side shown. Save front cab mount cap for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove hex flanged nut (Item 13) from hex flanged bolt (Item 14) and remove hex flanged
                    bolt. Save hex flanged nut and hex flanged bolt for installation, unless damaged and being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mounting insulator (Item 6) from lower chassis front cab mounting
                    support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save front cab mounting insulator for installation, unless
                    damaged and being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side front cab mounting insulator.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Upper Front Cab Mounting Bracket for on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603397"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to replace the upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7), use a
                    bottle jack between bottom of cab and frame rail to support cab, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove four hex flanged bolts (Item 15) from upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7),
                    driver side shown. Save hex flanged bolts for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7) from under cab, driver side shown. Save
                    front cab mounting bracket for installation, unless damaged and being replaced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side upper front cab mounting bracket.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting Carriage Bolts on Daycab</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">Figure 97</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603397"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the cab is lifted from the rear cab air suspension assembly (Item 10). The two
                    carriage bolts (Item 9) are secured to the cab underbody sill (Item 11) with cab mount retaining
                    clips (Item 12). The carriage bolts will remain with cab underbody sill when cab is lifted off the
                    rear cab air suspension assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to replace the two carriage bolts (Item 9), you will have to remove
                    the driver bucket seat and passenger bucket seat or fixed passenger seat.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove passenger air bucket seat or fixed passenger seat, and driver air bucket seat on
                    Daycab, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603313.xml" xrefid="x1603313">
                        <emph type="bold">SEATS</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="x1603313"/>. For removing passenger air bucket seat, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Passenger Air Bucket Seat on Daycab</emph>. For removing fixed passenger
                    seat, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Fixed Passenger Seat on Daycab</emph>. For removing driver air bucket seat,
                    refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Driver Air Bucket Seat on Daycab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove passenger air bucket seat or fixed passenger seat, and driver air bucket seat on
                    sleeper cab, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603313.xml" xrefid="x1603313">
                        <emph type="bold">SEATS</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="x1603313"/>. For removing passenger air bucket seat, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Passenger Air Bucket Seat on Sleeper Cab</emph>. For removing fixed
                    passenger seat, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Fixed Passenger Seat on Sleeper Cab</emph>. For removing driver air bucket
                    seat, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Remove Driver Air Bucket Seat on Sleeper Cab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the seats have been removed as required. Remove seat belt mounting bolts securing
                    seat belts to cab floor at the rear of the cab. Pull floor mat up to access carriage bolts in cab
                    underbody sill (Item 11), then pull them up and thread them off cab mount retaining clips (Item 12).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Daycab Rear Cab Air Suspension</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The Rear Cab Air Suspension System shown is built with the crossmember as part of the rear cab
                        air suspension system; it is installed as an assembly at the assembly plant. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603397">(Item 10, Figure 97)</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="f1603397"/>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If it is necessary to replace any part of the rear cab air suspension assembly (Item 10)
                    you will have to replace each component separately as they are built into the crossmember.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Short Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603398">Figure 98</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex nuts (Item 1) with two flat washers (Item 2) from two square head bolts
                    (Item 3) under lower chassis front cab mount support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save hex nuts and
                    flat washers for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mount cap (Item 5) from two square head bolts (Item 3) under front cab
                    mounting insulator (Item 6), driver side shown. Save front cab mount cap for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull two square head bolts (Item 3) out of upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7),
                    driver side shown. Save square head bolts for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side cab mounting hardware.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603398" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603399.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                         scalefitheight="456px"/>
                <caption>Figure 98. Short Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting and Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension
                    Mounting
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEX NUT (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLAT WASHER (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SQUARE HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER CHASSIS FRONT CAB MOUNT SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. FRONT CAB MOUNT CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT CAB MOUNTING INSULATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. UPPER FRONT CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 12 X 1.75-6G 150MM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. REAR CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 12 X 1.75-6G 150MM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. REAR CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. LINK HEX FLANGED HEAD SHOULDER BOLT (M6)</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. LINK FLAT WASHER (M6)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE LINKAGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. DRIVER SIDE FRAME RAIL</callout1>
                    <callout1>16 PASSENGER SIDE FRAME RAIL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Short Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603398">Figure 98</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603398"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex flanged bolts (Item 8) from rear cab mounting bracket (Item 9) under rear
                    of cab floor on driver side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex flanged bolts (Item 10) from rear cab mounting bracket (Item 11) under
                    rear of cab floor on passenger side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen link hex flanged head shoulder bolt (Item 12) with flat washer (Item 13) and
                    remove height control valve linkage (Item 14) from back of cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Inspect all cab to frame attaching points to be sure they are disconnected or damage can
                        result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using an overhead crane and cab lifting fixture, carefully lift cab from chassis. If
                    removing cab from overhead crane, set it on a suitable surface to protect painted surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Long Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603399">Figure 99</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex nuts (Item 1) with two flat washers (Item 2) from two square head bolts
                    (Item 3) under lower chassis front cab mount support (Item 4), driver side shown. Save hex nuts and
                    flat washers for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove front cab mount cap (Item 5) from two square head bolts (Item 3) under front cab
                    mounting insulator (Item 6), driver side shown. Save front cab mount cap for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull two square head bolts (Item 3) out of upper front cab mounting bracket (Item 7),
                    driver side shown. Save square head bolts for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove passenger side cab mounting hardware.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603399" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g16033a0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                         scalefitheight="456px"/>
                <caption>Figure 99. Long Sleeper Cab Front Cab Mounting and Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension
                    Mounting
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEX NUT (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLAT WASHER (M12)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SQUARE HEAD BOLT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. LOWER CHASSIS FRONT CAB MOUNT SUPPORT</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. FRONT CAB MOUNT CAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FRONT CAB MOUNTING INSULATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. UPPER FRONT CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 12 X 1.75-6G 150MM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. REAR CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. HEX FLANGED BOLT (M 12 X 1.75-6G 150MM)</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. REAR CAB MOUNTING BRACKET</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. LINK HEX FLANGED HEAD SHOULDER BOLT (M6)</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. LINK FLAT WASHER (M6)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE LINKAGE</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. DRIVER SIDE FRAME RAIL</callout1>
                    <callout1>16 PASSENGER SIDE FRAME RAIL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove Long Sleeper Cab Rear Cab Air Suspension Mounting</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603399">Figure 99</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603399"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex flanged bolts (Item 8) from rear cab mounting bracket (Item 9) under rear
                    of cab floor on driver side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two hex flanged bolts (Item 10) from rear cab mounting bracket (Item 11) under
                    rear of cab floor on passenger side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Loosen link hex flanged head shoulder bolt (Item 12) with flat washer (Item 13) and
                    remove height control valve linkage (Item 14) from back of cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Inspect all cab to frame attaching points to be sure they are disconnected or damage can
                        result.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using an overhead crane and cab lifting fixture, carefully lift cab from chassis. If
                    removing cab from overhead crane, set it on a suitable surface to protect painted surfaces.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_63.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_65.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
