<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - DESCRIPTION - DESCRIPTION OF APADS AND
        SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DESCRIPTION OF APADS AND SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>As a means of better understanding the overall system, consider the following description of the
                components used in an International truck air conditioning system with the air conditioning protection
                and diagnostics system (APADS) installed. The system has the following components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>APADS Control Module</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APADS Wiring Harness</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APADS High Pressure Cutout Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APADS High Side - Low Pressure Cutout Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APADS Low Side - Low Pressure Cutout Switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>APADS low side port adapter</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>APADS Function</title>
            <para>The air conditioning protection and diagnostics system (APADS) is designed to protect major air
                conditioning (A/C) components from damage, and to diagnose A/C system problems.
            </para>
            <para>APADS is a practical, user focused design, intended to reduce maintenance costs, increase A/C system
                durability, and ease troubleshooting tasks. The system achieves these objectives with low-risk, proven
                technology, without any changes to the basic A/C refrigerant system.
            </para>
            <para>The APADS will detect both major and minor problems early. This prevents the failure of major
                components, thus saving money and costly downtime.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602201">Figure 1</hotlnk>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602201" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 1. APADS Control Module and Pressure Switches</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
