<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - CF 500, CF 600 Heat Ventilation Air Conditioning (HVAC) System - SERVICE
        PROCEDURES - FLUSHING and PURGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1603013" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
        <title>FLUSHING and PURGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="t1200010">
                <title>Special Tools</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.98*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603061.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="72px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Evaporator Flush/Purge Adapter</para>
                                <para>ZTSE4718</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603010.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="96px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Flush Gun, Drain Hose and Adapters</para>
                                <para>(Obtain Locally)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <table id="t1200010">
                <title>Material</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.98*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Item</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Part No.</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>A/C Systems Flushing Solvent</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>See Fleetrite catalog</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603004.xml" xrefid="hl1603004">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                        read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                        could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Dry nitrogen gas is recommended for flushing and/or purging. Do not use nitrogen at pressures
                        over 862 kPa (125 psi). Personal injury or death may result from doing so. Commercial cylinders
                        of dry nitrogen contain pressures in excess of 13780 kPa (2000 psi). This pressure must be
                        reduced, using a pressure regulator, to 621 to 862 kPa (90 to 125 psi) for purging.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When flushing and/or purging components of the system use only dry nitrogen. The introduction
                        of compressed air into the A/C system may cause contamination of the system.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When flushing components, use only flushing agents approved for R-134a charged air
                        conditioning systems (refer to the Fleetrite HVAC catalog for an approved flush solvent). R-11
                        and any other flushing agents that were used to flush R-12 charged air conditioning systems
                        <emph type="bold">CANNOT</emph>
                        be used to flush R-134a systems. The residue left by these flushing products will destroy the
                        lubrication properties of the oil used in R-134a systems.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>A flush gun, along with compressed dry nitrogen, is required to inject the flushing agent into the
                component being flushed. All items can be obtained locally.
            </para>
            <para>Systems that have had an internal compressor failure, that have been overcharged with refrigeration
                oil, or that have been left open for an extended period of time, will need to be flushed, purged or
                both. Flushing is generally necessary only after an internal compressor failure has contaminated the
                refrigerant system. Flushing and purging are performed on a system after the refrigerant has been
                recovered and before the system is reassembled and evacuated.
            </para>
            <para>Flushing removes heavy contamination, such as gritty oil and large dirt buildup, which occur after an
                internal compressor failure. When a part is flushed, a flushing solvent is forced through it; the liquid
                solvent cleans the part, picks up contaminants and flushes them out.
            </para>
            <para>Purging must always be performed: after flushing the system; any time there is excessive refrigerant
                oil found in the system; or, when the system has been left open for an extended period of time. Purging
                removes flushing solvent, excessive refrigerant oil, damp air, and loose particles from A/C system
                components by passing a stream of inert, dry nitrogen gas through parts of the system or individual
                components. This assures that A/C system components are dry and free of any contaminants. If left in the
                system, these contaminants would have a negative effect on the life and operation of the air
                conditioning system.
            </para>
            <para>The following procedures must be observed whenever a component or system is flushed or purged.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Never flush or purge the entire system. Flush or purge the system in segments to lessen the
                        chance of blowing contaminants throughout the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never flush or purge the compressor, expansion valve or receiver/drier.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flush or purge each system section or component in the opposite direction of normal
                        refrigerant flow.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After flushing the system, it must be purged; then, replace the compressor, expansion valve,
                        and receiver/drier with new components prior to evacuating and charging the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the system is purged, without flushing (system not contaminated); change oil in the
                        compressor (refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603007.xml" xrefid="hl1603007">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>),
                        reinstall (or replace) the expansion valve, and install a new receiver/drier prior to evacuating
                        and charging the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following procedures for flushing and purging are general. The actual fittings and
                        adapters required for each procedure will vary according to the component or components being
                        connected.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flushing Procedure</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603003">FIGURE 7</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603003" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603011.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Typical Flushing and Purging Setup</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. NITROGEN IN</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. TO WASTE CONTAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. DRAIN LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COMPONENT TO BE FLUSHED OR PURGED</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FITTINGS OR ADAPTERS</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. SUPPLY LINE VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. NITROGEN BOTTLE REGULATOR/GAUGES</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. NITROGEN BOTTLE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. NITROGEN BOTTLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. FLUSH GUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. TRIGGER TYPE AIR GUN</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both ends of the component or components to be flushed, and tightly cap the
                    rest of the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the tank regulator (5) turned off (closed), open the main nitrogen tank valve (6),
                    and using the input gauge on the regulator, verify that enough pressure is available to perform the
                    flushing procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the input of the flush gun (8) to the output of the supply line from the
                    nitrogen tank. Some form of shutoff valve should be installed at the input of the flush gun.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or adapters (3), connect the drain line (1) to the component
                    to be flushed. Components are flushed in the opposite direction of normal refrigerant flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or adapters, connect the flush gun output to the component to
                    be flushed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the outlet of the drain line into a suitable waste container.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the flush gun tank with an appropriate amount of flushing agent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the supply line air regulator (5) to 75 psi.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the supply line valve (4) at the output of the tank regulator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open the flush gun valve and allow the flushing solvent to flow through the
                    system until the drain line is clear; then, close the flush gun valve. If a trigger type air gun (9)
                    is being used on the flush gun output, actuate the trigger to release all pressure from the flush
                    gun tank.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the supply line valve (4).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The flush gun MUST be removed from the equipment setup before performing the purge procedures.
                        The flush gun is not designed to be used at the pressures used for the purge procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the flushing equipment to the next component to be flushed; or, empty the flush
                    gun tank and
                    <emph type="bold">remove the flush gun</emph>
                    from the supply line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect drain hose and all fittings and adapters from the component.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the inlet and outlet of the component until it can be purged.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After flushing a component, that component must be purged</para>
                    <para>before connecting it to the air conditioning system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl1603017">PURGING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1603017">
            <title>Purging Procedure</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603003">FIGURE 7</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both ends of the component to be purged and tightly cap the rest of the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the tank regulator (5) turned off (closed), open the main nitrogen tank valve (6),
                    and using the input gauge on the regulator, verify that enough pressure is available to perform the
                    purging procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or adapters (3), connect the drain line (1) to the component
                    to be purged. Components are purged in the opposite direction of normal refrigerant flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or adapters, connect the nitrogen supply line output to the
                    component to be purged. A trigger type air gun (9) may be hand-held for some components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the outlet of the drain line into a suitable waste container.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the supply line air regulator (5) to 28 kPa (4 psi).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open the supply line valve (4) at the output of the tank regulator. If a trigger
                    type air gun is being used, actuate the trigger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Let the dry nitrogen flow at 28 kPa (4 psi) for one to two minutes, or until there is no
                    trace of refrigerant flushing agent or refrigerant oil flowing from the drain tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the pressure regulator, raise the pressure to 621 to 862 kPa (90 to 125 psi) and
                    let the dry nitrogen flow for 25 to 30 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the pressure regulator for 0 psi; then, close the supply line valve (4).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a trigger type air gun is being used, actuate the trigger to release pressure in the
                    hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the supply and drain lines from the part, and remove all fittings and
                    adapters (3). Tightly cap the openings of the part until you are ready to install it into the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always lubricate O-rings on fittings with mineral-based oil during installation.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The component is now ready to be installed into the air conditioner system using new
                    O-rings, where applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After purging the system, and prior to evacuating and charging the system;</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">replace the receiver/drier,</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">reinstall (or replace) the expansion valve,</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">determine the correct quantity of oil needed to refill the system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603007.xml" xrefid="hl1603007">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>,
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">reinstall (or replace) the compressor.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603014.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603007.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
