<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - REMOVE AND INSTALL - EVAPORATOR CORE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602510" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EVAPORATOR CORE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602508.xml" xrefid="f1602529">Figure 30</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove evaporator housing (1) from cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602508.xml" xrefid="hl1602508">REMOVE AND INSTALL, AIR CONDITIONER
                        (EVAPORATOR) HOUSING
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602508"/>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While separating the evaporator housing be careful not to damage the fins or fittings on the
                        evaporator core.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>The housing halves normally snap together and are secured with one screw (hi-lo thread);
                        however, mounting tabs are provided to allow assembling the halves with additional hi-lo thread
                        screws if the plastic snaps are damaged during disassembly. The mounting tabs are designed
                        specifically to use only hi-lo thread screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate the housing halves by removing one or more screws, releasing the snap tabs, and
                    pulling the halves straight away from each other.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When the housing is separated, the evaporator core (6) is accessible.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the evaporator core.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While assembling the evaporator housing be careful not to damage the fins or fitting on the
                        evaporator core.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>The housing halves normally snap together and are secured with one screw (hi-lo thread);
                        however, mounting tabs are provided to allow assembling the halves with additional hi-lo thread
                        screws if the plastic snaps are damaged during disassembly. The mounting tabs are designed
                        specifically to use only hi-lo thread screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Align the evaporator housing halves with the evaporator core (6) and the fresh/recirc
                    air door (3) installed between them. (If the door actuator was not removed, align the flats on the
                    door shaft with the actuator hub.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Join the housing halves by using the snap tabs and one screw. If any of the snap tabs
                    have been damaged, use additional hi-lo thread screws in the molded joining tabs to securely join
                    the halves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, never force the actuator drive collar into position. If the drive
                        collar position must be changed, follow the following procedures. Forcing the drive collar may
                        result in a broken actuator.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the fresh/recirculate air door actuator was previously removed, install the actuator
                    (4) by aligning the flats on the door shaft with the actuator hub, if possible. Secure the actuator
                    with two screws. If alignment is necessary:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the actuator into its approximate position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect a 9 Volt battery across pins A and F of the actuator connector, to rotate
                        the drive collar. (Reverse the connection to rotate the drive collar in the opposite direction.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Allow the drive collar to rotate until it is aligned with the door shaft, and the
                        actuator mounting screws can be inserted. Then, disconnect 9 Volt battery.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install evaporator housing onto cowl. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602508.xml" xrefid="hl1602508">REMOVE AND INSTALL, AIR CONDITIONER
                        (EVAPORATOR) HOUSING
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602508"/>
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602509.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602512.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
