<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc id="hl1603010">
        <title>Component Tests</title>
        <para>
            <title>Heater Core</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Carbon monoxide is colorless, odorless and dangerous. If it is necessary to operate the engine
                    with the vehicle in an enclosed area such as a garage, always use an exhaust collector to vent the
                    exhaust gases outside the enclosed area.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Testing of returned heater cores reveals that a large percentage of heater cores were good and did
                    not require replacement. If a heater core leak is suspected, the heater core must be tested by
                    following the plugged heater core component test before the heater core pressure test. Carry out a
                    system inspection by checking the heater system thoroughly as follows:
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Inspect for evidence of coolant leakage at the heater water hose to heater core attachments.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: Spring-type clamps are installed as original equipment. Installation and
                        overtightening of non-specification clamps can cause leakage at the heater water hose connection
                        and damage the heater core.
                    </emph>
                </para>
                <para>Check the integrity of the heater water hose clamps.</para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <title>Heater Core - Plugged</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The heater core inlet hose will become too hot to handle if the system is working correctly.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Check to see that the engine coolant is at the correct level.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Start the engine and turn on the heater.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>When the engine coolant reaches operating temperature, feel the heater core inlet and outlet hose
                    to see if they are hot.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>If the inlet hose is not hot:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>the thermostat is not working correctly.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>If the outlet hose is not hot:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>the heater core may have an air pocket.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>the heater core may be restricted or plugged.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>
            <title>Heater Core - Pressure Test</title>
        </para>
        <para>Use the Pressure Tester to carry out the pressure test.</para>
        <figure id="f1200003" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figal0/AL0143B.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1.</caption>
        </figure>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Clamp off the heater hoses.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect the heater water hoses from the heater core.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Install a short piece of heater water hose, approximately 101 mm (4 inches) long on each heater
                    core tube.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Fill the heater core and heater water hoses with water.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Install a plug and adapter that will allow for connection of the Pressure Tester to the heater
                    water hose ends. Secure the heater water hoses, plug and adapter with hose clamps.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Attach the pump and gauge assembly from the Pressure Tester to the adapter.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Close the bleed valve at the base of the gauge. Pump 138 kPa (20 psi) of air pressure into the
                    heater core.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Observe the pressure gauge for a minimum of 3 minutes.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the pressure drops, check the heater water hose connections to the core tubes for leaks. If the
                    heater water hoses do not leak, remove the heater core from the vehicle and carry out the bench
                    test.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
        <para>
            <title>A/C Evaporator/Condenser Core - On Vehicle Leak Test</title>
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The use of a refrigerant (recovery/recycling/recharging) station is recommended for servicing this
                    A/C system. If a refrigerant station is not available, refrigerant system testing and servicing may
                    be accomplished using a separate recovery station, vacuum pump, charging meter and manifold gauge
                    set. If separate equipment is used, refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that
                    equipment.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>The automatic shut-off valves on some gauge set hoses do not open when connected to the test
                    fittings. If available, use hoses without automatic shut-off valves. If hoses with automatic
                    shut-off valves are used, make sure the valve opens when attached to the test fittings or install an
                    adapter which will activate the valve. The test is not valid if the shut-off valve does not open.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <seqlist style="arabic">
            <item>
                <para>Recover the refrigerant. For additional information, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603003.xml" xrefid="hl1603003">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM (REFRIGERANT
                        RECOVERY)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Disconnect the suspect A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core from the A/C system. (If the
                    evaporator is being tested, the thermostatic expansion valve must be removed.)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Clean the fittings.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect the appropriate test fittings to the evaporator or condenser tube connections. (When
                    testing the evaporator core, the evaporator adapter must be installed.) The fittings must allow
                    connection of the refrigerant station (or manifold gauge set) to the component under test.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Connect the red and blue hoses from the R-134a refrigerant station (or manifold gauge set) to the
                    test fittings on the A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core. (If a manifold gauge set is being
                    used, connect the yellow hose to a known good vacuum pump.)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>On the refrigerant station, set both valves to the RECOVERY/VACUUM position, turn on the power,
                    and press the VACUUM button. Allow the vacuum pump to operate for a minimum of 45 minutes after the
                    low pressure gauge indicates 101 kPa (30 in-Hg). The 45 minute evacuation is necessary to remove any
                    refrigerant from oil left in the A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core. If the refrigerant is
                    not completely removed from the oil, outgassing will degrade the vacuum and appear as a refrigerant
                    leak.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the low pressure gauge reading will not drop to 101 kPa (30 in-Hg) when the valves are open and
                    the vacuum pump is operating, close the valves and observe the low pressure gauge. If the pressure
                    rises rapidly to zero, a large leak is indicated. Recheck the test fitting connections and test
                    equipment connections before installing a new A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>After evacuating the system for 45 minutes, close both valves. (If a separate vacuum pump is used,
                    switch off the vacuum pump.) Observe the low pressure gauge; it should remain at the 101 kPa (30
                    in-Hg) mark.
                </para>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>If the low pressure gauge reading rises 34 or more kPa (10 or more in-Hg) of vacuum from
                            the 101 kPa (30 in-Hg) position in 10 minutes, a leak is indicated.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a very small leak is suspected, wait 30 minutes and observe the vacuum gauge.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a small amount of vacuum is lost, operate the vacuum pump with gauge valves open for an
                            additional 30 minutes to remove any remaining refrigerant from the oil in the A/C evaporator
                            core or A/C condenser core. Then recheck for loss of vacuum.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>If a very small leak is suspected, allow the system to set overnight with vacuum applied
                            and check for vacuum loss.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core does leak, as verified by the above procedure,
                    install a new A/C evaporator core or A/C condenser core.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
