<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - OIL FILL GUIDELINES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601911" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OIL FILL GUIDELINES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml" xrefid="hl1601912">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                        read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                        could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not re-use recovered oil. Be sure to dispose of recovered oil properly to avoid an
                        environmental hazard.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>Replacement compressors may contain a quantity of oil when shipped. The quantity of oil in the
                        compressor must be measured (by dipstick or draining) to determine how much additional oil is
                        needed to return the system oil level to normal.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>During normal A/C operation, oil is circulated through the system with the refrigerant, and a
                        small amount is retained in each component. If certain components of the system are removed,
                        some of the refrigerant oil will go with the component. To maintain the original total oil
                        charge, it is necessary to compensate for the oil lost by adding oil to the system with the new
                        part.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The two compressors covered in this manual use different types of refrigerant oil. The following
                procedures cover both compressor types. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601918.xml" xrefid="hl1601918">REFRIGERANT OIL</hotlnk>
                for information on the refrigerant oil types used with the different compressors. System oil capacities
                are provided in the
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                section.
            </para>
            <para>The correct volume of refrigerant oil in the A/C system is critical for proper system operation.
                Insufficient oil will result in compressor failure. Too much oil decreases cooling efficiency, resulting
                in poor system cooling performance. In general, when servicing the system, ensure that the amount of oil
                (retained or added) in the repaired system (
                <emph type="bold">compressor and components</emph>) equals the total
                <emph type="bold">SYSTEM</emph>
                capacity indicated in
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>. Replacement oil may
                be added directly into the compressor before evacuation, or injected into the system after evacuation.
                The following paragraphs describe how to determine the quantity of refill oil needed under the most
                common conditions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Unless stated otherwise, the following procedures assume that the system is not being flushed
                        and/or purged.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>If the refrigerant was only recovered for the purpose of measuring the refrigerant charge, add
                        the amount of oil removed from the system during the refrigerant recovery procedure.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a compressor is replaced (and the system was
                        <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                        contaminated and had no leaks) fill the new compressor with the amount of oil removed from the
                        system during the refrigerant recovery procedure, plus the quantity of oil that was contained in
                        the old compressor. (NOTE: The amount of oil in new CCI compressors must be measured to
                        calculate the amount of oil to add to the system. The oil in new Sanden compressors must be
                        drained before adding the new oil to the system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601930.xml" xrefid="hl1601930">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                            LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to check the oil level in the refrigerant
                        compressor.) Refill the system (new compressor) as follows.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>(CCI Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure
                                <emph type="bold">+</emph>
                                oil measured in old compressor
                                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                the oil measured in the new compressor.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>(Sanden Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure
                                <emph type="bold">+</emph>
                                oil drained from old compressor.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a component other than the compressor is replaced, and there is no oil leak; add the amount
                        of oil removed from the system during the refrigerant recovery procedure, plus the amount
                        indicated for the replaced component in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="t1601903">Table 5</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure
                                <emph type="bold">+</emph>
                                oil indicated in component table.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the amount of oil in the system is unknown (due to an oil leak, ruptured hose, etc.); refer
                        to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl1601931">EXCESSIVE OIL LOSS DUE TO REFRIGERANT LEAK</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Whenever the refrigerant system has become contaminated: make the necessary repairs; flush and
                        purge the system; and replace the expansion valve, receiver-dryer, and compressor. (NOTE: The
                        amount of oil in new CCI compressors must be measured to calculate the amount of oil to add to
                        the system. The oil in new Sanden compressors must be drained before adding new oil to the
                        system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601930.xml" xrefid="hl1601930">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                            LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to check the oil level in the refrigerant
                        compressor.) Refill the system (compressor) as follows.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>(CCI Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                total system capacity as specified in SPECIFICATIONS
                                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                oil measured in the new compressor.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>(Sanden Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                total system capacity as specified in SPECIFICATIONS
                                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                0.5 fl.oz (oil film left in new compressor).
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <table id="t1601903" tblwidth="full-page">
                <title>Oil Capacity by Component</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="1" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>Component</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Typical oil amount</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>cc</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>fl.oz.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Evaporator</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>60</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Condenser</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>30</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Receiver-Dryer</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Hoses (normal length)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>10</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pressure Switches</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Expansion Valve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Separation During Refrigerant Recovery</title>
            <para>The oil removed from the system during the refrigerant recovery process must be replaced. Always empty
                the recovery station oil catch bottle before recovering the refrigerant. After recovering the
                refrigerant, check the calibrated bottle to determine how much oil has been removed from the system.
                This quantity may be used to help determine the amount of NEW oil that must be added to the system
                before or during the recharging of the A/C system. Do not use recovered refrigerant oil.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1601931">
            <title>Excessive Oil Loss Due to Refrigerant Leak</title>
            <para>When there is a refrigerant leak, an unknown amount of oil escapes from the system with the
                refrigerant. When a major leak is detected perform the following procedures to re-establish the correct
                system oil level.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When installing components, use new O-rings (and C-plates on Sanden compressor systems with
                        peanut fittings) lubricated with mineral oil.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the service equipment and observation to determine the location of the leak. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601922.xml" xrefid="hl1601922">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discharge the system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601915.xml" xrefid="hl1601915">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make any necessary repairs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system does not appear to be contaminated, purge the system. If the system
                    appears contaminated, such as after an internal compressor failure, it must be flushed before
                    purging. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601910.xml" xrefid="hl1601910">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system
                    <emph type="bold">was not</emph>
                    contaminated:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Re-establish the correct system oil level as follows: (NOTE: The amount of oil in CCI
                            compressors must be measured to calculate the amount of oil to add to the system. The oil in
                            Sanden compressors must be drained before adding new oil to the system. Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601930.xml" xrefid="hl1601930">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                                LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to check the oil level in the
                            refrigerant compressor.)
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>(CCI Compressor) Total added oil quantity
                                    <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                    total system capacity as specified in
                                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                                    <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                    oil measured in the compressor.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>(Sanden Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                    <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                    total system capacity as specified in
                                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                                    <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                    0.5 fl.oz (oil film left in compressor after draining).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>(Sanden Compressor) Install the compressor. (Compressor was removed to drain oil.)</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system
                    <emph type="bold">was</emph>
                    contaminated:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace the expansion valve.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Replace the compressor and re-establish the correct system oil level, as follows: (NOTE:
                            The amount of oil in new CCI compressors must be measured to calculate the amount of oil to
                            add to the system. The oil in new Sanden compressors must be drained before adding new oil
                            to the system. Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601930.xml" xrefid="hl1601930">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                                LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to check the oil level in the
                            refrigerant compressor.)
                        </para>
                        <randlist type="bullet">
                            <item>
                                <para>(CCI Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                    <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                    total system capacity as specified in
                                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                                    <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                    oil measured in the new compressor.
                                </para>
                            </item>
                            <item>
                                <para>(Sanden Compressor) Total replacement oil quantity
                                    <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                    total system capacity as specified in
                                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                                    <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                    0.5 fl.oz (oil film left in new compressor after draining).
                                </para>
                            </item>
                        </randlist>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dryer.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using new O-rings, and C-plates (Sanden compressor systems with peanut fittings),
                    lubricated with mineral oil; reconnect all the components of the A/C system. Torque all joints per
                    the
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601932.xml" xrefid="t1601906">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601913.xml" xrefid="hl1601913">EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601916.xml" xrefid="hl1601916">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601910.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601930.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
