<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - DIAGNOSIS AND
        TESTING - PHYSICAL CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601905" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PHYSICAL CHECKS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>To help isolate a malfunctioning component in the refrigerant system, perform the following physical
                checks, if necessary.
            </para>
            <para>Start the engine and turn on the A/C system.</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>With air conditioning controls set for maximum cooling (A/C selected, blower switch on HIGH
                        and temperature control to COLD), operate engine at 1800 RPM and air conditioning system for
                        about five minutes or until initial heat has been removed from the cab and an average flow of
                        cold air is achieved.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>With the system operating, feel all air conditioning system components and refrigerant lines
                        for proper operating temperatures, as described in the following paragraphs.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the system does not cool, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601904.xml" xrefid="hl1601904">AIR NOT COLD ENOUGH</hotlnk>
                        diagnosis chart.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Avoid contact with moving belts, pulleys and fan when making this check. Beware of extremely
                        high temperatures at compressor outlet (discharge) hoses and tubing as personal injury may
                        result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For vehicles equipped with a CCI compressor, additional A/C compressor and/or magnetic clutch
                        diagnosis can be found in
                        <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16017x.htm" bookname="s16017x">s16017</exhotlnk>, COMPRESSOR-CLUTCH
                        in the Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following is a brief description of symptoms or conditions that could exist if the vehicle air
                conditioning system is malfunctioning.
            </para>
            <para>From the discharge side of the compressor along the high pressure line, through the condenser,
                receiver-dryer and up to the expansion valve, everything should be hot or warm to the touch. The
                expansion valve, evaporator and all the lines on the low pressure side leading back to the compressor
                should be cool to the touch. Any deviation from the above conditions indicates a malfunction in the
                system.
            </para>
            <para>Malfunctions or stoppages may be indicated by extreme cold or frosted areas (example: a cold
                receiver-dryer frosted part way up indicates a stoppage or serious restriction in the receiver-dryer). A
                stoppage or severe restriction in the refrigerant system can be located by looking for these
                indications.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Receiver-Dryer</title>
            <para>The receiver-dryer is normally at outside temperature. To the touch, the entire length of the unit
                should be the same temperature. If noticeable cold spots exist, replace the receiver-dryer.
            </para>
            <para>A blockage at the receiver-dryer will cause high head pressure and little or no cooling.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Expansion Valve</title>
            <para>Problems that start in the expansion valve show up as follows: when stuck closed, the evaporator coil
                and expansion valve will be at outside temperature; when stuck open, both the evaporator coil and the
                valve will be extremely cold with frost or ice build-up.
            </para>
            <para>Because the expansion valve channels are very small, blockage in the system is usually found here (the
                valve is very sensitive to contamination). Usually the contamination is water; less than a drop of water
                is all it takes to make the valve inoperative. When water reaches the valve, the extreme cold that
                results from the pressure drop freezes the water, forming an ice blockage. After the system shuts down
                and the valve warms up, and the valve operates again, only to freeze up when the moisture returns and
                the temperature drops.
            </para>
            <para>On-and-off operation of the expansion valve means that the receiver-dryer is not removing moisture
                from the system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Refrigerant Compressor</title>
            <para>Compressor problems usually show in one of four ways: abnormal noise, seizure, leakage, or high
                suction and low discharge pressure. Resonant noises are not a cause for alarm; irregular noise or
                rattles are likely caused by broken parts.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The engine must be switched off before checking the compressor for seizure.</para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, the compressor should be turned only in its normal direction of
                        travel.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>To check for seizure, de-energize the magnetic clutch and attempt to turn the clutch drive plate using
                a clutch wrench. If it won't turn, the compressor has seized.
            </para>
            <para>If a compressor is suspected of malfunctioning, but testing has been inconclusive, a simple test may
                confirm the condition of the compressor. NOTE: This test can confirm that the compressor is operating
                correctly, but will not identify the faulty component if the test fails. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601933.xml" xrefid="hl1601933">COMPRESSOR TEST</hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For vehicles equipped with a CCI compressor, additional A/C compressor and/or magnetic clutch
                        information can be found in
                        <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16017x.htm" bookname="s16017x">s16017</exhotlnk>, COMPRESSOR-CLUTCH
                        in the Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Evaporator</title>
            <para>The evaporator coils are basically trouble-free when airflow over the fins is not blocked. External
                or, less often, internal blockage will cause low suction pressure as well as little or no cooling. If a
                leak exists in the system, and it cannot be traced to other parts or fittings, suspect damage to one of
                the evaporator coils.
            </para>
            <para>Evaporator Freeze-ups are the result of the moisture in the air condensing and then freezing on the
                evaporator core. The ice on the fins blocks the airflow through the evaporator and stops the cooling
                until the ice melts. If the components that control temperature and pressure in the evaporator
                malfunction and allow the evaporator's temperature to drop to 32 degrees F (0 degrees C), freeze-up of
                the evaporator core will occur.
            </para>
            <para>A flooded evaporator occurs when there is too much refrigerant flowing into the evaporator. On older
                systems, flooding can be the result of the sensing bulb of the expansion valve being misplaced,
                improperly insulated, in poor contact with the evaporator suction side tube, or a defective expansion
                valve. A starved evaporator occurs when there is not enough refrigerant flowing into the evaporator.
                Starvation can be caused by a defective expansion valve.
            </para>
            <para>The evaporator is the most difficult of all the components to inspect visually because of its enclosed
                location. Airflow blockage due to debris, bent fins, and/or refrigerant leaks (oil smudges) requires
                removal of the evaporator for visual inspection.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Condenser</title>
            <para>The condenser is usually trouble-free. Normally, the temperature of the condenser outlet line is
                noticeably cooler than the inlet line. However, when road debris (such as leaves or dirt build-up) cakes
                up, airflow over the condenser fins is reduced; air is not able to absorb enough heat to turn the hot
                refrigerant gas into a liquid. High discharge pressure will result. In these cases, carefully clean off
                the outer surface of the condenser with soap and water and compressed air; be careful not to bend the
                fins.
            </para>
            <para>High discharge pressure will also occur if the condenser's tubing is abnormally bent, restricting or
                blocking the flow of refrigerant. Frost will appear at the point where the flow of refrigerant is
                restricted. Less common internal blockage (foreign material or metallic grit build-up) will restrict or
                stop the flow of refrigerant.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostatic Switch</title>
            <para>Before troubleshooting the thermostatic switch, be sure there is a full charge of refrigerant in the
                system. The compressor will not operate, or will cycle too often if there is not enough refrigerant in
                the system.
            </para>
            <para>Quick or delayed cycling of the compressor may be caused by a thermostatic switch that is working, but
                is out of adjustment. If, after doing the test below, the switch seems to be out of adjustment, replace
                it.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the compressor clutch is operating correctly.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For vehicles equipped with a CCI compressor, additional clutch information can be found in
                            <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16017x.htm" bookname="s16017x">s16017</exhotlnk>,
                            COMPRESSOR-CLUTCH in the Master Service Manual.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Expose the evaporator coils.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine. Place the air conditioning temperature control at its coldest setting;
                    turn on the air conditioner and the fan.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place an accurate thermometer into contact with a tube in the evaporator coil. Be sure
                    it makes good contact with the tube, or you will get an incorrect reading.
                </para>
                <para>When the temperature drops below the 'A/C Off' set point, compressor clutch should disengage and
                    remain disengaged until evaporator temperature rises to the 'A/C On' set point. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="t1601907">THERMOSTATIC CONTROL SWITCH CYCLE
                        POINTS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the compressor clutch did not engage when the temperature was at or above the high
                    temperature 'A/C On' point, do the following:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect a voltmeter or a test light from one terminal on the thermostatic switch to
                        ground. Repeat on the other terminal of the switch. With the engine running and the air
                        conditioning and blower on, both terminals will show voltage when the compressor should be
                        engaged (temperature above 'A/C On' level). One terminal will show voltage when the compressor
                        should be disengaged (temperature below 'A/C Off' level).
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there is no voltage at either terminal, there is a problem in the electrical
                        system to the thermostatic switch. Check all circuits for the cause, and repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If there is voltage at only one terminal, even when the temperature is above the
                        'A/C On' level, the thermostatic switch is not functioning correctly. Check placement and
                        condition of capillary tube. If a problem with the capillary tube is not apparent, replace the
                        thermostatic switch.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">If voltages are correct, either the compressor clutch is malfunctioning; or, there
                        is a problem in the electrical circuit between the thermostatic switch and the compressor
                        clutch. Check all circuits for the cause, and repair.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For diagnosis and troubleshooting of electrical problems, refer to Group 8 ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT
                        DIAGRAMS; ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE; and/or HEATING, VENTILATION AND AIR
                        CONDITIONING (HVAC) TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE, in the MASTER SERVICE MANUAL, for the vehicle being
                        serviced.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Line Restrictions</title>
            <para>A restricted suction line causes low suction pressure at the compressor and little or no cooling. A
                restriction in a line between the compressor and the expansion valve can cause high discharge and low
                suction pressure, and poor cooling. Generally, if the line is not entirely blocked, the area immediately
                after the restriction will be cold. A completely blocked line will result in high head pressures, but no
                physical symptoms at the blockage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601909.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601933.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
