<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - INSTALL - WIRE HARNESS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WIRE HARNESS</title>
        <para>The wire harness install procedures are in the following steps.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate the air conditioning compressor and connect the green wire from the APADS control
                module to the wire connected to the air conditioning compressor clutch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The wire harness has bare leads on one end. It will be necessary to cut these wires based on the
                    required length needed for installation.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The quick disconnect spade connectors have an integral, heat shrinkable seal. After crimping the
                    connectors, use a heat gun to shrink the seal.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the blue wire from the APADS control module to the wire connected to the air
                conditioning compressor clutch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the power source wire from the air conditioning compressor. This connector should be
                located about eight inches from the compressor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the black wire to the ground wire in the power distribution box or the ground post
                on the alternator.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the red wire to the power wire to the 12 volt keyed ignition source at the power
                distribution box.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the six pin connector on the wire harness to the APADS control module. If harness is
                not long enough, use the extension harness.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Do not strain the wires in the harness. Use the extensions to provide strain relief.</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the low pressure switch wire harness connector to the A/C low pressure switch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the high pressure switch wire harness connector to the A/C high pressure switch.
                Connectors are arranged so that the connection can only be made the correct way.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and connect the four pin connector on the pressure switch wire harness to the four
                pin connector on the APADS control module.If harness is not long enough, use the extension harness.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Secure the wire harness using the tie wraps and conduit, protect the wires with conduit as
                necessary. Fasten the six pin wire harness to the vehicle.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Fasten wraps about every eight to ten inches.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Do not put too much stress on the harness when installing the tie wraps.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The wire should be fastened tightly but not so tight as to put stress on the harness.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Leave adequate strain relief for each component, including connectors.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn vehicle ignition to the ON position.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_33.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_35.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
