<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - EVACUATING THE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601913" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml" xrefid="hl1601912">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                    read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                    could lead to serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The amount of oil lost during the recovery process, component replacement, or purging/flushing
                    must be replaced with new oil. The method for determining how much refrigerant oil must be added to
                    the A/C system is located in the
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only the refrigerant oil specified for the A/C system being serviced (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>PAG oils absorb atmospheric moisture very quickly. Never leave PAG oil exposed to air for a
                    prolonged time. Tightly reseal the oil container immediately after each use.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not re-use recovered oil. Be sure to dispose of recovered oil properly to avoid an
                    environmental hazard.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The locations of the A/C system high pressure and low pressure service ports vary by vehicle model
                    and year. The high pressure service port is located on the compressor's high pressure discharge line
                    between the compressor and the expansion valve. Typical locations are on the receiver-dryer or on
                    the compressor. The low pressure port is located on the compressor suction line, between the
                    expansion valve and the compressor.
                </para>
                <para>Discharge and suction ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not
                    visible, you can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter hose connected to
                    the compressor.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Whenever the air conditioning system has been discharged, the system must be completely evacuated of air
            and moisture before being recharged. After evacuation the system vacuum should measure between 750 and 1000
            microns.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>During the following procedure, oil should not be added until the system has been leak tested, and
                    all leaks have been repaired.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Determine the amount of
                <emph type="bold">NEW</emph>
                refrigerant oil to be added to the system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>
                . If oil is being added directly to the compressor, it must be added before starting the evacuation
                procedure. If oil is to be added during the evacuation/charging procedure, you must follow the
                instructions furnished with the recovery station, or refrigerant oil injector tool, to add the oil
                before the charging procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station and hose fittings, verify that all valves are closed. The valves at
                the recovery station must be set to the CLOSED position. The valves (knobs) at the quick-connect
                fittings must be set fully counter-clockwise (CCW).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the electronic vacuum gauge to the recovery station, at the vacuum manifold, using a
                valve and 'T' fittings (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601957">Figure 42</hotlnk>). Close the valve that isolates the electronic vacuum gauge
                from the low pressure line.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1601957" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1601979.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
            <caption>Figure 42. Connection of Electronic Vacuum Gauge</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>The valve for the electronic vacuum gauge must be in the closed position until instructed to open
                    it. If the valve is open during system charging, excess pressure may damage the electronic vacuum
                    gauge.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the recovery station to the system as follows (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601925.xml" xrefid="f1601956">Figure 41</hotlnk>):
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Start with the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    low pressure hose, and connect it to the low pressure service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    hose to the high pressure service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the red and blue hoses, open the valves on the Metric SAE quick-connect fittings (turn
                the knobs fully CW).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station, set both hand valves to the RECOVERY/VACUUM position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station, turn on main power switch and press the VACUUM button.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the low pressure gauge on the station shows that vacuum is being established in the
                system, continue to operate the vacuum pump for ten minutes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After ten minutes, set both valves on the recovery station to the CLOSED position, and
                observe low side gauge for one minute. The gauge should
                <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                indicate a rise of more than 2 inches-Hg. If the gauge rises more than 2 inches-Hg in one minute, the
                system has a leak which must be repaired. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601922.xml" xrefid="hl1601922">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If there are no leaks:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Set both hand valves on the recovery station to the RECOVERY/VACUUM position and press
                    the VACUUM button.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Open the valve connecting the electronic vacuum gauge to the recovery station low side
                    line.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Continue to operate the recovery station vacuum pump until the system has pulled a
                    vacuum of 750 - 1000 microns as measured by the electronic vacuum gauge. NOTE: Operate the vacuum
                    pump for a minimum of 10 minutes even if the vacuum reaches its target value sooner.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Close both hand valves on the recovery station, and the valve connecting the electronic
                    vacuum gauge to the recovery station low side line.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The A/C system is ready to be charged.
                <emph type="bold">REMEMBER,</emph>
                if the full amount of refrigerant oil has not yet been added to the system, it must be added before
                charging the system with refrigerant, as explained in the following procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>DO NOT disconnect the recovery/recycling/charging station from the A/C system before charging the
                    system.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601915.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601916.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
