<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL - HEATER HOSES/LINES - FRONT
        HVAC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
        <title>HEATER HOSES/LINES - FRONT HVAC SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the pressure cap from the deaeration tank.
                        ALWAYS INSULATE the cap by wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth. To prevent possible injury
                        from scalding water or steam, DO NOT pull the pressure cap off immediately when it has been
                        loosened to the first "notch." Pause momentarily to allow time for excess pressure to release
                        through the overflow tube.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Engine coolant is routed to and from the heater core using a combination of hoses and hard lines that
                vary by vehicle model and engine. Most hoses and lines are replaced using common practices, standard
                hose clamps, or threaded fittings. Only new or unique equipment is described in this section. In all
                cases replacement hoses and lines must be routed and secured in the same manor as the original
                equipment. Additional information for the coolant system may be found in the appropriate section(s) in
                GROUP 12 of the Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Some heater line connections now employ a peanut fitting (1,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603935">Figure 35</hotlnk>) that is sealed with an O-ring (2) and secured with one
                nut. Before installing a peanut fitting always verify that a new O-ring is in place.
            </para>
            <para>Some engine options require a flow restrictor (3,
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603936">Figure 36</hotlnk>) in the top (inlet) heater hose where it connects to the
                heater core at the cowl. When replacing this hose note whether the original hose contained a restrictor.
                If necessary, install a new restrictor into the replacement hose before installing the hose onto the
                vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>Depending on the vehicle model/engine combination, replacement of specific heater lines may require
                the removal of nearby assemblies to gain access to the hoses/lines. Refer to the appropriate section(s)
                in the Master Service Manual for additional procedures. For information on draining and filling engine
                coolant, refer to the appropriate COOLING section in GROUP 12 of the Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603935" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603935.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Typical Coolant Line Peanut Fitting</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PEANUT FITTING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. O-RING</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1603936" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603936.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Flow Restrictor in Heater Hose</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HEATER CORE TUBES</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. FLOW RESTRICTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HEATER HOSES</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390812.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390814.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
