<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - PAINT REFINISHING - PANEL REPAIR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PANEL REPAIR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When repairing collision damage, the extent of repair and the technique required will dictate
                        whether complete panels must be replaced or whether spot repair procedures can be used. If the
                        damage is limited to a single panel, and is not too severe, spot repair is the appropriate
                        repair technique. Minor dents, scratches, and gouges can be repaired in this way.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Metal Riveted Panels</title>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 16-CAB in CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the procedure for repair of collision
                damage involving panel replacement. Particular care should be taken concerning the sealing of panel
                joints and the proper treatment of rivets. In the case of a repair involving a riveted panel, the
                following procedures should be followed before the panels are riveted together.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wash panel and rivets with lacquer solvent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Degrease the panel and rivets with Sikkens M600 Wax and Grease Remover. Use two cloths:
                    the first with M600, the second dry, as a wipe on and wipe off process. Follow direction listed in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_27.xml" xrefid="hl1600201">Sikkens Degreasers &#38; Cleaners</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the material is:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Aluminum, sand with #150 - #180 grit paper dry. Wear an approved mask.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Cold rolled steel, sand sequentially with #80 then #120 grit paper dry.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Galvanized steel, sand with #120 grit paper dry.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Stainless steel, sand with #150 - #180 grit paper dry.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove dust by using compressed air.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Failure to wear eye protection and a dust mask could result in personal injury or death.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Degrease again using Sikkens M600 Wax and Grease Remover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix 100 parts Autocryl Filler Off-White with 50 parts of Autocryl 1.2.3 Hardener and 40
                    parts Sikkens 1.2.3 Reducer according to the directions in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_30.xml" xrefid="hl1600203">Sikkens Autocryl Filler Off-White</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply mixed Autocryl Filler Off-White following the instructions in the technical data
                    sheet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow to dry a minimum of 15 minutes at 70 degrees F. If longer than one hour, sanding
                    is required to assure topcoat adhesion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If sanding is required, use #360 - #410 grit paper dry or #500 - #600 grit wet. After
                    sanding, degrease the surface with M600 wax and grease remover. Wear an approved dust mask.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a 3/16 inch - 1/4 inch bead of sealer - Essex 55802/Essex 435.21 Primer or Lord
                    Versilak 204/No. 4 Activator - to one surface on the centerline of the rivet holes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rivet panel in place and allow sealer to cure according to the manufacturers
                    instructions.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Degrease the panel with Sikkens M600 Wax and Grease Remover. Use two cloths: the first
                    with M600, the second dry, as a wipe on and wipe off process. Follow the direction listed in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_27.xml" xrefid="hl1600201">Sikkens Degreasers &#38; Cleaners</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix 1 part Wash primer CR with 1 part Wash Hardener.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply mixed Wash Primer CR in one medium coat at 0.3 - 0.4 mils per pass. Specific
                    application guidelines for spray gun tip and pressures can be found in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_29.xml" xrefid="hl1600202">Sikkens Washprimer CR</hotlnk>. The wash primer
                    should be applied at a minimum temperature of 60 degrees F and a maximum Rh of 75%. Be sure to
                    thoroughly cover the rivet head and edges with Wash Primer CR.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow paint to flash off at ambient conditions for a minimum 15 minutes but no more than
                    8 hours at 70 degrees F.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Do not sand Wash Primer CR. If sanding becomes necessary, repeat Steps 14-15.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Mix 100 parts Autocryl Filler Off-White with 50 parts of Autocryl 1.2.3 Hardener and 40
                    parts Sikkens 1.2.3 Reducer according to the directions in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_30.xml" xrefid="hl1600203">Sikkens Autocryl Filler Off-White</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply mixed Autocryl Filler Off-White following the instructions in the technical data
                    sheet.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow to dry a minimum of 15 minutes at 70 degrees F. If longer than one hour, sanding
                    is required to assure topcoat adhesion.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If sanding is required, use #360 - #410 grit paper dry or #500 - #600 grit wet. After
                    sanding, degrease the surface with M600 wax and grease remover. Wear an approved dust mask. DO NOT
                    SAND RIVET HEADS.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Topcoat with Sikkens Autobase/Clearcoat System following the instructions in
                    <hotlnk document="s16002_32.xml" xrefid="hl1600204">Sikkens Autobase Metallic-Autoclear
                        System</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
