<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - ORIGINAL FINISH RESTORATION -
        REMOVING MEDIUM TO HEAVY OXIDATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REMOVING MEDIUM TO HEAVY OXIDATION</title>
        <para>Older vehicles that were painted with earlier paint techniques such as lacquers, enamels, and acrylics are
            all vulnerable to finish oxidation. This oxidation appears as the finish color on the polishing cloth when
            the vehicle is waxed. Urethane Basecoat/Clearcoat finishes have resolved this issue.The five steps to remove
            oxidation are:
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Wash vehicle with a high quality wash and conditioner (such as Meguiars #62). Follow the
                manufacturers instructions to wash all painted surfaces.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Meguiars #15 Clear Coat Conditioner to the area to be buffed, and smear material
                evenly with pad before starting buffer. Start the buffer (recommended R.P.M. 1750 to 2000) and keep the
                buffer pad flat on the painted surface using medium to light pressure. To avoid heat build-up, do not
                buff the conditioner after it starts to dry. Wipe clean with a soft cloth.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Dry buffing could damage paint.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply Meguiars #15 Clearcoat Conditioner to area to be polished, and smear material evenly
                with a W-9000 finish pad before starting buffer. Polish by keeping the pad flat against the surface
                using medium to light pressure (recommended R.P.M. 1750 to 2000). To avoid heat build-up, do not buff
                conditioner after it starts to dry.
            </para>
            <para>If swirls are visible, use a D.A. random orbital adapted with Meguiars W-6000 D.A. polishing pad and
                Meguiars #15 Clearcoat Conditioner.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Protect finish with Meguiars #26 Hi-Tech Yellow Wax (liquid or paste). Follow the
                recommended instructions and apply by hand or machine.
            </para>
            <para>Maintain the finish with Meguiars #34 final inspection, following the recommended procedures. Meguiar
                products can be purchased at local paint supply warehouses.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_24.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_26.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
