<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 4100, 4200, 4300 AND 4400 MODELS - INSTALL - CAB DOOR LATCH</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1602632" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CAB DOOR LATCH</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Front Cab Door Latch on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab for all Models</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16026199">Figure 199</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position cab door latch (Item 1) onto inner cab door handle control rods (Items 2 and 3)
                    and rotate the cab door latch up around inner cab door handle control rods, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16026199" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16026c4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 199. Cab Door Latch and Inner Cab Door Handle Control Rods</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CAB DOOR LATCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INNER CAB DOOR HANDLE CONTROL ROD</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. INNER CAB DOOR HANDLE CONTROL ROD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602612.xml" xrefid="f1602688">Figure 88</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1602688"/>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the front cab door modular door hardware assembly
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602607.xml" xrefid="f1602672">(Item 1, Figure 72)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1602672"/>
                    placed on a suitable work surface. Position the hanger support bracket (Item 4) of the cab door
                    latch (Item 1) in place at window run channel (Item 2) and slide the hanger support bracket into
                    window run channel until the locking tab (Item 3) locks it in place, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cab door modular door hardware assembly, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602627.xml" xrefid="x1602627">MODULAR DOOR HARDWARE ASSEMBLY
                        <xref refid="x1602627"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing front cab door modular door hardware assembly, refer to Install Front Cab Door
                    Modular Door Hardware Assembly on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab for all Models.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cab door inner door panel water shield, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602625.xml" xrefid="x1602625">CAB DOOR INNER DOOR PANEL WATER SHIELD
                        <xref refid="x1602625"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing front cab door inner door panel water shield, refer to Install Front Cab Door Inner
                    Door Panel Water Shield on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab for all Models.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install front cab door trim panel, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602624.xml" xrefid="x1602624">CAB DOOR TRIM PANEL
                        <xref refid="x1602624"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . If front cab door is equipped with electric door window and locks, refer to Install Front Cab Door
                    Trim Panel with Electric Door Window and Locks. If front cab door is equipped with manual door
                    window and locks, refer to Install Front Cab Door Trim Panel with Manual Door Window and Locks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side front cab door latch.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Rear Cab Door Latch on Crew Cab for all Models</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16026199">Figure 199</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f16026199"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position cab door latch (Item 1) onto inner cab door handle control rods (Items 2 and 3)
                    and rotate the cab door latch up around inner cab door handle control rods, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602612.xml" xrefid="f1602688">Figure 88</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1602688"/>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the rear cab door modular door hardware assembly
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602607.xml" xrefid="f1602674">(Item 1, Figure 74)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1602674"/>
                    placed on a suitable work surface. Position the hanger support bracket (Item 4) of the cab door
                    latch (Item 1) in place at window run channel (Item 2) and slide the hanger support bracket into
                    window run channel until the locking tab (Item 3) locks it in place, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rear cab door modular door hardware assembly, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602627.xml" xrefid="x1602627">MODULAR DOOR HARDWARE ASSEMBLY
                        <xref refid="x1602627"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing rear cab door modular door hardware assembly, refer to Install Rear Cab Door
                    Modular Door Hardware Assembly on Crew Cab for all Models.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rear cab door inner door panel water shield, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602625.xml" xrefid="x1602625">CAB DOOR INNER DOOR PANEL WATER SHIELD
                        <xref refid="x1602625"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing rear cab door inner door panel water shield, refer to Install Rear Cab Door Inner
                    Door Panel Water Shield on Crew Cab for all Models.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rear cab door trim panel, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602624.xml" xrefid="x1602624">CAB DOOR TRIM PANEL
                        <xref refid="x1602624"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . If rear cab door is equipped with electric door window and locks, refer to Install Rear Cab Door
                    Trim Panel with Electric Door Window and Locks. If rear cab door is equipped with manual door window
                    and locks, refer to Install Rear Cab Door Trim Panel with Manual Door Window and Locks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side rear cab door latch.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602631.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_84.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
