<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        REMOVE AND INSTALL - BLOWER SCROLL HOUSING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160340617" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>BLOWER SCROLL HOUSING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The blower scroll housing must be removed prior to removing the heater core, the heater core housing,
                or any of the components within the blower scroll housing. Accessing the blower scroll housing may
                require the removal of trim panels not described in this manual.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuse panel cover, other trim covers (as necessary), and heater trim cover. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340614.xml" xrefid="hl160340614">REMOVE AND INSTALL, HEATER TRIM
                        COVER
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340614"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340615.xml" xrefid="f1603430">Figure 30</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following steps.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect electrical plug connected to the temperature door actuator (6, Figure 30).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove four screws securing blower scroll housing (3) to heater housing assembly (1).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step wiring connections to linear power module and blower motor must be
                        disconnected once blower scroll housing is partially separated from heater housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully separate blower scroll housing (3) from heater housing (1).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With blower scroll housing removed, blower assembly (8), linear power module (7), and
                    heater core (2) are accessible for service.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When replacing a damaged scroll housing, transfer all good components: blower assembly,
                    linear power module, and temperature door actuator (6), from damaged housing to new housing. Refer
                    to appropriate procedures in this manual for additional information.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340615.xml" xrefid="f1603430">Figure 30</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following steps.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Depending on the level of disassembly required for the repair, some of the following steps may
                        not be necessary for each installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If removed previously, install blower assembly (8, Figure 30), using three screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If removed previously, install linear power module (7) and LPM cover (10), using two
                    screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If temperature door actuator was removed previously, install actuator by rotating door
                    until flats on door shaft align with actuator drive collar, if possible; then carefully slip the
                    actuator (6) onto end of door shaft so that mounting holes are properly aligned. If actuator drive
                    collar must be moved to allow alignment:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place actuator into its approximate position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To rotate drive collar, connect a 9 Volt battery across the active pins of the
                        actuator connector (check mating connector if necessary). (Reverse connection to rotate drive
                        collar in opposite direction.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Allow drive collar to rotate until it is aligned with door shaft, and actuator
                        mounting screws can be inserted. Then, disconnect battery.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure actuator to blower scroll housing (3) using two screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing blower scroll housing, verify that heater core (2) is installed in
                    heater housing (1). To install the heater core refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340619.xml" xrefid="hl160340619">REMOVE AND INSTALL, HEATER CORE
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340619"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position blower scroll housing so that electrical connections to linear power module and
                    blower motor can be connected. After making connection, secure any excess wire so that it will not
                    interfere with installation of blower scroll housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When installing the blower scroll housing in the following step, pay close attention to how
                        the edges of the housing walls mate up with the walls of the heater housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully install blower scroll housing so that housing walls interlock with walls of
                    heater housing, and mounting holes line up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure blower scroll housing (3) to heater housing using four screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electrical control plug to temperature blend door actuator (6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install heater trim cover, other trim covers (as necessary), and fuse panel cover. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340614.xml" xrefid="hl160340614">REMOVE AND INSTALL, HEATER TRIM
                        COVER</hotlnk>,
                    <xref refid="hl160340614"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340616.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340618.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
