<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - DESCRIPTION
        OF SYSTEM COMPONENTS - RECEIVER-DRYER
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>RECEIVER-DRYER</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601913">Figure 12</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1601913" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1601913" filename="../figg16/g1601913a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Receiver-Dryer</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. INLET PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HIGH PRESSURE SERVICE VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SIGHT GLASS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. OUTLET PORT</callout1>
                <callout1>5. FILTER</callout1>
                <callout1>6. DESICCANT</callout1>
                <callout1>7. STRAINER</callout1>
                <callout1>8. PICKUP TUBE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The receiver-dryer performs three important functions:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Filters particles from the liquid refrigerant.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Removes moisture from the liquid refrigerant.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Stores a portion of the liquid refrigerant until needed in the system evaporator to meet high
                    cooling demands.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <para>High pressure liquid refrigerant flows from the condenser to the receiver-dryer. To protect the system
            from moisture, a drying agent (desiccant) absorbs and separates any moisture contained in the liquid
            refrigerant. The cylinder or tank portion of the receiver-dryer collects and stores liquid refrigerant until
            system demands require additional refrigerant. The primary function of the receiver-dryer, however, is the
            removal of any liquid or solid contamination before it can cycle through the system and cause internal
            damage. Moisture-free, contaminant-free, high temperature/high pressure liquid refrigerant leaves the
            receiver-dryer.
        </para>
        <para>If the compressor or any other component fails or requires replacement, the receiver-dryer must also be
            replaced to prevent subsequent corrosion and damage to the system.
        </para>
        <para>Always replace the receiver-dryer whenever the system has been opened to the atmosphere for more than 30
            minutes. This will help prevent moisture contamination of the system.
        </para>
        <para>System protection is provided by a direct-acting high pressure relief valve (on Service Parts
            Receiver-Dryers only) that will discharge refrigerant if the pressure exceeds the system limit. This is not
            a fusible plug and does not expel the entire charge. Relief pressure ranges from 450 psi to 600 psi. On some
            vehicles, the pressure relief valve has been moved from the receiver-dryer to the refrigerant compressor.
            Replacement receiver-dryers furnished by International will have the pressure relief valve on the
            receiver-dryer. The receiver-dryer used in production will be equipped with a service port.
        </para>
        <para>The receiver-dryer is not serviceable, and must be replaced if found to be defective.</para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
