<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - REFRIGERANT
        IDENTIFICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390903" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>REFRIGERANT IDENTIFICATION</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390901.xml" xrefid="hl160390901">SERVICE WARNINGS
                        <xref refid="hl160390901"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with
                    refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <note>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Before any work is done on an HVAC system the refrigerant should be identified.</para>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1603963">Figure 63</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1603963" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figG16/G1603963.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="416px"/>
            <caption>Figure 63. Refrigerant Identification Setup Diagram</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Calibrate the Refrigerant Identifier per the manufacturer's instructions.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the sampling hose to the low pressure service port located on the evaporator outlet
                line.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the other end of the sampling hose to the Refrigerant Identifier.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open the service valve.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start the sampling procedure (refer to the manufacturer's instructions).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the sampling is complete the Refrigerant Identifier will indicate a pass/fail
                condition, the type of refrigerant, and the percentage of concentration. International recognizes only
                R134a in a 98%, or greater, concentration. Anything else is considered contaminated.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close the service valve and disconnect the sampling hose.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that protective caps are installed on both vehicle service port fittings.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_67.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_69.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
