<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - FIBERGLASS - FIBERGLASS TYPES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FIBERGLASS TYPES</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Hand Lay-Up Type</title>
            <para>In the past, most fiberglass parts have been made from a hand lay-up type fiberglass. This material is
                made of woven fiberglass cloth which has been impregnated with a molding resin and molded to a desired
                shape. Much of the manufacturing process is done by hand as the name implies.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sheet Molding Compound (SMC) Type</title>
            <para>Currently, various parts are made from a newer type fiberglass called Sheet Molding Compound (SMC).
                This compression molded fiberglass differs from hand lay-up fiberglass in that it is made from a resin
                molding compound to which short or shredded glass fibers have been added. The resulting plastic mass can
                be compression molded to any desired shape without using cloth as is used for the hand lay-up type.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Resin Transfer Molding (RTM) Type</title>
            <para>A third kind of fiberglass called Resin Transfer Molding (RTM) is also being used. This type
                fiberglass is similar to both hand lay-up and SMC types in that it uses a glass mat or cloth in a closed
                mold to which the resin molding compound is added. A room temperature catalyst (curing or hardening
                agent) is also used. This type fiberglass also lends itself to production method of manufacture.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The external surface appearance of all three types of fiberglass material is similar. However,
                        the hand lay-up type material is rough textured on its internal surface (back side) while SMC
                        and RTM materials are smooth.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
