<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - BLOWER MOTOR CIRCUIT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1602565">
        <title>BLOWER MOTOR CIRCUIT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f1602567" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602567.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 69. HVAC Blower Motor Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BLOWER CONTROL (PART OF HVAC CONTROL HEAD)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2A. HVAC WIRE HARNESS (TWO PIECE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2B. HVAC WIRE HARNESS (ONE PIECE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. LINEAR POWER MODULE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. BLOWER MOTOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602567">HVAC BLOWER MOTOR</hotlnk>
                assembly consists of a permanent magnet motor attached to a balanced 'squirrel-cage' fan unit. The
                blower speed is controlled by the blower speed control (left knob) on the HVAC control panel, located on
                the instrument panel. The blower speed control is a long life potentiometer, detented to provide seven
                distinct blower speeds in addition to OFF.
            </para>
            <para>The following paragraphs describe the three variations of the electrical circuit used for the HVAC
                blower motor.
            </para>
            <para>In version 1 of the electrical circuit, battery voltage is routed to the Linear Power Module (LPM) and
                to one side of the blower motor. Based on the setting of the blower speed control, the HVAC control
                panel outputs a 0 to 5 Vdc signal to the LPM. The LPM responds by acting as a variable resistance
                between the blower motor and ground. As the blower speed control is turned cw, the apparent resistance
                to ground decreases, the voltage across the blower motor increases, and the blower speed increases.
            </para>
            <para>In version 2 of the electrical circuit, battery voltage is still routed to one side of the blower
                motor; however, switched ignition voltage provides the voltage source for the LPM. The remainder of the
                circuit is identical to version 1. Operation and function are also identical to version 1.
            </para>
            <para>Version 3 of the electrical circuit is identical to version 2 except connector (1203) has been
                removed, making the HVAC harness a single piece harness. Operation and function are also identical to
                version 2.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_83.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_85.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
