<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>The fittings on the service hoses for HFC-134A air conditioning systems are standard Metric SAE
                    quick-disconnect fittings that will work only on HFC-134A air conditioning systems (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16012v_22.xml" xrefid="hl1601212">MANIFOLD SERVICE HOSE SET</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Be sure to use a manifold gauge set dedicated to the type of system you are working on. DO NOT USE
                    THE SAME MANIFOLD GAUGE SET ON BOTH TYPES OF SYSTEMS.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the caps from both service ports.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the Manifold Gauge Set making sure that the hand valves are fully off by turning
                them clockwise. Start with the
                <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                manifold suction gauge hose and connect it to the compressor suction service port. Connect the
                <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                hose to the high pressure discharge service port.
            </para>
            <para>On HFC-134A Metric SAE quick- disconnect fittings, turn the valves on the red and blue hoses
                completely off (turn clockwise). Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16012v_22.xml" xrefid="hl1601212">MANIFOLD SERVICE HOSE SET</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Service ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not visible, you
                        can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter system hose connected to the
                        compressor.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the
                <emph type="bold">yellow</emph>
                hose to the center fitting on the Manifold Gauge Set and the other end to the inlet of the Recovery/
                Recycling Station (OEM-1380 for R-12, OEM-1418 for HFC-134A).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be certain that the yellow system service hose is firmly attached to the inlet of the
                        Recovery/ Recycling Station. Refrigerant can be hazardous if inhaled.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not vent refrigerant into the atmosphere. The use of R-12 is a worldwide environmental
                        concern. Because of the absence of chlorine in the molecular structure of HFC-134A, the use of
                        HFC-134A refrigerant will not have any harmful effects on the ozone layer of the atmosphere.
                        Because there is not enough evidence to determine the "greenhouse" effect of HFC-134A, recycling
                        of HFC-134A is recommended. Effective November 1995, recovery and recycling of HFC-134A will be
                        required by law.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open both hand valves of the manifold on the Recover/Recycling Station. Turn the main power
                switch on and press the compressor start switch. The Recover/ Recycling Station will automatically shut
                off when the refrigerant in the system has been exhausted to the storage tank.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Work may now begin on removal of components of the air conditioning system.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
