<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - SYSTEM
        MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SYSTEM MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="1">
            <title>PRE-SEASON SERVICING</title>
            <para>Field experience has indicated that many of the problems incurred with heating and air conditioning
                systems are the result of lack of regular maintenance. Preventive maintenance and cleanliness of all
                components within the system are extremely important. A complete step-by-step pre-season checkout of the
                air conditioner/heater system will substantially increase satisfactory operation during the season.
            </para>
            <para>Perform the following procedures:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the mounting fasteners of each component for looseness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition, tension and alignment of all drive belts. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601902.xml" xrefid="hl1601902">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                    for belt tension information.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition of heater hoses and engine cooling system hoses. Replace if necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the vehicle coolant level is correct.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check refrigerant hose retention and condition. Look for cracks, chafing, or other
                    damage. Inspect all tubing and hoses for dirty or loose connections. All connections must be clean
                    and tight.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If a patch of oily residue is found at or near a connection it may indicate a refrigerant
                        leak. Note its location in case a system operational test indicates a refrigerant leak or a low
                        refrigerant condition.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Cleanliness of the air conditioner components cannot be over-emphasized. Lack of proper
                        attention in this area is one of the major causes of costly and unsatisfactory unit operation.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all foreign material from condenser and radiator fins. As often as necessary,
                    squirt water through the condenser towards the radiator and through the radiator towards the
                    condenser to flush debris from the fins. Straighten bent fins with a fin straightening tool (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601951">Figure 53</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1601951" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601951" filename="../figg16/g1601951.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 53. Fin Straightening Tool</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check evaporator, heater core, and blowers for material that could restrict air flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new air filter in air conditioning unit housing. Refer to GROUP 16-AIR
                    CONDITIONING in the Master Service Manual for the vehicle being serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate air conditioner system and check operation of controls.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check operation of blower(s).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check water control valve adjustment. (2000, 4000 and 8000 Series vehicles built after
                    December 4, 1994, do not have a water valve.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check cooling system shutter operation (if installed). Refer to GROUP 12 in the Master
                    Service Manual for the system being serviced for specific procedures and adjustment.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate the air conditioner and check the system for leaks with a leak detector, refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601922.xml" xrefid="hl1601922">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine that the system is functioning properly. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601905.xml" xrefid="hl1601905">PHYSICAL CHECKS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the system is cooling properly in the A/C modes and heating properly in the
                    heat modes.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601922.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_50.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
