<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - PLASTIC (ABS) - EPOXY ADHESIVE FILLERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EPOXY ADHESIVE FILLERS</title>
        <para>Intended for use in repairing deep scratches, nicks and small holes less than 1/4 inch (6 mm) in
            diameter.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Epoxy adhesive/fillers are a two-part compound: one part resin, one part hardener. Epoxy adhesive
                    filler is not recommended for use on highly stressed areas or thin walled panels. There are a number
                    of epoxy adhesive/fillers available that will work on ABS plastic.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dispense equal parts of the resin and hardener on a clean, nonporous surface such as plastic
                or glass. Mix thoroughly in quantities that can be used in 15 minutes or less (
                <hotlnk document="s16003_10.xml" xrefid="f1600341">Figure 41</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Working time of the mixture is approximately 15 minutes at 75&#176;F (24&#176;C). Application
                        is best at 68&#176;F (20&#176;C). At temperatures below 65&#176;F (18&#176;C), it is recommended
                        to pre-warm the application surface to above 68&#176;F with a heat lamp.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Be careful not to overheat the surface of the damaged area. if the heat gun is held too
                        closely to the surface, or it remains aimed at a small area, the surface can become discolored.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply the mixture to the repair site slightly above the level of the desired contour.</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">When used as an adhesive, apply to both sanded surfaces. Clamp the pieces together and
                    smooth the excess adhesive with a plastic spreader or putty knife (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16003_8.xml" xrefid="f1600312">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">When filling "V" grooves, fill all the area using a plastic spreader or putty knife.
                    Apply pressure and extend coverage 1 to 1-1/2 inches (25 to 38 mm) beyond the "V" groove in either
                    direction.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Sand the filler material to the desired contour. Use coarse grit sand paper first and then
                finish sand and feather edge with fine grit.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Epoxy adhesive fillers can be sanded to a desired contour usually after a minimum of two hours
                        after application. If epoxy adhesive/filler is used as an adhesive, let the material cure for a
                        minimum of four hours at room temperature, preferably overnight for a complete cure.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
