<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AERODYNAMIC PANELS - CAB SIDE AIR DEFLECTORS - WITHOUT
        SLEEPER BOX - INSTALL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="3">
        <title>INSTALL</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Assemble air deflector extensions to the roof air deflector before assembling them to the cab.
                    Install each bolt with its washers and nut so that the bolt heads are visible on the finished side.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If you are replacing the roof air deflector and panel is not predrilled, prepare the new one
                as follows:
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cut two 1 x 4-1/2 inch (25.4 x 114.3mm) slots into upper corners, using the pattern in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601026">Figure 26</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601026" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601026" filename="../figg16/g1601026.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                    <caption>Figure 26. Install Air Deflector Extensions</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>A.1.0 INCH (25.4MM)</callout1>
                        <callout1>B.1.0 INCH (25.4MM) RADIUS</callout1>
                        <callout1>C.4 1/2 INCHES (114.3MM)</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Align the templates with the rear edge, as shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601027">Figure 27</hotlnk>, with the template positioned 27-1/2 inches (698.5mm)
                    from centerline of roof air deflector. The centerline is indicated by a die mark along the rear
                    edge.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601027" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601027" filename="../figg16/g1601027.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 27. Mark Locations of Holes</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1.ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR</callout1>
                        <callout1>2.CENTERLINE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3.HOLES TO ATTACH EXTENSION ANGLES</callout1>
                        <callout1>4.TEMPLATE IN POSITION</callout1>
                        <callout1>5.HOLES TO ATTACH AIR DEFLECTOR EXTENSIONS</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Cut out the slots with a suitable saw, then file and paint the rough edges.</para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Unpack the air deflector extensions and hardware. Paint them per the directions in GROUP 16
                - PAINTING in the CTS- 5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the air deflector bracket seals and the brackets to the cab. Always use new bracket
                seals.
            </para>
            <para>Install the air deflector seal to the cab. Use a new one if the old one is damaged.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the extension angles as templates, mark locations of four holes (Item 3, two per side)
                for the side extension angles to attach, as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601027">Figure 27</hotlnk>. Use an 11/32" diameter drill bit to drill the holes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use clamps to temporarily hold the extension angles in place on the roof air deflector, then
                assemble with four 5/16 - 18 x 1.0 inch hex head bolts, flatwashers, and lock bolts. Tighten all
                fasteners until snug.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten fasteners, as this will damage the fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the rearmost fastener from each roof rear mounting bracket (
                <hotlnk document="s16010_9.xml" xrefid="f1601007">Figure 7</hotlnk>). Use clamps to attach the left and
                right air deflector extensions (
                <hotlnk document="s16010_14.xml" xrefid="f1601025">Figure 25</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601028">Figure 28</hotlnk>) to the extension angles (Item 2,
                <hotlnk document="s16010_14.xml" xrefid="f1601025">Figure 25</hotlnk>) and upper deflector mounting
                channels (Item 5,
                <hotlnk document="s16010_14.xml" xrefid="f1601025">Figure 25</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601028" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601028" filename="../figg16/g1601028.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 28. Clamp Deflector Extensions to Extension Angles</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1.TRIM-FLEX MOLDING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2.ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR AND AIR DEFLECTOR EXTENSION</callout1>
                    <callout1>3.SELF-DRILLING SCREW</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the air deflector extensions as templates, mark locations of three holes for the air
                deflector extensions to attach, as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601027">Figure 27</hotlnk>. Use an 11/32 inch diameter drill bit to drill the holes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the extension angles as templates, mark locations of two holes in each air deflector
                extension. Use an 11/32 inch drill bit to drill the holes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fasten the air deflector extensions to the extension angles and to the roof air deflector
                with 5/16 - 18 bolts, flatwashers, and lock nuts. Use two washers for each bolt. Finger tighten these
                fasteners at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use the rear mounting bracket fasteners that were removed in step 6 to fasten the bottom of
                each air deflector extension to the roof air deflector. Finger tighten these fasteners at this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fasten the air deflector extensions to the upper deflector mounting channels with 5/16 - 18
                inch bolts, flatwashers and lock nuts. Use two washers for each bolt. Finger tighten these fasteners at
                this time.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the upper and lower deflector mounting channels inboard or outboard to obtain a
                vertical rear edge on the side air deflectors.
            </para>
            <para>Tighten all the fasteners from steps 9 through 11 until snug. Remove all the clamps.</para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not overtighten fasteners, as this will damage the fiberglass panels.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Slide the trim-flex moldings in place on the molding bracket edge on the air deflector
                extensions and on the side air deflectors. If lubrication is needed, use a foamy glass cleaner or a
                similar product.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Locate and mark positions for the self-drilling screws on all four molding brackets: lower
                position to 8 inches (203.2mm) from the bottom; upper position 34 inches (863.6mm) from the bottom.
                Fasten with self-drilling screws
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601028">Figure 28</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
