<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - SERVICE PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURES</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note and label electrical connections during removal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note cable routings during removal. Where necessary, cables should make sweeping curves.
                Sharp bends tend to increase resistance to bowden wire movement and sometimes cause kinks, which render
                the cable inoperative.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is important that all refrigerant hose O-rings and tubing fittings be lubricated with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                refrigerant oil (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601936">Figure 35</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Never use grease, penetrating oil, motor oil, Ester or PAG oil, etc. to lubricate fittings.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <figure id="f1601936" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601936" filename="../figg16/G1601936a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 35. Lubricating O-Rings and Fittings</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. C-PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. THREADS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten fittings as specified in the torque chart of the Air Conditioning - Heating Service
                Section for the particular vehicle. Use only a torque wrench known to be accurate. Always use a back-up
                wrench when loosening or tightening fittings (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601937">Figure 36</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601937" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601937" filename="../figg16/G1601937.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="152px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 36. Use a Back-Up Wrench When Loosening or Tightening Fittings</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dryer unit on any system which is opened for more than a very short
                period, when the system is flushed, and/or when the compressor is replaced because of an internal
                failure that contaminates the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be certain that the evaporator core temperature sensing capillary tube is properly inserted
                into the evaporator core.
            </para>
            <para>When re-installing the capillary tube,
                <emph type="bold">ALWAYS</emph>
                insert it into a new location in the evaporator. This will insure that the capillary tube makes contact
                with the evaporator for correct temperature control sensing (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601938">Figure 37</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601938" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601938" filename="../figg16/G1601938.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 37. Insert Capillary Tube in New Location</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On early production expansion valves, the expansion valve refrigerant temperature sensing
                tube must be securely attached to the evaporator refrigerant outlet tube. Also, the temperature sensing
                bulb and expansion valve must be tightly wrapped with insulating tape to prevent the ambient temperature
                from affecting correct sensing of the temperature of the refrigerant leaving the evaporator.
            </para>
            <para>The later production (block style) expansion valve does not have a refrigerant temperature sensing
                tube or equalizer line.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                original positions.
            </para>
            <para>Never bend to a radius less than ten (10) times the diameter of the hose.</para>
            <para>Never route any closer than two (2) inches from the exhaust manifold or related piping.</para>
            <para>Periodically inspect for leaks or brittleness. Replace lines immediately if damaged.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed or purged as described in this section any time
                the compressor is replaced due to internal failure. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601910.xml" xrefid="hl1601910">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                    SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The compressor oil level must be checked and replaced as specified in
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use extreme care to prevent moisture from entering the system. Moisture can freeze at the
                expansion valve metering orifice and block refrigerant flow during system operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All A/C component and refrigerant line openings should be immediately covered or plugged
                during removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other
                foreign material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a vulnerable place within
                the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never remove protective caps from components until the moment of assembly into the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never install non-sealed components.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Spare components should be stored in a warm, dry facility.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform service inside a warm, well ventilated dry shop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never use hot steam to clean the inside of the system. Dry nitrogen cleaning is recommended
                for this purpose. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601910.xml" xrefid="hl1601910">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                    SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601926.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
