<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 2000, 4000, AND 8000 - 12/06/1994 and After - SERVICE WITH R-134A
        PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601604" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE WITH R-134A PROCEDURES</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note cable routings during removal. Where necessary, cables should make sweeping curves.
                Sharp bends tend to increase resistance to bowden wire movement and sometimes cause kinks, which render
                the cable inoperative.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is most important that all refrigerant O-rings and tubing fittings be lubricated with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                refrigerant oil and tightened as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s16016_HL1601622.xml" xrefid="t1601601">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. Always use a back-up
                wrench when loosening or tightening fittings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Use mineral-based oil to lubricate O-rings and fittings. Do not use PAG or ESTER oils as they
                        absorb moisture and will cause fittings to corrode and become difficult to disassemble.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dehydrator unit on any system which is opened for more than a very
                short period, when the system is flushed, and/or when the compressor is replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be certain that the evaporator core temperature control sensing capillary tube is properly
                inserted into the evaporator core. When re-installing, do not put in the same opening that it was
                removed from.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                original positions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed as described in GROUP 16 - AIR CONDITIONING
                BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE with R-134a section in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual
                anytime the compressor is replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The compressor oil level must be checked and replaced as specified in GROUP 16 - COMPRESSOR
                in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>The type of refrigerant oil used in R-134a charged systems has been changed to a non-mineral based
                oil. The following information must be adhered to when servicing the air conditioning system in these
                vehicles.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>These model vehicles built between January 1, 1993, and February 1, 1995, had the compressor
                        filled with PAG oil. Effective approximately February 1, 1995, all refrigerant compressors are
                        filled with Lubrizol LZ2916 Ester Oil.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>If it is necessary to add oil when servicing the air conditioning system and the system is filled with
                PAG oil, it is recommended that the PAG oil be drained out of the compressor and replaced with Lubrizol
                LZ2916 Ester oil. Check the label on the compressor to verify the type of oil in the A/C system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing openings should be immediately covered or plugged during
                removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other foreign
                material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried in the system to the right place.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16016_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16016_HL1601606.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16016.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
