<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 9000 Pro Sleeper After 05/01/1997, and 9800 Model After 07/01/1997 -
        SERVICE HINTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE HINTS</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note electrical connections during removal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note cable routings during removal. Where necessary, cables should make sweeping curves.
                Sharp bends tend to increase resistance to bowden wire movement and sometimes cause kinks, which render
                the cable inoperative.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is most important that all refrigerant hose, O-rings, and tubing fittings be lubricated
                with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                refrigerant oil and tightened as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s16020_HL1602001.xml" xrefid="hl1602001">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. Use only a torque
                wrench known to be correct.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always use a back-up wrench when loosening or tightening fittings.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dryer on any system which is opened for more than a very short period
                (>30 minutes), when the system is flushed, and/or when the compressor is replaced due to an internal
                failure, causing system contamination.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and stay locks must be re-installed in their
                original position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed and purged as described in
                <exhotlnk document="../S16/S16019.htm" bookname="S16019">S16019</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING BASIC
                THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual, any time the compressor is replaced
                due to an internal failure, causing system contamination.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is critical that the system oil level be maintained whenever the refrigerant system is
                serviced. Refer to
                <exhotlnk document="../S16/S16019.htm" bookname="S16019">S16019</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING BASIC
                THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing openings should be immediately capped or plugged during
                removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other foreign
                material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a vulnerable place within the
                system.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16020_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16020_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16020.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
