<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a) - REMOVE
        AND INSTALL - SHAFT SEAL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="6">
        <title>SHAFT SEAL</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The seal can be replaced without compressor removal; however, the system must be discharged.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The shaft seal assembly of the compressor is of a simplified design, yet tight sealing, long lasting
                and, when necessary, easily and quickly replaced.
            </para>
            <para>The tendency to condemn a seal assembly because of very slight leakage is an error that is often
                committed. Few if any mechanical seal assemblies are 100% tight. The rubbing surfaces of the seal are
                separated by a very fine film of oil.
            </para>
            <para>Oil carries refrigerant, and minute quantities which seep to the outside may be detected with ultra
                sensitive leak detectors, which are capable of sensing leakage totalling one ounce of refrigerant over a
                twenty year period. Such sensitivity serves a useful purpose in critical applications, but for leak
                testing compressor joints or seal, a leak detector should be calibrated to pick up those leaks which are
                in excess of one ounce per year. Since shaft seals depend upon oil for lubrication and sealing, it is
                quite natural to find oil in the shaft cavity.
            </para>
            <para>Do not be too prone to condemn and replace a seal assembly until the seal has been given an
                opportunity to "run in" and until there is definite proof that replacement is really necessary. Refer to
                GROUP 16 - A/C THEORY AND SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for more
                detailed leak detection procedures.
            </para>
            <para>If a refrigerant leak from the area behind the compressor clutch is verified with a refrigerant leak
                detector, replacement of the compressor shaft seal is recommended.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Up to a few drops of compressor oil may normally be found in the area under the front seal. Do
                        not replace a seal based on the presence of small amounts of oil. Verify a leak with a
                        refrigerant leak detector before replacement, then proceed as follows:
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the compressor from the vehicle. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16017x_HL1601703.xml" xrefid="hl1601703">COMPRESSOR</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clutch pulley assembly and the clutch field coil. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16017x_HL1601704.xml" xrefid="hl1601704">CLUTCH</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the shaft key and dust cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the seal plate bolts and seal plate (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601709">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601709" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601709" filename="../figg16/g1601709.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Remove Seal Plate Bolts</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the seal retainer with a seal puller (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601710">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601710" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601710" filename="../figg16/g1601710.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. Remove Seal Retainer</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If any tool other than a seal puller is used, be careful not to damage the shaft or the
                            machined surface on the front of the crankcase.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discard the seal assembly, seal plate and O-ring.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the shaft and seal cavity with a clean, lint-free cloth.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dip the seal retainer in mineral oil.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the carbon ring from the new seal retainer assembly and set aside.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a seal installer tool, push the lubricated seal assembly onto the shaft (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601711">Figure 11</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601711" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601711" filename="../figg16/g1601711.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Lubricated Seal Onto Shaft</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the carbon ring in the ring retainer so the lapped surface is facing outward. Be
                    sure the notches in the outside edge of the carbon ring engage the dimpled ring lugs in the seal
                    spring retainer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lubricate the new O-ring with mineral oil and place it in the groove of the seal
                    plate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the seal plate with uniform clearance around the shaft and install the six
                    capscrews (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601712">Figure 12</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601712" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601712" filename="../figg16/g1601712.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Install Capscrews</caption>
                </figure>
                <para>Tighten the capscrews in the sequence shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601713">Figure 13</hotlnk>
                    to 5 to 8 ft-lbs. (6.8 to 10.8 N&#183;m) (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601714">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601713" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601713" filename="../figg16/g1601713.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Tighten Capscrews In Sequence</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601714" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601714" filename="../figg16/g1601714.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Use Proper Torque</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace the dust cover and key.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install clutch. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16017x_HL1601704.xml" xrefid="hl1601705">CLUTCH</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_HL1601704.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
