<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - FIBERGLASS - SURFACE FILLING AND FINISHING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1600304" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="4">
        <title>SURFACE FILLING AND FINISHING</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If you have used screws to align the panel, remove screws and fill the holes with body filler
                    before finishing the panel.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>After repairing the damaged area, apply filler and finish the surface using following procedure:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Following the manufacturer's instructions, mix enough body filler to re-establish the
                surface.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Mix filler on formica, teflon or other hard surface. Do not work on a porous surface such as
                        cardboard.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Work the filler into the repaired surface with a squeegee, making sure to fill all voids and
                remove large air bubbles (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600350">Figure 50</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600350" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600350" filename="../figg16/G1600350.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Work Filler into Repaired Surface</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Allow filler to extend above the original surface to allow for shrinkage.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the filler is firm to the touch, plane and/or file off the excess, still leaving the
                filler level slightly above that of the original surface (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600351">Figure 51</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600351" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600351" filename="../figg16/G1600351.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. Plane and/or File Off Excess Filler</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Now, pre-shrink the filler, using a heat gun or heat lamp. A minimum temperature of 120&#176;F
                (49&#176;C) is required for shrinkage (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600352">Figure 52</hotlnk>). Remove heat lamp when repaired area gets very warm,
                <emph type="underscr">NOT HOT.</emph>
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600352" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600352" filename="../figg16/G1600352.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 52. Pre-Shrink Filler</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Keep heat source at least 12 inches ( 305 mm) away from the repair area.</para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Power-sand the filler with 360 grit sandpaper until it is smooth and even with the original
                surface.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the filler is slightly porous (has fine pinholes), apply a thin coat of glazing putty (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600353">Figure 53</hotlnk>). If the filler is pockmarked, do not use glazing putty.
                Instead, apply another layer of body filler as covered in Steps 1 through 5 before applying the glazing
                putty.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600353" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600353" filename="../figg16/G1600353.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 53. Apply Thin Coat of Glazing Putty</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Allow the glazing putty to cure using a heat lamp, if necessary. Remove heat lamp when
                repaired area gets warm,
                <emph type="underscr">NOT HOT</emph>. Finish by sanding with a sanding block and 360 grit sandpaper.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the area with air and remask, if necessary. Then spot prime the surface and wet sand
                with 400 to 600 grit sandpaper. Complete the repair by painting the surface. Refer to GROUP 16 - PAINT
                section in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
