<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - SERVICE
        PROCEDURES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
        <title>SERVICE PROCEDURES</title>
        <para>The service procedures for both the day cab and sleeper versions of the ProStar HVAC system are described
            in this section. While the procedures for servicing the overall vehicle HVAC system (including sleeper A/C)
            are the same, the refrigerant charge required by each system is different. Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s16039_80.xml" xrefid="t1603922">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
            table for the correct refrigerant charge values for each system.
        </para>
        <para>In addition to the Service Warnings above, special attention to the following rules during servicing, and
            component remove and install, will aid in avoiding unnecessary and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform service inside a warm, well ventilated dry shop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When working on the A/C system keep the work area and tools as clean as possible. Also,
                clean all connections, ports or fittings before disconnecting or removing components.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never use hot steam to clean the inside of the system. Dry nitrogen cleaning is recommended
                for this purpose.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All A/C component and refrigerant line openings should be immediately plugged during removal
                and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other foreign material.
                Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a vulnerable place within the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never remove protective caps from components until the moment of assembly into the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Never install non-sealed components.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Anytime an A/C fitting is disconnected, the O-ring and C-plate must be replaced (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603961">Figure 61</hotlnk>). The new O-ring must be lubricated with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                oil (International P/N ZGGR6912). The C-plate does not require lubrication. Never use grease,
                penetrating oil, motor oil, Ester or PAG oil, etc. to lubricate O-rings and fittings.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603961" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603922.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 61. A/C Fitting C-Plate and O-Ring</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. C-PLATE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                original positions.
            </para>
            <para>Never bend a hose to a radius less than ten times the diameter of the hose.</para>
            <para>Never route a hose any closer than four inches from the exhaust manifold or related piping.</para>
            <para>Periodically inspect hoses for leaks or brittleness. Replace lines immediately if damaged.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All fittings must be tightened as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160391001.xml" xrefid="t1603921">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="t1603921"/>. Use only a torque wrench known to be accurate.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Whenever possible use a backup wrench when loosening or tightening fittings (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603962">Figure 62</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603962" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG16/G1603923.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 62. Use a Back-Up Wrench When Loosening or Tightening Fittings</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the filter-drier on any system which has been opened for more than a short period
                (approximately 30 minutes); after the system has been flushed or purged; and/or when the system has
                become contaminated (such as due to an internal compressor failure). If the filter-drier is one of
                multiple components being installed in the system, the filter-drier should be one of the last components
                installed. This reduces the amount of time that the filter-drier desiccant is exposed to atmospheric
                moisture.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refrigerant oil quickly absorbs moisture. Store oil only in moisture-free containers and
                keep oil containers closed until ready to use. Close refrigerant oil container immediately after use.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed or purged any time the system has become
                contaminated (such as due to an internal compressor failure). Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390909.xml" xrefid="hl160390909">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                    SYSTEM</hotlnk>,
                <xref refid="hl160390909"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Whenever the system is discharged, the refrigerant oil level must be checked and/or replaced
                as specified in
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390910.xml" xrefid="hl160390910">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>,
                <xref refid="hl160390910"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Any system that has been discharged due to leakage, or opened to replace a component, must
                be evacuated (and the system oil quantity must be returned to normal) before charging.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use extreme care to prevent moisture from entering the system. Moisture can freeze at the
                thermostatic expansion valve and block refrigerant flow during system operation. Always properly
                evacuate the system after service to remove any moisture and air from the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Spare components should be sealed and stored in a warm, dry facility.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390901.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390903.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
