<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB - MXT - Cab Installation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Cab Installation</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using an overhead crane and cab lifting fixture, lift cab over frame.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not put all cab weight on chassis until all mounting bolts are tightened.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Inspect all cab to frame attaching points to be sure they are aligned properly or damage can
                    result.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Carefully lower cab down over front and rear mounting locations, making sure that cab floor
                carriage bolts at rear and front cab mounting brackets are aligned properly as cab is lowered onto
                frame.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install hex flange nut onto the threaded stud of the front cab chassis mounting bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat step 3 for opposite side front mounting. Tighten both nuts but do not torque yet.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install three hex flange nuts onto the three carriage bolts (Item 2, Figure 2) protruding
                through rear bracket (Item 4, Figure 2) on underside of cab floor (Item 3, Figure 2). Tighten all nuts
                but do not torque yet.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat Step 5 for opposite side mounting. Tighten all nuts but do not torque yet.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque both front mounting hex flange nuts to 142 to 175 lbf-ft (193 - 213 Nm).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Torque all rear mounting hex flange nuts to 88 to 106 lbf-ft (119 to 144 Nm)</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the transmission module connector (Item 1, Figure 6) to the transmission control
                module (Item 2, Figure 6).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the ABS module reservoir line (Item 4, Figure 5) to the underside of the cab floor
                (Item 3, Figure 5) and secure with four clamps (Item 2, Figure 5) and four screws (Item 1, Figure 5).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the parking brake cable (Item 1, Figure 4) to the parking brake cable bracket (Item
                3, Figure 4) and secure with parking brake cable nut (Item 2, Figure 4).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the torsion bar (Item 3, Figure 3) to the torsion bar bracket (Item 2, Figure 3)
                with the hex head bolt (Item 1, Figure 3) and hex nut (Item 4, Figure 3).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the appropriate service manual replace all items that were disconnected prior to
                removing the cab.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Road test vehicle. Be sure all vehicle components are operating properly before putting
                vehicle back into operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16036_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16036_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16036.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
