<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 5000i, 9100i, 9200i, 9400i, 9900i MODELS - Starting 03/01/1999 -
        DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>The air handling unit of the Blend-Air heating and air conditioning system is a combination unit (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1602313">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Both the heater core and air conditioner evaporator are housed
            in one unit, and use common air ducts and blowers. The term "Blend-Air" refers to the mixing or blending
            together of air from the air conditioner, heater and outside air. This provides for heating, cooling,
            defrosting, dehumidifying and ventilation in whatever combination the driver chooses to select. The specific
            system covered in this manual is known as the 'lowered heater box' system; and, it can be identified by the
            side access cover that provides easy access to the system's air filter element.
        </para>
        <para>This system has used two methods to recirculate cabin air. In the first method, cabin air was drawn into
            the blend-air unit through the louvered filter access cover and a louvered panel on the front of the
            blend-air unit. Outside air was prevented from entering the system by a door in the air inlet duct. In the
            current method, cabin air is drawn into the blend-air unit through an opening in the air inlet duct, under
            the dash. This 'recirc' inlet is opened by the same air door that is used to block the outside air. The
            louvered panel on the front of the blend-air unit has been removed and the louvered filter access cover has
            been replaced with a solid cover.
        </para>
        <para>The same basic blend-air unit can be used for daycabs or sleepers. In the sleeper version a bunk blend-air
            door assembly is used to control the air at the bunk output port on the rear of the blend-air unit. Daycab
            versions use a dummy panel in place of the bunk blend-air door assembly, and a panel is used to cover the
            bunk output port.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1602313" figsize="full-pg">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602313d.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Blend-Air Heating and A/C Unit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. COVER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. COVER SEAL</callout1>
                <callout1>3. HEATER CORE</callout1>
                <callout1>4. GASKET</callout1>
                <callout1>5. PAN</callout1>
                <callout1>6. CAB BLEND-DOOR ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                <callout1>7. BLEND-DOOR LINKAGE</callout1>
                <callout1>8. CAB BLEND-DOOR ACTUATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>9. BLOWER SPEED CONTROL RESISTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>10. BLOWER SPEED CONTROL RESISTOR HOUSING</callout1>
                <callout1>11. MOTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>12. BLOWER WHEEL</callout1>
                <callout1>13. BLOWER HOUSING</callout1>
                <callout1>14. MOISTURE DRIP TUBE</callout1>
                <callout1>15. ASSEMBLY MOUNTING BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1>16. THERMOSTATIC SWITCH</callout1>
                <callout1>17. EXPANSION VALVE COVER</callout1>
                <callout1>18. PRESSURE SWITCHES</callout1>
                <callout1>19. EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                <callout1>20A. FILTER ACCESS COVER - VENTED</callout1>
                <callout1>20B. FILTER ACCESS COVER - SOLID</callout1>
                <callout1>21. COVER PANEL - DAYCABS</callout1>
                <callout1>22. FILTER</callout1>
                <callout1>23. EVAPORATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>24. DUMMY PANEL - DAYCABS</callout1>
                <callout1>25. BUNK BLEND-DOOR HOUSING - SLEEPERS</callout1>
                <callout1>26. BUNK BLEND-DOOR - SLEEPERS</callout1>
                <callout1>27. BUNK BLEND-DOOR ACTUATOR - SLEEPERS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The system's Blend-Air unit is integrated into the cab to provide a built-in appearance. The heater core,
            evaporator, blower and other parts of the system are located in the Blend-Air unit under the passenger seat.
            Heating and cooling controls along with a blower speed control are located in the cab and sleeper
            compartment.
        </para>
        <para>For greater detail in servicing the air conditioning system, refer to the following manuals, as necessary,
            for the model being serviced. (Manuals are located in the Master Service Manual.)
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16019.htm" bookname="s16019">s16019</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING BASIC
                    THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (Includes Sanden Compressor Info)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16022y.htm" bookname="s16022y">s16022</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING
                    PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTICS SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>
                    <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16017x.htm" bookname="s16017x">s16017</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING
                    COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH (CCI Type)
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>GROUP 8 ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>GROUP 8 ELECTRICAL TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023_X1602302.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
