<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL - CONDENSER CORE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390803" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CONDENSER CORE</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Depending on the vehicle model/engine combination, replacement of certain components may require the
                removal of nearby assemblies to gain access to fittings, components, or mounting hardware. Refer to the
                appropriate section(s) in the Master Service Manual for additional procedures.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390801.xml" xrefid="f1603924">Figure 24</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following Remove and Install procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discharge A/C system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390905.xml" xrefid="hl160390905">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390905"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, unclip or unbolt condenser line support clamps and disconnect pressure
                    transducer wiring connector to allow A/C lines to be moved out of the way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect A/C line fittings from condenser and position the A/C lines out of the way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two bolts securing top mounting hangers to radiator frame.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift mounting hangers from top of condenser. Insure that rubber isolators remain in
                    hanger sockets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift condenser from sockets in bottom rail. Insure that rubber isolators remain in
                    rail.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that rubber isolators are installed in bottom condenser support rail.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert posts on bottom of condenser into sockets until condenser is fully seated.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insure that rubber isolators are installed in top hanger sockets.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install top mounting hangers onto posts on top of condenser. Verify that posts are fully
                    seated into sockets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure top mounting hangers to radiator frame using two bolts removed earlier.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system is to be flushed or purged, perform that operation before completing
                    reassembly. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390909.xml" xrefid="hl160390909">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR
                        CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390909"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always lubricate A/C fitting O-rings with mineral-based oil during installation.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using new O-rings and C-plates connect A/C line fittings to condenser. Tighten to 19,000
                    to 21,000 N.mm (170 to 190 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If removed earlier, install any condenser line support clamps in their original location
                    and orientation. Connect wiring to pressure transducer.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install any assemblies that were removed to gain access to the condenser.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge A/C system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390907.xml" xrefid="hl160390907">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390907"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390802.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390804.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
