<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - BLOWER MOTOR CIRCUIT - EXTENDED DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EXTENDED DESCRIPTION</title>
        <para>When a blower speed is selected, the HVAC control head outputs a voltage (approximately 0 - 5 Volts dc) on
            circuit A73D. This voltage is based on the blower speed control setting. This variable voltage is input (via
            connector 1210) to the linear power module at terminal 2 of the Linear Power Module (LPM) connector. The LPM
            responds by acting as a variable resistance between terminal 4 of the LPM connector and ground. This
            variable resistance is in the ground path of the blower motor (terminal B of the blower motor connector). As
            the blower speed control is turned cw, the apparent resistance to ground decreases, the voltage across the
            blower motor increases, and the speed increases.
        </para>
        <para>A resistor connecting the input of the LPM to ground, maintains that point at a ground potential when the
            blower speed control is set to OFF. This prevents the blower motor from running when the control is in the
            OFF position.
        </para>
        <para>In version 1 of the electrical circuit, power for the LPM is routed from the battery (fuse F4 in the cab
            power distribution center), on circuit A73C, to LPM connector, terminal 1. Power is also routed from circuit
            A73C to the blower motor at terminal A of the blower motor connector. Ground for the LPM is supplied from
            negative stud (1851), on circuit A73-G, to the LPM connector, terminal 3.
        </para>
        <para>In version 2 and version 3 (early production) of the electrical circuit, power for the LPM is routed from
            the switched IGN voltage (fuse F6 in the cab power distribution center), on circuit A75D, to the LPM
            connector, terminal 1. Power for the blower motor is routed from the battery (fuse F4), on circuit A73C, to
            terminal A of the blower motor connector. Ground for the LPM is supplied from negative stud (1851), on
            circuit A73-G, to the LPM connector, terminal 3.
        </para>
        <para>The version 3 (late production) circuit is identical to the version 3 (early production) circuit except
            fuse F20 is used in place of F6.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_85.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_87.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
