<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - FIBERGLASS - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Observe the following when making repairs with fiberglass:</para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Avoid spilling the resin or hardener on skin or clothing. If this occurs, remove with
                    paint thinner or denatured alcohol. Then wash with soap and water. If the mixture contacts the eyes,
                    flush thoroughly with water immediately. Continue flushing for at least 15 minutes and contact a
                    physician as soon as possible.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">In some cases, some individuals may have skin sensitivity to the use of these
                    materials. Because of this, protective creams can be applied to the hands to guard against
                    irritation.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">When protective creams are not available, rubber gloves may be used to protect the
                    hands. The gloves can be removed quickly leaving the hands clean for other work.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">When working with fiberglass, always work in a well ventilated area. DO NOT SMOKE OR
                    EXPOSE FLAME WHERE KITS ARE BEING USED OR STORED. If possible, obtain a kit of material large enough
                    to accommodate only one or two jobs to avoid storing any quantity of the material. Resin liquid must
                    be kept in a metal container or cabinet when not being used.
                </emph>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">
                <emph type="bold">Repairs must be ground or sanded to match surrounding contours. When grinding or
                    sanding, use approved safety equipment.
                </emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>FIBERGLASS ABS PLASTIC REPAIRS To avoid breathing dust and fumes, wear approved protective
                        equipment. Breathing fiberglass ABS plastic dust and/or fumes can be hazardous to your health.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">1. OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements
                            as well as suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal
                            Regulations, Section 1910, 1001.)
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">2. Whenever possible work on fiberglass and ABS plastics in a separate area
                            away from other operations.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">3. Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all fiberglass or
                            ABS plastic repairs.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">4. Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking.</emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Fiberglass repairs are as safe as any other shop repairs, provided you take the proper
                        precautions. The following items should be particularly noted:
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">1. Before using any materials, read the manufacturer's instructions.</emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">2. Be sure work room is adequately ventilated. Prolonged exposure to resin
                            fumes is irritating to skin and eyes.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">3. Protect your eyes, face, and body from the fine dust that develops during
                            grinding and sanding operations. Wear goggles, respirator mask and protective clothing.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">4. Do not rub your face or eyes when working with fiberglass.</emph>
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
