<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 7000 AND 8000 SERIES MODELS - DESCRIPTION - CAB AIR SUSPENSION system</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="Describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CAB AIR SUSPENSION system</title>
        <figure id="f16038104" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G16038104.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 8. Cab Air Suspension</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. AIR SPRING (BAG)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SHOCK ABSORBER</callout1>
                <callout1>3. HEIGHT CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Cab rear air suspension enhances ride and cab component durability, resulting in less driver fatigue and
            greater productivity. The cab and cab components will experience greater durability due to less shock. The
            cab rear air suspension is standard on all 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, and 8600 model cabs.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The height control valve, air springs (bags), and shock absorbers are serviceable and can be
                    replaced individually.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>The cab air suspension system contains one or two air springs (bags) and two shock absorbers and is
            controlled by the height control valve. The air suspension assembly needs no lubrication and very little
            maintenance.
        </para>
        <para>The following components - air lines (to air springs), tee fitting, elbow fitting, air springs (bags),
            height control valve, shock absorbers, and lateral control rod - should be checked at the time the truck is
            being serviced. Immediate corrective action should be taken if a malfunction occurs.
        </para>
        <para>Periodically check the tightness of all fasteners and air line fitting connections. Refer to the
            <hotlnk document="s16038_X1603801.xml" xrefid="x1603801">
                <emph type="bold">TORQUE CHART</emph>
            </hotlnk>
            <xref refid="x1603801"/>
            for proper tightening of all fasteners and air line fitting connections.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
