<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CAB - TILT: 9600 AND 9700 SLEEPER AND NON-SLEEPER CABS -
        SHEET METAL REPAIRS - SELECT AND INSTALL RIVETS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SELECT AND INSTALL RIVETS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If panel is accessible from both sides, use a Lockbolt fastener of same diameter as rivet
                previously removed. If panel is accessible from one side only, use a 1/4 inch (6.35mm) Monobolt [or a
                1/4 inch (6.35mm) "Cherry G" rivet where required. See
                <hotlnk document="s16006_41.xml" xrefid="f1600654">Figure 52</hotlnk>
                ].
            </para>
            <para>In some severe cases, rivet holes may be too enlarged from damage, etc., to permit proper rivet
                installation. If you suspect that a rivet hole may be too large, check the hole with a new rivet. If the
                rivet hole is too large, weld the rivet hole shut, and metal finish the welded hole. When installing the
                new panel, drill panel and cab and install proper rivet in the same area that was welded.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The grip range (combined thickness of panels, reinforcements, framework, etc., being riveted)
                        is also important. Be sure to select the correct size rivet for the job it must do. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16006_41.xml" xrefid="hl1600619">Table 2
                            <xref refid="hl1600619"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a drill bit of same size as rivet selected (Monobolt or Lockbolt), redrill pilot hole
                at each rivet hole location. Drill four or five holes at one time and install that number of rivets.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert Monobolt in special installing tool and install Monobolt to panel (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600670">Figure 70</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600670" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600670" filename="../figg16/g1600670.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 70. Installing Monobolt Fastener</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Continue this procedure until all rivets are installed. Check panel fit intermittently so as
                to avoid any panel distortion or dimpling.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean up any sealant from panel edges and rivets.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_52.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_54.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
