<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Removal (Obstructed Access)</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>For proper rear window glass removal and installation, you will need the International&#174;
                    Bonded Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470. This kit comes complete with a toolbox and all the tools
                    required to remove and install bonded windshields. To order, call toll free in U.S. and Canada
                    1-800-520-2584 or Fax 1-800-578-7375. For additional materials contact International&#174; dealer
                    for service parts.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603824" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603824.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 37. Rear Window Glass</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. REAR WINDOW GLASS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. LOCATOR TAB</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SPRING CLIP</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place protective coverings over areas near the rear window glass inside the cab.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before removing rear window glass, it may be necessary to remove the seats. For removing
                rear bench seat, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16038_X1603804.xml" xrefid="x1603804">
                    <emph type="bold">REAR BENCH SEAT</emph>
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x1603804"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">For removing the front seats, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16038_X1603805.xml" xrefid="x1603805">
                    <emph type="bold">FRONT SEATS</emph>
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x1603805"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear protective eye wear and work gloves when removing rear window glass.</para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>For rear window removal and installation on vehicles with a van body (or other type of body) where
                    access is obstructed, the slide rail and suction cups from the International&#174; Bonded Windshield
                    Tool Kit ZTSE4470 must be used. The slide rail and suction cups require assembly.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603832" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603832.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 38. Slide Rail and Suction Cups</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PLUNGERS AND RED INDICATORS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SUCTION CUPS</callout1>
                <callout1>3. TOP RAILS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BOTTOM RAIL</callout1>
                <callout1>5. SCREWS</callout1>
                <callout1>6. WING NUTS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Assemble the slide rail by attaching the two top rails to the bottom rail. The three rails
                are identical and can be assembled in any one of the three locations. Line up the holes in the two top
                rails with holes in the bottom rail. Install three screws and tighten securely with three wing nuts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>It is very important that the area of the van body where the suction cups are being installed is
                    cleaned properly before the suction cups are attached. If the suction cups come off during the
                    removal or installation of the rear window glass, the rear window glass will be destroyed and the
                    vehicle damaged.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean the area on the van body where the suction cups will be installed to ensure the
                suction cups will stick securely.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach one suction cup to the van body on the driver side and attach the other to the
                passenger side. Position both suction cups so that the slide rail (which rests on top of each block)
                will be just below the bottom edge of the rear window glass. Repeatedly push the suction cup plungers
                until the red indicators are no longer visible; this indicates a good vacuum.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Periodically check the suction cups to see if the red indicator is starting to appear. If the
                    indicator is visible on either unit, push the plunger(s) repeatedly until the red indicator is no
                    longer visible.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603833" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603833.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 39. Installing Slide Rail</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. SUCTION CUP</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SLIDE RAIL</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SUCTION CUP BLOCK</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place the slide rail on top of each suction cup block.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603834" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603834.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 40. Securing Slide Rail with Pins</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. SLIDE RAIL</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SUCTION CUP BLOCK</callout1>
                <callout1>3. SUCTION CUP</callout1>
                <callout1>4. PINS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Starting with the driver side, align the hole in the slide rail with the hole in the suction
                cup block and install a pin to secure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Moving to the passenger side, reposition the suction cup to align the slide rail with the
                suction cup block and install a pin to secure. Repeatedly push suction cup plunger until the red
                indicator is not visible.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach a suction cup to the driver side of the rear window glass.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603825" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603825.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 41. Cutting Rear Window Out</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. POWER KNIFE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. SHORT INSIDE CUTTING BLADE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. REAR WINDOW GLASS FENCE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When using a power knife to cut around the rear window glass, use a spray bottle filled with water
                    to lubricate the cutting area. This will prevent burning of the urethane and rebonding of the rear
                    window glass.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">From inside the cab, use a power knife with a short inside cutting blade and cut all the way
                around the rear window glass until it is free from the window glass fence.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the suction cup, lift the rear window glass off the fence and set into the slide rail.
                Lean the top of the rear window glass against the van body.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603835" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603835.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 42. Removing Rear Window Glass</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. VAN BODY</callout1>
                <callout1>2. REAR WINDOW GLASS</callout1>
                <callout1>3. CAB</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">From outside the cab, slide the rear window glass down the slide rail and, with the aid of
                an assistant, remove rear window glass and place out of the way.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the suction cup from the rear window glass.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_14.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
