<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        REMOVE AND INSTALL - HEATER HOSES/LINES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="2">
        <title>HEATER HOSES/LINES</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Allow the engine to cool down before removing the pressure cap from the deaeration tank. ALWAYS
                    INSULATE the cap by wrapping it with a thick, heavy cloth. To prevent possible injury from scalding
                    water or steam, DO NOT pull the pressure cap off immediately when it has been loosened to the first
                    "notch." Pause momentarily to allow time for excess pressure to release through the overflow tube.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>Engine coolant is routed to and from the heater core using a combination of hoses and hard lines that vary
            by vehicle model and engine. Most hoses and lines are replaced using common practices, standard hose clamps,
            or threaded fittings. Only new or unique equipment is described in this section. In all cases replacement
            hoses and lines must be routed and secured in the same manor as the original equipment. Additional
            information for the coolant system may be found in the appropriate section(s) in GROUP 12 of the Master
            Service Manual.
        </para>
        <para>Some heater line connections now employ a peanut fitting (1, Figure 27) that is sealed with an O-ring (2)
            and secured with one nut. Before installing a peanut fitting always verify that a new O-ring is in place.
        </para>
        <para>Some engine options require a flow restrictor (3, Figure 28) in the top heater hose where it connects to
            the heater core at the cowl. When replacing this hose note whether the original hose contained a restrictor.
            If necessary, install a new restrictor into the replacement hose before installing the hose onto the
            vehicle.
        </para>
        <para>Depending on the vehicle model/engine combination, replacement of specific heater lines may require the
            removal of nearby assemblies (right splash panel, cab cowl tray, etc) to gain access to the hoses/lines.
            Refer to the appropriate section(s) in the Master Service Manual for additional procedures.
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>The cab cowl tray exists in several variations. Refer to the appropriate CAB section in GROUP 16
                    of the Master Service Manual for procedures covering cab cowl trays.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For most other under hood assemblies that may require removal, refer to the appropriate HOOD,
                    GRILLE, and FENDERS section in GROUP 09 of the Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>For information on draining and filling engine coolant, refer to the appropriate COOLING section
                    in GROUP 12 of the Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <figure id="f1603427" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603427.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
            <caption>Figure 27. Typical Coolant Line Peanut Fitting</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PEANUT FITTING</callout1>
                <callout1>2. O-RING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1603428" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603428.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Flow Restrictor in Heater Hose</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HEATER CORE TUBES</callout1>
                <callout1>3. FLOW RESTRICTOR</callout1>
                <callout1>4. HEATER HOSES</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340612.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340614.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
