<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 5000, 9000 Series Without Lowered heater Box - REMOVE AND INSTALL -
        BLEND-AIR UNIT HOUSING ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>BLEND-AIR UNIT HOUSING ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Most components can be serviced without removing the blend-air unit. This procedure should not
                        be performed unless there is definite reason for removing the unit.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A putty-type sealant is used where components pass through the cab floor. Carefully remove
                        this sealant when removing the components. Reseal the components after installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn off engine coolant supply to the heater with the heater hose gate valves in the
                    engine compartment, or clamp off the heater inlet and outlet hoses (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>) with C-clamps and wood blocks. Be sure not to damage
                    the hoses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recover the refrigerant from the Air Conditioning system. Refer to GROUP 16-AIR
                    CONDITIONING THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Under the Cab</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent personal injury from hot coolant, do not remove the heater hoses from the heater
                        core inlet and outlet until the cooling system has cooled down.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Note how the heater hoses are connected to the heater core, and label the hoses for
                    proper reconnection later. Remove the heater hoses from the heater core inlet and outlet tubes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601514" figsize="pg-wide">
                    <graphic filename="../figg16/g1601512b.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                             scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. A/C Heater Unit Connections Under Cab Floor</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. HEATER HOSE FITTINGS</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. MOISTURE DRAIN NIPPLE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. REFRIGERANT LOW PRESSURE SWITCH (R-12 ONLY) BEFORE 1/1/93</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. MOUNTING NUT AND WASHER</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. EVAPORATOR OUTLET HOSE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. EVAPORATOR INLET HOSE</callout1>
                        <callout1>7. SEALANT</callout1>
                        <callout1>8. CONDENSATE DRAIN</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Plug the heater hose inlet and outlet tubes to prevent coolant from being released inside the
                        cab during removal of the Blend-Air unit.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the evaporator hoses and fittings (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>). Cap or plug all hoses and fittings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the moisture drain nipple and evaporator drain tube, if so equipped, under the
                    cab (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the sealant from the components that pass through the cab floor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the unit mounting stud nuts and washers (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove - Inside the Cab</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the screws securing the passenger seat and the Blend-Air housing cover plate.
                    Remove the seat and cover from the cab.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the passenger side floor panel, as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the scuff plate from door sill.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the floor mat.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the screws securing the floor panel.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Take out the floor panel, exposing the air ducts.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the sheet metal screws securing the air ducts at the Blend-Air unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the control cables from inside the Blend-Air unit (at Blend-Air door and
                    thermostatic switch).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical wiring. If necessary, remove the passenger side kick panel to
                    gain access.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully lift the Blend-Air unit and remove it from the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Position the Blend-Air unit housing assembly in the cab with mounting studs, tubes and pipes
                protruding through the floor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install - Under the Cab</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install washers and nuts on the mounting studs (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>). Tighten mounting nuts to 22 to 28 lbf-ft (30 to 38
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the heater hoses on the heater core tubes making certain that the supply hose is
                    on the inlet tube and the return hose on the outlet tube. The heater core inlet tube is the one
                    nearest the center of the cab. Install the hose clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new O-rings, lubricate threads of the evaporator core fittings with
                    <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                    refrigerant oil and connect the inlet and outlet hoses to evaporator fittings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If applicable, connect electrical connector(s) to any pressure switches located below
                    the cab floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply sealant around the Blend-Air unit housing connections where they exit the cab
                    floor (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601514">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the heater water valves at the engine; or remove clamps used to close hoses, if
                    used.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install - Inside the Cab</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electrical wiring. Install the passenger side kick panel if it was removed
                    earlier.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the control cables are routed into the heater assembly. Connect the control
                    cables to the appropriate points in the Blend-Air unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the air ducts in place with sheet metal screws. Be certain the two rubber seals
                    are in place on the duct openings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the floor panel and the floor mat.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the control cables. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16015_HL1601502.xml" xrefid="hl1601502">CONTROL CABLE ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Replace coolant lost during heater hose removal. Refer to the Operator's Manual for the
                    correct type of coolant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate and charge the air conditioning system as described in GROUP 16-AIR
                    CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step, to verify correct heater and A/C operation at the air duct outlets, the
                        cover must be in place on the Blend-Air unit.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the engine and check the system for leaks (coolant and refrigerant) and proper
                    operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the Blend-Air unit cover and passenger seat assembly. Tighten the six thumb
                    screws.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015_25.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015_27.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
