<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING - DIAGNOSIS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="diagnose" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DIAGNOSIS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>An HVAC system is received for service because the operator feels that the system is not operating
                correctly. Usually, the operator will provide a symptom describing the operation of the system. In the
                following procedure, diagnosis begins by observing any Diagnostic Trouble Codes logged by the body
                controller. If no diagnostic trouble codes are displayed, the reported fault is verified by operating
                the system and observing the symptoms. Because the Fault Identification Procedure, Diagnostic Symptom
                Chart, and Troubleshooting Tables are organized in order of increasing confidence; any fault symptom
                must be resolved at its first appearance.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl16034050a">
            <title>Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
            <para>The body controller monitors parameters throughout the A/C system and generates Diagnostic Trouble
                Codes (DTC's) whenever a monitored parameter falls outside of its specified range. When any DTC is
                generated it is stored in memory. Observing DTC's is one of the first steps in diagnosing a
                malfunctioning A/C system, as indicated in the following procedure. Always resolve active DTC's before
                troubleshooting symptoms.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl16034050b">
            <title>FAULT IDENTIFICATION PROCEDURE</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following test may not perform correctly if the ambient temperature is too cold. If the
                        A/C compressor does not turn on when first attempted, allow the engine to warm up to operating
                        temperature, and try again. If the A/C compressor still will not turn on, a fault probably
                        exists.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>The cycling rate of the A/C compressor will vary with the ambient temperature. In cooler
                        ambient temperatures the compressor may cycle up to four times a minute.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Perform the following steps to determine if any HVAC related DTC's are being generated and/or to
                verify a reported symptom. Resolve each fault (DTC or symptom) at its first appearance. If a DTC is
                present when checked, follow the instructions provided in the Electrical Troubleshooting Guide. If no
                DTC's are displayed, perform the remainder of the procedure and note any symptoms observed. When a
                symptom is noted without a DTC, proceed to the
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl16034050c">DIAGNOSTIC SYMPTOM CHART</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl16034050c"/>.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check for HVAC related DTC's. Refer to the applicable Electrical Troubleshooting Guide
                    (on ISIS) for the vehicle being serviced.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no diagnostic trouble codes were displayed, start the engine and set the air
                    conditioning control panel for maximum cooling, as follows.
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set blower speed control to highest speed, full cw.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set temperature control for maximum cooling, full ccw.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set mode control to MAXA/C, full ccw.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the engine speed at 1500 RPM or above.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the air conditioning system for at least five minutes even if it appears that the
                    system is not operating correctly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step, verify only that the blower is operating and air flow is present at
                        some outlet. The air distribution system will be checked in a later step.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cycle the blower speed control through each of its settings and verify correct blower
                    operation. (Air flow stops in the OFF position and increases as the control is rotated in a
                    clockwise direction.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the blower speed control to the highest setting (full cw).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step verify that the main forced air flow is through the indicated outlets.
                        However, it is normal for a very slight amount of bleed-through air to be present at other
                        outlets.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly cycle the mode control through each of its settings and verify correct air
                    distribution at the various air outlets as indicated. Also note the strength of the air flow.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">MAX, NORM, and Vent Only settings direct air flow through the instrument panel vents
                        ONLY.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Bi-level setting directs air flow through the instrument panel vents and the floor
                        ducts ONLY.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Floor setting directs air flow through the floor ducts ONLY.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Floor/Defrost setting directs air flow through the floor ducts and the defrost ducts
                        ONLY.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Defrost setting directs air flow through the defrost ducts ONLY.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the mode control to the Floor setting.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The engine coolant must be at operating temperature before the next step will work
                        correctly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the temperature control to the maximum heat setting (full cw), and verify that the
                    temperature of the air flow at the floor ducts is warm to hot.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the temperature control to the maximum cooling setting (full ccw).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the mode control to the MAX air conditioning setting (full ccw), and verify that
                    within five minutes cold air is present at the instrument panel vents.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the mode control to the Defrost setting, and verify that the compressor cycles on
                    within two minutes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat the previous step with the mode control set to the Floor/Defrost setting; the
                    compressor should continue to operate.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the engine still running, check again for diagnostic trouble codes. Refer to the
                    applicable Electrical Troubleshooting Guide for complete procedures. If a diagnostic trouble code is
                    present when checked, follow the instructions provided in the Electrical Troubleshooting Guide;
                    otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If no diagnostic trouble codes are present, and the system is not operating correctly,
                    find the fault symptom in the
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl16034050c">DIAGNOSTIC SYMPTOM CHART</hotlnk>; otherwise, proceed to the next step.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The HVAC system is operating correctly. If you are performing this test after making
                    repairs; the fault has been repaired. Before returning the vehicle to service, perform a physical
                    inspection of the HVAC system including a refrigerant leak test.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl16034050c">
            <title>DIAGNOSTIC SYMPTOM CHART</title>
            <para>This chart is used to determine what action is required when a fault symptom exists but no diagnostic
                trouble code has been logged. After locating the fault symptom in the chart, service the system as
                instructed in the ACTION column.
            </para>
            <para>Once the system has been serviced, it should be tested to verify correct operation. If the fault was
                refrigerant based, verify the repairs by performing the
                <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340504.xml" xrefid="hl160340504">A/C SYSTEM PERFORMANCE TEST PROCEDURE
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl160340504"/>. If the fault was not refrigerant based, verify the repairs by performing
                the
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl16034050b">FAULT IDENTIFICATION PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl16034050b"/>.
            </para>
            <table id="t1603404" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Diagnostic Symptom Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="3.04in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="3.29in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Symptom</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Action</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <note>
                                    <para>This table is designed to be used after completing the FAULT IDENTIFICATION
                                        PROCEDURE and resolving any HVAC related Diagnostic Trouble Codes that were set.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <note>
                                    <para>Resolve any HVAC related symptoms in the order that they occurred during the
                                        performance of the FAULT IDENTIFICATION PROCEDURE.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>No Air Flow</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>This is an electrical problem related to the blower circuit. Refer to the
                                    applicable Electrical Troubleshooting Guide (on ISIS) for the vehicle being
                                    serviced.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Wrong Air Distribution</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603407">MODE SELECTION
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603407"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Low Air Flow</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603411">LOW AIR FLOW
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603411"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Insufficient Heat (Heater Mode)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603412">INSUFFICIENT HEAT
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603412"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Insufficient Cooling (A/C Mode) (Compressor may be operable or inoperable)</para>
                                <note>
                                    <para>If any diagnostic codes are set, refer to the applicable Electrical
                                        Troubleshooting Guide (on ISIS) for the vehicle being serviced.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603413">INSUFFICIENT COOLING
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603413"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Insufficient Defrost (Defrost Mode)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603414">INSUFFICIENT DEFROST
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603414"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Compressor Has Excessive Vibration or Noise</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml" xrefid="t1603415">NOISY COMPRESSOR
                                        TROUBLESHOOTING
                                    </hotlnk>
                                    table
                                    <xref refid="t1603415"/>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340503.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
