<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 4100, 4200, 4300 AND 4400 MODELS - INSTALL - Engine Cover And Cup Holder</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Engine Cover And Cup Holder</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Engine Cover on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab for all Models</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_55.xml" xrefid="f16026124">Figure 124</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f16026124"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position engine cover (Item 4) inside cab. Slide engine cover under dash panel, lift
                    bottom front edge of engine cover over transmission shift lever shaft
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_55.xml" xrefid="f16026125">(Item 4, Figure 125)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f16026125"/>, if so equipped, and slide it completely under dash panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull floor mat (Item 5) from under bottom edge of the engine cover (Item 4) to allow
                    engine cover mounting hole flanges to rest on the cab floor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull floor mat (Item 5, view circle B) back away from bottom edge across the front of
                    the engine cover (Item 4, view circle B). Install hex flanged bolt (Item 7, view circle B) through
                    engine cover into cab floor. Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull floor mat (Item 5, view circle C) back away from bottom edge across the front of
                    the engine cover (Item 4, view circle C). Install hex flanged bolt (Item 8, view circle C) through
                    engine cover into cab floor. Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull floor mat (Item 5, view circle A) back away from bottom edge on driver side of the
                    engine cover (Item 4, view circle A). Install two hex flanged bolts (Item 6, view circle A) on
                    driver side of the engine cover through engine cover into cab floor. Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Pull floor mat (Item 5, view circle D and E) back away from bottom edge on passenger
                    side of the engine cover (Item 4, view circle D and E). Install two hex flanged bolts (Item 9, view
                    circle D and E) on passenger side of the engine cover through engine cover into cab floor. Do not
                    tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two hex flanged bolts (Item 3) at the top of the engine cover (Item 4) through
                    engine cover into dash panel. Do not tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once all hex flanged bolts (Items 3, 6, 7, 8 and 9) have been installed, tighten them to
                    77 to 95 lbf-in (8.7 to 10.7 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_55.xml" xrefid="f16026125">Figure 125</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f16026125"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On a vehicle with standard transmission and air brakes, install gear shift lever (Item
                    2) with rubber boot (Item 1). If the rubber boot is not on the gear shift lever, slide the rubber
                    boot over the gear shift lever before installing gear shift lever.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold rubber boot (Item 1) up on the gear shift lever (Item 2) and install gear shift
                    lever onto transmission shift lever shaft (Item 4). Install allen screw (Item 3) securing gear shift
                    lever to transmission shift lever shaft and tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install rubber boot (Item 1) into cab floor around the gear shift lever (Item 2).</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_55.xml" xrefid="f16026124">Figure 124</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f16026124"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On a vehicle with automatic transmission and hydraulic brakes, position hydraulic hand
                    brake lever (Item 2) in place on the cab floor and install four hex flanged bolts (Item 1) through
                    the hydraulic hand brake lever mounting flange into the cab floor. Tighten to 77 to 95 lbf-in (8.7
                    to 10.7 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Cup Holder on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab for all Models</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_55.xml" xrefid="f16026123">Figure 123</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f16026123"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If so equipped, install cup holder and ashtray (Item 4) as follows.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position cup holder and ashtray (Item 4) underneath center dash panel (Item 1), slide
                    cup holder and ashtray forward to hook the back of the cup holder and ashtray to the underside of
                    the center dash panel. Install two torx head screws (Item 3) through the front center dash panel
                    into the cup holder and ashtray. Tighten them to 20 to 25 lbf-in (2.3 to 3.0 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the center dash panel trim bezel (Item 2) in place over the center dash panel
                    (Item 1). Carefully push it into center dash panel until it snaps into place.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install passenger bucket seat, fixed passenger seat and/or fixed passenger bench seat,
                    refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602633.xml" xrefid="x1602633">SEATS
                        <xref refid="x1602633"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_102.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_104.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
