<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL - TEMPERATURE BLEND AIR DOOR
        - REAR HVAC UNIT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390833" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TEMPERATURE BLEND AIR DOOR - REAR HVAC UNIT</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set ignition key to OFF.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Under the vehicle, use clamping pliers to pinch the rubber section of the rear heater
                    lines closed. Place the clamps several inches from the metal/rubber joint. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml" xrefid="f1603953">Figure 53</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>It may be easier to disconnect the hoses in the following step if the rear AC/heater line
                        hanger is loosened or removed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a clean drain pan positioned under the heater core connections, disconnect the
                    hoses from the heater core tubes (
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml" xrefid="f1603954">Figure 54</hotlnk>). Plug all open
                    tubes/hoses.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Through the passenger side access door, disconnect blower electrical connector from
                    linear power module (6,
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390826.xml" xrefid="f1603951">Figure 51</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove 4 Torx head screws securing blower to rear HVAC unit, and remove blower (5,
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390826.xml" xrefid="f1603951">Figure 51</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inside the sleeper, raise and support the lower bunk.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rear heater core and heater core inlet/outlet tubes (
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml" xrefid="f1603955">Figure 55</hotlnk>), as follows:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the 2 screws securing the heater core cover. Remove the cover.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>In the following step it may be easier to remove the clamp plate after lifting the
                                heater core slightly out of its cavity.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the clamp plate securing the heater core inlet and outlet tubes to the core.
                        Disconnect the tubes from the core, and rotate them out of the way. Retain the clamp plate and
                        mounting screw.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the heater core.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove the heater core inlet and outlet tubes.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect all remaining electrical connections to the rear HVAC unit.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rear HVAC controller - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">blend door actuator - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">outlet duct temperature sensor - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">rear linear power module - 1 connector (harness), blower connector was removed with
                        blower.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the rear HVAC unit outlet duct (1 screw). Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603956">Figure 56</hotlnk>. NOTE: It may be helpful to loosen or remove some
                    connected duct work.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603956" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603912.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 56. Location of Rear HVAC Unit</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. OUTLET DUCT, REAR HVAC UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. REAR HVAC UNIT</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. AIR INLET</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. AIR OUTLET VENT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the filter element (3, Figure 56) from the air intake of the rear HVAC unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove 15 screws securing the top housing of the HVAC unit to the bottom housing. It is
                    not necessary to remove the LPM, HVAC controller, and blend door actuator from the top housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before the top housing can be removed from the bottom housing, the foam seals at the air inlet
                        and outlet (under bunk) must be cut near the joint between the housing halves.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step, to provide additional clearance when removing the top housing, raise
                        the top housing enough to reach inside and disengage the blend door from the top and bottom
                        housings. Lay the door in the bottom housing until the top housing is removed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lift the top housing off of the rear HVAC unit.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the blend door (6,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603957">Figure 57</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603957" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603957.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 57. Internal Components of the Rear HVAC Unit</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. THERMOSTATIC EXPANSION VALVE (TXV)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FOAM SEAL, AIR INLET</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. UPPER LOCK PLATE FOR TXV</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FOAM SEAL, EVAPORATOR TUBES</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. EVAPORATOR CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. TEMPERATURE BLEND AIR DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. FOAM SEAL, AIR OUTLET</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before installing the top housing check the condition of the foam seals at the air inlet and
                        outlet (under bunk). If a seal requires replacement, the bottom housing must be removed from the
                        vehicle. The rear HVAC unit can then be reassembled on the bench (with new seals) before
                        installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From inside the sleeper, temporarily install the blend door into the bottom housing to
                    determine how the door is to be oriented (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603957">Figure 57</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step, it may be helpful to lay the blend door loosely in the bottom housing
                        until the top housing is nearly in position. Then lift the top housing enough to install the
                        blend door into its socket in the bottom housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the top housing onto the bottom housing so that the shaft of the blend door is
                    inserted into the hub of the actuator mounted on the top housing. The blend door must be captured
                    between the top and bottom housings.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install 15 screws securing the top housing of the HVAC unit to the bottom housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the rear HVAC unit outlet air duct (1 screw). Verify that all related duct work
                    is positioned and secured correctly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603956">Figure 56</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the rear heater core and heater core inlet/outlet tubes (
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml" xrefid="f1603955">Figure 55</hotlnk>), as follows.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Noting the position of the foam spacer and seal (below the housing), carefully
                        install the heater core inlet and outlet tubes and rotate them out of the way.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install the heater core.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>In the following step it may be easier to insert the inlet/outlet tubes by raising the
                                heater core slightly out of its cavity.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Using new O-rings, insert the heater core inlet and outlet tubes into the core.
                        Secure with the clamp plate and screw removed earlier.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Install heater core cover and secure with 2 screws.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Through the passenger side access door, position the blower assembly (5,
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390826.xml" xrefid="f1603951">Figure 51</hotlnk>) onto the rear HVAC
                    unit and secure with the 4 Torx head screws removed earlier.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the blower electrical connector into the linear power module (6,
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390826.xml" xrefid="f1603951">Figure 51</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect all electrical connections to the rear HVAC unit.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">blend door actuator - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">outlet duct temperature sensor - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">linear power module - 1 connector (harness), blower connector was installed with
                        blower.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Rear HVAC controller - 1 connector</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Under the vehicle, connect the heater core inlet/outlet hoses to the heater core tubes.
                    Install or tighten the rear AC/heater line hanger, if removed earlier (
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml" xrefid="f1603954">Figure 54</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the clamping pliers used to pinch the heater lines closed.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Add coolant drained during removal, to the coolant system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Calibration of the blend door actuator will occur the next time the IGN key is set to
                    IGN or ACCESSORY.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390832.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390834.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
