<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 AND 8600 MODELS - INSTALL - CAB DOOR HINGE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAB DOOR HINGE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Front Cab Door Hinge on Standard Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 and 8600 Models,
                Extended Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500 and 8600 Models and Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600
                Models
            </title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_21.xml" xrefid="f1602945">Figure 45</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The front cab door is mounted on upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) located on the cab
                hinge pillar (Item 3). Front cab door adjustment is provided by enlarged holes in front cab door hinge
                mounting holes. If cab door hinges are removed from the cab, upper and lower hinges can be interchanged.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) onto cab hinge pillar
                    (Item 3), use markings at upper and lower hinge position on cab hinge pillar to help position front
                    cab door hinges properly on the cab hinge pillar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position lower cab door hinge (Item 2), using markings on cab hinge pillar (Item 3).
                    Install two hex bolts with washers (Item 4) through lower cab door hinge and thread into the cab
                    hinge pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position upper cab door hinge (Item 1), using markings on cab hinge pillar (Item 3).
                    Install one hex bolt with washer (Item 4) through mounting hole nearest cab door opening and one hex
                    flanged locking bolt (Item 5) through forward mounting hole of the upper cab door hinge and thread
                    into the cab hinge pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After installing upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) on cab hinge pillar
                    (Item 3), install the front cab door onto front cab door hinges. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602923.xml" xrefid="x1602923">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOORS</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing front cab door, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Front Cab Door on Standard Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 and
                        8600 Models, Extended Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500 and 8600 Models and Crew Cab for
                        7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600 Models
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove upper and lower passenger side front cab door hinges.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Rear Cab Door Hinge on Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600 Models</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_21.xml" xrefid="f1602946">Figure 46</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The crew cab rear cab door is mounted on upper and lower crew cab rear door hinges (Items 1 and 2)
                located on the crew cab B pillar (Item 3). Rear cab door adjustment is provided by enlarged holes in
                rear cab door hinge mounting holes. If hinges are removed from the crew cab B pillar, upper and lower
                hinges can be interchanged.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing upper and lower crew cab rear door hinges (Items 1 and 2) onto crew cab
                    B pillar (Item 3), use markings at upper and lower hinge position on crew cab B pillar to help
                    position crew cab rear door hinges properly on the crew cab B pillar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position lower crew cab rear door hinge (Item 2), using markings on crew cab B pillar
                    (Item 3). Install two hex bolts with washers (Item 4) through lower crew cab rear door hinge and
                    thread into the crew cab B pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position upper crew cab rear door hinge (Item 1), using markings on crew cab B pillar
                    (Item 3). Install two hex bolts with washers (Item 4) through upper crew cab rear door hinge and
                    thread into the crew cab B pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After installing upper and lower crew cab rear door hinges (Items 1 and 2) on crew cab B
                    pillar (Item 3), install the rear cab door onto rear cab door hinges. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602923.xml" xrefid="x1602923">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOORS</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing rear cab door, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Rear Cab Door on Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600 Models</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install upper and lower passenger side crew cab rear door hinges.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602923.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_77.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
