<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - ADJUSTMENTS - Sleeper
        Cab Ride Height
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>Sleeper Cab Ride Height</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent property damage or personal injury, park the vehicle on a level surface, set the
                    parking brake, chock the wheels, and turn the engine off.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">These procedures are to provide instructions and specifications for setting the desired cab
                ride height. Before starting the adjustment procedure, be sure that the following conditions are met or
                performed.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Park the chassis on a flat level surface.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The chassis air system should be within the normal operating range of 100 to 120 psi.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Ensure that all cab mounting, hood mounting, muffler mounting components and air cleaner
                    mounting components are correctly installed to ensure free (unobstructed) movement of the cab.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">There must not be any occupants in the cab and no change in cab weight during the
                    adjustment procedures
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f16033e7" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g16033e7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 153. Sleeper Cab Ride Height Measurement</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. REAR CAB CROSSMEMBER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. FRAME RAIL</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The ride height adjustment for the sleeper cab is preset during manufacturing and is not
                    adjustable.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the cab ride height between the frame rail and the rear cab crossmember. This
                measurement must be made between the two measuring points that are specified and must meet the specified
                height of 9 inches (229.6 mm) for all ProStar&#8482; sleeper cab models.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_134.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_136.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
