<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - TROUBLESHOOTING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>TROUBLESHOOTING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Refer to Electrical Circuit Diagrams in the Circuit Diagrams section when troubleshooting.</para>
            <para>Refer to GROUP 16-AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master
                Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect all related connectors and wires for clean, tight connections free of damage or corrosion.
                Before beginning these test procedures, do the following:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Make sure the vehicle batteries are at 75% state of charge (SOC) or higher. This represents an
                        open circuit voltage (OCV) of 12.4 volts. Batteries with an OCV of 12 volts or less are either
                        completely discharged or have a dead cell.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check any light or indicator lamp filaments that are suspected of being open (burned out).
                        This is done to avoid unnecessary extensive circuit checks.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Inspect all connectors for loose or damaged pins, wires, etc. Refer to TEST EQUIPMENT and
                        Connector Repair section in Group 08 - Electrical in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the technician determines that a fuse is blown, while checking its condition, he is
                        directed to locate the cause of the overload condition and to repair it. While no further
                        instruction on this procedure is listed in the diagnostic tables, the common procedure is as
                        follows: isolate sections of the circuit by disconnecting connectors, and measure the resistance
                        to ground to find the circuit that is shorted to ground. Then locate the damaged spot in the
                        wire or connector and repair.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Diagnostics for circuits that are malfunctioning by sticking in the ON position are generally
                        not covered in detail. It is assumed that the mechanic knows to check for a malfunctioning
                        switch, relay, or solenoid.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
            <title>DIAGNOSIS AND TESTING</title>
            <para>Effective diagnosis and testing of the APADS begins with first determining the blinking code on the
                APADS control module and then completing the corrective action in the blink code troubleshooting. To
                ensure that the APADS is not working properly, perform the APADS tests 1 and 2.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
