<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - LEAK DETECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602534" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="2">
        <title>LEAK DETECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602524.xml" xrefid="hl1602524">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="hl1602524"/>. Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers
                        involved when working with refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>Refrigerant leaks are often indicated by an oily residue at the point of the leak.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1602535">
            <title>Electronic Leak Detectors</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To use the characteristics of the A/C system to your advantage while leak testing with an
                        electronic leak detector; check the high pressure side of the system with the system running,
                        and check the low pressure side of the system with the system (and engine) off.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>In terms of sensitivity and safety, the electronic leak detector (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602548">Figure 49</hotlnk>) is excellent for finding both slow and major system leaks.
                Ensure that the detector being used is intended for use with R134a refrigerant. Many leak detectors
                intended for use with R-12 cannot detect R134a leaks.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602548" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602548.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 49. Electronic Leak Detector</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The unit is a hand-held device having a flexible probe used to seek out refrigerant leaks. An audio
                leak indicator signals a warning in the presence of a leak. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602538.xml" xrefid="hl1602538">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl1602538"/>.
            </para>
            <para>Before starting to look for leaks, it is recommended to clean away all oil or grease, and blow away
                refrigerant residue from fittings and A/C components. All suspected areas should be cleaned using soap
                and water, not a solvent.
            </para>
            <para>It is important to become familiar with the leak detector instructions for the detector being used.
                The speed at which the probe is moved over the component being checked is very important in locating
                larger than permissible leaks. Leak check procedure should be in accordance with SAE J1628.
            </para>
            <para>A detected leak should be a flow of refrigerant, not a residual condition of refrigerant that is
                trapped under an oil film, etc. A detected leak rate in excess of 1.0 oz./year is unacceptable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ultraviolet Lamp Leak Testing</title>
            <para>An alternate method to electronic leak testing is ultraviolet light. The desiccant located in the
                accumulator contains a phosphor dye that will produce a bright yellow-green trace at the leak, when
                illuminated by an ultraviolet (UV) lamp. This dye is also included in replacement accumulators. The kit
                illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602549">Figure 50</hotlnk>
                provides the UV lamp used to illuminate the suspected leaks. The kit also contains connection hoses and
                a dye injector, as well as, eyeglasses used to enhance the effect of the UV light on the dye. A UV dye
                cleaner should be used to clean the HVAC system connections after repairs have been made.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602549" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602549.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 50. Ultraviolet Lamp Kit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>It has been discovered during the use of UV light, and phosphor dyes, that other types of leaks also
                appear as a yellow-green trace when the UV light shines on them. If an UV lamp is used for leak
                detection, it is also recommended that an electronic leak detector be used to verify that any detected
                leaks are, in fact, refrigerant leaks. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl1602535">ELECTRONIC LEAK DETECTORS
                    <xref refid="hl1602535"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602557.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_62.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
