<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - MAJOR STRUCTURAL REPAIR: 9600 - REPAIRING CO-9670 CABS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="26">
        <title>REPAIRING CO-9670 CABS</title>
        <para>In order to develop the preceding major structural repair instructions we did the actual work on two
            damaged CO 9670 cabs. The following photographs show this process. Both cabs were damaged as the result of
            jackknife accidents. Cab A was damaged badly enough so that the engine tunnel had to be removed and
            replaced. Cab B suffered less extensive damage and was repaired without removing the tunnel. The work was
            done in a commercial body shop by two regular employees. Neither of them had any special training in the
            repair of these cabs. Neither of them had worked on a CO 9670 cab before. According to both men, the
            construction and design of these cabs made their jobs very easy. Neither one encountered any difficulties.
        </para>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600110">CAB A. Figure 10:</hotlnk>
            This cab was badly damaged on the right rear corner. The force of the blow also buckled the engine tunnel
            and caused minor damage to other structures as well. It was necessary to remove the tunnel to properly
            repair this cab. To show how extensive damage can be easily repaired, the whole right floor assembly was
            also removed. Normally, the damage could have been repaired by splicing on a new right rear outer sill
            section and some new flooring
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600110" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600110" filename="../figg16/g1600110.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Cab A, Right Rear Corner Damage</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600111">CAB B, Figure 11:</hotlnk>
            This cab was hit more in the rear. The rear horse collar and the right rear outer sill were damaged. The
            impact caused some distortion of the tunnel and some minor damage to other structures. It was decided that
            this cab could be repaired without removing the tunnel. This proved to be true.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600111" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600111" filename="../figg16/g1600111.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 11. Cab B, Rear Horse Collar Damage</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600112">CAB A, Figure 12:</hotlnk>
            With the side and rear panels removed, the interior damage to the right rear corner can be seen. The force
            of the blow carried across the cab causing the tunnel to buckle. The left "B" pillar was damaged and the
            driver's door was sprung outward.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600112" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600112" filename="../figg16/g1600112.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Cab A, Side and Rear Panels Removed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600113">CAB B, Figure 13:</hotlnk>
            With the rear panel removed, you can see how the force of the blow bent the horse collar out of shape. The
            right rear outer sill was also bent. The force of the blow caused minor damage at other places in the cab,
            but most of the damage was located in the rear. The tunnel on this cab did not have to be replaced.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600113" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600113" filename="../figg16/g1600113.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 13. Cab B, Side with Rear Panel Removed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600114">CAB A, Figure 14:</hotlnk>
            This picture shows how badly the tunnel was buckled. The dashboards have been removed so that the tunnel
            could be removed from the front horse collar.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600114" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600114" filename="../figg16/g1600114.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. Cab A, Buckled Tunnel</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600115">CAB B, Figure 15:</hotlnk>
            With only the back and right quarter panels removed, a pulling bar is set up to straighten the cab as much
            as possible. The bar is placed along the direction of the impact. The forward end of the pull is fastened to
            a plate that is attached to the bolts that hold the left front pivot.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600115" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600115" filename="../figg16/g1600115.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 15. Cab B, Back and Right Quarter Panels Removed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600116">CAB A, Figure 16:</hotlnk>
            After the back and right rear quarter panels were removed, the tunnel was disassembled. The damaged right
            floor could have been repaired by splicing on a new section of outer sill and floor panel. It was decided to
            drop the whole floor in order to see if this made the repair more difficult. It did not cause any problems.
            The picture shows the floor being separated from the horse collar. Note the roof support and the pull that
            help hold the cab's shape.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600116" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600116" filename="../figg16/g1600116.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 16. Cab A, Tunnel Disassembly</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600117">CAB B, Figure 17:</hotlnk>
            This picture shows the other end of the pulling bar. It has been attached to the upper right corner of the
            rear horse collar. A jack has been placed to keep the lower corners of the horse collar the correct distance
            apart. Another pull (not visible) runs on the opposite diagonal to the pulling bar. The two pulls and the
            jack were tensioned until the diagonal underbody dimensions were correct. With everything still in tension,
            the tunnel was hammered back into shape.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600117" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600117" filename="../figg16/g1600117.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 17. Cab B, Pulling Bar at Right Corner - Horse Collar</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600118">CAB A, Figure 18:</hotlnk>
            Here is the new outer sill being attached to the old inner rail and floor beams.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600118" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600118" filename="../figg16/g1600118.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 18. Cab A, New Outer Sill</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600119">CAB B, Figure 19:</hotlnk>
            Once the tunnel d been hammered into shape, the rear horse collar was dropped out. You can see that the rear
            end of the tunnel has taken its correct shape. A jack and a pull hold the rear end of the tunnel in place.
            Note that the driver's door is sprung out. The top of the cab sprung to the left, then snapped back to the
            right. Another set of pulls will be used to realign it.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600119" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600119" filename="../figg16/g1600119.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 19. Cab B, Re-Aligning Cab</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600120">CAB A, Figure 20:</hotlnk>
            Here is the new floor panel welded to the repaired floor. Although care was taken to prevent heat build up,
            the plug welding did cause some distortion of the panel. Huck bolts or rivets could be used to avoid this
            problem.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600120" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600120" filename="../figg16/g1600120.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 20. Cab A, Floor Panel</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600121">CAB B, Figure 21:</hotlnk>
            A new section of sill is ready to be installed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600121" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600121" filename="../figg16/g1600121.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 21. Cab B, Section of Sill</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600122">CAB A, Figure 22:</hotlnk>
            The new floor has been attached to the horse collar and the door frame.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600122" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600122" filename="../figg16/g1600122.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 22. Cab A, Floor Attached to Horse Collar and Sill</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600123">CAB B, Figure 23:</hotlnk>
            This picture shows the new section of sill spliced in. The joint is welded and there is a plate backing up
            the joint and held in place by huck bolts.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600123" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600123" filename="../figg16/g1600123.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 23. Cab B, Sill Spliced In</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600124">CAB A, Figure 24:</hotlnk>
            The right tunnel section has been installed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600124" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600124" filename="../figg16/g1600124.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 24. Cab A, Right Tunnel Section Installation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600125">CAB B, Figure 25:</hotlnk>
            A small section of new drip rail is spliced on.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600125" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600125" filename="../figg16/g1600125.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 25. Cab B, Drip Rail Spliced In</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600126">CAB A, Figure 26:</hotlnk>
            The new horse collar is put in place and dropped down while the new tunnel pieces are being fitted. It will
            be lifted up after the tunnel has been fastened to the inner rails.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600126" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600126" filename="../figg16/g1600126.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 26. Cab A, Horse Collar Installation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600127">CAB B, Figure 27 :</hotlnk>
            The new horse collar is in place and the cab is ready for fitting the rear panel.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600127" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600127" filename="../figg16/g1600127.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 27. Cab B, Cab Ready for Rear Panel</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600128">CAB A, Figure 28:</hotlnk>
            The floor has been fastened to the horse collar with two 5/16" grade #8 bolts and two 1/4" huck bolts
            following the rules in the repair section of this service manual.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600128" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600128" filename="../figg16/g1600128.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Cab A, Fastening Floor to Horse Collar</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600129">CAB B, Figure 29:</hotlnk>
            Fitting the rear panel.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600129" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600129" filename="../figg16/g1600129.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 29. Fitting the Rear Panel</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600130">CAB A, Figure 30:</hotlnk>
            This shows the gusset at the left front end of the tunnel. This is a point of great stress and fasteners
            need to be used that meet current specifications. There is a special illustration of this area in the repair
            section of this service manual.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600130" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600130" filename="../figg16/g1600130.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 30. Cab A, Gusset at Left Front End of Tunnel</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600131">CAB B, Figure 31:</hotlnk>
            With the back panel held in place with clamps, pulls are used to bring the top of the cab in line.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600131" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600131" filename="../figg16/g1600131.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 31. Cab B, Installation of Top of Cab</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600132">CAB A, Figure 32:</hotlnk>
            The horse collar has been raised into position. Huck bolts were used on the sides of the horse collar and
            down the center of the tunnel. Plug welds were used across the top of the horse collar where the bunk floor
            rests. This cab did not require any pulling to bring it back to shape because so much of the structure was
            replaced. The new pieces fitted together easily.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600132" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600132" filename="../figg16/g1600132.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 32. Cab A, Installation of Horse Collar</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600133">CAB B, Figure 33:</hotlnk>
            The inner surfaces have been painted and the new outer panels can now be installed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600133" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600133" filename="../figg16/g1600133.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 33. Cab B, Inner Surface Painted</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600134">CAB A, Figure 34:</hotlnk>
            Repairs completed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600134" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600134" filename="../figg16/g1600134.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 34. Cab A, Repairs Completed</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600135">CAB B, Figure 35:</hotlnk>
            Repairs completed.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600135" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600135" filename="../figg16/g1600135.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 35. Cab B, Repairs Completed</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16001_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
