<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - CF 500, CF 600 Heat Ventilation Air Conditioning (HVAC) System - Description
        and Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Principles of Air Conditioning / RefRigeration</title>
            <para>There are 4 main principles involved with the basic theory of operation:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Heat transfer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Latent heat of vaporization</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Relative humidity</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Effects of pressure</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Heat Transfer</emph>
            </para>
            <para>If 2 substances of different temperature are placed near each other, the heat in the warmer substance
                will transfer to the colder substance.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Latent Heat of Vaporization</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When a liquid boils (changes to gas), it absorbs heat without raising the temperature of the resulting
                gas. When the gas condenses (changes back to a liquid), it gives off heat without lowering the
                temperature of the resulting liquid.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Relative Humidity</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The amount of moisture (water vapor content) that the air can hold is directly related to the air
                temperature. The more heat there is in the air, the more moisture the air can hold. The lower the
                moisture content in the air, the more comfortable you feel. Removing moisture from the air lowers its
                relative humidity and improves personal comfort.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Effects of Pressure on Boiling or Condensation</emph>
            </para>
            <para>As the pressure is increased on a liquid, the temperature at which the liquid boils (changes to gas)
                also increases. Conversely, when the pressure on a liquid is reduced, its boiling point is also reduced.
                When in the gas state, an increase in pressure causes an increase in temperature, while a decrease in
                pressure will decrease the temperature of the gas.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">The Refrigerant Cycle</emph>
            </para>
            <para>During stabilized conditions (air conditioning system shutdown), the refrigerant is in a vaporized
                state and pressures are equal throughout the system. When the A/C compressor is in operation, it
                increases pressure on the refrigerant vapor raising its temperature. The high-pressure, high-temperature
                vapor is then released into the top of the A/C condenser core.
            </para>
            <para>The A/C condenser core, being close to ambient temperature, causes the refrigerant vapor to condense
                into a liquid when heat is removed from the refrigerant by ambient air passing over the fins and tubing.
                The now liquid refrigerant, still at high pressure, exits from the bottom of the A/C condenser core and
                enters the inlet side of the receiver/drier.
            </para>
            <para>The receiver/drier is designed to remove moisture from the refrigerant. The refrigerant, still at high
                pressure, exits the receiver/drier and enters the thermostatic expansion valve.
            </para>
            <para>The thermostatic expansion valve is the restriction in the refrigerant system that creates the
                high-pressure buildup in the A/C condenser core and separates the high and low-pressure sides of the A/C
                system. As the liquid refrigerant leaves this restriction, its pressure and boiling point are reduced.
            </para>
            <para>The liquid refrigerant is now at its lowest pressure and temperature. As it passes through the A/C
                evaporator core, it absorbs heat from the passenger compartment airflow passing over the plate/fin
                sections of the A/C evaporator core. This addition of heat causes the refrigerant to boil (convert to
                gas). The now cooler passenger compartment air can no longer support the same humidity level of the
                warmer air and this excess moisture condenses on the exterior of the evaporator coils and fins and
                drains outside the vehicle.
            </para>
            <para>The refrigerant cycle is now repeated with the A/C compressor again increasing the pressure and
                temperature of the refrigerant.
            </para>
            <para>The A/C thermostatic cycling switch interrupts compressor operation before the external temperature of
                the A/C evaporator core gets low enough to cause the condensed water vapor (excess humidity) to turn to
                ice.
            </para>
            <para>The low charge protection switch protects the A/C compressor in the event of a low refrigerant charge.
                The low charge protection switch interrupts the A/C demand signal when the refrigerant pressure drops
                below acceptable levels.
            </para>
            <para>The high side line pressure is also monitored so that A/C compressor operation can be interrupted if
                system pressure becomes too high.
            </para>
            <para>The A/C compressor relief valve will open and vent refrigerant to relieve unusually high system
                pressure.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION - Air Distribution and Filtering</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The air distribution system of this vehicle cannot be equipped with a cabin air filter.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>There are 2 sources of air available to the air distribution system:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Outside air</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Recirculated air</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Recirculated air is available in any mode when the air inlet selector is in the RECIRC position.
            </para>
            <para>Air distribution within the vehicle is determined by the function selector switch position. Airflow
                mode doors are used to direct airflow within the heater core and evaporator core housing. An airflow
                mode door control cable is used to position these airflow mode doors.
            </para>
            <para>Air enters the passenger compartment from the:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>instrument panel A/C registers.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>floor duct.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>windshield defroster.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>side window demisters.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Passenger compartment air is exhausted from the vehicle through open windows or cab air vents.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION - Control Components</title>
            <para>The manual climate control system heats or cools the vehicle interior depending on the function
                selector position and the temperature selected. The function selector position determines air
                distribution. The temperature blend control setting determines air temperature.
            </para>
            <para>The manual climate control components are used to:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>select the air inlet source (FRESH or RECIRC).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>select the blower motor speed.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>select the discharge air temperature (temperature blend).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>select airflow mode (DEFROST, PANEL, FLOOR).</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>select A/C compressor clutch operation.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Climate Control Assembly</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The climate control assembly has 4 system controls:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The function selector operates the airflow mode doors using a push-pull type airflow mode door
                        control cable. The airflow mode door control cable attaches to the airflow mode door linkage to
                        operate the 2 airflow mode doors.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature selector operates the temperature blend door using a push-pull type
                        temperature blend door control cable. The temperature blend door control cable attaches to the
                        temperature blend door linkage to operate the temperature blend door.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet selector operates the air inlet door using a push-pull type air inlet door
                        control cable. The air inlet door control cable attaches to the air inlet door linkage to
                        operate the air inlet door between the FRESH and RECIRC modes.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor switch controls blower motor speed by adding or bypassing resistors in the
                        blower motor resistor.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A/C Switch</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The A/C switch is used to select A/C operation in any mode.</para>
            <para>The A/C request button is enabled by the blower motor switch. The A/C request button is disabled when
                the blower motor switch is in the OFF position. A 5-volt reference voltage from the engine control
                module (ECM) is received at the A/C switch. When the A/C request button is activated (indicator ON), the
                reference voltage is grounded through the blower motor switch. When the reference voltage is grounded,
                an A/C demand signal is recognized by the ECM.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Blower Motor Resistor</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The blower motor resistor adjusts the blower motor speed based on the blower motor switch setting. The
                blower motor resistor contains 3 resistor coils in series. The end of each resistor coil is wired to a
                setting in the blower motor switch. Voltage is available at the blower motor at all times when the
                ignition is in the ON position and then continues to the blower motor resistor. The blower motor switch
                will allow a path to ground with the addition of 1, 2 or 3 coils in the blower motor resistor to the
                circuit.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>When the blower motor switch is in the MED HI position, the blower motor switch will add a
                        path to ground through one coil in the blower motor resistor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the blower motor switch is in the MED LO position, the blower motor switch will add a
                        path to ground through 2 coils (in series) in the blower motor resistor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the blower motor switch is in the LO position, the blower motor switch will add a path to
                        ground through 3 coils (in series) in the blower motor resistor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>When the blower motor switch is in the HI position, the blower motor resistor is bypassed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description - System Airflow</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1200001">FIGURE 1</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1200001" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0020719.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Panel/defrost mode door</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Temperature blend door</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Evaporator core</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. Air inlet door</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. Blower motor</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. Panel/floor mode door</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">OFF</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When OFF is selected on the blower motor switch:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The airflow mode doors are in the position indicated by the function selector.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C compressor will not operate and the indicator will not illuminate.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor is OFF.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PANEL</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When PANEL is selected:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The panel/defrost door closes off the defrost outlet and opens the panel outlet. The
                        panel/floor door closes off the floor outlet and opens the panel outlet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature can be adjusted to heat the air but the air cannot be cooled below the outside
                        temperature unless A/C is selected ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C switch is enabled if the blower motor switch is in an ON position. The A/C compressor
                        will operate if the A/C switch is selected (indicator ON) and the outside temperature is above
                        approximately 6&#176;C (43&#176;F).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor speed is selected on the blower motor switch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">PANEL/FLOOR</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When PANEL/FLOOR is selected:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The panel/defrost door closes off the defrost outlet and opens the panel outlet. The
                        panel/floor door is in the mid-position to open the floor outlet and panel outlet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature can be adjusted to heat the air but the air cannot be cooled below the outside
                        temperature unless A/C is selected ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C switch is enabled if the blower motor switch is in an ON position. The A/C compressor
                        will operate if the A/C switch is selected (indicator ON) and the outside temperature is above
                        approximately 6&#176;C (43&#176;F).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor speed is selected on the blower motor switch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FLOOR</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When FLOOR is selected:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The panel/defrost door closes off the defrost outlet and opens the panel outlet. The
                        panel/floor door closes off the panel outlet and opens the floor outlet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature can be adjusted to heat the air but the air cannot be cooled below the outside
                        temperature unless A/C is selected ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C switch is enabled if the blower motor switch is in an ON position. The A/C compressor
                        will operate if the A/C switch is selected (indicator ON) and the outside temperature is above
                        approximately 6&#176;C (43&#176;F).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor speed is selected on the blower motor switch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">FLOOR/DEFROST</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For most efficient defrost operation, the air inlet selector should be in the FRESH position
                        and the A/C should be selected ON.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When FLOOR/DEFROST is selected:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The panel/defrost door is in the mid-position to open the defrost outlet. The panel/floor door
                        is in the mid-position to open the floor outlet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature can be adjusted to heat the air but the air cannot be cooled below the outside
                        temperature unless A/C is selected ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C switch is enabled if the blower motor switch is in an ON position. The A/C compressor
                        will operate if the A/C switch is selected (indicator ON) and the outside temperature is above
                        approximately 6&#176;C (43&#176;F).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor speed is selected on the blower motor switch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">DEFROST</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For most efficient defrost operation, the air inlet selector should be in the FRESH position
                        and the A/C should be selected ON.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When DEFROST is selected:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The air inlet door is positioned by the air inlet selector and can be switched between FRESH
                        and RECIRC.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The panel/defrost door closes off the panel outlet and opens the defrost outlet. The
                        panel/floor door closes off the floor outlet.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature can be adjusted to heat the air but the air cannot be cooled below the outside
                        temperature unless A/C is selected ON.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C switch is enabled if the blower motor switch is in an ON position. The A/C compressor
                        will operate if the A/C switch is selected (indicator ON) and the outside temperature is above
                        approximately 6&#176;C (43&#176;F).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The blower motor speed is selected on the blower motor switch.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION - Heating and Ventilation</title>
            <para>The heating and ventilation system has the following features:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Controls the temperature and during A/C operation (if equipped), reduces the relative humidity
                        of the air inside the vehicle
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Delivers heated or cooled air to maintain the vehicle interior temperature and comfort level
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Cooling or heating can be adjusted to maintain the desired temperature</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>System uses a reheat method to provide conditioned air to the passenger compartment</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The temperature blending is varied by the air temperature control door, which regulates the
                        amount of air that flows through and around the heater core, where it is then mixed and
                        distributed
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Blower Motor</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The blower motor pulls air from the air inlet and forces it into the heater core and evaporator core
                housing where it is mixed and distributed.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Heater Core and Evaporator Core Housing</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The heater core and evaporator core housing directs airflow from the blower motor through the
                evaporator core (if equipped) and heater core. All airflow from the blower motor passes through the
                evaporator core (if equipped). The airflow is then directed through or around the heater core by a
                cable-actuated temperature blend door. After passing through the heater core, the airflow is distributed
                to the selected outlet by 2 cable-actuated airflow mode doors.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Heater Core</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The heater core consists of fins and tubes arranged to extract heat from the engine coolant and
                transfer it to air passing through the heater core from the blower motor.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>DESCRIPTION - Air Conditioning</title>
            <para>The A/C refrigerant system is a clutch cycling thermostatic expansion valve (TXV) type. The system
                components are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A/C compressor and clutch assembly</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A/C condenser core</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A/C evaporator core</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Receiver/drier</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Connecting refrigerant lines</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The refrigeration system operation is controlled by the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Thermostatic expansion valve</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Thermostatic A/C cycling switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>High-pressure cutoff switch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Low-charge protection switch</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The refrigerant system incorporates an A/C compressor controlled by a thermostatic A/C cycling switch.
                The thermostatic A/C cycling switch senses evaporator core temperature to control operation of the A/C
                compressor.
            </para>
            <para>An A/C compressor pressure relief valve is installed to protect the compressor against excessively
                high refrigerant pressures. A TXV is used to meter the liquid refrigerant into the A/C evaporator core.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A/C Compressor and Clutch Assembly</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Internal A/C compressor and clutch components are not serviced separately. The FS-10 A/C
                        compressor/clutch is serviced only as an assembly.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Whenever a new A/C compressor is installed due to a failure that produces foreign material in
                        the refrigerant system, also install a new receiver/drier and TXV. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603007.xml" xrefid="hl1603007">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The FS-10 A/C compressor has the following characteristics:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A 10-cylinder swashplate design utilizing the tangential design mount.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A 1-piece lip-type seal is used to seal it at the shaft opening in the assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Five double-acting pistons operate within the cylinder assembly. The pistons are actuated by a
                        swashplate that changes the rotating action of the shaft to a reciprocating force.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Reed-type discharge valves are located between the cylinder assembly and the head at each end
                        of the A/C compressor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C compressor uses PAG Refrigerant Compressor Oil.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>When battery voltage is applied to the A/C compressor clutch field coil, the clutch plate and hub
                assembly is drawn toward the A/C clutch pulley. The magnetic force locks the clutch plate and hub
                assembly and the A/C clutch pulley together as one unit, causing the compressor shaft to rotate. When
                battery voltage is removed from the A/C compressor clutch field coil, springs in the clutch plate and
                hub assembly move the clutch plate away from the A/C clutch pulley.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Thermostatic Expansion Valve</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The thermostatic expansion valve (TXV) is located at the evaporator core inlet and outlet fittings
                below the instrument panel. The TXV provides a restriction to the flow of refrigerant from the high
                pressure side of the refrigerant system and separates the low pressure and high pressure sides of the
                refrigerant system. Refrigerant entering or exiting the evaporator core passes through the TXV through 2
                separate flow paths. An internal temperature sensing bulb senses the temperature of the refrigerant
                flowing out of the evaporator core and adjusts an internal pin-type valve to meter the refrigerant flow
                into the evaporator core. The internal pin-type valve decreases the amount of refrigerant entering the
                evaporator core at lower temperatures and increases the amount of refrigerant entering the evaporator
                core at higher temperatures.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A/C Evaporator Core</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If an evaporator core leak is suspected, the evaporator core must be vacuum leak tested before
                        it is removed. For additional information, refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_7.xml" xrefid="hl1603010">COMPONENT TESTS</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The evaporator core is an aluminum plate/fin type and is located in the heater core and evaporator
                core housing. A mixture of refrigerant and oil enters the bottom of the evaporator core through the
                evaporator core inlet tube and then moves out of the evaporator core through the evaporator core outlet
                tube. Air from the blower motor is cooled and dehumidified as it flows through the evaporator core fins.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A/C Condenser Core</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The condenser is an aluminum fin and tube design heat exchanger, located in front of the vehicle
                radiator. It cools compressed refrigerant gas by allowing air to pass over fins and tubes to extract
                heat and by condensing gas to liquid refrigerant as it is cooled.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Thermostatic A/C Cycling Switch</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The thermostatic A/C cycling switch monitors the temperature of the evaporator core. It is used (by
                the ECM) to prevent freezing of the evaporator core by controlling A/C compressor clutch
                engagement/disengagement. When the evaporator core temperature drops below specification, the
                thermostatic A/C cycling switch opens, interrupting the A/C demand signal to the ECM. When the
                evaporator core temperature rises above specification, the thermostatic A/C cycling switch contacts
                close.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Low-Charge Protection Switch</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The low-charge protection switch is used to prevent A/C compressor damage in the event of a low
                refrigerant charge, by interrupting the A/C demand signal to the ECM, when the low side refrigerant
                pressure drops below acceptable levels. The electrical switch contacts open when the suction pressure
                drops below normal levels. The contacts close when the suction pressure rises.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">High-Pressure Cutoff Switch</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure cutoff switch is used to interrupt A/C compressor operation, by interrupting the A/C
                demand signal to the ECM, in the event of high system discharge pressures. When the A/C compressor
                discharge pressure rises, the switch contacts open. When the pressure drops, the contacts close.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">A/C Compressor Pressure Relief Valve</emph>
            </para>
            <para>An A/C compressor pressure relief valve is incorporated in the compressor manifold and tube assembly
                to prevent damage to the A/C compressor and other system components and to avoid total refrigerant loss
                by relieving unusually high refrigerant system discharge pressure buildups.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Service Gauge Port Valves</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The high-pressure service gauge port valve is located on the receiver/drier.</para>
            <para>The low-pressure service gauge port valve is located on compressor manifold and tube near the
                evaporator fitting.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1201002" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../fign00/N0015648.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. Low-pressure service gauge port valve cap</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. Low-pressure service gauge port valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. Low-pressure Schrader-type valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. High-pressure Schrader-type valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. High-pressure service gauge port valve</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. High-pressure service gauge port valve cap</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The fitting is an integral part of the refrigeration line or component.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Special couplings are required for both the high-side and low-side service gauge ports.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>A very small amount of leakage will always be detectable around the Schrader-type valve when
                        the service gauge port valve cap is removed and is considered normal. A new Schrader-type valve
                        core can be installed if the seal leaks excessively.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The service gauge port valve caps are used as primary seals in the refrigerant system to
                        prevent leakage through the Schrader-type valves from reaching the atmosphere. Always install
                        and tighten the A/C service gauge port valve caps to the correct torque after they are removed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603004.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
