<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl160390800">
        <title>REMOVE AND INSTALL</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface,
                        shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake, and block wheels before performing
                        diagnostic or service procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent damage to the equipment and/or personal injury, always turn the vehicle ignition
                        key OFF before performing Removal and Installation procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury or death, refer to the manufacturer's service information before
                        working on any high voltage equipment. By definition high voltage circuits and components
                        contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage, electrical shock and/or electrocution if
                        handled incorrectly.
                    </para>
                    <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work
                        around or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent contamination of the HVAC system as well as continued leakage from an open line,
                        always cap or plug all open tubes or ports after disconnecting components.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Cleanliness of the air conditioner components cannot be over-emphasized. Lack of proper
                        attention in this area is one of the major causes of costly and unsatisfactory unit operation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Special attention to the following, during component remove and install, will aid in avoiding
                        unnecessary and time-consuming problems.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>When working on the A/C system keep the work area and tools as clean as possible. Also, clean
                        all connections, ports or fittings before disconnecting or removing components.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All A/C component and refrigerant line openings should be immediately covered or plugged
                        during removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and
                        other foreign material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a
                        vulnerable place within the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never remove protective caps from components until the moment of assembly into the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never install non-sealed components.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the filter drier is one of multiple components being installed in the system, it should be
                        the last component installed. This reduces the amount of time that the filter drier desiccant is
                        exposed to atmospheric moisture.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Anytime an A/C fitting is disconnected, the O-ring and/or C-plate must be replaced (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603922">Figure 22</hotlnk>). The new O-ring must be lubricated with
                        <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                        oil. The C-plate does not require lubrication. Never use grease, penetrating oil, motor oil,
                        Ester or PAG oil, etc. to lubricate O-rings and fittings.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                        original positions.
                    </para>
                    <para>Never bend a hose to a radius less than ten times the diameter of the hose.</para>
                    <para>Never route a hose any closer than four inches from the exhaust manifold or related piping.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Whenever possible use a backup wrench when loosening or tightening fittings (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603923">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All fittings must be tightened as specified in the
                        <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160391001.xml" xrefid="t1603921">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="t1603921"/>. Use only a torque wrench known to be accurate.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f1603922" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603922.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 22. A/C Fitting C-Plate and O-Ring</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. C-PLATE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1603923" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603923.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 23. Use a Back-Up Wrench When Loosening or Tightening Fittings</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following figures and procedures cover most typical engine/chassis configurations. Some
                        configurations may differ slightly due to component mounting locations and/or hose routings.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The removal and installation procedures for this heating - air conditioning system are organized in
                the following order. Under hood components are covered first, followed by the in-cab components, then
                sleeper components.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390706.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390801.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
