<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CAB - TILT: 9600 AND 9700 SLEEPER AND NON-SLEEPER CABS -
        CAB TILTING PROCEDURE - LIFT CAB MECHANICALLY (WITH HOIST - Figure 12 )
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1600603" svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="1">
        <title>LIFT CAB MECHANICALLY (WITH HOIST -
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600612">Figure 12</hotlnk>)
        </title>
        <figure id="f1600612" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600612" filename="../figg16/G1600612.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 12. Lifting Cab with Hoist (Mechanically)</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. CHAIN TO LIFTING DEVICE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CHAIN/STRAP LIFTING SUPPORT</callout1>
                <callout1>3. LIFTING SUPPORT HOOKS WITH CAB WOOD BLOCK PROTECTORS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If the hydraulic system must be opened for replacement or repairs, make sure an overhead hoist is
                    available. Keep dirt or other contaminants from entering the hydraulic system. Do not attempt to
                    mechanically pull the cylinders to retract or extend as pressure at the cylinder port is required to
                    release cylinder check valves. Cylinder damage may result from the mechanical pull.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>To lift the cab to make the necessary hydraulic repairs, use the following procedures.</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the cab in the down position, remove both left and right rams from the cab hinge. This
                can be accomplished by turning the steering wheel to the left and right to have access to the ram lock
                pin. Remove lock pin from clevis pin, then remove clevis pin. Ram will fall free from the cab hinge.
                Repeat this procedure for each ram.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a chain or lift strap connected to a lift hoist, place the chain/strap hooks to lock
                under the back of cab as shown in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600612">Figure 12</hotlnk>. Place a suitable piece of wood between the cab and lift
                hook as not to damage the back of cab.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Make sure that the lift hooks, when placed at the back of the cab tunnel, DO NOT catch or
                        pinch any of the lines that are routed in that area.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a lifting hoist, lift cab slowly only to the point where you have enough room to do
                your necessary repairs to the hydraulic system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Use a suitable safety prop to support the cab.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After repairs are made, remove safety prop. Lower cab; leave lift chain/strap attached.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach left and right side rams to cab hinges. It may be necessary to raise the cab slightly
                with the hoist to align the clevis pins. Install clevis pins and clevis lock pins. Remove hoist lift
                chain/strap from back of cab.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check cab operation. It may be necessary to bleed the cab hydraulic system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16006_12.xml" xrefid="hl1600604">BLEEDING THE CAB HYDRAULIC SYSTEM
                    <xref refid="hl1600604"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
