<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 2000, 4000, AND 8000 - Before 12/06/1994 - REMOVE AND INSTALL - EXPANSION
        VALVE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>EXPANSION VALVE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure the key switch is off.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recover the air conditioning system. Refer to GROUP 16 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY,
                    DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the access cover from the passenger side of the instrument panel and the
                    Blend-Air unit housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the wiring harness connector from the blower resistor located on the bottom
                    of the blower housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the insulated tape from the expansion valve and evaporator inlet and outlet
                    tubes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using two wrenches, disconnect the expansion valve equalizer line from the fitting on
                    the evaporator outlet tube (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601420">Figure 20</hotlnk>). Plug or cap the outlet tube.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601420" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601420" filename="../figg16/G1601420.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="352px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Expansion Valve Removal</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. EVAPORATOR CORE OUTLET TUBE</callout1>
                        <callout1>3. EQUALIZER LINE</callout1>
                        <callout1>4. FEELER BULB AND CLAMP</callout1>
                        <callout1>5. EXPANSION VALVE INLET TUBE</callout1>
                        <callout1>6. EVAPORATOR CORE INLET TUBE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the screw and clamp securing the expansion valve feeler bulb to the evaporator
                    outlet tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the expansion valve inlet tube from the expansion valve. Plug or cap the
                    inlet valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the bolt, nut and clamp securing the expansion valve to the bracket on the blower
                    housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using two wrenches, disconnect the expansion valve from the evaporator core inlet tube.
                    Remove the expansion valve. Plug or cap the inlet tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring, lubricate the threads with MINERAL-BASED refrigerant oil and
                    connect the expansion valve to the evaporator core inlet tube. Using two wrenches, tighten to 25 to
                    28 ft-lbs. (34 to 38 Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the clamp, bolt and nut securing the expansion valve to the bracket on the
                    blower housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new O-ring, lubricate the threads with MINERAL-BASED refrigerant oil and
                    connect the expansion valve inlet tube to the expansion valve. Tighten to 13 to 20 ft-lbs. (18 to 27
                    Nm).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the expansion valve feeler bulb on the evaporator core outlet tube and secure
                    with the clamp and screw (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601420">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Install a new O-ring, lubricate the threads with
                <emph type="bold">mineral-based</emph>
                refrigerant oil and connect the expansion valve equalizer to the fitting on the evaporator outlet tube (
                <hotlnk document="s16014_33.xml" xrefid="f1601423">Figure 23</hotlnk>). Using two wrenches, tighten to
                10 to 15 ft-lbs. (14 to 20 Nm).
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wrap the expansion valve and evaporator inlet and outlet tubes with insulating tape.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the wiring harness connector to the blower resistor.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate and charge the air conditioning system as described in GROUP 16 - AIR
                    CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run the engine and check the operation of the system. Check for leaks and repair as
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the access covers on the Blend-Air unit housing and the instrument panel.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014_30.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014_32.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
