<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        GENERAL DESCRIPTION - SYSTEM OPERATIONAL DESCRIPTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>SYSTEM OPERATIONAL DESCRIPTION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (General)</title>
            <para>The following figure (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603404">Figure 4</hotlnk>) is a cross-sectional view of the air-handling components of
                the HVAC system, as they are mounted in the vehicle. The figure shows the system's four air doors and
                indicates their range of travel.
            </para>
            <para>The electrically actuated fresh/recirculate air door (14, Figure 4) is located in the evaporator
                housing (12), and is controlled by the mode control (right knob) on the HVAC control panel. When the
                door is in the recirculate position, outside air is blocked by the door. Recirculation air, from the
                cab, enters the upper rear of the evaporator housing through the upper portion of the dash panel cutout
                (13). With the fresh/recirculate air door in the fresh air position, fresh outside air enters the top of
                the evaporator housing via an air duct which is part of the cowl drain tray (15). (The recirculate air
                is blocked by the fresh/recirculate air door.) In both cases the air is pulled by the blower assembly
                (8) through the evaporator core (10) to exit the evaporator housing through the lower portion of the
                dash panel cutout. The air entering the heater housing from the evaporator housing enters the dual
                inlet, single scroll blower assembly and is pushed through the heater housing.
            </para>
            <para>An air filter (11), optional on some models, can be mounted vertically in front of the evaporator
                core, within the evaporator housing. On some vehicles, a second air filter (17) is located at the air
                intake of the evaporator housing, and is accessible from above the cowl drain tray.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603404" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603404.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Cross-Section of HVAC Air Handling Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. DEFROST DUCT (PART OF INSTRUMENT PANEL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLOOR DUCT OUTLET FROM HEATER MODULE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. VENT DUCT FOR INSTRUMENT PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DEFROST/FLOOR DOOR (MODE DOOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. IP VENTS/FLOOR DOOR (MODE DOOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. HEATER CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. BLOWER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. FLOOR (CAB INTERIOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. A/C EVAPORATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. AIR FILTER ELEMENT</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. A/C EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. RECIRCULATE AIR INLET (OPEN TO CAB INTERIOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. FRESH/RECIRCULATION AIR DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. COWL TRAY</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. HOOD</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. HVAC AIR INLET GRILLE/FILTER</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The temperature blend door (7) is controlled by the temperature control (center knob) on the HVAC
                control panel. The electrically actuated temperature blend door diverts air from the blower assembly
                (8), either through the heater core (6), or around it depending on the temperature selected for the
                outlet air.&#160; Engine coolant flows through the heater core at all times. The air proceeds to the
                mode doors.
            </para>
            <para>The two mode doors, defrost/floor (4) and IP vent/floor (5), are controlled by the mode control (right
                knob) on the HVAC control panel. The doors are located at the top of the heater housing and are
                controlled together via a gear assembly and another electrical actuator. These mode doors direct air to
                the air outlets (floor ducts, instrument panel vents, and/or defrost vents) based on the mode selected
                by the operator. The ductwork for the instrument panel vents (3) and the defrost vents (1) is integrated
                into the instrument panel structure. The upper surfaces of the heater housing interface with ductwork
                through two large openings in the bottom of the Instrument Panel. Left-hand drive (LHD) vehicles have a
                passenger floor duct attached to the right side of the heater housing and a driver side floor duct (2)
                attached to the left side of the housing.
            </para>
            <para>The speed of the system blower motor, which controls the volume of air moved through the system, is
                selected by the fan speed control (left knob) on the HVAC control panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (Air Conditioning)</title>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>A illustrates the system airflow when operating in the MAX
                A/C mode. In the MAX A/C mode the fresh/recirculate air door is in the recirculate position; outside air
                is blocked by the door. Recirculation air (REC), from the cab, enters the upper rear of the evaporator
                housing through the upper portion of the dash panel cutout. (This air inlet is located behind the heater
                housing.) The air is pulled by the blower assembly, through the evaporator core. The air entering the
                heater housing from the evaporator housing enters the dual inlet, single scroll blower assembly and is
                pushed through the heater housing. The temperature blend air door diverts air either through the heater
                core or past it depending on the temperature selected for the outlet air. Although the temperature
                control is operational while in the A/C modes, the temperature control is generally set to divert all
                air around the heater core. The air proceeds to the mode doors where all of the air is directed to the
                instrument panel vents.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>B illustrates the system airflow when operating in the NORM
                A/C mode. In the NORM A/C mode the fresh/recirculate air door is in the fresh air position. Fresh
                outside air enters the top of the evaporator housing via an air duct which is part of the cowl drain
                tray. The remainder of NORM A/C operation is identical to MAX A/C operation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>C illustrates the system airflow when operating in the
                Bi-Level A/C mode. The Bi-Level A/C mode operation is identical to NORM A/C operation; except, the mode
                doors direct the output air to both the floor ducts, and the instrument panel vents.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603405" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603405A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="586px"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. System Airflow by Mode</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (Heat and Ventilation)</title>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>B illustrates the system airflow when operating in the Heat
                and Ventilation Vent mode. In the Heat and Ventilation Vent mode the fresh/recirculate air door is in
                the fresh air position. Fresh outside air enters the top of the evaporator housing via an air duct which
                is part of the cowl drain tray. The air is pulled by the blower assembly, through the evaporator core.
                The air entering the heater housing from the evaporator housing enters the dual inlet, single scroll
                blower assembly and is pushed through the heater housing. The temperature blend air door diverts air
                either through the heater core or past it depending on the temperature selected for the outlet air. The
                temperature blended air proceeds to the mode doors where all of the air is directed to the instrument
                panel vents.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>D illustrates the system airflow when operating in the Heat
                and Ventilation Floor mode. The Heat and Ventilation Floor mode is identical to the Heat and Ventilation
                Vent mode; except, the mode doors direct all of the output air to the floor ducts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (Defrost)</title>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>E illustrates the system airflow when operating in the
                Bi-Level Defrost/Heat mode. In the Bi-Level Defrost/Heat mode the fresh/recirculate air door is in the
                fresh air position. Fresh outside air enters the top of the evaporator housing via an air duct which is
                part of the cowl drain tray. The air is pulled by the blower assembly, through the evaporator core. The
                air entering the heater housing from the evaporator housing enters the dual inlet, single scroll blower
                assembly and is pushed through the heater housing. The temperature blend air door diverts air either
                through the heater core or past it depending on the temperature selected for the outlet air. The air
                proceeds to the mode doors where the doors direct the output air to both the defrost ducts, and the
                floor ducts.
            </para>
            <para>
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603405">Figure 5</hotlnk>F illustrates the system airflow when operating in the
                Defrost mode. The Defrost mode is identical to the Bi-Level Defrost/Heat mode; except, the mode doors
                direct all of the output air to the defrost ducts.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>A/C Refrigerant Flow</title>
            <para>The refrigerant cycle (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603406">Figure 6</hotlnk>) consists of four phases: compression, condensation,
                expansion, and evaporation. Consider the starting point at the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>When any air conditioning position is selected on the HVAC control panel, the clutch assembly mounted
                to the front of the compressor becomes engaged. When engaged, the clutch armature assembly is
                magnetically drawn to the pulley assembly on the compressor shaft, thereby engaging the clutch and
                driving the compressor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603406" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603406.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. A/C Refrigerant Flow Diagram</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The suction side of the compressor draws low pressure refrigerant vapor (5 to 50 psi) from the low
                side of the system, coming from the evaporator, through the thermostatic expansion valve. The compressor
                then compresses the refrigerant vapor and discharges it at increased temperature and pressure (120 to
                300 psi) through the high side line which connects the compressor to the condenser.
            </para>
            <para>An internal lubricating system uses the suction side intake crankcase pressure differential to coat
                internal parts with a thin film of oil. This lubrication also travels along with the refrigerant
                throughout the air conditioning system to lubricate various system components.
            </para>
            <para>High pressure/high temperature refrigerant vapor from the compressor enters at the top of the
                condenser, circulates down through the coils and exits at the bottom of the condenser as high
                pressure/high temperature refrigerant liquid. As the vapor condenses (changes state), some of its heat
                is released to the coils and fins of the condenser. This heat is continually carried away by the outside
                air which passes over the external fin surfaces as it flows through the condenser.
            </para>
            <para>The efficiency of the condenser operation is affected by ram air flowing through the condenser. For
                this reason, it is important that the engine cooling fan be operating properly, and that the condenser
                cooling fins remain free of airborne contamination (leaves, insects, dirt, etc.) which can block the
                fins and cause system temperatures to run higher than normal.
            </para>
            <para>When operating properly, the condenser acts as an efficient heat exchanger, containing refrigerant
                vapor in approximately two-thirds of the upper portion of its coils and condensed refrigerant liquid in
                the lower one-third portion. A pressure transducer located in the output line of the condenser is used
                to control system operation by providing inputs to the refrigerant control and diagnostic software
                within the Body Controller. The condenser passes high temperature/high pressure liquid refrigerant to
                the filter drier. The primary function of the filter drier is the removal of any moisture or solid
                contamination from the refrigerant before it can cycle through the system and cause internal damage.
            </para>
            <para>The next component in the refrigerant system is the expansion valve. The expansion valve is the
                dividing line between the high and low pressure sides of the system. High pressure liquid refrigerant
                enters the expansion valve from the filter drier. The valve senses the temperature of the refrigerant
                leaving the evaporator core. Then, based on the sensed temperature, the valve regulates the amount of
                refrigerant that it passes to the evaporator core. While leaving the expansion valve, the refrigerant
                starts to expand, entering the evaporator core as a low pressure, low temperature liquid.
            </para>
            <para>Within the evaporator core, the lower pressure permits the liquid refrigerant to boil or evaporate,
                changing its state from a liquid to a low pressure/low temperature vapor; and absorbing heat from the
                evaporator core and the air surrounding it. Cooling and dehumidifying of the cab's interior takes place
                as the refrigerant vapor passes through the evaporator's finned tubes and absorbs heat from the cab air
                pulled through the evaporator core by the system blower. Humidity condenses on the external surfaces of
                the cooled evaporator fins and is channeled (drained) out of the evaporator housing through drain
                valves. The refrigerant exits the evaporator outlet as a low pressure/low temperature vapor and is drawn
                through the low pressure side of the expansion valve by the suction created by the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>Thermistors are located at the input and output of the evaporator to monitor the temperature or the
                refrigerant at these points. The inputs from these sensors are used to control system operation by
                providing inputs to the body controller.
            </para>
            <para>The compressor repressurizes the refrigerant causing it to again become a high pressure/high
                temperature vapor that is pumped to the condenser, where the cycle is repeated.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
