<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - PAINT REFINISHING</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>PAINT REFINISHING</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Paint repairs and refinishing can be done with acrylic or urethane enamels. Various manufacturers,
                including Sikkens, DuPont, PPG Industries and Sherwin-Williams, offer satisfactory materials for
                refinishing. The guidelines contained within this section have been prepared in cooperation with
                Sikkens. When other manufacturers' products are used, the user should make sure that they are equivalent
                products.
            </para>
            <para>All warnings and instructions furnished by the manufacturers of the products you use must be closely
                followed. Observe all safety precautions on instruction labels for each paint product. Special care
                should be followed for proper respirators when using and spraying Isocyanate Hardeners and Activators.
            </para>
            <para>These instructions are intended to provide general guidance in repair and refinishing of any original
                acrylic enamel or urethane finishes. For more detailed information relating to paint repairs and
                materials, refer to the paint manufacturer's service information and bulletins.
            </para>
            <para>Prior to applying any type of cleaning solvent or sanding, it is important that the panel or complete
                vehicle (depending upon the type of painting operation) be cleaned with mild detergent and water. A good
                washing of the area to be refinished will remove normal road dirt such as tree sap, bird droppings, mud
                and normal dust.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
