<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - OIL FILL GUIDELINES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160340710" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>OIL FILL GUIDELINES</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340701.xml" xrefid="hl160340701">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="hl160340701"/>. Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers
                        involved when working with refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not re-use recovered oil. Be sure to dispose of recovered oil properly to avoid an
                        environmental hazard.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>Replacement compressors contain a quantity of oil when shipped. This oil must be drained from
                        the new compressor before refilling the compressor (and system) with the correct amount of new
                        oil.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <caution>
                    <para>During normal A/C operation, oil is circulated through the system with the refrigerant, and a
                        small amount is retained in each component. If certain components of the system are removed,
                        some of the refrigerant oil will go with the component. To maintain the original total oil
                        charge, it is necessary to compensate for the oil lost by adding oil to the system with the new
                        part.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The correct volume of refrigerant oil in the A/C system is critical for proper system operation.
                Insufficient oil will result in compressor failure. Too much oil decreases cooling efficiency, resulting
                in poor system cooling performance. In general, when servicing the system, ensure that the amount of oil
                (retained or added) in the repaired system (compressor and components) equals the total system capacity
                indicated in
                <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340800.xml" xrefid="hl160340800">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl160340800"/>. Replacement oil may be added directly into the compressor before
                evacuation, or injected into the system after evacuation. The following paragraphs describe how to
                determine the quantity of refill oil needed under the most common conditions.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Unless stated otherwise, the following procedures assume that the system is not being flushed
                        and/or purged.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>If the refrigerant was only recovered for the purpose of measuring the refrigerant charge, or
                        to replace a thermistor, add the amount of oil removed from the system during the refrigerant
                        recovery procedure.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a compressor is replaced (and the system was
                        <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                        contaminated and had no leaks) refill the new compressor with the amount of oil removed from the
                        system during the refrigerant recovery procedure, plus the quantity of oil that was contained in
                        the old compressor. NOTE: New compressors must be drained of shipping oil before filling with
                        new oil. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340711.xml" xrefid="hl160340711">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                            LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to drain and fill the oil in the
                        refrigerant compressor.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure
                                <emph type="bold">+</emph>
                                oil drained from old compressor.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If a component other than the compressor is replaced, and there is no oil leak, add the amount
                        of oil removed from the system during the refrigerant recovery procedure, plus the amount
                        indicated for the replaced component in
                        <hotlnk xrefid="t1603416">table 16</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                oil from refrigerant recovery procedure
                                <emph type="bold">+</emph>
                                oil indicated in component table.
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the amount of oil in the system is unknown (due to an oil leak, ruptured hose, etc.); refer
                        to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl160340710a">EXCESSIVE OIL LOSS DUE TO REFRIGERANT LEAK</hotlnk>, below.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Whenever the refrigerant system has become contaminated; make the necessary repairs, flush and
                        purge the system, and replace the compressor, expansion valve, and filter-drier. The new
                        compressor must be drained of shipping oil before filling with new oil. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340711.xml" xrefid="hl160340711">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                            LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows, for the procedures to drain and fill the oil in the
                        refrigerant compressor. The replacement oil may be added to the compressor before installing it.
                        Refill the system with a full refill of new oil.
                    </para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                                <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                                total system capacity as specified in
                                <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340800.xml" xrefid="hl160340800">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                                <xref refid="hl160340800"/>
                                <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                                0.5 fl. oz (oil film left in new compressor after draining shipping oil).
                            </para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <table id="t1603416">
                <title>Oil Capacity by Component</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.83in"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col2" nameend="col3" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" morerows="1" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>Component</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>Typical oil amount</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>cc</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>fl.oz.</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Evaporator</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>60</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>2.0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Condenser</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>30</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>1.0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Filter-drier</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>0.5</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Expansion valve</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Hoses (normal length)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>10</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0.3</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>Thermistor</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>0</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Oil Separation During Refrigerant Recovery</title>
            <para>The oil removed from the system during the refrigerant recovery process must be replaced. Always empty
                the refrigerant station oil catch bottle before recovering the refrigerant. After recovering the
                refrigerant, check the calibrated bottle to determine how much oil has been removed from the system.
                This quantity is used to help determine the amount of NEW oil that must be added to the system before or
                during the recharging of the A/C system. Do not use recovered refrigerant oil.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl160340710a">
            <title>Excessive Oil Loss Due to Refrigerant Leaks</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>After servicing the A/C system, always use new O-rings and C-plates when reassembling the
                        system components. O-rings must be lubricated with mineral oil.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>When there is a significant refrigerant leak, an unknown amount of oil escapes from the system with
                the refrigerant. When a significant leak is detected, perform the following procedures to replace the
                old system oil with a full refill of new oil.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the service equipment and observation to determine the location of the leak. Refer
                    to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340712.xml" xrefid="hl160340712">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340712"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discharge the system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340705.xml" xrefid="hl160340705">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340705"/>,
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make any necessary repairs.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the system does
                    <emph type="bold">not</emph>
                    appear to be contaminated, purge the system. If the system appears contaminated, such as after an
                    internal compressor failure, it must be flushed before purging. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340709.xml" xrefid="hl160340709">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR
                        CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340709"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the removed refrigerant
                    <emph type="bold">was not</emph>
                    contaminated:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Reinstall the expansion valve (removed for purging).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Drain and discard the old oil from the compressor. Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340711.xml" xrefid="hl160340711">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                                LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Refill compressor with new oil; then, install compressor.</para>
                        <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                            <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                            total system capacity as specified in
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340800.xml" xrefid="hl160340800">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                            <xref refid="hl160340800"/>
                            <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                            0.5 fl. oz (oil film left in compressor after draining old oil).
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install a new filter-drier.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the removed refrigerant
                    <emph type="bold">was</emph>
                    contaminated:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install a new expansion valve.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Add new refrigerant oil to a
                            <emph type="bold">new</emph>
                            compressor; then, install compressor. NOTE: New compressors must be drained of shipping oil
                            before filling with new oil. Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340711.xml" xrefid="hl160340711">CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL
                                LEVEL</hotlnk>, that follows.
                        </para>
                        <para>Total replacement oil quantity
                            <emph type="bold">=</emph>
                            total system capacity as specified in
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340800.xml" xrefid="hl160340800">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                            <xref refid="hl160340800"/>
                            <emph type="bold">minus</emph>
                            0.5 fl. oz (oil film left in new compressor after draining shipping oil)
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Install a new filter-drier.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340706.xml" xrefid="hl160340706">EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340706"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340707.xml" xrefid="hl160340707">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                        (FULL CHARGE)
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160340707"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After repairing a leak, remove all traces of the fluorescent dye from the repaired area
                    before retesting the area. The dye can be removed with UV Dye Cleaner, ZTSE4618-2.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After running the system, retest the repaired area to verify the repair.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340709.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340711.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
