<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s16012v" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5062" revno="J" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM)</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/29/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/29/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/29/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/29/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <title>GENERAL</title>
                <lev1>
                    <title>BASIC PRINCIPLES</title>
                    <para>To meet the Federal Government's scheduled phase-out of CFC-12 (R-12) refrigerant,
                        International will start building vehicles charged with the new refrigerant HFC-134A on the
                        following dates:
                    </para>
                    <para>5000, 9200, 9300, 9400 Series on November 30, 1992.</para>
                    <para>2000, 4000, 8000, 9600, 9700 Series on January 1, 1993.</para>
                    <para>Vehicle air conditioning is the cooling or refrigeration of air in the passenger compartment (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601201">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Refrigeration is accomplished by the practical
                        application of three laws of nature. These are: heat transfer, latent heat of vaporization, and
                        pressure of vaporization.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1601201" figsize="pg-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1601201" filename="../figg16/G1601201.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="514px" scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Basic Refrigeration System</caption>
                    </figure>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>HEAT TRANSFER</title>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">When two substances of different temperatures are placed next to each
                                other, the heat in the warmer substance will always travel to the colder substance until
                                both are of equal temperature.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>For example, the ice in a cold drink does not transfer its coldness to the beverage. The
                            heat in the beverage transfers to the ice which has less heat. As the beverage transfers
                            heat to the ice the beverage becomes cooler and the ice is converted to water. The unit used
                            to measure heat transfer is the British Thermal Unit (BTU) and is the amount of heat
                            required to raise the temperature of one pound (.454 kg) of water 1&#176;F (.55&#176;C).
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>LATENT HEAT OF VAPORIZATION</title>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">When a liquid boils (changes to gas), it absorbs heat without raising the
                                temperature of the liquid or the resulting gas. When the gas condenses (changes back to
                                a liquid), it gives off heat without lowering the temperature of the gas or resulting
                                liquid</emph>.
                        </para>
                        <para>Nature throws us a curve here. Once a liquid reaches its boiling point, it never gets any
                            hotter regardless of how much more heat is added. A three-minute boiled egg will always take
                            three minutes to cook regardless of how high you turn up the heat. What does happen is that
                            as more heat is applied, the more rapidly the water is converted to vapor. Neither the
                            temperature of the water or the vapor will exceed 212&#176;F.
                        </para>
                        <para>The excess heat that is used in the conversion of water to vapor is the "heat of
                            vaporization" or latent heat. Latent is a Latin word meaning "hidden" or "concealed." The
                            heat required to change the water to vapor remains hidden within the water molecules. The
                            temperature of the vapor does not increase.
                        </para>
                        <para>When the vapor is changed back to water, it is said to condense and the hidden heat in the
                            molecules is absorbed by the surrounding air. The molecules are once again held together in
                            a liquid state. This is what takes place in the condenser of an air conditioning system.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>PRESSURE OF VAPORIZATION</title>
                        <para>
                            <emph type="bold">The saturation temperature (the temperature where boiling or condensation
                                occurs) of a liquid or vapor increases or decreases according to the pressure exerted on
                                it.
                            </emph>
                        </para>
                        <para>Going back to the example of the boiled egg which takes three minutes to cook at sea level
                            where the boiling point of water is 212&#176;F, the situation changes as we increase or
                            decrease elevation. If we take a camping trip to the mountains, we will discover that our
                            three-minute egg now takes much longer to cook because the decrease in air pressure at
                            higher elevations allows water to boil at lower temperatures. If on the way home from the
                            mountains we stop at Death Valley, which is below sea level, we will find our eggs cook in
                            less than three minutes because the increase in air pressure causes the boiling point
                            temperature of water to increase.
                        </para>
                        <para>A more common example of the effect of high pressure on the boiling point of water, and
                            all liquids for that matter, is the radiator in truck cooling systems. As the coolant warms,
                            the pressure increases inside the sealed system. Because of the higher pressure inside the
                            system, the boiling point of the coolant rises above 212&#176;F. As long as the system
                            remains sealed and pressure maintained, the coolant will not boil. If the radiator cap is
                            removed, however, pressure in the system is rapidly reduced to the ambient air pressure and
                            the coolant immediately boils over.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>BASIC REFRIGERATION</title>
                        <para>With these basic ground rules: 1. All liquids absorb quantities of heat without getting
                            any warmer when they boil into a vapor and 2. Pressure can then be used to make a vapor
                            condense back into a liquid so that it can be used over again, we have the knowledge to
                            build a basic air conditioning or refrigeration system.
                        </para>
                        <para>International air conditioning systems use R-12 and HFC-134A refrigerant. The refrigerant
                            boils at -15.7&#176;F. at sea level. As pressure is increased, the boiling point of the
                            refrigerant is raised well above the temperatures encountered on the hottest days. The low
                            boiling point plus the fact that R-12 and HFC-134A can be cycled through the system nearly
                            an endless number of times without loss of efficiency makes them ideal refrigerants.
                        </para>
                        <para>Due to the difference in density between R-12 and HFC-134A, the amount of HFC-134A
                            refrigerant required to charge a typical air conditioning system has been reduced from 4.5
                            lbs. to 3.5 lbs.
                        </para>
                        <para>The ideal temperature for the refrigerant to boil is 30&#176;F. Systems are designed to
                            keep their pressure so the refrigerant boils at about this temperature. This creates the
                            right temperature for taking the heat out of the cab. If it were any colder, the
                            condensation in the evaporator would freeze, and if any warmer, the cooling would be
                            inefficient.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>HOW THE SYSTEM WORKS</title>
                        <para>If we start at the evaporator (Item 11,
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601202">Figure 2</hotlnk>), the refrigerant has taken on heat from the cab
                            and changed to low pressure vapor. Even though it has taken on great quantities of heat from
                            the cab, it is still only about 30&#176;F. The outside air will range anywhere from 60&#176;F
                            to 100&#176;F and the refrigerant must somehow be cooled before it can condense back into a
                            liquid.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601202" figsize="pg-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601202" filename="../figg16/G1601202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="472px" scalefitheight="432px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 2. Typical Air Conditioning System</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1>1. COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                                <callout1>2. PRESSURE SWITCHES, FAN DRIVES AND RADIATOR SHUTTERS</callout1>
                                <callout1>3. LOW PRESSURE SWITCH</callout1>
                                <callout1>4. CONDENSER</callout1>
                                <callout1>5. RADIATOR SHUTTER SOLENOID VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>6. SIGHT GLASS</callout1>
                                <callout1>7. FILTER-DEHYDRATOR</callout1>
                                <callout1>8. BLEND AIR DOOR AND AIR DUCTS</callout1>
                                <callout1>9. HEATER CORE</callout1>
                                <callout1>10. RELAYS (PRIOR TO 12/91)</callout1>
                                <callout1>11. EVAPORATOR</callout1>
                                <callout1>12. EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>13. HEATER WATER VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>14. HEATER HOSES</callout1>
                                <callout1>15. THERMOSTATIC TEMPERATURE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>16. HIGH PRESSURE SAFETY SWITCH (HFC-134A)</callout1>
                                <callout1>17. PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE (HFC-134A)</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                        <para>The answer to our problem is the compressor. It takes the refrigerant vapor and squeezes
                            it into a smaller space, concentrating the heat it contains. This makes the vapor hotter
                            without adding any heat. The refrigerant can now pass on to the condenser as a high pressure
                            vapor and pass heat off to the relatively colder outside air and condense back to a liquid.
                        </para>
                        <para>As the now liquid refrigerant leaves the condenser it flows to the receiver/dehydrator
                            which strains the refrigerant and removes any moisture. The liquid refrigerant is passed
                            from here to the expansion valve where it arrives at a high pressure, 100 to 250 psi. The
                            expansion valve has two jobs. It meters the amount of refrigerant passing to the evaporator
                            and lowers the pressure of the refrigerant so it can enter the evaporator at that ideal 30&#176;F
                            boiling point, take on heat from the cab and repeat the cycle.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>DESCRIPTION OF SYSTEM COMPONENTS</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
                        <para>The compressor is a two-cylinder, reciprocating unit with a magnetic clutch pulley drive.
                            It is mounted on the engine and belt-driven (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601203">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601203" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601203" filename="../figg16/G1601203.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="502px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 3. Refrigerant Compressor and Clutch</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1>1. REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                                <callout1>2. CLUTCH COMPRESSOR DRIVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>3. PORT CAPS (KEEP IN PLACE WHEN LINES ARE DISCONNECTED)</callout1>
                                <callout1>4. OIL FILL PLUG</callout1>
                                <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>6. LABEL</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                        <para>It receives evaporated refrigerant at a pressure of 12 to 50 psi and increases it to
                            120-300 psi depending on surrounding air temperature and compressor speed.
                        </para>
                        <para>Refer to AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH Service Manual Sections in GROUP 16 of the
                            CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for greater detail on these units.
                        </para>
                        <para>The label on the clutch side of the compressor (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601203">Figure 3</hotlnk>) will list type of refrigerant and oil used in
                            the system and the refrigerant charge quantity recommended by International.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2 id="hl1601201">
                        <title>REFRIGERANT OIL</title>
                        <para>The type of refrigerant oil used in HFC-134A charged systems has been changed to a
                            non-mineral base oil. The following information must be adhered to when servicing air
                            conditioning systems.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>The refrigerant oil used in R-12 charged air conditioning systems CANNOT be used
                                    in HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems. The oil used in HFC-134A charged air
                                    conditioning systems CANNOT be used in R-12 charged air conditioning systems.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                        <para>If you put the wrong oil in the system you are servicing, the system will function poorly
                            and the life of the compressor will be drastically reduced.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <caution>
                                <para>Keep spare HFC-134A refrigerant oil in a sealed container. The oil draws moisture
                                    and will become moisture contaminated if exposed to the atmosphere for any period of
                                    time.
                                </para>
                            </caution>
                        </specpara>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>DO NOT use oil approved for HFC-134A air conditioning systems to lubricate
                                    fittings and O-rings on R-12 or HFC-134A systems. The oil absorbs too much moisture
                                    which may corrode the fittings and make them difficult to disassemble. Use
                                    mineral-based oil (R-12 oil) to lubricate fittings and O-rings on both systems.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>SYSTEM HOSES</title>
                        <para>Hoses used with HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems are smaller in diameter than
                            hoses used on R-12 charged air conditioning systems. When servicing HFC-134A air
                            conditioning systems, use only replacement hoses approved for HFC-134A air conditioning
                            systems.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>CONDENSER</title>
                        <para>The air conditioning condenser (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601204">Figure 4</hotlnk>) is located at the front of the vehicle between
                            the engine radiator and the grille. The condenser receives high pressure, high temperature
                            refrigerant gas from the compressor.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601204" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601204" filename="../figg16/G1601204.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 4. Refrigerant Condenser</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <para>As the hot refrigerant gas flows through the condenser, it releases heat to the air
                            passing over the fins. The cooler, compressed refrigerant gas condenses to a liquid, then
                            flows through the receiver/dehydrator, expansion valve, evaporator and back to the
                            compressor suction port.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>RECEIVER/DEHYDRATOR</title>
                        <para>The receiver/dehydrator (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601205">Figure 5</hotlnk>) absorbs any moisture and filters any foreign
                            particles from the system refrigerant. The unit also serves as a reservoir for storing
                            liquid refrigerant, making it available as the system requires.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601205" figsize="pg-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601205" filename="../figg16/G1601205.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="392px" scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 5. Receiver/Dehydrator - Typical</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1>1. OUTLET PORT</callout1>
                                <callout1>2. SIGHT GLASS</callout1>
                                <callout1>3. SERVICE VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>4. INLET PORT</callout1>
                                <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE (HFC-134A) (SERVICE DRYERS ONLY)</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                        <para>System protection is provided by a direct-acting high pressure relief valve that will
                            discharge refrigerant into the atmosphere if the pressure exceeds the system limit. This is
                            not a fusible plug and does not expel the entire charge. Relief pressure ranges from 450 psi
                            to 600 psi depending on the particular system.
                        </para>
                        <para>The receiver-dryer used on HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems has different
                            desiccant material. On new vehicles, the pressure relief valve has been moved from the
                            receiver-dryer to the refrigerant compressor. Replacement receiver-dryers furnished by
                            International will have the pressure relief valve on the receiver-dryer. The receiver-dryer
                            used in production will be equipped with a service port.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>DO NOT use a receiver- dryer designed for use on an R-12 charged air conditioning
                                    system on an HFC-134A charged air conditioning system. The desiccant material will
                                    break down and plug the system. The receiver- dryer designed for use on an HFC-134A
                                    charged air conditioning system CAN be used on an R-12 charged air conditioning
                                    system. The receiver-dryer provided by International service parts will service both
                                    systems.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                        <para>The receiver/dehydrator is located on the discharge (high pressure) side of the system
                            between the condenser and expansion valve.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>EVAPORATOR CORE</title>
                        <para>The evaporator core is a radiator-like core (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601206">Figure 6</hotlnk>). The line from the expansion valve connects at
                            the bottom of the core. The suction line is connected at the top. Refrigerant is sprayed
                            into the evaporator as a low temperature, low pressure liquid. The refrigerant absorbs heat
                            through the plates and fins of the evaporator and becomes a gas. The now warm vapor is
                            pulled from the evaporator through the suction line by the compressor.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601206" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601206" filename="../figg16/G1601206.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 6. Evaporator Core</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>EXPANSION VALVE</title>
                        <para>The expansion valve (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601207">Figure 7</hotlnk>) is located between the receiver/dehydrator and
                            the evaporator, and regulates the flow of refrigerant entering the evaporator.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601207" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601207" filename="../figg16/G1601207.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 7. Expansion Valve</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1>1. EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                                <callout1>2. FEELER BULB</callout1>
                                <callout1>3. EQUALIZER LINE</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                        <para>Leaving the expansion valve, the refrigerant starts to expand, entering the evaporator as
                            a low pressure, low temperature liquid.
                        </para>
                        <para>Attached to the top of the expansion valve is a capillary tube with a feeler bulb which is
                            clamped to the outlet (suction) pipe of the evaporator. The sealed bulb and tube are filled
                            with gas that expands and contracts according to temperature surrounding the bulb. The
                            feeler bulb senses the temperature of refrigerant leaving the evaporator.
                        </para>
                        <para>A second capillary tube is attached under the valve diaphragm and is connected to the
                            evaporator outlet (suction) pipe. This is an equalizer line which senses suction pressure.
                            Together, they regulate the amount of refrigerant entering the evaporator.
                        </para>
                        <para>The expansion valve used on HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems is different than
                            the valve used on R-12 charged air conditioning systems. The capillary tube and sensing bulb
                            are filled with HFC-134A.
                        </para>
                        <specpara>
                            <important>
                                <para>DO NOT USE an expansion valve designed for use on an HFC-134A charged air
                                    conditioning system on an R-12 charged air conditioning system. DO NOT USE an
                                    expansion valve designed for use on an R-12 charged air conditioning system on an
                                    HFC-134A charged air conditioning system.
                                </para>
                            </important>
                        </specpara>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>THERMOSTATIC CONTROL SWITCH</title>
                        <para>The thermostatic control switch (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601208">Figure 8</hotlnk>) is a thermal device that controls an electrical
                            switch. A connected refrigerant-filled capillary tube is inserted in the fins and tubes of
                            the evaporator core. The capillary tube is attached to a bellows inside the thermostat,
                            which in turn closes a set of contacts at a pre-determined temperature. When the capillary
                            tube senses 45&#176;F (7&#176;C.), the thermostat closes sending current to the magnetic
                            clutch engaging the compressor. When the capillary tube senses 34&#176;F (2&#176;C.), the
                            thermostat switch opens, disengaging the magnetic clutch so the evaporator does not freeze
                            up and stop air flowing through it. Blend Air units in the 5000 and 9000 Series vehicles
                            have a manually adjustable thermostatic control switch. All other vehicles are automatic as
                            described above.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601208" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601208" filename="../figg16/G1601208.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 8. Thermostatic Control Switch</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>REFRIGERANT LOW PRESSURE SWITCH</title>
                        <para>A low pressure switch (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601209">Figure 9</hotlnk>) is used to protect the compressor. It is
                            located in the refrigerant return line and prevents compressor operation if the ambient
                            temperature is too low. The low pressure also prevents compressor operation if the
                            refrigerant level is too low. Low refrigerant also means low lubricant and can result in
                            compressor damage.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601209" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601209" filename="../figg16/G1601209.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="152px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 9. Refrigerant Low and High Pressure Switch</caption>
                        </figure>
                        <para>The switch is normally closed. When the system operates, normal system pressure holds the
                            switch open. If system low pressure (compressor suction) gets too low, the switch closes,
                            energizing a relay that opens the circuit to the compressor magnetic clutch and stops
                            operation of the compressor.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>HIGH PRESSURE SAFETY SWITCH</title>
                        <para>A high pressure safety switch has been added to HFC-134A air conditioning systems. The
                            high pressure switch will disengage the A/C clutch when abnormally high pressures (375 psi
                            &#177; 20 psi) are reached. Refer to the air conditioning service section for the vehicle
                            being serviced for the location of the switch.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>FAN DRIVE AND RADIATOR SHUTTER OVERRIDE SWITCHES</title>
                        <para>Vehicles with an engine cooling fan clutch have a fan drive switch located in the
                            refrigerant compressor service port (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601210">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601210" figsize="pg-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601210" filename="../figg16/G1601210.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="432px" scalefitheight="392px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 10. Fan Drive and Radiator Shutter Override Switches</caption>
                            <calloutgroup>
                                <callout1>1. FAN DRIVE OR SHUTTER OVERRIDE SWITCH</callout1>
                                <callout1>2. COMPRESSOR SERVICE PORTS</callout1>
                            </calloutgroup>
                        </figure>
                        <para>When the compressor discharge pressure exceeds the high pressure limit, this switch is
                            activated and the engine fan drive clutch engages to provide maximum air flow through the
                            condenser. The fan remains engaged until the compressor discharge pressure falls below the
                            low pressure limit (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601210">Figure 10</hotlnk>). There are several types of fan drives and
                            each has a specific switch and valve combination. For more detailed information, refer to
                            GROUP 12, ENGINE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                        </para>
                        <para>Vehicles equipped with radiator shutters have a pressure switch also located in the
                            refrigerant compressor discharge line. It is identical in appearance to the fan drive
                            switch, but is set to operate at different pressure levels.
                        </para>
                        <para>The radiator shutters are held open by spring pressure and are closed by an air cylinder
                            working against the spring(s). The switch operates a solenoid valve that shuts off the
                            compressed air to the cylinder and allows the spring(s) to open the shutters.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>FAN DRIVE AND RADIATOR SHUTTER SOLENOID VALVES</title>
                        <para>The fan clutches and radiator shutters are operated by compressed air. The air is
                            controlled by solenoid valves that are operated by the pressure switches. The valves are all
                            of the same construction (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601211">Figure 11</hotlnk>), but have different operating characteristics
                            depending on the system where they are installed.
                        </para>
                        <figure id="f1601211" figsize="col-wide">
                            <graphic id="g1601211" filename="../figg16/G1601211.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                     scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px" resolution="72"/>
                            <caption>Figure 11. Fan Drive and Radiator Shutter Solenoid Shutter Valves</caption>
                        </figure>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>VARIATIONS OF TRUCK MODELS</title>
                        <para>For a complete description of the components and their layout, refer to the service manual
                            section for the particular truck model being serviced.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
