<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WEST COAST MAGNUM MIRRORS AND AERO MIRRORS - WEST COAST
        MAGNUM SERVICE PROCEDURES - Mirror Head Installation To "C" Loop
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Mirror Head Installation To "C" Loop</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s16028_3.xml" xrefid="f1602802">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the mirror so the wire harness pigtail hangs down to mate with the "C" loop wire
                harness. Install a washer on the lower pivot rod, then insert the rod through the lower mounting
                bracket/diagonal brace. Install the lock washer and nut. Replace the gray plastic thread cap.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install a washer on the upper pivot rod.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Support the mirror head, position the upper pivot rod into the upper mounting
                bracket/diagonal brace and install a flat washer and lock nut. Tighten upper and lower locknuts to 84
                in-lbs. Replace the plastic cap on the pivot rod end.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use an appropriate tool to remove the strain relief from the lower plate on the new mirror
                head. Pull wires out of the new mirror head as far as possible. Wires in replacement mirror head should
                be stripped for splicing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Color match the new wires with the existing wires from the "C": loop. Splice each wire using
                the butt splices provided with the replacement mirror. Wrap all splices with electrical tape or heat
                shrink tubing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push wires into mirror head. Be sure splices are inside mirror head.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that mirror functions (heat, motor, light).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use an appropriate tool to install strain relief. Check mirror travel, manually or with
                control switch.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16028_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16028_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16028.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
