<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - WEST COAST MAGNUM MIRRORS AND AERO MIRRORS - AERO TUBULAR
        SERVICE PROCEDURES - MIRROR HEAD ASSEMBLY REBUILD
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>MIRROR HEAD ASSEMBLY REBUILD</title>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s16028_4.xml" xrefid="f1602803">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove mirror shell, then remove mirror head from "C" loop (see Steps 1 and 2 above).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove flat glass mirror, push the top of the glass in, tilting it to expose the locking
                lever access opening on the bottom lip of the glass bezel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Push the top of the glass in while reaching into the access opening and pushing the
                interface locking lever toward the outside edge of the mirror. This unlocks the glass. Remove the glass,
                disconnect the heater connectors on the reverse side.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the flat glass actuator/adjuster, remove (3) mounting screws, remove the unit with
                its wire harness (if applicable) from the head.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the convex mirror, slide finger tips behind the top of the mirror panel and pull
                out. Convex mirror will snap out of its mounting gimbal. Disconnect the heater connectors on the reverse
                side.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To remove the convex mirror mounting gimbal, remove (3) mounting screws and lift the unit
                from its mounting pedestals.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect heater wire harness from the mirror head.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To replace the convex mirror mounting gimbal, position it to its mounting pedestals and
                install (3) mounting screws.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To replace the convex glass, reconnect heater connectors on the reverse side, install (2)
                O-rings as shown in
                <hotlnk document="s16028_4.xml" xrefid="f1602803">Figure 3</hotlnk>, then lightly place and center the
                mirror on its gimbal mechanism. With equal pressure, snap the mirror onto its gimbal mechanism. Be sure
                the mirror has snapped into place and is secured to its gimbal mounting.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To replace the flat glass actuator/adjuster, push the wire harness connectors through the
                access hole in the mirror head, then position the unit by aligning the mounting holes. Install with (3)
                screws. Be sure the wire harness is fully extended on the reverse side of the head.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To replace flat glass, connect the heater connectors on the back of the mirror glass. Be
                sure the locking lever on the glass interface ring is all the way to the right, position the glass,
                align the interface ring on the glass back with the interface ring in the actuator/adjuster. With the
                interface rings aligned, rotate the locking lever to the left to lock the glass in place. Be sure the
                glass is locked onto the actuator/adjuster by indexing it up, down, right and left.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To install the mirror head to its C-loop, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16028_12.xml" xrefid="x1602802">Mirror Head Removal and Replacement</hotlnk>, Steps 6
                through 10.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check all mirror functions prior to placing vehicle in service.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16028_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16028.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
