<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT - FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FAULT DETECTION MANAGEMENT</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The testing method for troubleshooting the electrical systems covered in this manual is a basic
                    voltage test. An alternate method of checking for voltage drops within a given circuit may be a
                    quicker method of identifying an exact problem.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>This section describes the symptoms that may result from a failure in the temperature actuator motor
            circuits. A list of the possible causes of the circuit failure is also provided.
            <hotlnk xrefid="t1602533">Table 32</hotlnk>
            lists and describes the Diagnostic Trouble Codes associated with the temperature door motor circuits.
            <hotlnk xrefid="t1602534">Table 33</hotlnk>
            provides the troubleshooting procedures for isolating the cause of the failure.
        </para>
        <para>A fault in the temperature actuator circuits will be apparent when either the temperature door diagnostic
            trouble code is displayed, or the HVAC system air temperature cannot be adjusted. Problems in the
            temperature actuator motor circuits can be attributed to shorted or open circuits between the control head
            and the actuator motor, a fault in the control head, a fault in the ESC, or a fault in the motor. Refer to
            the
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1602565">TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUITS</hotlnk>
            diagram. A mechanical problem, such as a broken mechanism or physical blockage may also keep the temperature
            blend air door and motor from operating correctly.
        </para>
        <para>Anytime the temperature actuator motor is provided power but does not move to its selected position, due
            to an electrical or mechanical problem, the HVAC control head will sense the fault. The control head will
            communicate this fault condition to the ESC, and the ESC will then set the corresponding diagnostic trouble
            code.
        </para>
        <table id="t1602533" tblwidth="pg-wide" numbered="no" view="reveal">
            <title>HVAC Temperature Actuator Motor Circuit Diagnostic Trouble Codes</title>
            <tgroup cols="6">
                <colspec colname="1" colwidth="2.03in"/>
                <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.83in"/>
                <colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.73in"/>
                <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.87in"/>
                <colspec colname="6" colwidth="1.10in"/>
                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="2" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                <spanspec namest="3" nameend="6" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                <spanspec namest="4" nameend="6" spanname="S4T6"/>
                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6" align="center">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="bold">Diagnostic Codes</emph>
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN1" valign="bottom">
                            <para>613 14 1 2</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="4" spanname="SPAN2" valign="bottom">
                            <para>Hot/cold temp mix control fault</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                            <para>This diagnostic code is logged when the temperature actuator motor does not respond to
                                voltage from the HVAC control head. The code could be the result of any of the following
                                conditions:
                            </para>
                            <randlist type="bullet">
                                <item>
                                    <para>a short to ground in the circuits between the HVAC control head and the
                                        temperature actuator motor.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>an open circuit in the circuits between the HVAC control head and the
                                        temperature actuator motor.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>a defective temperature actuator motor</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>a defective HVAC control head</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>a defective ESC</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>a mechanical problem: blocked, binding, or broken temperature door. Refer to
                                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602549.xml" xrefid="t1602509">HEATER/AIR CONDITIONER
                                            TEMPERATURE MIX TROUBLESHOOTING
                                        </hotlnk>
                                        table
                                        <xref refid="t1602509"/>.
                                    </para>
                                </item>
                            </randlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
        <figure id="f1602565" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602565.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
            <caption>Figure 67. Temperature Actuator Motor Circuits-Always Refer to Circuit Diagram Book for Latest
                Circuit Information
            </caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>(1200) HVAC CONTROL CONNECTOR
                    <callout2>LOCATED BEHIND CONTROL HEAD</callout2>
                </callout1>
                <callout1>(1210) HVAC WIRE HARNESS CONNECTOR
                    <callout2>LOCATED ON HEATER HOUSING ASSEMBLY</callout2>
                </callout1>
                <callout1>TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CONNECTOR
                    <callout2>LOCATED AT TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR</callout2>
                </callout1>
                <callout1>(1600) ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER CONNECTOR
                    <callout2>LOCATED ON CAB SIDE OF ESC</callout2>
                </callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <table id="t1602534" tblwidth="pg-wide" numbered="no" view="reveal">
            <title>HVAC Temperature Actuator Motor Circuit Troubleshooting Chart</title>
            <tgroup cols="6">
                <colspec colname="1" colwidth="1.79in"/>
                <colspec colname="2" colwidth="0.92in"/>
                <colspec colname="3" colwidth="0.98in"/>
                <colspec colname="4" colwidth="0.89in"/>
                <colspec colname="5" colwidth="0.87in"/>
                <colspec colname="6" colwidth="1.26in"/>
                <spanspec namest="3" nameend="6" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                <spanspec namest="4" nameend="6" spanname="S4T6"/>
                <spanspec namest="1" nameend="6" spanname="S1T6"/>
                <spanspec namest="2" nameend="3" spanname="S2T3"/>
                <tbody>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="BOLD">HVAC Temperature Actuator Motor Circuit Troubleshooting</emph>
                            </para>
                            <para>Turn off ignition and disconnect connector from temperature actuator motor. Motor
                                remains mounted to blower housing.
                            </para>
                            <note>
                                <para>Always check connectors for damage and pushed-out terminals.</para>
                            </note>
                            <note>
                                <para>Whenever the door actuator motor is energized while disconnected (such as during
                                    testing), it must be recalibrated after it is reconnected. After reassembling the
                                    door and motor, and reconnecting the motor electrical connector, disconnect and
                                    reconnect the HVAC control head connector (1200). This will initiate the door
                                    position calibration procedure.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1" align="center">
                            <para>Test Points</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                            <para>Spec.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                            <para>Comments</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1">
                            <para>While observing the drive collar of the temperature actuator motor use a 9 Volt
                                battery and jumpers to apply 9 Volts dc to terminals A and B of the temperature actuator
                                motor. After noting the results, swap the jumpers to reverse the polarity of the voltage
                                at terminals A and B.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                            <para>The drive collar of the temperature actuator motor should rotate to one end of its
                                travel when voltage is first applied, and to the opposite end of its travel when the
                                voltage polarity is reversed.
                            </para>
                            <note>
                                <para>If the actuator motor is already at the end of its travel when voltage is first
                                    applied, it may be necessary to switch polarities twice to see rotation in both
                                    directions.
                                </para>
                            </note>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                            <para>If motor operates correctly, proceed to the next step.</para>
                            <para>If motor does not rotate through its entire range:</para>
                            <seqlist>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Remove jumpers.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Remove motor from blower housing.</para>
                                </item>
                                <item>
                                    <para>Reconnect 9 Volts dc to the motor and verify that the motor drive collar will
                                        rotate in both directions.
                                    </para>
                                    <seqlist>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>If motor still does not rotate, replace motor.</para>
                                        </item>
                                        <item>
                                            <para>If motor does rotate, repair mechanical failure or blockage in
                                                temperature door or blower housing. Refer to
                                                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602549.xml" xrefid="t1602509">HEATER/AIR
                                                    CONDITIONER TEMPERATURE MIX TROUBLESHOOTING
                                                </hotlnk>
                                                table
                                                <xref refid="t1602509"/>.
                                            </para>
                                        </item>
                                    </seqlist>
                                </item>
                            </seqlist>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1">
                            <para>Isolate circuits between HVAC control head and temperature actuator motor.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                            <para>Check for open circuits or circuits shorted to ground.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                            <para>If faulty circuits are found, repair the circuits.</para>
                            <para>If circuits check good, replace HVAC control head.</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colspan="6" spanname="S1T6">
                            <para>
                                <emph type="BOLD">HVAC Temperature Actuator Motor Troubleshooting Chart (Continued)
                                </emph>
                            </para>
                            <para>Check with HVAC control head connector (1200) reconnected, ESC connector (1600)
                                reconnected thru breakout box ZTSE4477, and ignition key ON.
                            </para>
                            <note>
                                <para>Always use breakout box to take measurements on ESC connectors.</para>
                            </note>
                            <note>
                                <para>Always check connectors for damage and pushed-out terminals.</para>
                            </note>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1">
                            <para>Test Points</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                            <para>Spec.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                            <para>Comments</para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                    <row>
                        <entry colname="1">
                            <para>connector (1600), cavity 8 to ground.</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="2" spanname="S2T3">
                            <para>Alternating voltage, pulse rate should be 2.5 sec high/2.5 sec low.</para>
                            <para>low &#60; 2 Vdc</para>
                            <para>high > 7 Vdc</para>
                        </entry>
                        <entry colspan="3" spanname="S4T6">
                            <para>If the alternating voltage, has a 3 second cycle (1.5 sec high/1.5 sec low), replace
                                HVAC control head.
                            </para>
                            <para>If alternating voltage, with a 5 second cycle (2.5 sec high/2.5 sec low) is present,
                                replace ESC.
                            </para>
                        </entry>
                    </row>
                </tbody>
            </tgroup>
        </table>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602564.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_82.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
