<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM (FULL CHARGE)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601207" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM (FULL CHARGE)</title>
        <para>In preparation for charging, the air conditioning system must be evacuated of all air and moisture and be
            completely leak free. Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s16012v_11.xml" xrefid="hl1601206">EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Manifold suction and discharge gauge hoses remain connected to compressor service ports from
                evacuating operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the charging station with the required amount of refrigerant. See specifications on
                truck being serviced for the required amount of refrigerant (follow charging station manufacturer's
                instruction).
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT OVERCHARGE THE SYSTEM.</emph>
                Excessively high head pressures during operation will result from overcharging. Make sure all valves on
                charging cylinder are closed after filling.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Due to the difference in density between R-12 and HFC-134A, the amount of HFC-134A refrigerant
                        required to charge a typical air conditioning system has been reduced. Be sure to check
                        specifications on the truck being serviced to prevent over-charging the system and damaging the
                        compressor.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect service hose (yellow) from center manifold fitting to bottom valve on the charging
                station.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open proper (see manufacturer's instructions) valve on the charging station.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the engines shut down, open manifold discharge gauge valve and fill the air
                conditioning system with refrigerant.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the air conditioning system is fully charged, close the manifold discharge valve and
                charging valve. Disconnect the hose from the charging valve.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform
                <hotlnk document="s16012v_4.xml" xrefid="hl1601204">SYSTEM PRESSURE CHECK</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After pressure test is completed, disconnect manifold gauge hoses from the compressor
                service ports. Replace the caps on both the suction and discharge service ports.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
