<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM
        (REFRIGERANT RECOVERY)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602528" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM (REFRIGERANT RECOVERY)</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602524.xml" xrefid="hl1602524">SERVICE WARNINGS
                        <xref refid="hl1602524"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with
                    refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <note>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>If the system is being discharged because a leak is suspected, the leak must be located before
                    discharging the system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602534.xml" xrefid="hl1602534">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602534"/>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1602541">Figure 43</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Empty the 'recovered oil' catch bottle on the recovery station. This will make it easier to
                determine the amount of oil recovered during the refrigerant recovery procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from both service ports.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station and hose fittings, verify that all valves are closed. The valves at
                the recovery station must be set to the CLOSED position. The valves at the quick-disconnect fittings
                must be set fully counter-clockwise (CCW).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1602541" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602541.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                     scalefitheight="592px"/>
            <caption>Figure 43. Equipment Hookup for Servicing the System</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. LOW PRESSURE HOSE (BLUE)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HIGH PRESSURE HOSE (RED)</callout1>
                <callout1>3. RECOVERY/RECYCLING/CHARGING STATION</callout1>
                <callout1>4. HIGH PRESSURE PORT (MODEL 8600 ONLY)</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the recovery station to the system as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Start with the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    low pressure hose, and connect it to the low pressure service port located on the
                    evaporator-to-accumulator line.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    hose to the high pressure service port located on the compressor-to-condenser line.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open (turn cw) the valves on the Metric SAE quick-disconnect fittings connected to the
                service ports on the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set both hand valves on the recovery station to the RECOVERY/VACUUM position.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>During the recovery process in the next step, refrigerant may become trapped in the accumulator.
                    Heating the accumulator with a heat gun will force the refrigerant out of the accumulator and assure
                    that all of the refrigerant is recovered from the system.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Never use an open flame torch to heat the accumulator. Heating the accumulator with an open flame
                    could result in equipment damage and/or bodily injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the recovery station main power switch on and press the RECOVER button. The recovery
                station will automatically shut off when the refrigerant in the system has been exhausted to the storage
                tank.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close the valves on the quick-disconnect fittings by turning them fully CCW; and set both
                valves on the recovery station to the CLOSED position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When recovering refrigerant by use of a recovery station, system oil is separated from the
                refrigerant during the recovery cycle. When the refrigerant recovery operation is complete, the recovery
                station will drain the oil into the station's calibrated catch bottle. The amount of oil recovered may
                be used to determine the amount of NEW oil that must be added back to the A/C system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602526.xml" xrefid="hl1602526">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>,
                <xref refid="hl1602526"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the
                <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                and
                <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                hoses from the service ports on the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Work may now begin on the air conditioning system.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_53.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602529.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
