<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - FIBERGLASS - PANEL BOND SEPARATION</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>PANEL BOND SEPARATION</title>
        <para>Panel separation is a fiberglass structural defect that occurs when the adhesive bond between panels
            fails. It can be caused by fatigue, abuse or improper assembly.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform the steps listed under
                <hotlnk document="s16003_HL1600301.xml" xrefid="hl1600301">PREPARATION PROCEDURE</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Separate fiberglass panels until the separation reaches the point where bonding is secure.
                Use wood block, screwdriver or putty knife, etc. to hold panels apart (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600339">Figure 39</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600339" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600339" filename="../figg16/g1600339.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Use Wood Block, Screwdriver or Putty Knife to Hold Panels Apart</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a coarse grinder or burr to clean old adhesive from between panels (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600340">Figure 40</hotlnk>). Use an air gun to remove dust from the bonding surfaces.
                Then, wipe the surfaces clean using an acetone solvent.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600340" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600340" filename="../figg16/g1600340.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Use Grinder or Burr to Clean Old Adhesive From Between Panels</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Obtain an epoxy adhesive repair kit and mix the adhesive following the instructions supplied
                with the kit (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600341">Figure 41</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600341" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600341" filename="../figg16/g1600341.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Mix Epoxy Adhesive</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before mixing and using adhesive, observe the supplier instructions for handling and disposing
                        of this material.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use an applicator or make a craft paper cone dispenser to spread adhesive on or between the
                panels (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600342">Figure 42</hotlnk>). Make sure the bond area is completely covered.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600342" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600342" filename="../figg16/g1600342.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 42. Spread Adhesive On or Between Panels</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press panels together and use clamps or weights to hold panels in place (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600343">Figure 43</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600343" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600343" filename="../figg16/g1600343.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Use Clamps or Weights to Hold Panels in Place</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a rag and acetone to remove any excess adhesive squeezed out. After adhesive has cured,
                it will be difficult to remove except by grinding or sanding.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Allow sufficient time for adhesive to cure before removing clamps or weights. Heat lamp or gun will speed
            up curing time.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Keep heat source at least 12 inches (305 mm) away from the repair area. Remove when repaired area
                    gets very warm, not hot
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
