<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - HVAC ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS OVERVIEW - Refrigerant Control and
        Diagnostic (RCD) System
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602568" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Refrigerant Control and Diagnostic (RCD) System</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Refrigerant Control and Diagnostic (RCD) system is the software used by the Electronic System
                Controller (ESC) to control the A/C compressor. The purposes of the RCD system are:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Verify that safe operating conditions exist before the compressor clutch is energized.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Keep the A/C system operating within its optimum range by controlling the cycling of the
                        refrigerant compressor.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Detect faults or abnormal conditions within the A/C system.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Protect the A/C compressor by deactivating the compressor when destructive conditions are
                        detected.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Generate diagnostic trouble codes that may be used to diagnose and isolate problems in the
                        system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>To do this the RCD system monitors seven input signals from the A/C system and its environment. When
                certain nondestructive conditions are detected, the RCD system will allow the A/C system to continue
                operating while it generates diagnostic trouble codes. If destructive conditions are detected, in
                addition to generating diagnostic trouble codes, the RCD system will protect the compressor by
                commanding the ESC to turn the compressor off, shutting down the A/C system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The RCD system is continually being improved and revised. If an invalid DTC has been set (see
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_18.xml" xrefid="t1602504">DIAGNOSTIC CHART 'A'</hotlnk>)
                        <xref refid="t1602504"/>, reflash (update) the ESC software to the latest revision.
                    </para>
                    <para>If no invalid DTC's have been set, do not reflash the ESC unnecessarily. If the ESC software
                        is suspected of being out of date, contact Technical Services at 1-800-336-4500 to determine if
                        reflashing the ESC is necessary.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The RCD software is used to control a microprocessor located in the ESC. The microprocessor cycles the
                A/C compressor clutch on and off by controlling a 10 Amp FET (also located in the ESC). The seven inputs
                used by that microprocessor are described in
                <hotlnk xrefid="t1602501">Table 21</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <table id="t1602501" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Inputs of the RCD System</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="2.02in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="4.66in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Inputsto The RCD System</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Descriptions of RCD System Inputs</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>A/C REQUEST</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The A/C REQUEST signal originates in the HVAC control head, and indicates that the
                                    operator has set the controls to a combination that requires operation of the A/C
                                    system. This condition occurs when any A/C or defrost position is selected AND the
                                    fan control is NOT set to OFF. In this condition, the control head provides a
                                    chassis ground on the A/C REQUEST line, which is monitored by the ESC.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>HVAC CONTROL HEAD DIAGNOSTICS</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The control head diagnostics signals are generated by the HVAC control head to
                                    indicate the current status of several control head related circuits. In addition to
                                    the 'normal' signal, there are five signals indicating various fault conditions. The
                                    ESC monitors the DIAGNOSTICS line. Some fault conditions cause the ESC to log a
                                    fault and disable the A/C system. Lesser faults cause the ESC to log a fault, but
                                    allow the A/C system to continue to operate.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>HIGH SIDE PRESSURE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The HIGH SIDE PRESSURE signal is an analog signal that originates at the pressure
                                    transducer in the condenser-to-evaporator A/C refrigerant line. The ESC provides the
                                    transducer with +5V and the Zero Volt Reference (ZVR). The output signal of the
                                    transducer reflects the pressure level in the high side of the A/C system, and is
                                    monitored by the ESC. The high side pressure information is used by the ESC to
                                    disable the A/C clutch if high side pressure is too high or too low for safe
                                    compressor operation. The pressure information is also used by the ESC to control an
                                    optional on-off cooling fan drive. The high side pressure input is similar in
                                    functionality to a high-pressure cut-off switch, a low-pressure cut-off switch, and
                                    a cooling fan switch on a conventional A/C system.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>EVAPORATOR INLET REFRIGERANT TEMPERATURE (INLET THERMISTOR)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The EVAPORATOR INLET REFRIGERANT TEMPERATURE input is actually a variable
                                    resistance that is monitored by a circuit in the ESC. The temperature of the
                                    refrigerant in the evaporator inlet A/C line, is measured by a thermistor with a
                                    negative temperature coefficient. As the refrigerant temperature increases, the
                                    thermistor resistance decreases. Under normal operating conditions, this temperature
                                    information is used by the ESC to determine when to cycle the A/C compressor clutch.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>EVAPORATOR OUTLET REFRIGERANT TEMPERATURE (OUTLET THERMISTOR)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The EVAPORATOR OUTLET REFRIGERANT TEMPERATURE input is actually a variable
                                    resistance that is monitored by a circuit in the ESC. The temperature of the
                                    refrigerant in the accumulator, located at the evaporator outlet, is measured by a
                                    thermistor with a negative temperature coefficient. As the refrigerant temperature
                                    increases, the thermistor resistance decreases. Under light heat load conditions,
                                    this temperature information is used by the ESC to cycle the A/C compressor clutch
                                    to prevent evaporator freeze-up. The ESC also uses this temperature information, in
                                    conjunction with the high side pressure information, to determine if the ambient
                                    temperature is too low for safe compressor operation.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>ENGINE RPM</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The ENGINE RPM information is received by the ESC as a J1939 Drivetrain data link
                                    message. The ENGINE RPM information is monitored by the ESC to establish one of the
                                    conditions required for activation of the A/C compressor clutch.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1">
                                <para>VEHICLE SPEED</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2">
                                <para>The VEHICLE SPEED information is received by the ESC as a J1939 Drivetrain data
                                    link message. The ESC uses the VEHICLE SPEED information, in conjunction with the
                                    high side pressure information, to determine if a fault should be logged for
                                    excessive high side pressure. This fault would cause the ESC to disable the A/C
                                    compressor clutch, preventing A/C system operation.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Normal A/C System Operation</title>
            <para>The A/C system is activated by energizing the A/C compressor clutch. One of the purposes of the RCD
                system is to verify that safe operating conditions exist before the compressor clutch is energized.
                <emph type="bold">ALL</emph>
                of the following conditions must exist before the RCD system (the ESC) will energize the compressor
                clutch by supplying 12V on the clutch line.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>A J1939 engine RPM signal (indicating an engine RPM of at least 300) must have been present at
                        the ESC for at least 8 seconds. Engine RPM signals that are temporarily lost must have been
                        returned for at least 8 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C REQUEST line from the A/C control head to the ESC must be &#60;0.8Vdc. This line is
                        pulled low by the control head when an A/C or defrost mode is selected, and the Blower Speed
                        Control is NOT set to OFF.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The signal from the high side pressure transducer must indicate a pressure value that is &#60;250
                        psi and >40 psi. A value of &#60;250 psi indicates that an 'excessive high pressure' condition
                        does not exists. The ESC also verifies that the pressure is >40 psi. This value is used in
                        conjunction with the temperature value indicated by the outlet thermistor (must be >33&#176;F)
                        to verify that the ambient temperature is high enough for safe compressor operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The value of the outlet thermistor must indicate a temperature of >33&#176;F. The ESC uses
                        this value, in conjunction with the pressure value indicated by the high side pressure
                        transducer (must be >40 psi) to verify that the ambient temperature is high enough for safe
                        compressor operation.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The value of the inlet thermistor must indicate a temperature of >43&#176;F,
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the A/C compressor clutch must have been off for
                        <emph type="underscr">></emph>8 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>There must be no
                        <emph type="bold">active</emph>
                        faults detected in the transducer or thermistor circuits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The HVAC control head DIAGNOSTIC signal must be present at the ESC input,
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        it must not indicate multiple faults.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C compressor clutch virtual fusing circuit in the ESC must not be faulted. The virtual
                        fuse circuit activates when the clutch draws more than 10 Amps, indicating a fault.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Once the A/C compressor is turned on and the system is operating normally, the evaporator inlet
                refrigerant temperature (inlet thermistor) is used to determine when to cycle the compressor off. Too
                low of an evaporator temperature will cause moisture condensed on the evaporator to turn to ice and
                block airflow through the evaporator (evaporator freeze-up). When evaporator inlet refrigerant
                temperature drops to 30&#176;F
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                the compressor has been on for
                <emph type="underscr">></emph>7 seconds, the A/C compressor clutch is de-energized (cycled off).
            </para>
            <para>After the compressor has been off for at least 8 seconds, the cycle will be repeated when the
                evaporator inlet refrigerant temperature again reaches 43&#176;F. Both conditions must exist before the
                compressor can be energized.
            </para>
            <para>Therefore, under light heat load conditions, the fastest cycle rate for the compressor is 15 seconds
                (8 seconds off and 7 seconds on). Under high heat load conditions, the compressor may remain energized
                continuously until the engine or the A/C system is shut off. This is because the evaporator inlet
                refrigerant temperature may not drop below 30&#176;F.
            </para>
            <para>Under some light heat load conditions, the evaporator outlet refrigerant temperature may be several
                degrees lower than the evaporator inlet refrigerant temperature. If the outlet refrigerant temperature
                drops below 24&#176;F,
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                at least 7 seconds have elapsed since the compressor was cycled on, the ESC will de-energize the A/C
                compressor clutch to help prevent evaporator freeze-up.
            </para>
            <para>On vehicles equipped with an on-off fan drive, the ESC will request the engine controller to switch on
                the engine fan when the pressure transducer indicates a pressure greater than 285 psi. This
                ESC-to-engine controller communication is sent over the drivetrain data link. The engine fan will be
                turned on for one minute intervals until the high side pressure drops below 185 psi. Therefore, once the
                pressure drops below 185 psi, the fan will remain on until one minute after it was last turned on. The
                fan will also turn on when an AC RQST signal is received and the following conditions exist: vehicle
                speed &#60; 10 mph, engine speed > 1200 rpm, high side pressure > 100 psi, and the inlet thermistor
                temperature >85&#176;F.
            </para>
            <para>The ESC will also de-energize the A/C compressor clutch if the pressure transducer indicates a high
                side pressure greater than 400 psi.
            </para>
            <para>In conclusion, the RCD system (ESC) will de-energize the A/C compressor clutch if/when ANY of the
                following conditions occur.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The J1939 engine RPM signal indicates that the engine has stopped
                        <emph type="bold">OR</emph>
                        the signal is lost.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The evaporator inlet refrigerant temperature is &#60;30&#176;F
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the A/C compressor clutch has been energized for at least 7 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The evaporator outlet refrigerant temperature is &#60;24&#176;F
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the A/C compressor clutch has been energized for at least 7 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The high side pressure transducer indicates a pressure >400 psi.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C REQUEST line from the A/C control head to the ESC is >4.0Vdc. This normally indicates
                        that an A/C or defrost mode is not selected, or the Blower Speed Control is set to OFF.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The ESC has detected an
                        <emph type="bold">active</emph>
                        fault in the transducer or thermistor circuits.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The HVAC control head DIAGNOSTIC signal is missing from the ESC input,
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the A/C compressor clutch has been energized for at least 7 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The HVAC control head DIAGNOSTIC signal is indicating multiple faults,
                        <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                        the A/C compressor clutch has been energized for at least 7 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The A/C compressor clutch virtual fusing circuit in the ESC has been activated. The virtual
                        fuse circuit activates when the clutch draws more than 10 Amps, indicating a fault.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Refrigerant Charge Diagnostics</title>
            <para>One purpose of the RCD system is to protect the A/C system by monitoring the system sensors and
                indicating when the refrigerant level is low before all cooling ability is lost. The RCD system enables
                the ESC to diagnose a refrigerant charge problem, and indicate the severity of the problem with three
                fault levels (marginal charge, low charge, and very low charge).
            </para>
            <para>When the A/C compressor is on, the temperature difference between the evaporator inlet refrigerant
                (inlet thermistor) and the evaporator outlet refrigerant (outlet thermistor) is used to help determine
                the condition of the system refrigerant charge. In addition to the temperature differential, the RCD
                system considers the heat load and time to calculate the charge level (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="t1602546">VALUES FOR REFRIGERANT CHARGE DIAGNOSTICS</hotlnk>). The following
                descriptions assume that the compressor is running and the cab temperature has stabilized.
            </para>
            <para>With a fully charged system the temperature difference between the evaporator inlet refrigerant (inlet
                thermistor) and the evaporator outlet refrigerant (outlet thermistor) is minimal (&#60; 18&#176;F at
                Extreme operating temperatures). Depending on the heat load, the evaporator inlet refrigerant
                temperature will be slightly lower or higher than the evaporator outlet refrigerant temperature.
            </para>
            <para>With an A/C system that is less than fully charged, the evaporator inlet refrigerant temperature will
                be much lower than the evaporator outlet refrigerant temperature. This is because there is an
                insufficient amount of refrigerant moving through the evaporator to absorb any more heat. The level of
                system charge is indicated by the magnitude of this temperature differential. The greater the
                temperature differential, the lower the charge level of the system.
            </para>
            <para>If the RCD system determines that the charge level is too low for safe compressor operation, the ESC
                will de-energize the A/C compressor clutch and set either a 'SERVICE NOW low charge' fault or a 'SERVICE
                NOW very low charge' fault. Under Extreme operating temperatures, the 'low charge' fault is indicated by
                a thermistor temperature differential of
                <emph type="underscr">></emph>35&#176;F, but &#60;50&#176;F, for a period > 30 minutes. Under Extreme
                operating temperatures, the 'very low charge' fault is indicated by a thermistor temperature
                differential of
                <emph type="underscr">></emph>50&#176;F, for a period > 15 minutes . In addition the ESC will command
                the EGC to turn on the CHECK AC warning indicator. The ESC will continue to inhibit A/C compressor
                operation until the problem is fixed and the fault is cleared.
            </para>
            <table id="t1602546" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Values for Refrigerant Charge Diagnostics</title>
                <tgroup cols="5">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.00*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col4" colwidth="0.42*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col5" colwidth="1.59*"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col3" nameend="col4" spanname="SPAN3"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col1" nameend="col5" spanname="SPAN2"/>
                    <spanspec namest="col3" nameend="col5" spanname="SPAN1"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry morerows="1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">OperatingCondition</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry morerows="1" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Averaged Value of Outlet Thermistor(X3)</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="3" spanname="SPAN1">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">Fault Detection Thresholds(Temperature Differential between Outlet
                                        Thermistor and Inlet Thermistor)
                                    </emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>-</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">dTLow Charge</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">dTVery Low Charge</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Extreme</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>>65&#176;F</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="underscr">></emph>35&#176;
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="underscr">></emph>50&#176;
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Normal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>55&#176; - 65&#176;F</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="underscr">></emph>20&#176;
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center"></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Cold</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>&#60;55&#176;F</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colspan="2" spanname="SPAN3" align="center">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="underscr">></emph>15&#176;
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center"></entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <note>
                                    <para>The temperature differences in the table above must be maintained for the
                                        following time periods, before a fault code will be set.
                                    </para>
                                </note>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>A low charge fault will be set if the temperature difference is in the low
                                            charge range for > 30 minutes.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>A very low charge fault will be set if the temperature difference is in
                                            the very low charge range for > 15 minutes.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <para>
                                    <emph type="bold">EXAMPLES</emph>
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry colspan="5" spanname="SPAN2">
                                <seqlist>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Low Charge Fault under Cold Operating Conditions (X3 = &#60;55&#176;F):
                                        </para>
                                        <para>dT
                                            <emph type="underscr">></emph>15&#176; for 30 minutes.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Very Low Charge Fault under Extreme Operating Conditions (X3 = >65&#176;F):</para>
                                        <para>dT
                                            <emph type="underscr">></emph>50&#176; for 15 minutes.
                                        </para>
                                    </item>
                                </seqlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>System Pressure Diagnostics</title>
            <para>Another purpose of the RCD system is to protect the A/C system from excessive pressure by monitoring
                the pressure transducer and other operating conditions. Under certain conditions the RCD system will
                cycle the A/C system off without commanding the ESC to set a fault. This allows temporary high pressure
                conditions to occur without disabling the A/C system. When high pressure conditions are determined to be
                unsafe for A/C compressor operation, the ESC will set an 'excessive pressure' fault, and will command
                the EGC to turn on the CHECK AC warning indicator. The ESC will inhibit A/C compressor operation until
                the problem is fixed and the fault is cleared.
            </para>
            <para>If the pressure transducer indicates a high side pressure greater than 400 psi, the RCD system will
                command the ESC to de-energize the A/C compressor. The RCD system then checks the vehicle speed by
                monitoring the J1939 drivetrain data link.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle speed is &#60;20 mph, the ESC will not set a fault. The ESC will prevent the compressor
                from turning on until the high side pressure drops to
                <emph type="underscr">&#60;</emph>250 psi
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                the compressor has been off for at least 8 seconds. If this cycle repeats a number of times, the ESC
                will disable the A/C compressor clutch for 5 minutes or until the vehicle speed exceeds 20 mph. If the
                vehicle speed remains below 20 mph, the ESC will permit this pattern (including the 5 minute rest
                periods) to continue without setting a fault.
            </para>
            <para>If the vehicle speed is
                <emph type="underscr">></emph>20 mph and the high side pressure reaches 400 psi on 60 successive clutch
                ON cycles, the ESC will set a 'SERVICE NOW excessive pressure' fault, and will command the EGC to turn
                on the CHECK AC warning indicator. The ESC will inhibit A/C compressor operation until the problem is
                fixed and the fault is cleared.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Transducer Diagnostics</title>
            <para>For diagnostic purposes, the RCD system analyzes the voltage value of the high side pressure
                transducer to determine if the transducer circuit is operating outside of its normal range. If the RCD
                system detects a voltage value at either extreme of the transducer's range, it assumes that a fault
                exists in the circuit. The ESC will command the EGC to turn on the CHECK AC warning indicator. In
                addition, the ESC will inhibit A/C compressor operation until the fault is no longer detected,
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                at least 8 seconds have elapsed since the A/C compressor clutch was de-energized.
            </para>
            <para>If the voltage value approaches 5 Vdc (indicating a pressure of
                <emph type="underscr">></emph>500 psi), the ESC will set a fault indicating that the high side pressure
                transducer is operating above the normal range.
            </para>
            <para>The ESC will also set a fault if the transducer voltage value drops to near 0 Vdc (indicating a
                pressure of 0 psi or the presence of a vacuum). The fault will indicate that the pressure transducer is
                operating below the normal range.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Shorted Thermistor Diagnostics</title>
            <para>For diagnostic purposes, the RCD system analyzes the resistance values of the inlet and outlet
                thermistors to determine if either thermistor circuit is open or shorted to ground (or zero volt
                reference). Because the RCD system does not detect the full range of resistance values it cannot
                directly detect an open or shorted circuit.
            </para>
            <para>If the RCD system reads a thermistor resistance value at the low end of its range it assumes that the
                thermistor circuit is shorted to ground, because this value (which corresponds to 240&#176;F) does not
                reflect a normal reading. The ESC will set a fault indicating that that particular thermistor is shorted
                to ground. The ESC will also command the EGC to turn on the CHECK AC warning indicator. In addition, the
                ESC will inhibit A/C compressor operation until the short is no longer detected,
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                at least 8 seconds have elapsed since the A/C compressor clutch was de-energized.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Open Thermistor Diagnostics</title>
            <para>If the RCD system reads a thermistor resistance value at the high end of its range it cannot assume
                that the thermistor circuit is open because this value (which corresponds to 0&#176;F) can also occur
                during normal operation. Therefore, to determine if a thermistor circuit is open, the RCD system must
                perform these additional checks.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The thermistor resistance values are checked while the A/C compressor is cycled OFF.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The high side pressure transducer value is checked to verify that the ambient temperature is
                        not excessively low. Its value must be greater than 20 psi.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The resistance values of the two thermistors are compared. If one indicates 0&#176;F and the
                        other one indicates
                        <emph type="underscr">></emph>30&#176;F, the thermistor circuit indicating 0&#176;F is
                        considered open.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>After making these additional checks, if the RCD system determines that a thermistor circuit is open,
                the ESC will set a fault indicating that that particular thermistor circuit is open. The ESC will also
                command the EGC to turn on the CHECK AC warning indicator. In addition, the ESC will inhibit A/C
                compressor operation until the open is no longer detected,
                <emph type="bold">AND</emph>
                at least 8 seconds have elapsed since the A/C compressor clutch was de-energized.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>OBSERVING THE RCD SIGNALS WITH THE EZ-TECH&#174; SERVICE TOOL</title>
            <para>The EZ-Tech electronic service tool, running diagnostic software allows the servicer to monitor the
                HVAC electrical signals that pass through the ESC. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16025_110.xml" xrefid="f1602589">Figure 93</hotlnk>,
                <xref refid="f1602589"/>. When used in conjunction with these procedures or the electrical
                troubleshooting manual, the EZ-Tech allows the servicer to isolate electrical faults efficiently. See
                the diagnostic software manual for details on using the software.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_62.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602560.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
