<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - MANIFOLD GAUGE SET
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>MANIFOLD GAUGE SET</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340701.xml" xrefid="hl160340701">SERVICE WARNINGS
                            <xref refid="hl160340701"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        . Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with
                        refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>The fittings on the service hoses for R-134a air conditioning systems are standard Metric SAE
                        quick-disconnect fittings that will work only on R-134a air conditioning systems service ports.
                    </para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>This information covering the manifold gauge set hookup is provided in case service equipment with an
                internal gauge set is not available.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603439">Figure 39</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from both service ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the Manifold Gauge Set, verify that all valves are closed.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603439" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603439.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 39. Typical Manifold Gauge Set Installation</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOW PRESSURE HOSE (BLUE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HIGH PRESSURE HOSE (RED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. SERVICE HOSE (YELLOW)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CONNECT TO SERVICE EQUIPMENT</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the Manifold Gauge Set to the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Start with the
                        <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                        manifold suction hose, and connect it to the low pressure service port located on the evaporator
                        outlet line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the
                        <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                        hose to the high pressure service port located on the compressor-to-condenser line.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the
                        <emph type="bold">yellow</emph>
                        hose on the center fitting of the Manifold Gauge Set following the instructions provided with
                        the service equipment being used.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>DO NOT OPEN the valves on the manifold gauge set, or the valves on the quick-disconnect
                        fittings, until instructed to do so in the procedures. The quick-disconnect fittings must be
                        connected to the service ports on the vehicle; and the yellow service hose must be connected to
                        the equipment required for each specific procedure being performed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Once the quick-disconnect fittings are attached to the service ports, turning the knob
                <emph type="bold">clockwise</emph>
                (CW) pushes an internal pin down
                <emph type="bold">to open</emph>
                the service port valve (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603440">Figure 40</hotlnk>). Turning the knob CCW raises the pin, closing the service
                port valve. Once closed the quick-disconnect fitting can be removed without venting refrigerant from the
                system.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603440" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603440.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="168px"/>
                <caption>Figure 40. Turning the Quick-Disconnect Fitting Knob Clockwise Lowers a Pin to Open the Valve
                    in the Service Port
                </caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the knobs on the quick-disconnect fittings, on the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    hoses, are set fully CCW.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the manifold gauge set valves, at the manifold, are set fully clockwise.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    (low pressure) and
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    (high pressure) hoses from the vehicle service ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that protective caps are installed on both vehicle service port fittings.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the
                    <emph type="bold">yellow</emph>
                    hose from the service equipment currently connected to it. Follow the instructions provided with
                    that service equipment.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340703.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340705.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
