<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Cab - Safety Belt System - Diagnosis and Testing</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="test" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Diagnosis and Testing</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Inspection and Verification</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify the customer's concern by operating the active restraint system to duplicate the
                    condition.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect to determine if any of the following mechanical or electrical concerns apply:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0120004">
                <title>Visual Inspection Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.16*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.84*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Mechanical</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Electrical</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Safety belt webbing integrity</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Safety belt buckle and tongue assembly</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Safety belt retractor</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Open fuse</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Bare, broken or disconnected wire</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Connector not tightly engaged</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Safety belt warning indicator lamp burned out or broken</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the inspection reveals an obvious concern(s) that can be readily identified, service
                    as required. With the exception of removing a twist from the safety belt webbing, do not attempt to
                    repair a component of the safety belt system; new components must be installed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the concern remains after the inspection, determine the symptom. GO to the Symptom
                    Chart.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To check the active restraint system for correct operation, carry out the appropriate
                    Functional Test(s).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <table id="t0120005" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>Symptom Chart</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="0.78*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.16*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.06*"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Condition</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Possible Sources</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry align="center">
                                <para>Action</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>The safety belt warning indicator lamp does not operate, the safety belt warning
                                    chime is OK
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Burned-out bulb.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Circuitry.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Instrument cluster.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <exhotlnk document="../S08/S08307.htm" bookname="S08307">Instrument Cluster in
                                        S08307</exhotlnk>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Neither the safety belt warning chime nor the safety belt warning indicator lamp
                                    operates
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Safety belt l switch.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Instrument cluster.</para>
                                    </item>
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Circuitry.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Refer to
                                    <exhotlnk document="../S08/S08307.htm" bookname="S08307">Instrument Cluster in
                                        S08307</exhotlnk>.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Excessive pressure on the occupant during normal wear, the webbing cannot be
                                    extracted, excessive slack in webbing does not retract
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <randlist type="bullet">
                                    <item>
                                        <para>Front safety belt retractor and tongue.</para>
                                    </item>
                                </randlist>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>CARRY out the component Functional Test in this section. INSTALL a new retractor
                                    if necessary.
                                </para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Component Tests</title>
            <para>Carry out the appropriate Functional Test(s) as determined in Inspection and Verification.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">Functional Test I (Buckle and Tongue)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The safety belt buckle and tongue assembly must operate freely during the latching and unlatching
                function. Fasten the safety belt by inserting the tongue (male portion) into the buckle (female
                portion).
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the following during the latching sequence:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Tongue insertion is not hindered by excessive effort.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>A "click" is heard when the buckle latches the tongue.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the system integrity by forcefully pulling on the belt webbing.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Unlatch the belt by fully depressing the buckle release button and allowing the belt to
                        release and retract.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the following during the unlatching process:</para>
                    <randlist type="bullet">
                        <item>
                            <para>Push-button depression does not require excessive effort.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Tongue can removed easily from the buckle.</para>
                        </item>
                        <item>
                            <para>Repeat the above steps 3 times.</para>
                        </item>
                    </randlist>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the inspection reveals an obvious concern(s) that can be readily identified, install a new
                        safety belt buckle or safety belt retractor assembly as required. Do not attempt to carry out
                        any repair on the buckle and tongue assembly. If a concern still exists with either component, a
                        new safety belt buckle and safety belt and retractor assembly must also be installed.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">Functional Test II (Retractor)</emph>
            </para>
            <para>The safety belt and retractor assembly must be freely operational for extraction and retraction of the
                safety belt webbing between full extension and in-vehicle stowed positions.
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Extract and retract the safety belt between the full extension and stowed positions.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Verify the retractor operates without excessive effort or binding.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Install a new safety belt buckle retractor and tongue assembly if no obvious concerns are
                        noticed and the complaint has been verified.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">Functional Test III (System Road Test Inspection)</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the RH or the rear safety belts are to be tested, a passenger must be used.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fasten the safety belts and proceed to a safe area.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Attain a speed of 8 km/h (5 mph).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The driver and passenger must be prepared to brace themselves if the retractor does not
                        lock.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test the safety belts.</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Grasp the shoulder harness and prepare to lean forward.</para>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>The maximum brake application should be on dry concrete or equivalent hard surface,
                                NEVER on wet pavement or gravel.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <specpara>
                        <warning>
                            <para>The driver and passenger must be prepared to brace themselves in the event the
                                retractor does not lock.
                            </para>
                        </warning>
                    </specpara>
                    <specpara>
                        <note>
                            <para>Do not jerk on the safety belt webbing when carrying out this test. Lean forward
                                slightly when the brake application is made.
                            </para>
                        </note>
                    </specpara>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Make a maximum brake application without a skid.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The safety belts should lock up with minimum webbing extension.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If there is a lockup of both shoulder straps, the safety belt assemblies are functioning
                    correctly. Should either or both retractors fail to lock up at the 8 km/h (5 mph) speed, repeat the
                    test at a constant 24 km/h (15 mph) speed. (This test must be carried out with a RH front or rear
                    passenger if the RH front or rear outboard safety belts are to be tested.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before installing a new safety belt assembly, inspect the mounting area for damage and
                        distortion. If the retractor of a new safety belt assembly has been bolted into a damaged or
                        distorted mounting area, the retractor could be warped and may not function. If this is the
                        case, remove the retractor, return the sheet metal to the original configuration and install
                        another complete safety belt assembly.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If either or both retractors do not lock up at the 24 km/h (15 mph) test, return the
                    vehicle for service of malfunctioning safety belts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <emph type="italic">Functional Test IV (Automatic Locking Retractor)</emph>
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>After any vehicle collision, the safety belt system at all outboard seating positions (except
                        driver, which has no "automatic locking retractor" feature) must be checked by a qualified
                        technician to verify that the "automatic locking" feature for child seats is still functioning
                        properly, in addition to other checks for proper safety belt system function. A safety belt and
                        retractor assembly must be replaced if the safety belt assembly's "automatic locking retractor"
                        feature or any other safety belt function is not operating properly when checked according to
                        the procedures in the workshop manual. Failure to replace the safety belt and retractor assembly
                        could increase the risk of injury in collisions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Position the seat back into the full up position.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Position the height adjuster (as equipped) in the full down or up position.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Latch the seat belt buckle and tongue assembly.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pull the shoulder belt out until the automatic locking retractor (ALR) feature is activated.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Release the shoulder belt and allow it to retract until it stops.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pull on the shoulder belt to check that the belt has remained in the ALR mode. If the belt is
                        not locked, install a new safety belt and retractor assembly.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Unlatch the safety belt tongue from the buckle and allow the safety belt to retract to its
                        stowed position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Pull the shoulder belt to verify the retractor assembly has converted automatically out of the
                        ALR mode. If the shoulder belt remains locked in the stowed position, install a new safety belt
                        and retractor assembly.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_29.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_31.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
