<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601910" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="2">
        <title>PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml" xrefid="hl1601912">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                        read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                        could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para id="hl1601927">Dry nitrogen gas is recommended for flushing and/or purging. Do not use
                        nitrogen at pressures over 1378 kPa (200 psi). Personal injury or death may result from doing
                        so. Commercial cylinders of dry nitrogen contain pressures in excess of 13780 kPa (2000 psi).
                        This pressure must be reduced, using a pressure regulator, to 1378 kPa (200 psi) for purging.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The A/C system can be flushed or purged only after the refrigerant has been discharged
                        (recovered).
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When flushing and/or purging components of the system use only dry nitrogen. The introduction
                        of compressed air into the A/C system may cause contamination of the system.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>When flushing components, use only flushing agents approved for R-134a charged air
                        conditioning systems (refer to the Fleetrite HVAC catalog for an approved flush solvent). R-11
                        and any other flushing agents that were used to flush R-12 charged air conditioning systems
                        <emph type="bold">CANNOT</emph>
                        be used to flush R-134a systems. The residue left by these flushing products will destroy the
                        lubrication properties of the oil used in R-134a systems.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A flush gun is required to inject the flushing agent into the component being flushed. Refer
                        to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601929.xml" xrefid="hl1601929">FLUSH GUN</hotlnk>
                        for complete information on this service equipment .
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Special adapters are required to connect the service equipment to some A/C system components.
                        Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601920.xml" xrefid="hl1601920">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                        for complete information on these service adapters . Standard fittings and adapters can be
                        purchased or fabricated locally. Quick disconnect fittings can reduce the time required to swap
                        hoses, adapters and components.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Systems that have had an internal compressor failure, that have been overcharged with refrigeration
                oil, or that have been left open for an extended period of time, will need to be flushed, purged or
                both. Normally, the system always has pressure in it. Some loss of refrigerant from one season to the
                next is normal, and does not mean that the system is dirty. Flushing is generally necessary only after
                an internal compressor failure has contaminated the refrigerant system. Flushing and purging are
                performed on a system after the refrigerant has been discharged (recovered) and before the system is
                reassembled and evacuated.
            </para>
            <para>Flushing removes heavy contamination, such as gritty oil and large dirt buildup, which occur after an
                internal compressor failure. When a part is flushed, a flushing solvent is forced through it; the liquid
                solvent cleans the part, picks up contaminants and flushes them out.
            </para>
            <para>Purging must always be performed: after flushing the system; any time there is excessive refrigerant
                oil found in the system; or, when the system has been left open for an extended period of time. Purging
                removes flushing solvent, excessive refrigerant oil, damp air, and loose particles from A/C system
                components by passing a stream of inert, dry nitrogen gas through parts of the system or individual
                components. This assures that A/C system components are dry and free of any contaminants. If left in the
                system, these contaminants would have a negative effect on the life and operation of the air
                conditioning system.
            </para>
            <para>The following procedures must be observed whenever a component or system is flushed or purged.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Never flush or purge the entire system. Flush or purge the system in segments (never larger
                        than one component and one hose) to lessen the chance of blowing contaminants throughout the
                        system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never flush or purge the compressor, receiver-dryer, or expansion valve.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Flush or purge each system section or component in the opposite direction of normal
                        refrigerant flow.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>After flushing or purging the system, change oil in the compressor (refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>) and
                        replace the receiver-dryer prior to evacuating and charging the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601958">Figure 43</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601959">Figure 44</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601958" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG16/G1601980.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 43. Typical Equipment Used for Flushing and Purging the A/C System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PRESSURIZED NITROGEN CYLINDER/CART/CONTROLS</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FLUSH GUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. DRAIN HOSE WITH COMPRESSION FITTING AND ADAPTERS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1601959" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figG16/G1601981.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 44. Typical Flushing and Purging Setup</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>A. NITROGEN IN</callout1>
                    <callout1>B. TO WASTE CONTAINER</callout1>
                    <callout1>1. FLUSH GUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TRIGGER TYPE AIR GUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EVAPORATOR CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DRAIN LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. CONDENSER (CCI COMPRESSOR SYSTEMS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. BLOCK FITTING ADAPTERS (SANDEN COMPRESSOR SYSTEMS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. CONDENSER (SANDEN COMPRESSOR SYSTEMS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. NITROGEN BOTTLE REGULATOR/GAUGES</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. NITROGEN BOTTLE CONTROL VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. NITROGEN BOTTLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. SUPPLY LINE VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following procedures for flushing and purging are general. The actual fittings and
                        adapters required for each procedure will vary according to the component or components being
                        connected.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flushing Procedure</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601959">Figure 44</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Assemblies to be flushed must be no larger than one component and one attached hose.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the system is discharged.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both ends of the component or components to be flushed, and tightly cap the
                    rest of the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the tank regulator (8) turned off (closed), open the main nitrogen tank valve (9),
                    and using the input gauge on the regulator, verify that enough pressure is available to perform the
                    flushing procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the input of the flush gun (1) to the output of the supply line from the
                    nitrogen tank. Some form of shutoff valve should be installed at the input of the flush gun.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or block fitting adapters (6), connect the drain line (4) to
                    the component to be flushed. Components are flushed in the opposite direction of normal refrigerant
                    flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or block fitting adapters (6), connect the flush gun output
                    to the component to be flushed. NOTE: A trigger type air gun (2) may also be used as the flush gun
                    output.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the outlet of the drain line into a suitable waste container.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the flush gun tank with an appropriate amount of flushing agent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the supply line air regulator (8) to 75 psi.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the supply line valve (11) at the output of the tank regulator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open the flush gun valve and allow the flushing solvent to flow through the
                    system until the drain line is clear; then, close the flush gun valve. If a trigger type air gun (2)
                    is being used on the flush gun output, release all pressure from the flush gun tank by pointing the
                    air gun into the waste container, and actuating the trigger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the supply line valve (11).</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>The flush gun MUST be removed from the equipment setup before performing the purge procedures.
                        The flush gun is not designed to be used at the pressures used for the purge procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the flushing equipment to the next component to be flushed; or, empty the flush
                    gun tank and
                    <emph type="bold">remove the flush gun</emph>
                    from the supply line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect drain hose and all fittings and adapters from the component.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Plug the inlet and outlet of the component until it can be purged.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>After flushing a component, that component must be purged before connecting it to the air
                        conditioning system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl1601919">PURGING PROCEDURE</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1601919">
            <title>Purging Procedure</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Dry nitrogen gas is recommended for purging. Do not use nitrogen at pressures over 1378 kPa
                        (200 psi). Personal injury or death may result from doing so. Commercial cylinders of dry
                        nitrogen contain pressures in excess of 13780 kPa (2000 psi). This pressure must be reduced,
                        using a pressure regulator, to 1378 kPa (200 psi) for purging.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Assemblies to be purged must be no larger than one component and one attached hose.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601959">Figure 44</hotlnk>
                for all Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that the system is discharged.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect both ends of the component to be purged and tightly cap the rest of the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the tank regulator (8) turned off (closed), open the main nitrogen tank valve (9),
                    and using the input gauge on the regulator, verify that enough pressure is available to perform the
                    purging procedure.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or block fitting adapters (6), connect the drain line (4) to
                    the component to be purged. Components are purged in the opposite direction of normal refrigerant
                    flow.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the correct fittings or block fitting adapters, connect the nitrogen supply line
                    output to the component to be purged. A trigger type air gun (2) may be hand-held for some
                    components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the outlet of the drain line into a suitable waste container.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the supply line air regulator (8) to 28 kPa (4 psi).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open the supply line valve (11) at the output of the tank regulator. If a trigger
                    type air gun is being used, actuate the trigger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Let the dry nitrogen flow at 28 kPa (4 psi) for one to two minutes, or until there is no
                    trace of refrigerant flushing agent or refrigerant oil flowing from the drain tube.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the pressure regulator (8), raise the pressure to 1378 kPa (200 psi) and let the
                    dry nitrogen flow for 25 to 30 seconds.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the pressure regulator for 0 psi; then, close the supply line valve (11).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If a trigger type air gun (2) is being used, release all pressure from the hose by
                    pointing the air gun into the waste container, and actuating the trigger.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the supply and drain lines from the part, and remove all fittings and
                    adapters (6). Tightly cap the openings of the part until you are ready to install it into the
                    system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When reconnecting components, always install new O-rings and C-plates on the systems equipped
                        with Sanden compressors with peanut fittings.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always lubricate O-rings and threads on fittings with mineral-based oil during installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The component is now ready to be installed into the air conditioning system using new
                    O-rings and/or C-plates.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After purging the system, and prior to evacuating and charging the system:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Change oil in the compressor. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dryer.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Reinstall (or replace) all other components that were removed for service.</para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_44.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
