<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - AC COMPRESSOR CIRCUITS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1602561">
        <title>AC COMPRESSOR CIRCUITS</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f1602555" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602555.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 55. AC Compressor Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AC COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER (ESC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HVAC CONTROL HEAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. REFRIGERANT SENSORS (INLET/OUTLET THERMISTORS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. REFRIGERANT PRESSURE TRANSDUCER</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ENGINE CONTROLLER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>When an air conditioning (or defrost) mode is selected on the HVAC control head, and the blower speed
                control is NOT set to OFF, the control head will send an AC Request signal to the Electrical System
                Controller (ESC). If the ESC senses that the system parameters are within operating limits, it turns on
                the AC compressor by providing it with power (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602555">AC COMPRESSOR FUNCTION DIAGRAM</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <para>The AC compressor is mounted on the engine and is belt-driven through an electromagnetic clutch which
                acts to engage (turn ON) or disengage (turn OFF) the compressor in response to the air conditioning
                system controls (HVAC control panel and ESC). When engaged, the clutch armature assembly is magnetically
                drawn to the pulley assembly on the compressor shaft, thereby engaging the clutch and allowing the drive
                belt to drive the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>The Refrigerant Control and Diagnostic (RCD) system is the software used by the ESC to monitor and
                control A/C system operation. The RCD system monitors the refrigerant sensors (transducer and
                thermistors) and other system parameters to determine if all parameters are within acceptable limits.
                This information allows the ESC to keep the A/C system operating within its optimum range by controlling
                the cycling of the AC compressor.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_67.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_69.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
