<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - FIBERGLASS - MATERIALS REQUIRED</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="5">
        <title>MATERIALS REQUIRED</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fiberglass Mat</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600302">Figure 2</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600302" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600302" filename="../figg16/g1600302.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Fiberglass Mat</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This blanket of randomly arranged fibers is the repair material you will use in all repairs requiring
                a backing patch. Its weight is measured in ounces per square foot. For most of your repairs, a 1-1/2 oz.
                mat is required.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fiberglass Cloth</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600303">Figure 3</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600303" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600303" filename="../figg16/g1600303.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 3. Fiberglass Cloth</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This material is made from continuous filament glass fibers that are commercially woven on regular
                textile machinery. Fiberglass cloth is used where the most strength and the least thickness is needed.
                Its weight is measured in ounces per square yard. A 10 oz. cloth is recommended for most repairs.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Resin</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600304">Figure 4</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600304" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600304" filename="../figg16/g1600304.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 4. Resin</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Resin is a liquid plastic that hardens when combined with another substance known as a catalyst or
                hardener. The resin used for most fiberglass repairs is polyester resin. Because it is inexpensive and
                has a short hardening (curing) time, it is used for repairs requiring the pre-forming of a backing patch
                and is available at your local body equipment/paint outlets.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Epoxy Adhesive</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600305">Figure 5</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600305" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600305" filename="../figg16/g1600305.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 5. Epoxy Adhesive</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>This is the bonding cement used to create a strong durable bond between the back side of repair area
                and the backing patch. It is also used for bonding reinforcement panels to the back side of an outer
                panel. It is available at your local body equipment/paint outlets.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Body Fillers</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600306">Figure 6</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600306" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600306" filename="../figg16/g1600306.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 6. Body Fillers</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Polyester body filler is used in most repair shops because it is easy to apply and shape to the
                contour of the surrounding piece. Machining of the body filler surface can be followed if necessary by
                an application of glazing putty to eliminate porosity and provide a smooth surface for painting. It is
                available from:
            </para>
            <para>EVERCOAT - "RAGE" Autobody Polyester Filler: Fiberglass-Evercoat Co., Inc., 6600 Cornell Road,
                Cincinnati, OH 45242
            </para>
            <para>SIKKENS - "POLYSOFT" Polyester Filler: Sikkens, AKZO Coating, Inc., 5555 Spalding Dr., Norcross, GA
                30092
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="underscr">SPOT PUTTY:</emph>Evercoat - Ever-Glaze Spot Putty, Sikkens - Kombi Putty
            </para>
            <para>As a matter of economy and to maintain the curing properties of the resin, store the resin in a sealed
                container within a cool, dry enclosure. This precaution will reduce aging caused by changing
                temperatures.
            </para>
            <para>Keep a record of each purchase of resin. In this way, you can always use the oldest stock first.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The shelf life of resin varies; therefore, they should be tested before using and discarded if
                        not up to specifications.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_HL1600301.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
