<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s16017x" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5241" date="05/09/1996">
        <title>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a)
        </title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/29/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/29/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/29/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>11/29/1992</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>1000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700
                    <daterange>
                        <startdate>01/01/1993</startdate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9800</truckmodel>
                <ucodegroup/>

                <ucode>16000</ucode>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <title>SERVICE TIPS</title>
                    <para>The majority of compressor parts are made up of aluminum alloys and care must be taken in
                        handling not to mar, nick or scratch. All machined surfaces must be free of nicks and burrs to
                        insure proper fit and gasket seating. When replacing parts and securing with bolts or capscrews,
                        the specified torque requirements found in the
                        <hotlnk document="s16017x_14.xml" xrefid="hl1601701">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                        should never be exceeded. Bolts should all be run in until the bolt heads make contact, then
                        tightened with a torque wrench in a sequence resulting in tightening of diagonally opposite
                        bolts until all are drawn up to specified torques.
                    </para>
                    <para>An important factor in compressor servicing is cleanliness and care should be exercised to
                        prevent dirt or foreign material from entering the compressor when it is opened. All old gaskets
                        should be removed and replaced. All gasket surfaces should be clean and all parts to be reused
                        should be washed in a suitable petroleum base solvent. Before assembly to the compressor, all
                        gaskets should be dipped in clean mineral oil.
                    </para>
                    <para>Gaskets are made of a neoprene composition fiber and wicking action will result as oil follows
                        the fiber. Do not mistake this wicking action for leaking. Wicking is a normal condition and is
                        to be expected.
                    </para>
                    <para>Do not use refrigerant oil to lubricate O-rings, gaskets or seals. Use only mineral oil to
                        lubricate these items.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
                    <para>The compressor is a two-cylinder reciprocating unit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601701">Figure 1</hotlnk>). It is belt driven through a magnetic clutch
                        located on the compressor crankshaft.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1601701" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1601701" filename="../figg16/g1601701.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Air Conditioner Compressor</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. CLUTCH COMPRESSOR DRIVE</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. PORT CAPS (KEEP IN PLACE WHEN LINES ARE DISCONNECTED)</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. OIL FILL PLUG</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE</callout1>
                            <callout1>6. TAG</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The functions of the compressor are to push the refrigerant through the air conditioning
                        system, and compress and superheat the heat-saturated refrigerant returned from the evaporator.
                    </para>
                    <para>The compressor crankcase, cylinder head, pistons, connecting rods, bearing housing, valve
                        plate and base plate are die cast aluminum. The crankshaft is cast iron as are the cylinder
                        liners, which are permanently cast into the crankcase.
                    </para>
                    <para>A splash lubrication system provides lubrication to the front and rear crankshaft bearings,
                        connecting rods and cylinder walls. The existing pressure differential between the suction
                        intake and the crankcase provides lubricating oil to the front shaft seal. An oil plug on each
                        side of the crankcase permits oil checking regardless of compressor mounting.
                    </para>
                    <para>With the introduction of R-134A refrigerant, the high pressure relief valve is moved from the
                        receiver-dryer to the compressor on production vehicles (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601701">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Replacement receiver-dryers will have a pressure
                        relief valve.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>MAGNETIC CLUTCH</title>
                    <para>The compressor magnetic clutch is secured to the compressor crankshaft (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601702">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The purpose of the clutch is to engage and
                        disengage the belt drive as necessary to maintain desired interior cab temperature.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1601702" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1601702" filename="../figg16/g1601702.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Magnetic Clutch</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. PULLEY ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. FIELD COIL</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The primary components of the clutch are: the pulley assembly, which contains the clutch disc
                        and bearing and is mounted on the crankshaft, and the stationary field coil, mounted on the
                        compressor housing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601702">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
