<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - BASIC
        PRINCIPLES - LATENT HEAT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="2">
        <title>LATENT HEAT</title>
        <para>Latent heat is the term applied to the heat required to cause a change of state of matter. This heat
            cannot be recorded on a thermometer, and it cannot be felt. A change of state occurs when a solid changes to
            a liquid or a liquid changes to a gas or vice versa. Water at 32 degrees F (0 degrees C) is called
            <emph type="bold">subcooled liquid</emph>. Water at 212 degrees F (100 degrees C) is called
            <emph type="bold">saturated liquid</emph>. That is, water at 212 degrees F (100 degrees C) contains all the
            heat it can hold and still remain a liquid. Additional heat will cause the water to vaporize (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601901">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f1601901" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1601901" filename="../figg16/G1601901a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 1. Water Vaporizing</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>To change water to steam requires heat. This heat is called the
            <emph type="bold">latent heat of vaporization</emph>. Remember this heat cannot be measured on a thermometer
            and does not cause a change in the temperature of the water.
        </para>
        <para>To change steam back into water, the steam must give up heat as it condenses into a liquid. The heat
            released in this process is called the latent heat of condensation (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601902">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f1601902" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1601902" filename="../figg16/G1601902a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Latent Heat of Condensation</caption>
        </figure>
        <para>Additional removal of heat will continue to lower the temperature of the water. This temperature decrease
            can be measured on a thermometer until 32 degrees F (0 degrees C) is reached. At 32 degrees F (0 degrees C),
            all the heat that can be removed from the water without causing a change of state is removed. The heat that
            must be removed to change the water from a liquid to a solid (ice) is called
            <emph type="bold">latent heat of fusion</emph>.
        </para>
        <para>This principle governing the addition and removal of heat energy is the basis for air conditioning. A
            refrigerant is selected for its ability to absorb and to give up large quantities of heat rapidly.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
