<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 5000i AND 9000i CONVENTIONAL - INSTALL - TWO PIECE ENCAPSULATED WINDSHIELD</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="11">
        <title>TWO PIECE ENCAPSULATED WINDSHIELD</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>There are two types of urethane adhesive that may be used to install encapsulated windshields on the
                vehicles covered in this service manual.
            </para>
            <para>It is recommended to use the two part U216 urethane adhesive that comes in the Essex&#174; windshield
                installation kit
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                . The use of this urethane adhesive allows for a 30 minute drive away time for the customer.
            </para>
            <para>An optional one part U400HV urethane adhesive may be used when installing encapsulated windshields,
                but the cure time is based on time, temperature and humidity and the cure table for U400HV urethane
                adhesive. This requires a much longer drive away time for the customer.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Two Piece Encapsulated Windshield using Two Part U216 Urethane Adhesive (adhesive A and
                curative B)
            </title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602104">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The 5000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                Series and 9000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                Series vehicles come standard with a one piece encapsulated windshield (Item 1). A two piece
                encapsulated windshield (Item 2) is available as an option.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>To install a two piece encapsulated windshield you will need to have the INTERNATIONAL&#174;
                        Bonded Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470. This kit has a tool box that includes the tools required to
                        remove and install bonded windshields. To order, call toll free in U. S. and Canada
                        1-800-520-2584 or Fax 1-800-578-7375.
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE</emph>
                        - The INTERNATIONAL&#174; Bonded Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470 is no longer available through the
                        INTERNATIONAL&#174; tool supplier. For materials that are available contact INTERNATIONAL&#174;
                        service parts.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>To install a two piece encapsulated windshield, you will also need the Essex&#174; windshield
                installation kit
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                . One Essex&#174; windshield installation kit will be needed for each half of the windshield if both
                halves are being replaced at the same time. The kit includes:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>U413 windshield fence primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U401 windshield glass prep</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U402 windshield glass primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U216 adhesive (two tubes, adhesive A and curative B)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Application mixing head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Applicator nozzle</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>These materials must be used on or before expiration date marked on container. U413 windshield Fence
                Primer, U401 windshield Glass Prep and U402 windshield Glass Primer have a 6 month shelf life. U216
                Urethane adhesive A and Curative B tubes have a 9 month shelf life.
            </para>
            <para>In addition to the items supplied in the Essex&#174; windshield installation kit
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                , you will need the following materials:
            </para>
            <para>In addition to the items supplied in the kit listed above, you will need the following materials:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Essex&#174; GC800 glass cleaner</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>White or brown paper towels</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Applicator nozzles from Essex&#174; to puncture U216 adhesive (two tubes, adhesive A and
                        curative B)
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For the windshield, use only laminated safety glass (AS-1 per ANSI Z26.1-Latest revision) and
                        International TMS-9522 (SAE J1203).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, wear protective work gloves when handling the windshield. Also wear
                        appropriate protective gloves when using any of the Betaseal system chemicals from the Essex&#174;
                        windshield installation kit.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never try to use any remaining U216 urethane adhesive left over after installing first
                        windshield half when installing both windshield halves at the same time. Due to the quick cure
                        time of U216 urethane adhesive, the adhesive will have started curing by the time you are ready
                        to apply it to the other windshield half. You must use a second Essex&#174; windshield
                        installation kit
                        <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                        when installing the second windshield half.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before installing new windshield, wipe off any water remaining around windshield fence and
                        surrounding cab area with a lint free cloth.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dry fit new windshield on vehicle to make sure the windshield fits windshield opening
                    properly before applying U216 adhesive. Once the windshield is positioned properly in the windshield
                    opening place a piece of tape as a reference mark across the center upper portion of windshield and
                    cab. Use a utility knife and cut the tape between the cab and windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove new windshield from vehicle and place it on a suitable padded work stand to
                    prepare it for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021124">Figure 124</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove urethane adhesive (Item 1) from windshield fence (Item 2) around windshield
                    opening with a gasket chisel (Item 3). A thin layer of old urethane adhesive of 2 to 3 mm thick
                    (Item 4) may be left on windshield fence. Try to keep a consistent thickness of old urethane
                    adhesive around the perimeter of the windshield fence.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021125">Figure 125</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean dirt and any water left from spraying around windshield during removal off
                    windshield fence (Item 1) with a brush or clean, lint free cloth (Item 2) before installing new
                    windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Take U413 windshield fence primer
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 1, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit. Shake U413 windshield fence primer (Item 1) for at
                    least one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021127">Figure 127</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U413 windshield fence primer (Item 1) with a clean dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    cover scratches and bare metal on windshield fence (Item 3). DO NOT apply U413 windshield fence
                    primer over old urethane adhesive left on windshield fence.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow U413 windshield fence primer to dry for 6 to 10 minutes minimum after
                    application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With new windshield on a padded stand and prepare windshield for installation as
                    follows:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a razor blade if necessary and plastic scrubbing pad, remove any windshield
                    encapsulation flash from bonding surface of new windshield. Clean new windshield thoroughly with
                    Essex&#174; glass cleaner GC800
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021144">(Figure 144)</hotlnk>. Dry thoroughly with paper towels. Make sure
                    windshield is completely clean and dry before proceeding.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021144" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 144. Cleaning Windshield for U401 Windshield Glass Prep, U402 Windshield Glass Primer
                    and U216 Adhesive Application
                </caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once new windshield has been cleaned, take U401 windshield glass prep
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 2, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit. Shake U401 windshield glass prep (Item 1) for at least
                    one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Read completely through step 11 below to ensure the correct application and removal of the
                        windshield glass prep U401.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021145">Figure 145</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U401 windshield glass prep (Item 1) with a clean, dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    bonding surface only on new windshield (Item 3). If applied to clear glass surface, glass will haze.
                    Immediately wipe windshield glass prep off by following eight to ten inches behind the applicator
                    with a white or brown paper towel. DO NOT use a cloth shop towel. After completing first application
                    of windshield glass prep, repeat windshield glass prep application and removal process. This is a
                    clear liquid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021145" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c1.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 145. Application of U401 Windshield Glass Prep to Windshield</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. U401 WINDSHIELD GLASS PREP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. APPLICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NEW WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once U401 windshield glass prep has been applied and wiped off new windshield, take U402
                    windshield glass primer
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 3, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit. Shake U402 windshield glass primer (Item 1) for at
                    least one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021146">Figure 146</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U402 windshield glass primer (Item 1) with a clean, dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    bonding surface on new windshield (Item 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021146" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c2.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 146. Application of U402 Windshield Glass Primer to Windshield</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. U402 WINDSHIELD GLASS PRIMER</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. APPLICATOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NEW WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow U402 windshield glass primer to dry to a tack free condition for 6 to 10 minutes
                    minimum after application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Once the windshield has been primed, ensure there is no contact with bonding surface as oil
                        from skin will affect bonding performance. If the windshield is not bonded properly the cab
                        strength and safety would be compromised. If contact with bonding surface has occurred, repeat
                        the cleaning process and reapply U402 windshield glass primer and allow it to dry for 6 to 10
                        minutes before applying U216 adhesive.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove Essex&#174; U216 adhesive (two tubes, adhesive A and curative B), application
                    mixing head and applicator nozzle
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Items 4 thru 7, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021131">Figure 131</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the pull tab or a screwdriver (Item 1) if pull tab not supplied, pry out bottom
                    cover (Item 2) from both adhesive A and curative B adhesive tubes (Item 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021132">Figure 132</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use one applicator nozzle (Item 1) supplied separately by Essex&#174; to puncture
                    adhesive A tube (Item 2). Use the other applicator nozzle (Item 1) supplied separately by Essex&#174;
                    to puncture curative B tube (Item 2). DO NOT use the same applicator nozzle to puncture both tubes;
                    this keeps from contaminating the other tube before installing application mixing head
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 6, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    . Be sure to push applicator nozzle all the way in to ensure adhesive tubes are fully opened.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once both adhesive A and curative B adhesive tubes (Item 2) have been prepared for use,
                    remove application mixing head
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 6, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021133">Figure 133</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install both adhesive A and curative B adhesive tubes (Item 1) on application mixing
                    head (Item 2).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021134">Figure 134</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once both adhesive A and curative B adhesive tubes (Item 1) are installed on application
                    mixing head (Item 2), remove applicator nozzle
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Item 7, Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                    from Essex&#174; windshield installation kit. Install applicator nozzle (Item 3) on application
                    mixing head (Item 2). Cut tab (Item 4) off applicator nozzle. Measure and mark a 3/8 inch wide by
                    5/8 inch long with a 1/8 inch wide dimension at the base of the new notch (Item 5) to replace the
                    current V-notch on the applicator nozzle. Use a utility knife and cut out new notch to allow for
                    proper adhesive application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021135">Figure 135</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before loading adhesive tubes with application mixing head and applicator nozzle (Item
                    1) into betagun (Item 2), pull trigger and run plungers (Item 3) all the way back to allow for
                    adhesive tubes to be loaded. Open front cover (Item 4) on betagun and install adhesive tubes with
                    application mixing head and applicator nozzle into betagun.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021136">Figure 136</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once adhesive tubes with application mixing head and applicator nozzle (Item 1) have
                    been installed into betagun (Item 2), close front cover (Item 3). Run plungers (Item 4) forward on
                    betagun until plungers are in position to apply adhesive. Stop when adhesive reaches applicator
                    nozzle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing both passenger and driver side windshields the passenger side windshield should
                        be installed first, then install driver side windshield. If passenger side windshield only is
                        being replaced, there is a tab which is part of the encapsulation rubber trim at the top of the
                        driver side windshield that must be flipped out from behind the passenger side windshield after
                        installation. This encapsulation rubber trim tab has a beveled edge that lays over and matches
                        the beveled edge of the encapsulation rubber trim on the passenger side windshield.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Application of adhesive bead shall be 0 to 2 mm from encapsulation edge and be at least 5/8 to
                        3/4 inch (15 to 20 mm) high and 3/8 to 1/2 inch (8 to 12 mm) wide maximum.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>If U216 two part adhesive runs out before getting all the way around the windshield, it is
                        acceptable to fill in the gap left (6 inches or less) with U400HV one part urethane adhesive
                        using a standard cocking gun. It is recommended that because of the short time frame in which to
                        install the windshield to have a tube of U400HV one part urethane adhesive loaded into a cocking
                        gun and ready to use so the time will not run out to get the windshield installed onto the
                        vehicle.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021147">Figure 147</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Holding betagun (Item 1) and applicator nozzle (Item 2) as close to a 90 degree angle as
                    possible and starting at the International logo on lower driver side corner, pull trigger to apply a
                    uniform bead of adhesive (Item 3) going across the bottom all the way around windshield. The harder
                    you pull the trigger the faster the adhesive will extrude. Use this variable speed control to slow
                    down as you apply adhesive around the corners. Overlap adhesive at the seam slightly, and use a
                    plastic or wood tongue depressor (Item 4) to smooth or even out adhesive as required before
                    installing windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021147" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 147. Using Betagun to Apply Adhesive</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BETAGUN</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. APPLICATOR NOZZLE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. ADHESIVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PLASTIC OR WOOD TONGUE DEPRESSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once adhesive has been applied on windshield it MUST be installed within 5 to 7 minutes
                    maximum. Adhesive starts curing immediately and will not provide an adequate bond if not installed
                    within the 5 to 7 minute time frame.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carry windshield to vehicle and install as follows, driver side windshield shown
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021148">(Figure 148)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021148" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c4.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 148. Installing Windshield</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021149">Figure 149</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle has a sun shade, position new windshield under sun shade being careful
                    not to touch windshield on cab. Align tape mark (Item 1) on windshield with tape mark on top of cab
                    (Item 2) and align windshield locator tabs (Item 3) on new windshield with cab locator darts (Item
                    4) at the bottom of windshield opening on cab, driver and passenger side windshield shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021149" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="408px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 149. Positioning Windshield Locator Tabs on Cab Locator Darts</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TAPE MARK ON WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TAPE MARK ON TOP OF CAB</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WINDSHIELD LOCATOR TAB</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAB LOCATOR DARTS</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">Figure 150</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On vehicles without a sun shade, align the piece of tape (Item 1) at the top of the
                    windshield with tape (Item 2) above windshield opening on the cab, then position windshield locator
                    tabs (Item 3) on cab locator darts (Item 4). While holding windshield locator tabs in place on cab
                    locator darts, push driver side windshield (Item 5) or passenger side windshield (Item 6) back
                    against windshield fence (Item 7). Check windshield encapsulation rubber trim (Item 8) to make sure
                    it is positioned properly around windshield opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021150" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="368px"/>
                <caption>Figure 150. Pushing Windshield into Place</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TAPE ON WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TAPE ON CAB</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WINDSHIELD LOCATOR TAB</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. CAB LOCATOR DARTS</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. DRIVER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PASSENGER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. WINDSHIELD FENCE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. WINDSHIELD ENCAPSULATION RUBBER TRIM</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. CENTER DIVIDER BAR TRIM STRIP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021151">Figure 151</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure gap (Item 1) for center divider bar trim strip
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">(Item 9, Figure 150)</hotlnk>
                    between driver side windshield (Item 2) and passenger side windshield (Item 3) is even and free of
                    any obstruction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021151" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c7.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 151. Center Divider Bar Gap between Driver and Passenger Side Windshields</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. GAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PASSENGER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once windshield is in correct position gently push on windshield all around outer edge
                    to set it properly against windshield fence
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021152">(Figure 152)</hotlnk>. There are tabs built into the windshield to keep
                    it from being pushed in too far, driver side windshield shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021152">Figure 152</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both pieces of tape (Items 1 and 2) from windshield and cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021152" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c8.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 152. Pushing Windshield Back Against Windshield Fence</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TAPE ON CAB</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TAPE ON WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021153">Figure 153</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing center divider bar trim strip
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">(Item 9, Figure 150)</hotlnk>
                    use betagun (Item 1) and apply a small bead of adhesive, about 1 inch in length (Item 2), at the top
                    and bottom of center divider bar trim strip gap (Item 3) between driver side windshield (Item 4) and
                    passenger side windshield (Item 5). Use a plastic or wood tongue depressor (Item 6) and smooth
                    adhesive in gap. This will insure that center divider bar trim strip will not slide up or down after
                    installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021153" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021c9.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 153. Center Divider Bar Gap between Driver and Passenger Side Windshields</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. BETAGUN (CAULKING GUN WHEN USING ONE PART U400HV URETHANE ADHESIVE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. BEAD OF ADHESIVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CENTER DIVIDER BAR TRIM STRIP GAP</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. DRIVER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PASSENGER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PLASTIC OR WOOD TONGUE DEPRESSOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021154">Figure 154</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Starting at the top, install center divider bar trim strip (Item 1). Using your fingers
                    push center divider bar trim strip between driver side windshield (Item 2) and passenger side
                    windshield (Item 3). Use a small plastic roller (Item 4) or soft rubber mallet to seat center
                    divider bar trim strip into gap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16021154" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16021d0.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                         scalefitheight="472px"/>
                <caption>Figure 154. Center Divider Bar Gap between Driver and Passenger Side Windshields</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CENTER DIVIDER BAR TRIM STRIP</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. DRIVER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PASSENGER SIDE WINDSHIELD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PLASTIC ROLLER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602105">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the unit is equipped with an exterior sun shade (Item 1) remove piece of tape (Item
                    2) from bottom side of each sun shade mounting bracket (Item 3) used to protect sun shade mounting
                    bracket paint while cutting out windshield. If sun shade was removed, reinstall sun shade. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_X16021111.xml" xrefid="x16021111">
                        <emph type="bold">SUN SHADE</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <emph type="bold">, Install Sun Shade for 5000</emph>
                    <emph type="boldital">i</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">or 9000</emph>
                    <emph type="boldital">i</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">Series</emph>
                    as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position both defroster duct cover panels
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 2, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    in place inside cab and install ten torx pan head screws
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 1, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602106">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position driver side A pillar trim panel (Item 2) in place inside cab and install four
                    torx self-drilling screws (Item 3). Reinstall four fastener covers (Item 1) on fasteners of A pillar
                    trim panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing passenger side A pillar (Item 5), install passenger side window demist
                    duct with rubber tube (Item 8) in place and install two torx self-drilling screws (Item 7) to secure
                    it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a blunt tip screwdriver to pry the side cab trim panel out slightly to position the
                    bottom of the passenger side A pillar trim panel (Item 5) in place behind it. Note that the bottom
                    torx self-drilling screw (Item 6) goes through the inner side cab trim panel and passenger side A
                    pillar trim panel. Position passenger side A pillar in place inside cab and install three torx
                    self-drilling screws (Item 6) securing it to the cab. Reinstall fastener covers (Item 4) on two
                    upper fasteners only on passenger side A pillar trim panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once both defroster duct cover panels
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 2, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    , driver side A pillar trim panel (Item 2) and passenger side A pillar trim panel (Item 5) have been
                    reinstalled inside the cab, turn the blower onto high speed to check that the defroster works
                    properly and to blow out any debris that may have fallen into the ducts while removing the
                    windshield. If any debris came out, wipe it away.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall windshield wiper arms and blades. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_X16021118.xml" xrefid="x16021118">
                        <emph type="bold">WINDSHIELD WIPER ARM AND BLADE ASSEMBLY</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <emph type="bold">, Install Windshield Wiper Arm and Blade Assembly</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test operation of windshield wipers and washer, then clean windshield and surrounding
                    area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and latch hood on both sides.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The quick curing time of U216 two part urethane adhesive allows the vehicle to be driven 30
                        minutes after completing windshield installation. If the vehicle is equipped with AIR BAGS, the
                        U216 two part urethane adhesive should be allowed to cure for 60 minutes before driving. Even if
                        U400HV one part urethane adhesive has to be used to fill in a gap of
                        <emph type="bold">6 inches or less</emph>
                        during the application of U216 two part urethane adhesive the cure time before the vehicle can
                        be driven will be the same as above.
                        <emph type="bold">If more than 6 inches of U400HV one part urethane adhesive is used</emph>, you
                        will need to use the area on the Form Bonded Windshield Replacement Report
                        <hotlnk document="s16021_130.xml" xrefid="f16021183">(Figure 183)</hotlnk>
                        to record Time, Temperature and Humidity and follow the cure table for U400HV.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Two Piece Encapsulated Windshield using One Part U400HV Urethane Adhesive</title>
            <para>Although it is recommended to use the two part U216 urethane adhesive that comes in the Essex&#174;
                windshield installation kit
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021123">(Figure 123)</hotlnk>
                . The optional one part U400HV urethane adhesive may be used when installing a two piece encapsulated
                windshield.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602104">Figure 4</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The 5000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                Series and 9000
                <emph type="italic">i</emph>
                Series vehicles come standard with a one piece encapsulated windshield (Item 1). A two piece
                encapsulated windshield (Item 2) is available as an option.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>To install a two piece encapsulated windshield you will need to have the INTERNATIONAL&#174;
                        Bonded Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470. This kit has a tool box that includes the tools required to
                        remove and install bonded windshields. To order, call toll free in U. S. and Canada
                        1-800-520-2584 or Fax 1-800-578-7375.
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE</emph>
                        - The INTERNATIONAL&#174; Bonded Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470 is no longer available through the
                        INTERNATIONAL&#174; tool supplier. For materials that are available contact INTERNATIONAL&#174;
                        service parts.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>To install a one piece encapsulated windshield, you will also need the following items.</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>U413 window fence primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U401 window glass prep</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U402 window glass primer</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>U400HV adhesive (one tube)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Standard caulking gun</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>These materials must be used on or before expiration date marked on container. U413 windshield Fence
                Primer, U401 windshield Glass Prep and U402 windshield Glass Primer have a 6 month shelf life. U400HV
                Urethane adhesive tube has a 9 month shelf life.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>When using U400HV one part urethane adhesive, you will need to use the area on the Form Bonded
                        Windshield Replacement Report
                        <hotlnk document="s16021_X16021210.xml" xrefid="f16021181">(Figure 181)</hotlnk>
                        to record Time, Temperature and Humidity and follow the cure table for U400HV. This is critical
                        to when the vehicle can be driven after completing the windshield installation.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>In addition to the items listed at the beginning of this section, you will need the following
                materials:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Essex&#174; GC800 glass cleaner</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>White or brown paper towels</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Applicator nozzles supplied by Essex&#174; to puncture UU400HV adhesive tube</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For the windshield, use only laminated safety glass (AS-1 per ANSI Z26.1-Latest revision) and
                        International TMS-9522 (SAE J1203).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, wear protective work gloves when handling the windshield. Also wear
                        appropriate protective gloves when using any of the Betaseal system chemicals from Essex&#174;.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before installing new windshield, wipe off any water remaining around windshield fence and
                        surrounding cab area with a lint free cloth.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Dry fit new windshield on vehicle to make sure the windshield fits windshield opening
                    properly before applying U400HV adhesive. Once the windshield is positioned properly in the
                    windshield opening, place a piece of tape as a reference mark across the center upper portion of
                    windshield and cab. Use a utility knife and cut the tape between the cab and windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove new windshield from vehicle and place it on a suitable padded work stand to
                    prepare it for installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021124">Figure 124</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove urethane adhesive (Item 1) from windshield fence (Item 2) around windshield
                    opening with a gasket chisel (Item 3). A thin layer of old urethane adhesive of 2 to 3 mm thick
                    (Item 4) may be left on windshield fence. Try to keep a consistent thickness of old urethane
                    adhesive around the perimeter of the windshield fence.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021125">Figure 125</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean dirt and any water left from spraying around windshield during removal, off
                    windshield fence (Item 1) with a brush or clean, lint free cloth (Item 2) before installing new
                    windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Take a bottle of U413 windshield fence primer from Essex&#174;. Shake U413 windshield
                    fence primer (Item 1) for at least one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021127">Figure 127</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U413 windshield fence primer (Item 1) with a clean, dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    cover scratches and bare metal on windshield fence (Item 3). DO NOT apply U413 windshield fence
                    primer over old urethane adhesive left on windshield fence.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow U413 windshield fence primer to dry for 6 to 10 minutes minimum after
                    application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With new windshield on a padded work stand, prepare windshield for installation as
                    follows:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a razor blade if necessary, and plastic scrubbing pad, remove any windshield
                    encapsulation flash from bonding surface of new windshield. Clean new windshield thoroughly with
                    Essex&#174; glass cleaner GC800
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021144">(Figure 144)</hotlnk>
                    . Dry thoroughly with paper towels. Make sure windshield is completely clean and dry before
                    proceeding.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the new windshield has been cleaned, take U401 windshield glass prep from Essex&#174;.
                    Shake U401 windshield glass prep (Item 1) for at least one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from
                    container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Read completely through Step 11 below to ensure the correct application and removal of the
                        glass prep U401.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021145">Figure 145</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U401 windshield glass prep (Item 1) with a clean, dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    bonding surface only on new windshield (Item 3). If applied to clear glass surface, glass will haze.
                    Immediately wipe windshield glass prep off by following eight to ten inches behind the applicator
                    with a white or brown paper towel. DO NOT use a cloth shop towel. After completing first application
                    of windshield glass prep, repeat windshield glass prep application and removal process. This is a
                    clear liquid.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021126">Figure 126</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once U401 windshield glass prep has been applied and wiped off new windshield, take U402
                    windshield glass primer from Essex&#174;. Shake U402 windshield glass primer (Item 1) for at least
                    one minute. Remove cover (Item 2) from container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021146">Figure 146</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply U402 windshield glass primer (Item 1) with a clean, dry applicator (Item 2) to
                    bonding surface on new windshield (Item 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow U402 windshield glass primer to dry to a tack free condition for 6 to 10 minutes
                    minimum after application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Once the windshield has been primed, ensure there is no contact with bonding surface as oil
                        from skin will affect bonding performance. If the windshield is not bonded properly the cab
                        strength and safety would be compromised. If contact with bonding surface has occurred, repeat
                        the cleaning process and reapply U402 windshield glass primer and allow it to dry for 6 to 10
                        minutes before applying U400HV adhesive.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021131">Figure 131</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using the pull tab or a screwdriver (Item 1), if pull tab not supplied, pry out bottom
                    cover (Item 2) from U400HV urethane adhesive tube (Item 3).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021132">Figure 132</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use applicator nozzle (Item 1) supplied by Essex&#174; to puncture U400HV urethane
                    adhesive tube (Item 2). Be sure to push applicator nozzle all the way in to ensure urethane adhesive
                    tube is fully opened. Wipe off any adhesive from applicator nozzle before it can dry.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021142">Figure 142</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the U400HV urethane adhesive tube (Item 1) has been punctured. Install applicator
                    nozzle (Item 2) on the U400HV urethane adhesive tube. Cut tab (Item 3) off applicator nozzle.
                    Measure and mark a 3/8 inch wide by 5/8 inch long with a 1/8 inch wide dimension at the base of the
                    new notch (Item 4) to replace the current V-notch on the applicator nozzle. Use a utility knife and
                    cut out new notch to allow for proper adhesive application.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Load U400HV one part urethane adhesive into a standard caulking gun.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A battery powered or electric powered betagun is available from Essex&#174; for easier
                        application of the U400HV urethane adhesive onto the windshield.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing both passenger and driver side windshields the passenger side windshield should
                        be installed first, then install driver side windshield. If passenger side windshield only is
                        being replaced, there is a tab which is part of the encapsulation rubber trim at the top of the
                        driver side windshield that must be flipped out from behind the passenger side windshield after
                        installation. This encapsulation rubber trim tab has a beveled edge that lays over and matches
                        the beveled edge of the encapsulation rubber trim on the passenger side windshield.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Application of adhesive bead on new windshield shall be 0 to 2 mm from encapsulation edge and
                        be at least 5/8 to 3/4 inch (15 to 20 mm) high and 3/8 to 1/2 inch (8 to 12 mm) wide maximum.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021143">Figure 143</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold caulking gun (Item 1) with applicator nozzle (Item 2) as close to a 90 degree angle
                    as possible and start at the outer edge of locating tab on bottom edge of windshield at either
                    driver or passenger side. Going toward the corner, apply a uniform bead of adhesive (Item 3) all the
                    way around windshield. Overlap adhesive at the seam slightly, and use a plastic or wood tongue
                    depressor (Item 4) to smooth or even out adhesive as required before installing windshield.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once adhesive has been applied on windshield. Carry windshield to vehicle and install as
                    follows, driver side windshield shown
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021148">(Figure 148)</hotlnk>
                    as follows:
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021149">Figure 149</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the vehicle has a sun shade
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml" xrefid="f16021139">(Item 1, Figure 139)</hotlnk>
                    , position new windshield under sun shade being careful not to touch windshield on cab. Align tape
                    mark (Item 1) on windshield with tape mark on top of cab (Item 2) and align windshield locator tabs
                    (Item 3) on new windshield with cab locator darts (Item 4) at the bottom of windshield opening on
                    cab, driver and passenger side windshield shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">Figure 150</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On vehicles without a sun shade, align the piece of tape (Item 1) at the top of the
                    windshield with tape (Item 2) above windshield opening on the cab, then position windshield locator
                    tabs (Item 3) on cab locator darts (Item 4). While holding windshield locator tabs in place on cab
                    locator darts, push driver side windshield (Item 5) or passenger side windshield (Item 6) back
                    against windshield fence (Item 7). Check windshield encapsulation rubber trim (Item 8) to make sure
                    it is positioned properly around windshield opening.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021151">Figure 151</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make sure gap (Item 1) for center divider bar trim strip
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">(Item 9, Figure 150)</hotlnk>
                    between driver side windshield (Item 2) and passenger side windshield (Item 3) is even and free of
                    any obstruction.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once windshield is in correct position gently push on windshield all around outer edge
                    to set it properly against windshield fence
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021152">(Figure 152)</hotlnk>
                    . There are tabs built into the windshield to keep it from being pushed in too far, driver side
                    windshield shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021152">Figure 152</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove both pieces of tape (Items 1 and 2) from windshield and cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021153">Figure 153</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing center divider bar trim strip
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f16021150">(Item 9, Figure 150)</hotlnk>
                    use caulking gun (Item 1) and apply a small bead of adhesive, about 1 inch in length (Item 2), at
                    the top and bottom of center divider bar trim strip gap (Item 3) between driver side windshield
                    (Item 4) and passenger side windshield (Item 5). Use a plastic or wood tongue depressor (Item 6) and
                    smooth adhesive in gap. This will insure that center divider bar trim strip will not slide up or
                    down after installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16021154">Figure 154</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Starting at the top, install center divider bar trim strip (Item 1). Using your fingers
                    push center divider bar trim strip between driver side windshield (Item 2) and passenger side
                    windshield (Item 3). Use a small plastic roller (Item 4) or soft rubber mallet to seat center
                    divider bar trim strip into gap.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602105">Figure 5</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If the unit is equipped with an exterior sun shade (Item 1) remove piece of tape (Item
                    2) from bottom side of each sun shade mounting bracket (Item 3) used to protect sun shade mounting
                    bracket paint while cutting out windshield. If sun shade was removed, reinstall sun shade. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_X16021111.xml" xrefid="x16021111">
                        <emph type="bold">SUN SHADE</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <emph type="bold">, Install Sun Shade for 5000</emph>
                    <emph type="boldital">i</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">or 9000</emph>
                    <emph type="boldital">i</emph>
                    <emph type="bold">Series</emph>
                    as required.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position both defroster duct cover panels
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 2, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    in place inside cab and install ten torx pan head screws
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 1, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602106">Figure 6</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position driver side A pillar trim panel (Item 2) in place inside cab and install four
                    torx self-drilling screws (Item 3). Reinstall four fastener covers (Item 1) on fasteners of A pillar
                    trim panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before installing passenger side A pillar (Item 5), install passenger side window demist
                    duct with rubber tube (Item 8) in place and install two torx self-drilling screws (Item 7) to secure
                    it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a blunt tip screwdriver to pry the side cab trim panel out slightly to position the
                    bottom of the passenger side A pillar trim panel (Item 5) in place behind it. Note that the bottom
                    torx self-drilling screw (Item 6) goes through the inner side cab trim panel and passenger side A
                    pillar trim panel. Position passenger side A pillar in place inside cab and install three torx
                    self-drilling screws (Item 6) securing it to the cab. Reinstall fastener covers (Item 4) on two
                    upper fasteners only on passenger side A pillar trim panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once both defroster duct cover panels
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_12.xml" xrefid="f1602107">(Item 2, Figure 7)</hotlnk>
                    , driver side A pillar trim panel (Item 2) and passenger side A pillar trim panel (Item 5) have been
                    reinstalled inside the cab, turn the blower onto high speed to check that the defroster works
                    properly and to blow out any debris that may have fallen into the ducts while removing the
                    windshield. If any debris came out, wipe it away.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall windshield wiper arms and blades. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16021_X16021118.xml" xrefid="x16021118">
                        <emph type="bold">WINDSHIELD WIPER ARM AND BLADE ASSEMBLY</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <emph type="bold">, Install Windshield Wiper Arm and Blade Assembly</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test operation of windshield wipers and washer, then clean windshield and surrounding
                    area.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close hood and latch hood on both sides.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>
                        <emph type="bold">To allow for the correct curing time of U400HV one part urethane
                            adhesive</emph>, you will need to use the area on the Form Bonded Windshield Replacement
                        Report
                        <hotlnk document="s16021_130.xml" xrefid="f16021183">(Figure 183)</hotlnk>
                        to record Time, Temperature and Humidity and follow the cure table for U400HV.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16021_61.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16021_63.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16021.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
