<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 4100, 4200, 4300 AND 4400 MODELS - INSTALL - CAB DOOR LOCK CYLINDER</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1602629" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAB DOOR LOCK CYLINDER</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Cab Door Lock Cylinder on Front Cab Door on Standard Cab, Extended Cab and Crew Cab Models
                and Rear Cab Doors on Crew Cab Models
            </title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602609.xml" xrefid="f1602678">Figure 78</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1602678"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The cab door lock cylinder (Item 7) on the front doors on standard cab, extended cab and crew cab
                models and rear cab doors on crew cab models are key coded the same as the ignition switch on instrument
                panel, so that one key operates both the ignition switch and door locks.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position cab door lock cylinder (Item 7) back in the cavity of the outer cab door handle
                    (Item 6), make sure cab door lock cylinder is positioned properly. Install retaining clip (Item 5)
                    securing it in outer cab door handle , driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the cab door lock cylinder (Item 7) has been secured in the outer cab door handle
                    (Item 6). Make sure the cab door lock cylinder is working properly before proceeding.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>A new outer cab door handle trim bezel (Item 3) will need to be installed if the plastic tabs
                        securing it to the cab door, broke off during removal.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position four plastic tabs of the outer cab door handle trim bezel (Item 3) into
                    mounting holes in the outer cab door handle (Item 6) and carefully push it in place to secure it ,
                    driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side cab door lock cylinder into front or rear cab
                    doors.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_78.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263_X1602630.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160263.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
