<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 2000, 4000, AND 8000 - Before 12/06/1994 - SERVICE HINTS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE HINTS</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note cable routings during removal. Where necessary, cables should make sweeping curves.
                Sharp bends tend to increase resistance to bowden wire movement and sometimes cause kinks, which render
                the cable inoperative.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is most important that all refrigerant hose, O-rings, and tubing fittings be lubricated
                with MINERAL-BASED refrigerant oil and tightened as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s16014_37.xml" xrefid="hl1601401">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. Always use a back-up wrench
                when loosening or tightening fittings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>DO NOT use oil approved for HFC-134A air conditioning systems to lubricate fittings and
                        O-rings on R-12 or HFC-134A systems. The oil absorbs too much moisture which may corrode the
                        fittings and make them difficult to disassemble. Use mineral-based oil (R-12 oil) to lubricate
                        fittings and O-rings on both types of systems.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dehydrator unit on any system which is opened for more than a very
                short period, when the system is flushed, and/or when the compressor is replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be certain that the evaporator core temperature control sensing capillary tube is properly
                inserted into the evaporator core.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The expansion valve refrigerant temperature sensing tube must be securely attached to the
                evaporator refrigerant outlet tube. Also, the temperature sensing bulb and expansion valve must be
                tightly wrapped with insulating tape to prevent the ambient temperature from affecting correct sensing
                of the temperature or the refrigerant leaving the evaporator.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                original positions.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed as described in GROUP 16 - AIR CONDITIONING
                BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual any time the compressor
                is replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The compressor oil level must be checked and replaced as specified in GROUP 16 in the
                CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
            </para>
            <para>The type of refrigerant oil used in HFC-134A charged systems has been changed to a non-mineral base
                oil. The following information must be adhered to when servicing air conditioning systems.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The refrigerant oil used in R-12 charged air conditioning systems CANNOT be used in HFC-134A
                        charged air conditioning systems. The oil used in HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems
                        CANNOT be used in R-12 charged air conditioning systems.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>If you put the wrong oil in the system you are servicing, the system will function poorly and the life
                of the compressor will be drastically reduced.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Keep spare HFC-134A refrigerant oil in a sealed container. The oil draws moisture and will
                        become moisture contaminated if exposed to the atmosphere for any period of time.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing openings should be immediately covered or plugged during
                removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other foreign
                material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried in the system to the right place.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014_HL1601404.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16014.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
