<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - SIKKENS TECHNICAL DATA SHEETS -
        WASHPRIMER EM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1600206" svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>WASHPRIMER EM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Technical Data Sheet</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>Two-part self etching and passivating primer for cars, trucks and fleets. It offers excellent
                protection against corrosion to bare metal, eliminating the need for metal conditioning, provided a
                minimum film thickness of 1 mil is applied.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Product &#38; Additives: Main Product &#38; Hardener</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM; Washhardener</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Application: Suitable Surfaces</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM can be applied directly over:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Degreased and sanded existing finishes, with the exception of thermoplastic acrylic
                        lacquers.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Steel, aluminum and galvanized steel.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Fiberglass</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Sikkens Polykit&#174;, Sikkens Polystop&#8482; LP, Sikkens Kombi Putty, Sikkens
                        Polysurfacer.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Surface Preparation</title>
            <para>Degrease and sand steel, remove any mild by sandblasting if necessary. Then final sand with #80 - #120
                grit paper dry.
            </para>
            <para>Degrease aluminum and sand with #150 - #180 grit dry or scuff with a red scuffing pad.</para>
            <para>Degrease galvanized steel and sand with #1 - #180 grit dry.</para>
            <para>Degrease fiberglass and sand with #150 - #240 grit dry.</para>
            <para>Wet sand Sikkens Kombi Putty with #400 - #500 grit.</para>
            <para>Dry sand Sikkens Polykit, Polystop LP, Polysoft, or Sikkens Polysurfacer. Final sand with #240 - #280
                grit dry.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mixing Ratio</title>
            <para>1 part by volume of Washprimer EM with 1 part by volume of Washhardener.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Spraying Viscosity</title>
            <para>The proper spraying viscosity is achieved by using the recommended mixing ratio. 19-20 sec ZAHN cup
                #2(17-18 sec DIN #4) at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C).
            </para>
            <para>Contains Polyvinyl Resins. When mixed, contains Phosphoric Acid.</para>
            <para>Mixing Ration is 100:100, Autobase Metallic, Sikkens 1.2.3 Reducer</para>
            <para>Use any Sikkens Measuring Stick</para>
            <para>Application Method: use a syphon gun, 1-2 x 1; 0.055" - 0.063" (1.4 - 1.6mm); 25-30 psi (1 - 1/2 - 2
                bar)
            </para>
            <para>Flash Off: 4-6 minutes at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C)</para>
            <para>Drying Time: 1 hour at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C)</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Humidity</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM can be applied at a relative humidity of up to 90 percent.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pot Life</title>
            <para>After the components have been mixed, the pot life is 14 days at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C).</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Spray Gun and Pressure</title>
            <table id="t1600205" tblwidth="full-page">
                <title>Spray Gun and Pressure Table</title>
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.75in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="4" colname="4" colwidth="1.75in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Type</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spray Gun Fluid Tip</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Spraying Pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Fluid Pressure</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Siphon Feed</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.063" - 0.071" (1.6 - 1.8 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40 - 50 psi (3 - 4 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Gravity Feed</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.059" - 0.067" (1.5 - 1.7 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40 - 50 psi (3 - 4 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#160;</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Pressure Feed</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.039" - 0.047" (1.0 - 1.2 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>40 - 50 psi (3 - 4 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>10 - 14 psi (0.8 - 1.0 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>HVLP</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>0.039" - 0.067" (1.0 - 1.7 mm)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>MAX 10 psi (MAX 0.8 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>3 - 8 psi (0.3 - 0.6 bar)</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Application Method</title>
            <para>PRIMARY USE: As a sef etching passivating primer on bare metal, two or three coats can be applied. It
                is recommended to spray a lighter coat first on topcoats that are not fully cured (fresh synthetic
                surfaces).
            </para>
            <para>ALTERNATE USE: As additional corrosion protection prior to application of Autocryl Filler Off White,
                Autocryl 3+1 Filler, Autonova Filler, Autonova Non Sanding Filler or Priming Filler 680. Apply one
                single coat only of Washprimer EM.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Film Thickness</title>
            <para>Approximately 1.0 mil per single coat.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clean of Equipment</title>
            <para>With Sikkens Cleaning Solvent or lacquer thinner.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drying</title>
            <para>
                <title>Primary Use</title>Dry to sand: 30 minutes at 140&#176; F (60&#176;C); 1 hour at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C);
                1-1/2 hour at 50&#176;F (10&#176;C). Force drying at temperatures of up to 250&#176;F is possible.
            </para>
            <para>
                <title>Alternate Use:</title>Dry to recoat: 15 minutes at 70&#176;F (20&#176;C); 30 minutes at 50&#176;F
                (10&#176;C).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Never apply a polyester based product directly over Washprimer EM.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sanding</title>
            <para>Presand with #400 grit paper wit moving in stages to final sanding with #500-#600 grit west or presand
                with #240 grit dry moving in stages to final sanding with #360-#400 grit dry.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Suitable Topcoats</title>
            <para>WAshing Primer EM can be topcoated after sanding with Autocryl Acrylic Urethane Enamel system or
                Autobase/Autoclear system.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Autobase Solid Colors: When refinishing with Autobase solid colors containing 75% or more "00"
                        White, Washprimer EM must be isolated. Products that may be used are: Autocryl Filler Off White,
                        Autocryl 3+1 Filler, Autonova Filler, and Autonova Non-Sanding Filler.
                    </para>
                    <para>Autonov/Autonova Clear: When refinishing with Autonova or Autobase/Autonova Clear, Washprimer
                        EM must first be recoated with Autonova Filler or Autonova Non-Sanding Filler.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Coverage Rate</title>
            <para>99 sq. ft./liter of unmixed paint per single coat.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stock Keeping</title>
            <para>Color: Beige</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Container Size</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM: 1 quart and 1 gallon</para>
            <para>Washhardener: 1 quart and 1 gallon</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Minimum Shelf Life</title>
            <para>Two years if stored unopened at room temperature</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Aspects: Flashpoint (Closed Cup)</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM: 54&#176;F</para>
            <para>Washhardener: 46&#176;F</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VOC Content</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM: 5.5 lbs/gal; 660 grams/liter</para>
            <para>Washhardener: 6.7 lbs/gal; 810 grams/liter</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>RTS VOC</title>
            <para>Washprimer EM: 6.2 lbs/gal; 745 grams/liter</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Warnings</title>
            <para>This material is designed for application only by trained professional personnel using proper
                equipment and is not intended for sale to the general public. READ AND UNDERSTAND THE MATERIAL SAFETY
                DATA SHEET BEFORE USING THIS PRODUCT.
            </para>
            <para>Isolate from heat, electrical equipment, sparks, and open flame. Vapor may cause flash fires. Use with
                adequate ventilation. Do not breathe vapors or spray mist. Use NIOSH/MSHA approved respirator during any
                contact with this product. Follow manufacturer's directions for respirator selection and use. In
                confined areas, use NIOSH/MSHA approved airline respirator or hood.
            </para>
            <para>Avoid contact with eyes, skin, and clothing. Wear personal protective equipment as outlined in the
                Aerial Safety Data Sheet. Wash thoroughly with soap and water in case of any contact. When a finish,
                exhaust all vapors in a safe manner. Product produced from welding or cutting the dried finish should be
                avoided.
            </para>
            <para>Keep container tightly closed when not in use. In case of spillage, absorb with inert material and of
                in accordance with applicable regulations. Paint arrestors (spray booth filters), sanding dust, rags,
                paint strainers, etc., may be considered as hazardous waste and must be disposed of in accordance with
                applicable regulations.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>First Aid</title>
            <para>In case of eye contact, flush immediately with plenty of water for at least 15 minutes and get
                attention; for skin, wash thoroughly with soap and water. If affected by inhalation of vapor or-by mist,
                remove to fresh air, get medical attention. If swallowed, get medical attention.
            </para>
            <para>The contents of this package must be blended with other components before the product can be used.
                Before opening packages, read all warning labels and the Material Safety Data Sheet and follow all
                precautions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Notice</title>
            <para>Reports have associated repeated and prolonged occupational overexposures to solvents with permanent
                brain nervous system damage. Intentional misuse by deliberately concentrating and inhaling contents may
                be harmful or fatal.
            </para>
            <para>This product contains chromates (Cr VI); dispose of the can and any items (rags, filters, paint booth
                arrestors, etc.) that come into contact, as hazardous waste. Inform your hazardous waste management
                company.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disclaimer</title>
            <para>The technical information and suggestions for use made herein are based on Akzo Coatings Inc. research
                and experience and are believed to be reliable, but such information and suggestions do not constitute a
                warranty.
            </para>
            <para>Since Akzo Coatings Inc. has no control over the conditions under which the product is transported,
                stored, handled, used or applied, buyers must determine for themselves, by preliminary tests or
                otherwise, the suitability of the product for their purposes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_27.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_29.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
