<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - LEAK DETECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390912" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="3">
        <title>LEAK DETECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk xrefid="hl160340701">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="hl160340701"/>. Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers
                        involved when working with refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <note>
                    <para>When servicing the A/C system, insure that the inner gaskets are present in both service port
                        caps; and verify that the caps are installed when service is completed. The service port caps,
                        with functioning gaskets, are an important part of maintaining a leak free A/C system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refrigerant leaks are often indicated by an oily residue at the point of the leak.</para>
                </note>
                <note>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>There are several methods of refrigerant leak detection. The method used could depend on many factors
                including equipment availability, layout of the system being serviced, or even personal preference. The
                primary recommended methods are the electronic refrigerant leak detector and the phosphor
                dye/ultraviolet lamp method. In addition, brief descriptions are provided for two alternate methods
                (ultrasonic leak detection and soap solution). By using the described methods, either separately or in
                some combination, it should be possible to locate and verify most refrigerant leaks.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl160390912a">
            <title>Electronic Leak Detectors</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>To use the characteristics of the A/C system to your advantage while leak testing with an
                        electronic leak detector; check the high pressure side of the system with the system running,
                        and check the low pressure side of the system with the system (and engine) off.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>In terms of sensitivity and safety, the electronic leak detector (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603971">Figure 71</hotlnk>) is excellent for finding both slow and major system leaks.
                Ensure that the detector being used is intended for use with R134a refrigerant. Many leak detectors
                intended for use with R-12 cannot detect R134a leaks. The detector is also listed in the
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160391100.xml" xrefid="hl160391100">SPECIAL TOOLS</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl160391100"/>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603971" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603971.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 71. Electronic Leak Detector</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>The unit is a hand-held device having a flexible probe used to seek out refrigerant leaks. An audio
                leak indicator signals a warning in the presence of a leak. It is important to become familiar with the
                instructions for the detector being used. The speed at which the probe is moved over the component being
                checked is very important in locating larger than permissible leaks. Leak check procedure should be in
                accordance with SAE J1628.
            </para>
            <para>Before starting to look for leaks, it is recommended to clean away all oil or grease, and blow away
                refrigerant residue from fittings and A/C components. All suspected areas should be cleaned using soap
                and water, not a solvent. A detected leak should be a flow of refrigerant, not a residual condition of
                refrigerant that is trapped under an oil film, etc. A detected leak rate in excess of 1.0 oz./year is
                unacceptable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ultraviolet Lamp Leak Testing</title>
            <para>An alternate method to electronic leak testing is ultraviolet light. The desiccant located in the
                filter-drier contains a phosphor dye that will produce a bright yellow-green trace at the leak, when
                illuminated by an ultraviolet (UV) lamp. This dye is also included in replacement filter-driers. The kit
                illustrated in
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603972">Figure 72</hotlnk>
                provides the UV lamp used to illuminate the suspected leaks. The kit also contains connection hoses and
                a dye injector, as well as, eyeglasses used to enhance the effect of the UV light on the dye. A UV dye
                cleaner should be used to clean the HVAC system connections after repairs have been made.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603972" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603972.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 72. Ultraviolet Lamp Kit</caption>
            </figure>
            <para>It has been discovered during the use of UV light, and phosphor dyes, that other types of leaks also
                appear as a yellow-green trace when the UV light shines on them. If an UV lamp is used for leak
                detection, it is also recommended that an electronic leak detector be used to verify that any detected
                leaks are, in fact, refrigerant leaks. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl160390912a">ELECTRONIC LEAK DETECTORS
                    <xref refid="hl160390912a"/>
                </hotlnk>
                .
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ultrasonic Leak Detectors</title>
            <para>An ultrasonic leak detector listens for the distinctive 'sound' of a gas passing through an opening.
                To use this type of detector effectively, the refrigerant system is first discharged, and then
                pressurized to 300 psi using dry nitrogen and a manifold gauge set. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl160390912b">REFRIGERANT LEAK TESTING WITH NITROGEN</hotlnk>. The detector is then used
                to scan the suspected joints or components. Depending on the detector being used, a leak may be
                indicated by a visual or audible signal. Suspected leaks
                <emph type="bold">should not be cleaned</emph>
                with a soap solution prior to scanning with this tool, as any solution remaining at the leak site may
                mask the leak.
            </para>
            <para>The unit is a hand-held device and may include attachments to vary the directional sensitivity of the
                unit. Because this type of sensor does not sample the gas used in the system, it may be used with any
                refrigerant system. It may also be used to detect leaks in the vehicle air system. It is important to
                become familiar with the instructions for the leak detector being used.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Soap Solution with Nitrogen</title>
            <para>Another alternative method of leak detection is the soap solution method. To improve the results of
                this method the refrigerant system is first discharged, and then pressurized to 300 psi using dry
                nitrogen. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl160390912b">REFRIGERANT LEAK TESTING WITH NITROGEN</hotlnk>. A solution of soap and
                water is then sprayed on the suspected joints or components. A leak is indicated by bubbles forming at
                the point where the pressurized nitrogen is escaping.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl160390912b">
            <title>Refrigerant Leak Testing with Nitrogen</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Before pressurizing the system with nitrogen the system refrigerant must be recovered.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>When checking for refrigerant leaks using an ultrasonic detector or a soap solution, the refrigerant
                in the system must first be recovered; then, the system must be pressurized with dry nitrogen, as
                follows.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a manifold gauge set to the a/c system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603973">FIGURE 73</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Initially keep both gauge valves on manifold gauge set closed.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">High pressure hose (red) to high pressure port on vehicle. (Open quick connect
                        valve.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Low pressure hose (blue) is not connected. (Keep gauge valve and quick connect valve
                        closed.)
                        <emph type="bold">NOTE: Opening the low pressure gauge valve while the system is pressurized may
                            damage the low pressure gauge.
                        </emph>
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect pressurized nitrogen cylinder to the manifold gauge set and pressurize a/c
                    system to 300 PSI.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect manifold gauge set yellow hose to nitrogen source.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Set output pressure at nitrogen cylinder regulator to 300 PSI.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Slowly open high side gauge valve on manifold gauge set to pressurize a/c system
                        (high side gauge should read 300 PSI).
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Test for leaks using an ultrasonic detector or a soap solution.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After locating the leak, set the nitrogen cylinder regulator to 0 PSI.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>In the following step, the pressure must be released in a manner that does not trap pressure
                        in the a/c system.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before disconnecting the manifold gauge set, slowly release the pressure from the a/c
                    system by
                    <emph type="bold">partially</emph>
                    disconnecting a fitting until the pressure is released.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the manifold gauge set from the a/c system and repair the leak.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390906.xml" xrefid="hl160390906">EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390906"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Charge the system; refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390907.xml" xrefid="hl160390907">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                        (FULL CHARGE)
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390907"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603973" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603973.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 73. Using Nitrogen to Pressurize the A/C System</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. LOW PRESSURE VALVE AND GAUGE (MANIFOLD GAUGE SET)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HIGH PRESSURE VALVE AND GAUGE (MANIFOLD GAUGE SET)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. NITROGEN CYLINDER AND REGULATOR</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390911.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160391000.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
