<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - PAINT PROBLEMS - PAINT FLAWS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PAINT FLAWS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The following list is a guide to most of the common flaws you are likely to encounter before painting
                a vehicle:
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bleeding</title>
            <para>Commonly seen in instances where a light color is painted over a darker color, especially reds or
                maroons. Bleeding refers to the showing through of the original paint or primer into the new finish
                coat. Bleeding is caused by the solvent penetration of the new paint into the old finish, usually
                because the old finish has not been properly sealed. To remove areas of bleeding, sand off the new
                finish, apply surface sealer, and recoat; or, allow the new finish to properly cure, apply surface
                sealer, and then recoat.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blistering</title>
            <para>This problem can show up immediately or often months after the paint has been applied. Blistering
                appears as bubbles in the finish, caused by pockets of air or moisture trapped under the paint. As the
                paint continues to cure over a period of time, these pockets expand and form blisters. Common causes of
                blistering are improperly cleaned or dried surfaces, improper solvent mixing, a too thick application of
                paint coats with not enough drying time between coats, and water or impurities in the air lines.
                Blistering can be repaired by sanding and refinishing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Chalking</title>
            <para>A fine white powdery condition at the surface of lighter colors and distinctly bronze colored
                appearance on dark reds and blues. Almost invariably these conditions are confined to old paint films
                which have weathered for several years. Collapse of the paint film binder results from prolonged
                exposure to light and weathering. Regular maintenance will delay the occurrence of this problem but once
                breakdown has started, the only effective cure is complete removal of the paint film and then refinish.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cracking and Checking</title>
            <para>Often found in clear cover coats, cracking and checking are usually caused by abrupt changes in
                temperature and humidity, excessively heavy paint coats, incompatibility of paint products, poorly mixed
                (weak) paint and poorly prepped paint surfaces. Careful adherence to proper paint techniques should
                prevent cracking and checking. If they do occur, sand down affected area and repaint.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Crazing</title>
            <para>This condition can be identified by the appearance of fine, irregular splits and cracks that
                completely cover an area. Crazing is, in effect, a shattering of the original finish, usually caused by
                the chemical action of the solvent on a cold paint surface. It can be overcome by either using fast
                drying thinner to minimize solvent penetration, or by applying very wet (solvent heavy) paint coats to
                penetrate the old paint. This should melt the craze pattern and blend the new and old paint together (in
                lacquer systems only).
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Peeling and Chipping</title>
            <para>Poor adhesion of paint to surface can result in peeling and chipping. This condition usually occurs
                because the surface was not thoroughly cleaned or sealed, or the paint was not properly mixed. When
                peeling and chipping appear, remove the fresh paint and reclean the surface before repainting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Popping</title>
            <para>Appearing much like blisters, popping is caused when solvents are trapped under the top coat. Solvents
                can be trapped by particles of dirt on the paint surface, improper paint/solvent mixture or insufficient
                drying time between coats. In mild cases, the blisters can be sanded out after the paint dries and then
                refinished. In vere cases, the entire finish must be removed and repainted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Sand Scratches</title>
            <para>This condition appears as scratches showing through the finish coat. Improper surface preparation or
                sealing is the cause. Affected areas should be sanded down and sealed before repainting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Shrinking</title>
            <para>This usually occurs in an area that has been repaired with plastic filler or body putty. The paint
                will sometimes separate from the repaired area due to the shrinking of the putty as it dries after
                repainting. If this happens, the affected area should be sanded down to bare metal and the putty or
                plastic reapplied in thin coats. Seal and repaint.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Water Spots</title>
            <para>Much like the spots that appear on dishes when left to self-dry, water spots are caused by exposing a
                paint job to water before the paint is completely dry. Spots can be removed by compounding or polishing.
                In severe cases, sanding and refinishing is needed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
