<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - REAR HVAC system -
        COMPONENTS - REAR HVAC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390302" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>COMPONENTS - REAR HVAC SYSTEM</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Only those components unique to the sleeper HVAC system are described in the following paragraphs. All
                information covering the front HVAC system in these vehicles can be found in
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390202.xml" xrefid="hl160390202">COMPONENTS - FRONT HVAC SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
                The electrical control systems are covered in the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS manual and/or
                ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                for locations of the components described in the following paragraphs.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV)</title>
            <para>The rear expansion valve (1,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603917">Figure 17</hotlnk>) controls the amount of liquid refrigerant that enters the
                rear evaporator core. The valve is connected to both the input and output lines of the evaporator core.
                By sensing the temperature of the refrigerant at the output of the evaporator, the valve determines what
                amount of refrigerant is needed at the evaporator input to keep the evaporator operating within
                operational parameters. The rear TXV is serviced from under the vehicle cab, after discharging the A/C
                system.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603917" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603917.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 17. Rear Thermostatic Expansion Valve</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Evaporator</title>
            <para>The evaporator core (6,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>) is located in the rear
                HVAC unit. The core is a cooling assembly made of fin and tube construction. The inlet and outlet tubes
                protrude through the floor of the cab for connection directly to the rear TXV. Servicing the evaporator
                core requires splitting the rear HVAC unit and discharging the A/C system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear HVAC Plumbing</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603918">Figure 18</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Two under cab A/C lines are used to splice the rear A/C components into the front A/C lines near the
                front evaporator housing. International "C-plate" style block fittings are utilized on the refrigerant
                line connections to the front system. This block fitting incorporates a secondary moisture and dirt seal
                within a unique plate inserted into the block fitting. The primary O-ring seal has a large cross section
                for improved sealing as well. Connections at the rear TXV are via O-rings and clamping plates.
                Refrigerant hose assemblies are constructed from steel tubing coupled to Goodyear Galaxy hose. This
                nylon barrier type of hose prevents the refrigerant from escaping through the walls of the hose into the
                atmosphere. When servicing air conditioning systems, use only replacement hoses approved for air
                conditioning systems.
            </para>
            <para>Two under cab heater lines connect the rear heater core in parallel with the front heater core. The
                lines are spliced into the front heater hoses using 'T' fittings.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603918" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="G1603918" filename="../figg16/g1603918.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 18. Under Cab HVAC Lines for Rear System</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater Core</title>
            <para>The rear heater core is located in the rear HVAC unit (15,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>). The heater core is a
                heating assembly made of fin and tube construction and is connected in parallel with the front heater
                core. The inlet and outlet tubes protrude through the floor of the cab for connection to under cab
                heater lines. Engine coolant flows through the heater core at all times. The heater core can be serviced
                without splitting the rear HVAC unit housings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blower Assembly</title>
            <para>The rear blower assembly is mounted to the rear HVAC unit (4,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>). The blower assembly
                used in the sleeper HVAC system consists of a permanent magnet motor attached to a balanced
                'squirrel-cage' fan unit. The motor speed is controlled by the rear HVAC controller. The blower provides
                air circulation through the evaporator and heater core, and delivery of the treated air throughout the
                sleeper interior. The blower assembly can be serviced without splitting the rear HVAC unit housings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Linear Power Module</title>
            <para>The rear Linear Power Module (LPM) (9,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                and
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603919">Figure 19</hotlnk>) is mounted to the rear HVAC unit near the blower. The LPM
                allows a low current signal, from the rear HVAC controller, to control the speed of the higher current
                blower assembly. The LPM establishes the blower speed by reading the rear HVAC controller output signal,
                whose value is determined by the setting of either the blower speed control in the sleeper or the SLPR
                FAN switch in the instrument panel (whichever was adjusted last). More information on the electrical
                control systems can be found in the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS manual and/or ELECTRICAL
                SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603919" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603919.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="128px"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Rear Linear Power Module</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Temperature Blend Air Door Actuator</title>
            <para>The temperature blend air door actuator (12,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>) is located on the rear
                HVAC unit. The actuator rotates the blend air door according to signals provided by the rear HVAC
                controller. The position of the blend air door determines the amount of air flowing through the heater
                core; and therefore, the temperature of the air being output by the rear HVAC unit.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear HVAC Controller</title>
            <para>The rear HVAC controller (10,
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603914">Figure 14</hotlnk>) is mounted on the rear
                HVAC unit. The controller sets the blower speed, and temperature setting, of the sleeper HVAC system,
                based on the last sleeper HVAC control adjusted. This allows the sleeper system to be controlled by
                either the sleeper control panel or the switches in the instrument panel (
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603915">Figure 15</hotlnk>). When any sleeper
                related HVAC control is adjusted, it is sensed by the rear HVAC controller, and it becomes the active
                control. The rear controller then adjusts the blower speed, or blend air door, to match the setting of
                that control.
            </para>
            <para>In general, the air conditioning mode is automatically requested by the sleeper HVAC controller
                whenever the active temperature control for the sleeper system is set to a temperature that is lower
                than the current temperature sensed by the rear HVAC unit. Upon receiving the A/C request, the body
                controller will energize the A/C compressor if all requirements are met. For example, to energize the
                A/C compressor, the blower control on the front HVAC control panel must NOT be set to OFF. More
                information on the electrical control systems can be found in the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS
                manual and/or ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear HVAC Control Panel</title>
            <para>The rear HVAC control panel (
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603915">Figure 15</hotlnk>) is located on the
                driver's side of the sleeper rear wall. These HVAC controls are available in either digital or analog
                form, as determined by vehicle trim level.
            </para>
            <para>The analog control panel consists of two knobs actuating two long life potentiometers. The settings of
                these controls are read and interpreted by the rear HVAC controller. When these controls are active, the
                controller uses their settings to determine the rear blower motor speed and the position of the
                temperature blend air door.
            </para>
            <para>The digital control panel consists of four push buttons and a digital display. The push buttons allow
                up and down adjustment of the temperature and the blower speed. The actuations of these controls are
                read and interpreted by the rear HVAC controller. The display provides two bar graphs indicating the
                temperature and blower speed settings, as interpreted by the controller. When one of the buttons is
                pressed, the controller adjusts the setting of the blower motor speed, or temperature blend air door, to
                reflect the button actuation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear HVAC Control Switches (Located in Instrument Panel)</title>
            <para>Two rocker switches, located in the center console of the instrument panel (
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml" xrefid="f1603915">Figure 15</hotlnk>), allow the driver to
                adjusts the temperature setting and blower speed of the sleeper HVAC system. The rocker switches allow
                up and down adjustment of the temperature and the blower speed. The actuations of these switches are
                read and interpreted by the rear HVAC controller. When either switch is actuated, the controller adjusts
                the setting of the blower motor speed, or temperature blend air door, to reflect the switch actuation.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390301.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
