<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 5000, 9000 Series Without Lowered heater Box - COMPONENTS - CONTROL UNIT,
        SWITCH AND CABLES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CONTROL UNIT, SWITCH AND CABLES</title>
        <para>The control unit (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601509">Figure 9</hotlnk>) is mounted in the instrument panel and provides the means of
            operating the system. The levers and pull knob operate push-pull cables that are connected to the control
            switches and devices in the system. The HTR lever sets the amount of heat desired from OFF to HOT. The AIR
            OUTLET lever sets the air distribution from DEF (defrost air to windshield only) to CAB (air to floor ducts
            only). The A/C lever sets the amount of cooling desired from OFF to COLD. All of these controls are
            proportional and provide more or less heat, cold, and air mix (windshield to floor outlets) in relation to
            the position of the lever. Heat and cold can be used together to dehumidify the cab.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1601509" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1601507A.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 9. A/C Heater Control Unit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. A/C LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HEATER (HTR) LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>3. AIR OUTLET LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BLOWER SWITCH</callout1>
                <callout1>5. RECIRCULATING AIR KNOB</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>Outside air is controlled by the PULL-RECIRC knob. This is mounted on the instrument panel next to, but
            separate from, the control assembly. It is used to reduce or shut off outside air when maximum heat or
            cooling is desired or when outside odors or fumes need to be shut out. Air velocity is controlled by the
            blower switch. The BLOWER SWITCH is the lever with a fan symbol and has an OFF and three speed positions.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16015.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
