<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - TROUBLESHOOTING - APADS CONTROL AND
        DIAGNOSTIC FUNCTIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>APADS CONTROL AND DIAGNOSTIC FUNCTIONS</title>
        <para>
            <title>A/C Compressor Control Rules</title>
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The A/C compressor is absolutely kept OFF for the first 15 seconds after ignition switch
                engagement (module power-up).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The thermostat input is ignored and the A/C compressor is turned ON for 15 seconds directly
                after the 15 second ignition switch engagement timer (rule 1) times out. If the high or low pressure
                switches indicate out of bound or fault conditions, the compressor is turned OFF.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All three inputs (TSTAT, HPx, LPx) that can control the A/C compressor are governed by
                control logic that limits the maximum cycle rate to once every 15 seconds.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The evaporator thermostat is the primary control. The A/C compressor will cycle at the
                frequency governed by the thermostat but is limited to a maximum of one cycle per 15 seconds (rule 3).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the high pressure cutout switch indicates a high pressure condition, the A/C compressor
                is disengaged. The compressor is allowed to turn ON after the high pressure switch resets and rule 3 is
                satisfied.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the low pressure switch indicates a low pressure condition, the compressor is turned
                OFF. The compressor is allowed to turn ON after the low pressure switch resets and rule 3 is satisfied.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the supply voltage drops below 11.0 volts, the compressor is turned OFF. It is allowed to
                turn ON again after there has been sufficient rise in system voltage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The A/C compressor is latched OFF until the next ignition cycle if any open clutch fault is
                detected.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
