<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - SYSTEM MAINTENANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>SYSTEM MAINTENANCE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
            <title>PRE-SEASON SERVICING</title>
            <para>Field experience has indicated that many of the problems incurred with air conditioning- heater
                systems are the result of lack of regular maintenance. Preventive maintenance and cleanliness of all
                components within the system are extremely important.
            </para>
            <para>A complete step-by-step pre-season checkout of the air conditioning/heater system will substantially
                increase satisfactory operation during the season.
            </para>
            <para>Perform the following procedures:</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the unit mountings for looseness.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition and tension of all drive belts. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16012v_27.xml" xrefid="hl1601208">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check heater core fins for material that could restrict air flow.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check adjustment of controls.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check operation of blowers. Clean blower fans if necessary.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check water control valve adjustment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check cooling system shutter operation.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check condition of heater hoses and engine cooling system hoses. Replace if necessary.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to Service Manual Section for the system being serviced for specific procedures and
                            adjustment.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check compressor drive belt alignment.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check refrigerant hose retention and condition. Look for cracks, chafing, or other
                    damage. Inspect all tubing and hoses for dirty or loose connections. All connections must be clean
                    and tight.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install new air filter in air conditioning unit housing.</para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Refer to Service Manual Section for the system being serviced for specific procedures and
                            adjustment.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean all foreign material from con- denser, radiator, evaporator core and blowers.
                    Cleanliness of the air conditioner components cannot be overemphasized. Lack of proper attention in
                    this area is one of the major causes of costly and unsatisfactory unit operation. As often as
                    necessary, squirt water through the condenser towards the radiator and through the radiator towards
                    the condenser to flush debris from the fins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Operate the air conditioner and check the system for leaks with a leak detector.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the sight glass (system operating) to see that there are no bubbles.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Determine that the system is functioning properly. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16012v_3.xml" xrefid="hl1601203">PHYSICAL CHECKS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_15.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_17.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
