<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - PLASTIC (ABS) - TOOLS AND SUPPLIES</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>TOOLS AND SUPPLIES</title>
        <para>To repair damaged ABS plastic, one or a combination of the following items will be needed:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>ABS pellets-Methyl Ethyl Keytone (MEK) or Methylene Chloride (MCL).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Epoxy Adhesive Filler</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Adhesive Polyamids</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ABS Rods</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Heat (Hot Air) Gun</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>No. 40/80/220/360 grit Sand Paper</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sikkens Surface Cleaner No. M600</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Sikkens Autocryl Filler, Autocryl Color, Matting Clear and Auto Clear</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Scotch Brite No. 7447 Red Pad</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pneumatic or electric drill with sanding attachment, burr bits and tapered bits</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>The ABS solvent cement, primers and paints are all hazardous material. Keep away from sparks and
                    open flame. Vapors are harmful.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>FIBERGLASS ABS PLASTIC REPAIRS - To avoid breathing dust and fumes, wear approved protective
                    equipment. Breathing fiberglass ABS plastic dust and/or fumes can be hazardous to your health.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>1. OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as well as suggested
                    procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal Regulations, Section 1910,
                    1001.)
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>2. Whenever possible work on fiberglass and ABS plastics in a separate area away from other
                    operations.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>3. Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all fiberglass or ABS plastic
                    repairs.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>4. Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking.</para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
