<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - TROUBLESHOOTING - APADS DIAGNOSTIC FAULT
        DESCRIPTIONS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="troubleshoot" graphiccount="0">
        <title>APADS DIAGNOSTIC FAULT DESCRIPTIONS</title>
        <deflist>
            <term>Static Low Pressure:</term>
            <def>When the system exhibits states and conditions that are indicative of complete loss of refrigerant, the
                Static Low Pressure fault is asserted.
            </def>
            <term>Dynamic Low Pressure:</term>
            <def>Detected by rapid low pressure switch cycling, this behavior is symptomatic of partial loss of
                refrigerant. If the low pressure switch dominates control and tries to cycle the compressor, displaying
                certain dynamic characteristics, the Dynamic Static Low Pressure fault is asserted.
            </def>
            <term>High Pressure:</term>
            <def>This is detected by monitoring the High Pressure switch activity after the fan has been engaged. This
                fault can be caused by fan drive failure, debris on the condenser or refrigerant overcharging. If the
                high pressure switch controls the system with a certain dynamic behavior, the High Pressure fault is
                asserted.
            </def>
            <term>Open Clutch:</term>
            <def>This is detected by sensing the current flow to the A/C clutch. If no current flow is sensed when the
                A/C DRIVE is turned ON, an open connection to the clutch coil is inferred.
            </def>
            <term>Shorted Clutch:</term>
            <def>This is detected by sensing excessive current flow to the A/C clutch. This is indicative of either a
                short in the clutch coil or the wiring from the module to the A/C clutch.
            </def>
            <term>Low Psw Open:</term>
            <def>Indicates that the wiring to the low pressure switch is defective or there is a parasitic current
                leakage path between the switch wires. This can be caused by an unseated connector, break in the wiring
                harness, or moisture intrusion into the connectors or switch.
            </def>
            <term>High Psw Open:</term>
            <def>Indicates that the wiring to the high pressure switch is defective or there is a parasitic current
                leakage path between the switch wires. This can be caused by an unseated connector, break in the wiring
                harness, or moisture intrusion into the connectors or switch.
            </def>
            <term>Low Voltage:</term>
            <def>Indicates a low voltage condition. This can be caused by a defective alternator, discharged batteries
                or excessive electrical loads. This diagnostic is self clearing, the blink code is displayed only while
                low voltage is present.
            </def>
        </deflist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
