<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        REMOVE AND INSTALL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl160340600">
        <title>REMOVE AND INSTALL</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To prevent damage to the equipment and/or personal injury, always turn the vehicle ignition
                        key OFF before performing Removal and Installation procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Special attention to the following, during component remove and install, will aid in avoiding
                        unnecessary and time-consuming problems.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>When working on the A/C system keep the work area and tools as clean as possible. Also, clean
                        all connections, ports or fittings before disconnecting or removing components.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All A/C component and refrigerant line openings should be immediately covered or plugged
                        during removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and
                        other foreign material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a
                        vulnerable place within the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never remove protective caps from components until the moment of assembly into the system.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Never install non-sealed components.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the filter drier is one of multiple components being installed in the system, it should be
                        the last component installed. This reduces the amount of time that the filter drier desiccant is
                        exposed to atmospheric moisture.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Anytime an A/C fitting is disconnected, the O-ring and/or C-plate must be replaced (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603414">Figure 14</hotlnk>). The new O-ring must be lubricated with
                        <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                        oil. The C-plate does not require lubrication. Never use grease, penetrating oil, motor oil,
                        Ester or PAG oil, etc. to lubricate O-rings and fittings.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be re-installed in their
                        original positions.
                    </para>
                    <para>Never bend a hose to a radius less than ten times the diameter of the hose.</para>
                    <para>Never route a hose any closer than four inches from the exhaust manifold or related piping.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Whenever possible use a backup wrench when loosening or tightening fittings (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603415">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>All fittings must be tightened as specified in the
                        <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340801.xml" xrefid="t1603417">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="t1603417"/>. Use only a torque wrench known to be accurate.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <figure id="f1603414" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603414.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="152px"/>
                <caption>Figure 14. A/C Fitting C-Plate and O-Ring</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. O-RING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. C-PLATE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <figure id="f1603415" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603415.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Use a Back-Up Wrench When Loosening or Tightening Fittings</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The following figures and procedures cover most typical engine/chassis configurations. Some
                        configurations may differ slightly due to component mounting locations and/or hose routings.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The removal and installation procedures for this heating - air conditioning system are organized in
                the following order. Under hood components are covered first, followed by the in-cab components.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340506.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340601.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
