<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - DIAGNOSIS AND TESTING - PHYSICAL CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601203" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PHYSICAL CHECKS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With air conditioning controls set for maximum cooling (A/C lever on COLD, blower switch on
                HIGH and HTR lever on OFF), operate engine and air conditioning system for about five minutes or until
                initial heat has been removed from the cab and an average flow of cold air is achieved. If the system
                does not cool, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16012v_7.xml" xrefid="hl1601202">TROUBLESHOOTING,</hotlnk>
                "Air Not Cold Enough",
                <hotlnk document="s16012v_6.xml" xrefid="f1601212">Figure 16</hotlnk>
                diagnosis chart.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With system operating, feel all air conditioning system components and refrigerant lines for
                proper operating temperatures.
            </para>
            <para>From the discharge side of the compressor along the high pressure line, through the condenser,
                receiver/ dehydrator tank and up to the expansion valve, everything should be hot or warm to the touch.
                The expansion valve, evaporator and all the lines on the low pressure side leading back to the
                compressor should be cool to the touch. Any deviation from the above conditions indicates a malfunction
                in the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Malfunctions or stoppages may be indicated by extreme cold or frosted areas (example: a cold receiver/
            dehydrator tank frosted part way up indicates a stoppage or serious restriction in the tank). A stoppage or
            severe restriction in the refrigerant system can be located by looking for these indications.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1"></para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Avoid contact with moving belts, pulleys and fan when making this check. Beware of extremely
                        high temperatures at compressor outlet (discharge) hoses and tubing as personal injury may
                        result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For additional A/C compressor and/or magnetic clutch diagnosis, refer to GROUP 16 in the
                        CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_2.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_4.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
