<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Thermostatic Expansion Valve (TXV) System, March 2007 and Later -
        SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - SERVICE WARNINGS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160340701" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE WARNINGS</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Safety goggles or other adequate eye protection must be worn when working with refrigerant. The
                    temperature of liquid refrigerant is -20 degrees F (-29 degrees C). Serious injury or blindness will
                    result from refrigerant contacting the eyes.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>If the refrigerant should contact the eyes, DO NOT rub them. Splash the eyes with cold water to
                    gradually get the temperature above the freezing point. See a doctor immediately.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear nonporous gloves. (Nitril is the recommended material.) Should liquid refrigerant come into
                    contact with the skin, remove any contaminated clothing, including shoes; then treat the injury as
                    though the skin had been frostbitten or frozen. See a doctor immediately.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Be certain that pressurized refrigerant containers are not exposed to open flame or temperatures
                    above 125 degrees F (51 degrees C). Do not discard empty refrigerant containers where they are
                    likely to be subjected to the heat of trash burners, etc.; they may explode, resulting in personal
                    injury or possible death. Containers must be stored, installed, and disposed of in accordance with
                    all state and local ordinances.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Never weld, solder, steam clean or use excessive heat on any of the air conditioning lines or
                    equipment while the system is charged. Heat applied to any part will cause the pressure within the
                    system to become excessive, which may result in an explosion and possible personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not smoke or allow any type of fire or flame in the immediate area while servicing the air
                    conditioning system. Refrigerant is not combustible; however, in the presence of heat it changes to
                    a poisonous gas. Inhalation can cause death or serious injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>R-134a must not be mixed with air and then pressurized. When mixed with large quantities of air
                    and pressurized, R-134a becomes combustible.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the system
                    are removed or replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause personal
                    injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not remove the compressor oil fill plug to check the oil level in the refrigerant compressor
                    while the A/C system is charged with refrigerant. The crankcase side of the compressor is under
                    pressure and personal injury may result. It is not possible to check the oil level in the compressor
                    on an A/C system that is under system pressure.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not install or remove A/C testing or charging equipment while the engine is running. Serious
                    injury may result from doing so.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Always use approved refrigerant recycling equipment when working with R-134a to prevent accidental
                    discharge. If released into the atmosphere, the refrigerant evaporates very quickly and may displace
                    the oxygen surrounding the work area, especially in small or enclosed areas. This situation creates
                    the hazard of suffocation or brain damage for anyone in the work area. If a leak should occur, avoid
                    breathing the refrigerant and lubricant vapor. Thoroughly ventilate the area before continuing with
                    service. Federal and state laws require that refrigerant be recovered and recycled to help protect
                    the environment.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>With the manifold gauge set connected to both the air conditioning system and the refrigerant
                    supply cylinder, never open the high side hand valve of the manifold gauge set while the A/C system
                    is operating. If hot, high pressure refrigerant is forced through the gauge to the refrigerant
                    supply cylinder; it could cause the cylinder to rupture and cause personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>When purging the system or components, do not use nitrogen at pressures over 200 psi. Personal
                    injury or death may result from doing so.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Always use correct replacement refrigerant hoses. Do not use hoses other than those specified for
                    the system being serviced. The use of improper hoses may cause a hose rupture, which may result in
                    personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>During system
                    <emph type="underscr">diagnostic</emph>
                    tests, DO NOT turn either hand valve on the manifold gauge set for any reason. Equipment can be
                    damaged, and personal injury can result. When connected to the A/C system the gauges will indicate
                    the system pressures with the valves closed (fully CW). These valves are used only while
                    <emph type="underscr">servicing</emph>
                    the A/C refrigerant system.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>To prevent damage to the test equipment, make sure test equipment is clear of all moving parts in
                    the engine compartment.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When installing and removing any service hose or fitting, a small amount of refrigerant may
                    escape. Always follow all safety precautions to avoid injury.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>Before connecting any service equipment to the refrigerant system, the refrigerant in the system
                    must be identified. Failure to identify system refrigerant before connecting equipment could result
                    in contamination of your service equipment and any refrigerant stored in the equipment.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>When servicing the A/C system, insure that the inner gaskets are present in both service port
                    caps; and verify that the caps are installed when service is completed. The service port caps, with
                    functioning gaskets, are an important part of maintaining a leak free A/C system.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_HL160340700.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034_48.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16034.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
