<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - GLOSSARY OF
        TERMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GLOSSARY OF TERMS</title>
        <para>Refer to the following terms for a better understanding of the heater/air conditioning system.</para>
        <para>
            <title>AIR CONDITIONING</title>
            - A device used to control the temperature, humidity, cleanliness and movement of air.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>AIR PRESSURE</title>
            - The pressure exerted in every direction at any given point. Normal atmospheric pressure (that is, the
            pressure caused by the weight of the atmosphere) at sea level is 14.696 psi (101.60 kPa).
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>AMBIENT AIR TEMPERATURE</title>
            - The temperature of air around an object; the outside temperature.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>BLOWER</title>
            - A motor and fan used to draw air through the evaporator, and force it through the heater core and into the
            cab.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>BLOWER SPEED CONTROL RESISTORS</title>
            - Inline resistors that control the amount of voltage going to the blower motor. By controlling the voltage,
            you can control the speed.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>BOILING POINT</title>
            - The temperature at which a liquid changes to a gas, at a certain pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>BULK CHARGING</title>
            - Use of large containers of refrigerant for charging a refrigerant system. Normally used for charging empty
            systems.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CFM</title>
            - Cubic feet per minute.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CHARGE</title>
            - A specific amount of refrigerant or oil by volume or weight. Also, the act of placing an amount of
            refrigerant or oil in the air conditioning system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>COLD</title>
            - The absence of heat. (The lowest possible temperature is believed to be -459 degrees F (-273 degrees C.).
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
            - An assembly used to draw low pressure, low temperature refrigerant gas from the evaporator and squeeze it
            into a high pressure, high temperature gas. This causes the refrigerant to have a higher temperature than
            the surrounding air, allowing the condenser to change the gas back into a liquid. A secondary purpose of the
            compressor is to move refrigerant and oil through the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CONDENSATE</title>
            - Water, taken from the air, which forms on the outer surface of the evaporator.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CONDENSER</title>
            - A heat exchanger that is used to remove heat from refrigerant, changing it from a high temperature, high
            pressure gas into a high temperature, high pressure liquid.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CONDENSING PRESSURE</title>
            - Pressure, as read from the gauge at the discharge service port; pressure from the discharge side of the
            compressor into the condenser; high side pressure; discharge pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>CONTAMINANTS</title>
            - Anything other than refrigerant or refrigerant oil in the system. Usually means water in the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DEHUMIDIFY</title>
            - To remove water from the air, at the evaporator coils.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DESICCANT</title>
            - A drying agent used in the refrigerant system (in the receiver-dryer) to remove moisture.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DISCHARGE</title>
            - To remove some or all of the refrigerant from the air conditioning system using a recovery/recycling
            station.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DISCHARGE LINE</title>
            - Connects the refrigerant compressor outlet to the condenser inlet.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DISCHARGE PRESSURE</title>
            - Pressure of the refrigerant leaving the compressor; high side pressure; condensing pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DISCHARGE SERVICE PORT</title>
            - A device typically located in the refrigerant line attached to the discharge side of the compressor; it
            allows high side pressure to be checked.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>DRYING AGENT</title>
            - See "Desiccant."
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>ELECTRONIC VACUUM GAUGE</title>
            - A high vacuum gauge sensitive to pressures ranging from atmospheric pressure to 10 microns, with scales
            reading from 20,000 microns to 10 microns.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EVACUATE</title>
            - Evacuation places a vacuum in the refrigerant system, it dehydrates all traces of moisture and is used to
            determine if the system has any leaks before installing a charge of refrigerant in the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EVAPORATE</title>
            - A change of state from a liquid to a gas.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EVAPORATOR CORE</title>
            - A component of the air conditioning system in which liquid refrigerant changes to a gas after it absorbs
            heat from the air. Also collects cab moisture.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>EXPANSION VALVE</title>
            - A device that causes a pressure drop of the refrigerant and also regulates flow.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>FLUSHING</title>
            - A process of forcing a flushing agent through a contaminated system component. Flushing is used to remove
            heavy contaminants that cannot be removed by purging.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>FREEZE-UP</title>
            - Failure of a unit to operate properly because of ice forming at the expansion valve orifice or on the
            evaporator coils or fins.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>HEAD PRESSURE</title>
            - Refrigerant pressure from the discharge side of the compressor to the condenser and expansion valve.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>HUMIDITY</title>
            - The amount of water vapor in the air.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>HYDRAULIC LOCK</title>
            - The return of liquid refrigerant to the compressor which could damage the compressor.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>LEAK DETECTOR</title>
            - A device used to detect a leak in the air conditioning system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>LOW SUCTION PRESSURE</title>
            - Low side pressure that is lower than normal due to a system problem.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>MAGNETIC CLUTCH</title>
            - An electrical coupling device used to engage or disengage the refrigerant compressor.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>MANIFOLD GAUGE SET</title>
            - A manifold that is complete with gauges and charging hoses and used to measure or test pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>MICRON</title>
            - A metric measurement of mercury, (1.0 mm/Hg = 1000 microns and 0.1 in/Hg = 2540 microns). Measurement in
            microns is the only accurate way to determine the amount of pressure that is left in a refrigerant system by
            a high vacuum pump.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>NITROGEN</title>
            - A colorless, orderless, dry, inert gas that can be used to purge light contaminants from air conditioning
            parts.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>OVERCHARGED</title>
            - Too much refrigerant or oil in the system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>PURGE</title>
            - To remove damp air, traces of refrigerant, and loose dirt by purging with dry nitrogen.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>RECEIVER-DRYER</title>
            - A combination desiccant, filter, and storage container for liquid refrigerant.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>REFRIGERANT (R-134a)</title>
            - The cooling agent used in automotive air conditioning systems.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>REFRIGERATION CYCLE</title>
            - The complete circulation of refrigerant through an air conditioning system, accompanied by changes in
            temperature and pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>RESISTOR</title>
            - A voltage dropping device, usually wire wound, for controlling fan speed.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>SENSOR (TEMPERATURE)</title>
            - A temperature-sensing unit that is used to sense air temperatures and provide a control voltage for
            operation of automatic temperature control units.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>SUCTION PRESSURE</title>
            - Compressor inlet pressure (the system low side pressure).
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>SUCTION SIDE SERVICE PORT</title>
            - A device located in the refrigerant line connected to the suction side of the compressor that allows low
            side pressure to be checked, and other service operations to be performed.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>THERMOSTATIC SWITCH</title>
            - A temperature sensitive switch used to control system temperature and prevent evaporator freeze-up; it
            does this by controlling compressor operation.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>VACUUM</title>
            - Refers to pressure that is less than atmospheric pressure.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>VACUUM PUMP</title>
            - A mechanical device used to evacuate and place a high vacuum in the refrigerant system.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>VAPOR</title>
            - The gaseous state of material.
        </para>
        <para>
            <title>WATER VALVE</title>
            - A valve, mechanically operated to control the flow of hot coolant to the heater core.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601932.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
