<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390100" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <para>Refrigerant R-134a is a nonflammable, nonexplosive, and noncorrosive hydrofluorocarbon refrigerant. R-134a
            is heavier than air and has a slight ether-type odor. Although R-134a is classified as a safe refrigerant,
            the following precautions must be observed to protect the A/C system components and the person working on
            the system.
        </para>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury, or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface,
                    shift transmission to park or neutral, set parking brake, and block wheels before performing
                    diagnostic or service procedures.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid personal injury or death, refer to the manufacturer's service information before working
                    on any high voltage equipment. By definition high voltage circuits and components contain voltage
                    levels that may cause equipment damage, electrical shock and/or electrocution if handled
                    incorrectly.
                </para>
                <para>Only a trained technician may perform service inside high voltage components. If you work around
                    or maintain high voltage circuits, please seek high voltage training.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Carbon monoxide is a colorless, odorless, and dangerous gas that is present in vehicle exhaust.
                    When it is necessary to operate the engine during vehicle service in a confined area, always use the
                    proper equipment to vent the exhaust gasses outside of the work area.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Safety goggles or other adequate eye protection must be worn when working with refrigerant. The
                    temperature of liquid refrigerant is -20 degrees F (-29 degrees C). Serious injury or blindness will
                    result from refrigerant contacting the eyes.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>If the refrigerant should contact the eyes, DO NOT rub them. Splash the eyes with cold water for
                    at least 15 minutes to gradually get the temperature above the freezing point. See a doctor
                    immediately.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear nonporous gloves. Should liquid refrigerant come into contact with the skin, remove any
                    contaminated clothing, including shoes; then treat the injury as though the skin had been
                    frostbitten or frozen. See a doctor immediately.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Be certain that pressurized refrigerant containers are not exposed to open flame or temperatures
                    above 125 degrees F (51 degrees C). Do not discard empty refrigerant containers where they are
                    likely to be subjected to the heat of trash burners, etc.; they may explode, resulting in personal
                    injury or possible death. Containers must be stored, installed, and disposed of in accordance with
                    all state and local ordinances.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Never weld, solder, steam clean or use excessive heat on any of the air conditioning lines or
                    equipment while the system is charged. Heat applied to any part will cause the pressure within the
                    system to become excessive, which may result in an explosion and possible personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not smoke or allow any type of fire or flame in the immediate area while servicing the air
                    conditioning system. Refrigerant is not combustible; however, in the presence of heat it changes to
                    a poisonous gas. Inhalation can cause death or serious injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>R-134a must not be mixed with air and then pressurized. When mixed with large quantities of air
                    and pressurized, R-134a becomes combustible.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the system
                    are removed or replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause personal
                    injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not remove the compressor oil fill plug to check the oil level in the refrigerant compressor
                    while the A/C system is charged with refrigerant. The crankcase side of the compressor is under
                    pressure and personal injury may result. It is not possible to check the oil level in the compressor
                    on an A/C system that is under system pressure.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not install or remove A/C testing or charging equipment while the engine is running. Serious
                    injury may result from doing so.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Always use approved refrigerant recycling equipment when working with R-134a to prevent accidental
                    discharge. If released into the atmosphere, the refrigerant evaporates very quickly and may displace
                    the oxygen surrounding the work area, especially in small or enclosed areas. This situation creates
                    the hazard of suffocation or brain damage for anyone in the work area. If a leak should occur, avoid
                    breathing the refrigerant and lubricant vapor. Thoroughly ventilate the area before continuing with
                    service. Federal and state laws require that refrigerant be recovered and recycled to help protect
                    the environment.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>While the manifold gauge set is connected to both the air conditioning system and refrigerant
                    supply cylinder, never open the high side hand valve of the manifold gauge set while the A/C system
                    is operating. If hot, high pressure refrigerant is forced through the gauge to the refrigerant
                    supply cylinder; it could cause the cylinder to rupture and cause personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>When purging the system or components, do not use nitrogen at pressures over 200 psi. Personal
                    injury or death may result from doing so.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Always use correct replacement refrigerant hoses. Do not use hoses other than those specified for
                    the system being serviced. The use of improper hoses may cause a hose rupture, which may result in
                    personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only new or recycled R-134a refrigerant; not any of the so called "direct replacement"
                    refrigerants. Use of a recovery machine dedicated for R-134a is necessary to reduce the possibility
                    of oil and refrigerant incompatibility concerns.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only the specified PAG lubricant in the refrigerant system (International P/N ZGGR725028). PAG
                    oils absorb atmospheric moisture very quickly. Never leave PAG oil exposed to air for a prolonged
                    time. Wear nonporous gloves while handling PAG oil, and tightly reseal the oil container immediately
                    after each use.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only MINERAL BASED refrigerant oil (International P/N ZGGR6912) to lubricate O-rings and
                    fittings
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Disconnect battery ground cable during service to prevent possible damage to the vehicle
                    electrical system. If the battery must remain connected for a specific test, use extreme caution
                    when taking measurements.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When purging the system, or components of the system, use only dry nitrogen. The introduction of
                    compressed air into the A/C system may cause contamination of the system.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>After replacing a compressor verify that the pulley alignment and belt tension are correct.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When charging the A/C system the refrigerant tank must be kept upright. If the tank is not in the
                    upright position, liquid refrigerant may enter the system and cause compressor damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When pressure cleaning the A/C components under the hood, do not direct the high pressure stream
                    directly at the actuator for the fresh air/recirculate air door.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390200.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
