<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - MAJOR STRUCTURAL REPAIR: 9600 - FASTENERS AND SEALERS -
        FASTENERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="1">
        <title>FASTENERS</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace old rivets with the next larger size (such as 3/16" old would go to 1/4" new).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use aluminum rivets to replace aluminum rivets. Use steel to replace steel. if steel rivets
                are used, they must be coated to prevent corrosion in contact with the aluminum.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replacement fasteners should be of the same type as the ones removed. The solid squeeze
                rivets may be replaced by lockbolts and collars of the proper grip length,if desired.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">if you cannot get at both sides, use Monobolts or erry G's. Use Cherry G's if the surface is
                curved, or if you need greater clamp-up power to pull several thicknesses of material together. Use
                Monobolts to fasten two flat parts together.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">There are some places where spot welds are used in the assembly of this cab. Use plug welds
                to reassemble if a weld is necessary. in some places, such as attaching the tunnel to the tunnel rails,
                1/4" Lockbolts may be used instead of welds. Plug welding, because of its high heat, may distort large
                panels. Lockbolts do not cause this problem.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">At the forward end of the tunnel, there are places where the original fasteners should be
                replaced with 5/16" Magnagrips. If your equipment cannot pull 5/16" Magnagrips, replace the fasteners
                with 5/16", grade #8, hex head, coated bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">In the case of older cabs with serial numbers below 16529, you should replace the original
                aluminum rivets in the area of the gusset (which is located at the left front corner of the tunnel) with
                coated steel rivets or bolts following the rules that have been stated above.
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600108">Figure 8</hotlnk>
                shows this area in detail. This is an area of great stress and it is very important to use the correct
                fasteners.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600108" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600108" filename="../figg16/g1600108.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Rivets to be Replaced as Viewed Through Cab Grille Opening</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. CAB OUTER SILL (FRONT) TO INNER SILL ANGLE BRACKET. FOUR RIVETS TO BE REPLACED.
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>2. FRONT CROSSMEMBER TO INNER SILL ANGLE BRACKETS. FOUR RIVETS TO BE REPLACED.</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. CAB TUNNEL GUSSET, CAB TUNNEL TO INNER SILL. SIX RIVETS TO BE REPLACED.</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16001_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16001_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16001.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
