<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING - PHYSICAL CHECKS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602545" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PHYSICAL CHECKS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The Physical Checks provide a simple, convenient method of determining the condition of the A/C
                refrigerant system. Perform these checks when referenced from the troubleshooting tables.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Physical Check Procedure</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start the engine and set the air conditioning control panel for maximum cooling, as
                    follows:
                </para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set blower speed control to highest speed, full cw.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set temperature control for maximum cooling, full ccw.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Set mode control to MAXA/C, full ccw.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Set the engine speed at 1500 RPM or above, and run the air conditioning system for at
                    least five minutes.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Avoid contact with moving belts, pulleys and/or fan when making the following checks. Beware
                        of extremely high temperatures at compressor outlet (discharge) hoses and tubing, as personal
                        injury may result.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the system operating, feel all air conditioning system components and refrigerant
                    lines for proper operating temperatures, as indicated in the following paragraphs.
                </para>
                <para>In general, from the discharge side of the compressor along the high pressure line, through the
                    condenser and up to the input to the orifice tube, everything should be hot or warm to the touch.
                    From the output of the orifice tube, the evaporator, the accumulator, and all the lines on the low
                    pressure side leading back to the compressor should be cool to the touch. Any deviation from the
                    above conditions may indicate a malfunction in the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>The following is a brief description of symptoms or conditions that could exist if the vehicle air
                conditioning system is malfunctioning. The conditions are listed by system component.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Refrigerant Compressor</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the ambient temperature is very low, the engine may have to reach operating temperature
                        before the ESC will energize the A/C compressor. Before the A/C compressor can be energized the
                        inlet thermistor must read >43&#176;F, the outlet thermistor must read >33&#176;F, and the
                        pressure transducer must read >40 psi. After warmup, underhood heat will allow the compressor to
                        cycle on at very low ambient temperatures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Compressor problems are usually revealed in one of five ways: abnormal noise, seizure, leakage, high
                suction pressure, or low discharge pressure.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, the A/C compressor should be turned in a clockwise (CW) direction only
                        (as viewed from the front).
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Resonant noises are not a cause for alarm; irregular noise or rattles are likely caused by broken
                parts. To check for seizure, turn the engine off, de-energize the magnetic clutch and see if the drive
                plate can be turned. If it won't turn, the compressor has seized.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the fittings, oil fill plug, and all gasket joints on the compressor for signs of refrigerant
                leakage.
            </para>
            <para>Verify that the wires to the compressor clutch are in good condition and have not become
                disconnected.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Condenser</title>
            <para>The condenser is usually trouble-free. Normally, the temperature of the condenser outlet line is
                noticeably cooler than the inlet line.
            </para>
            <para>When road debris (such as leaves or dirt build-up) cakes up, airflow over the condenser fins is
                reduced and the air is not able to absorb enough heat to turn the hot refrigerant gas into a liquid.
                High discharge pressure will result. In these cases, carefully clean off the outer surface of the
                condenser with soap and water and compressed air; be careful not to bend the fins.
            </para>
            <para>High discharge pressure will also occur if the condenser's tubing is abnormally bent, restricting or
                blocking the flow of refrigerant. Frost will appear at the point where the flow of refrigerant is
                restricted.
            </para>
            <para>Less common internal blockage (foreign material or metallic grit build-up) will restrict or stop the
                flow of refrigerant.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the fittings and the condenser tubing for signs of refrigerant leakage.</para>
            <para>Reduced performance may also result from excess oil in the refrigerant system. This excess oil tends
                to collect in the bottom of the condenser.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>High Pressure Transducer</title>
            <para>Verify that the wires to the high pressure transducer are in good condition and have not become
                disconnected.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the transducer mounting for signs of refrigerant leakage.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermistors</title>
            <para>Verify that the wires to the thermistors are in good condition and have not become disconnected.
            </para>
            <para>Inspect the thermistor mountings for signs of refrigerant leakage.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the electrical connection to either thermistor is suspected of being intermittent, perform
                        the
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602573.xml" xrefid="hl1602573">THERMISTOR CONNECTOR REPAIR</hotlnk>
                        procedures
                        <xref refid="hl1602573"/>.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Clutch Cycling Orifice Tube</title>
            <para>A partially blocked orifice tube may cause the evaporator inlet tube to become very cold. In addition,
                the evaporator pressure may read very low, possibly even a negative value. A fully blocked orifice tube
                will result in high head pressure; however, there will be no physical symptoms at the location of the
                orifice tube.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Evaporator</title>
            <para>The evaporator coils are basically trouble-free when air flow over the fins is not blocked. Normally,
                the evaporator outlet tube and accumulator will feel cool to cold. External or, less often, internal
                blockage will cause low suction pressure, as well as, little or no cooling.
            </para>
            <para>If a leak exists in the system, and it cannot be traced to other parts or fittings, suspect damage to
                one of the evaporator coils.
            </para>
            <para>Evaporator freeze-ups are the result of the moisture in the air condensing and then freezing on the
                evaporator core. The ice on the fins blocks the air flow through the evaporator and stops the cooling
                until the ice melts. Evaporator freeze-up is generally caused by a problem with the sensing circuitry
                that controls the cycling of the A/C compressor (input thermistor circuit or output thermistor circuit).
            </para>
            <para>A starved evaporator occurs when there is not enough refrigerant flowing into the evaporator.
                Starvation can be caused by a blocked orifice tube or a low refrigerant charge. A starved evaporator may
                cause the evaporator outlet tube or accumulator to feel warmer than usual: at or near ambient
                temperature.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Never force the fresh/recirculate air door open. If the door position must be changed, refer
                        to
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602522.xml" xrefid="hl1602522">REMOVE AND INSTALL, AIR FILTER
                        </hotlnk>
                        <xref refid="hl1602522"/>. Forcing the door will result in a broken door shaft and a costly
                        repair.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>The evaporator is the most difficult of all the components to inspect visually because of its enclosed
                location. To detect airflow blockage due to debris, bent fins, and/or refrigerant leaks (oil smudges)
                inspect the inlet side of the evaporator. The fresh air/recirculate air door must be in the open (fresh
                air) position (the mode control cannot be set to the MAX A/C position). Remove the grille from the cowl
                tray air inlet, and remove the air filter, if necessary. Using a flashlight and inspection mirror,
                inspect the inlet side of the evaporator core.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accumulator</title>
            <para>When operating normally, the accumulator will be cold. Internal blockage will cause low suction
                pressure as well as little or no cooling.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Line Restrictions</title>
            <para>A restricted suction line causes low suction pressure at the compressor and little or no cooling. A
                restriction in a line between the compressor and the clutch cycling orifice tube can cause high
                discharge and low suction pressure, and poor cooling. Generally, if the line is not entirely blocked,
                the area immediately after the restriction will be cold. A completely blocked line will result in high
                head pressures, but no physical symptoms at the blockage.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_18.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602546.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
