<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SYSTEM MAINTENANCE - AIR FILTERS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>AIR FILTERS</title>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Never force the fresh/recirculate air door open. If the door position must be changed, follow the
                    referenced procedures. Forcing the door will result in a broken door shaft and a costly repair.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <para>Inspect the HVAC inlet air filter elements for dust and road dirt at the beginning of each cooling season.
            Clean or replace the elements as needed. More frequent cleaning and/or replacement may be required on
            vehicles operated in severe conditions.
        </para>
        <para>A filter/grille assembly is located at the top of the fresh air intake, above the front evaporator
            housing. This filter is mounted to the air intake above the cowl drain tray. This filter assembly is secured
            with thumb screws and does not require tools for removal and installation.
        </para>
        <para>Another filter element is located inside the front evaporator housing, under the fresh/recirculate air
            door. To replace this air filter refer to
            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390805.xml" xrefid="hl160390805">AIR FILTER, REMOVE AND INSTALL</hotlnk>
            <xref refid="hl160390805"/>.
        </para>
        <para>If the vehicle is equipped with a sleeper HVAC system, a filter element is located at the rear HVAC unit
            air intake. Clean or replace with a new element if necessary. The filter element can be accessed by lifting
            the lower bunk.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_20.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390700.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
