<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - HVAC ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS OVERVIEW
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>HVAC ELECTRICAL CIRCUITS OVERVIEW</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The heater/ventilation/air conditioning (HVAC) system contains both mechanical and electrical
                components. The next several sections cover the electrical part of the system; including descriptions,
                diagnosis, and troubleshooting for each of the electrical circuits.
            </para>
            <para>The HVAC electrical system, refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602551">HVAC ELECTRICAL SYSTEM FUNCTION DIAGRAM</hotlnk>, consists of the following
                components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>the refrigerant compressor/clutch/solenoid,</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the HVAC control head,</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the electronic system controller (ESC),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the blower motor (located in HVAC module),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the linear power module (located in HVAC module),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the actuator for mode control air doors (located on HVAC module),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the temperature control air door actuator (located on HVAC module),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the fresh air/recirculate air door actuator (located on evaporator module),</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>the engine controller,</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>cooling fan/fan drive/drive control solenoid,</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>two AC refrigerant thermistors,</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>and the AC pressure transducer.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <figure id="f1602551" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602551.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 51. HVAC Electrical System Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. AC COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. ELECTRICAL SYSTEM CONTROLLER (ESC)</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. HVAC CONTROL HEAD</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HVAC MODULE (BLOWER MOTOR, LINEAR POWER MODULE, AIR DOOR ACTUATORS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. EVAPORATOR MODULE (AIR DOOR ACTUATOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ENGINE CONTROLLER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. COOLING FAN/FAN DRIVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. REFRIGERANT SENSORS (INLET/OUTLET THERMISTORS)</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. REFRIGERANT PRESSURE TRANSDUCER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The controls on the HVAC control head can be set to adjust the cab air temperature mix, select the
                blower speed, and select the system operating mode, including recirculation and distribution of cab air.
                The control head has a direct digital fault communication circuit to the ESC which will tell the ESC to
                log diagnostic trouble codes for conditions monitored by the control head (operation of the air door
                actuator motors). The control head also communicates with the ESC to request compressor turn on (for AC
                and defrost operation).
            </para>
            <para>The ESC contains the circuitry and the program that controls the cycling of the air conditioner
                compressor. The program is known as the Refrigerant Control and Diagnostic (RCD) System. For a more
                complete description of the RCD system, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602568.xml" xrefid="hl1602568">SECTION 8.1</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl1602568"/>. In general the ESC monitors the refrigerant sensors (transducer and
                thermistors) and other system parameters to determine if all parameters are within acceptable limits. If
                parameters are acceptable, the ESC will turn on the compressor when requested by the HVAC control head,
                and will cycle the compressor to keep the system within acceptable operating parameters.
            </para>
            <para>When the ESC detects readings outside of the acceptable ranges, it will generate and log a diagnostic
                trouble code and requests the electronic gauge cluster to turn on the CHECK AC warning light. If the ESC
                determines that continued operation would be destructive, it shuts down the A/C system by preventing the
                compressor from turning on.
            </para>
            <para>Should a function of the HVAC system fail to operate, the problem could be attributed to one of the
                following electrical components:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Electrical System Controller (ESC) defective</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>fuse</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>wiring</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>HVAC control head</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>blower motor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>linear power module</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>air door actuator/motor</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>thermistor (refrigerant temperature sensor)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>pressure transducer (refrigerant pressure sensor)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>AC compressor/clutch</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>engine controller (engine RPM signal and cooling fan signal during high head pressure)</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>Malfunctions in the HVAC system could be attributed to either mechanical or electrical failures in the
                system. Diagnosis of a malfunctioning system should always begin by performing the procedures in the
                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602541.xml" xrefid="hl1602541">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl1602541"/>
                to determine what part of the system is malfunctioning. The procedures in the sections covering the
                electrical circuits will be referenced when an electrical malfunction is indicated. Use the
                troubleshooting procedures and table(s) in the referenced section to isolate and repair the fault.
            </para>
            <para>After repairs have been made, clear the fault codes and repeat the
                <hotlnk document="s16025_18.xml" xrefid="hl1602558">FAULT IDENTIFICATION PROCEDURE</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl1602558"/>
                to verify that all faults have been repaired.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602534.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602568.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
