<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - GLOSSARY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>GLOSSARY</title>
        <para>Refer to the following terms for a better understanding of the heater/air conditioning system.</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>ACCUMULATOR - A combination desiccant, filter, and storage container for liquid refrigerant.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ACTUATOR - An electrical device that performs a mechanical action based on an electrical input,
                    (similar to a servo motor).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>AIR CONDITIONER - A device used to control the temperature, humidity, cleanliness and movement of
                    air.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>AIR PRESSURE - The pressure exerted in every direction at any given point. Normal atmospheric
                    pressure (that is, the pressure caused by the weight of the atmosphere) at sea level is 101.60 kPa
                    (14.696 psi).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>AMBIENT AIR TEMPERATURE - The temperature of air around an object; the outside temperature.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>BLOWER - A motor and fan used to draw air through the evaporator, and force it through the heater
                    core and into the cab.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>LINEAR POWER MODULE - An electrical module that controls the amount of voltage going to the blower
                    motor, based on an input signal from the HVAC control head panel (and blower speed control). The
                    amount of voltage going to the blower motor determines the speed of the blower.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>BOILING POINT - The temperature at which a liquid changes to a gas, at a certain pressure.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>BULK CHARGING - Use of large containers of refrigerant for charging a refrigerant system. Normally
                    used for charging empty systems.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CFM - Cubic feet per minute. The metric equivalent of one CFM is 28.3 Liters per minute.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CHARGE - A specific amount of refrigerant or oil by volume or weight. Also, the act of placing an
                    amount of refrigerant or oil into the air conditioning system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>COLD - The absence of heat. (The lowest possible temperature is believed to be -273 degrees C
                    (-459 degrees F).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>COMPRESSOR - An assembly used to draw low pressure, low temperature refrigerant gas from the
                    evaporator and squeeze it into a high pressure, high temperature gas. This causes the refrigerant to
                    have a higher temperature than the surrounding air, allowing the condenser to change the gas back
                    into a liquid. A secondary purpose of the compressor is to move refrigerant and oil through the
                    system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CONDENSATE - Water, taken from the air, which forms (condenses) on the outer surface of the
                    evaporator.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CONDENSER - A heat exchanger that is used to remove heat from refrigerant, changing it from a high
                    temperature, high pressure gas into a high temperature, high pressure liquid.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>CONTAMINANTS - Anything other than refrigerant or refrigerant oil in the system. Usually means
                    water in the system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DEHUMIDIFY - To remove water from the air, at the evaporator coils.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DESICCANT - A drying agent used in the refrigerant system (in the accumulator) to remove
                    moisture.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DISCHARGE - To remove some or all of the refrigerant from the air conditioning system using a
                    recovery/recycling station.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DISCHARGE LINE - Connects the refrigerant compressor outlet to the condenser inlet. (High pressure
                    line).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DISCHARGE PRESSURE - Pressure of the refrigerant leaving the compressor; high side pressure.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DISCHARGE SERVICE PORT - A fitting that is located in the system on the discharge (high pressure)
                    side of the compressor. It allows the connection of service equipment for monitoring high side
                    pressure and for performing other service related tasks.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>DRYING AGENT - See "Desiccant."</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EVACUATE - Evacuation pumps the contents out of the refrigerant system, creating a vacuum. It
                    dehydrates all traces of moisture and is used to determine if the system has any leaks before
                    installing a charge of refrigerant in the system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EVAPORATE - A change of state from a liquid to a gas.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>EVAPORATOR CORE - A component of the air conditioning system in which liquid refrigerant changes
                    to a gas after it absorbs heat from the air. Also collects cab moisture.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>FLUSHING - A process of forcing a solvent through a refrigerant part to remove dirt and
                    contaminants. Flushing is used to remove heavy contamination, such as gritty oil and large dirt
                    buildup, that cannot be removed by purging.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>FREEZE-UP - Failure of a unit to operate properly because of ice forming at the orifice tube
                    orifice or on the evaporator coils or fins.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>HEAD PRESSURE - Refrigerant pressure from the discharge side of the compressor to the condenser
                    and orifice tube.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>HUMIDITY - The amount of water vapor in the air.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>LEAK DETECTOR - A device used to detect a leak in the air conditioning system.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>LOW SUCTION PRESSURE - Low side pressure that is lower than normal due to a system problem.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MAGNETIC CLUTCH - An electrical coupling device used to engage or disengage the refrigerant
                    compressor.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MANIFOLD GAUGE SET - A manifold that is complete with gauges and charging hoses and used to
                    measure or test pressure.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MICRON - A metric measurement of mercury equal to one-thousandth of one millimeter. Therefore,
                    one-tenth of an inch of mercury equals 2540 microns. Measurement in microns is the only accurate way
                    to determine the amount of pressure that is left in a refrigerant system by a high vacuum pump.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>MINERAL BASED OIL - A type of oil used on seals and O-rings in A/C systems to lubricate them and
                    keep them from drying out.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>NITROGEN - A colorless, odorless, dry, inert gas that can be used to purge light contaminants from
                    air conditioning parts.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>ORIFICE TUBE - A device that causes a pressure drop of the refrigerant and also regulates flow.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>OVERCHARGED - Too much refrigerant or oil in the system.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>PAG OIL - A specific type of oil carried by the refrigerant and used to lubricate the components
                    of some A/C systems.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>PRESSURE TRANSDUCER - A device with electrical characteristics that vary according to the pressure
                    it senses.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>PULSE WIDTH MODULATION - A type of electrical signal that uses pulses to represent specific
                    values.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>PURGE - To remove damp air, traces of refrigerant, and loose dirt from a system part by blowing
                    pressurized dry nitrogen through the part.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>REFRIGERANT (R-134a) - The cooling agent used in automotive air conditioning systems.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>REFRIGERATION CYCLE - The complete circulation of refrigerant through an air conditioning system,
                    accompanied by changes in temperature and pressure.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>SUCTION PRESSURE - Compressor inlet pressure (the system low side pressure).</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>SUCTION SIDE SERVICE PORT - A fitting that is located in the system on the suction (low pressure)
                    side of the compressor. It allows the connection of service equipment for monitoring low side
                    pressure and for performing other service related tasks.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>THERMISTOR - A device, used as an sensor for an electrical circuit, that changes its apparent
                    resistance based on the temperature it senses.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>THERMOSTATIC VACUUM GAUGE - A high vacuum gauge sensitive to pressures ranging from atmospheric
                    pressure to less than 1 micron, with scales reading from 25,000 microns to 1 micron.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>VACUUM - Refers to pressure that is less than atmospheric pressure.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>VACUUM PUMP - A mechanical device used to evacuate and place a high vacuum in the refrigerant
                    system.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>VAPOR - The gaseous state of material.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_110.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602570.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
