<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CAB - TILT: 9600 AND 9700 SLEEPER AND NON-SLEEPER CABS -
        CAB TILTING PROCEDURE - BLEEDING THE CAB HYDRAULIC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1600604" svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="3">
        <title>BLEEDING THE CAB HYDRAULIC SYSTEM</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>To operate efficiently and without excessive cab bounce, which may be detrimental to the cab
                    structure, the hydraulic system must have a solid head of fluid (no air in the system). If air in
                    the system is suspected, bleed system as follows.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Be sure that the pump reservoir is at the proper level.
            <hotlnk document="s16006_7.xml" xrefid="f1600608">Figure 8</hotlnk>shows the location of the reservoir fill
            screw.
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600613">Figure 13</hotlnk>
            and
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600614">Figure 14</hotlnk>
            show the ram hydraulic lines.
        </para>
        <figure id="f1600613" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600613" filename="../figg16/g1600613.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 13. Cab Lift Ram Hose Connections, Right Side</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. RAISE PORT CONNECTION</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HYDRAULIC LINES</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <figure id="f1600614" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1600614" filename="../figg16/g1600614.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 14. Cab Lift Ram and Hose Connections, Left Side</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. RAISE PORT CONNECTION</callout1>
                <callout1>2. HYDRAULIC LINES</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn pump control lever to "RAISE" position and raise cab approximately 2 or 3 feet off the
                pads.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Support cab with suitable safety prop.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>There is a cab hydraulic bleeder screw located on the top of the left side cab latch assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600615">Figure 15</hotlnk>). With an assistant, bleed cab hydraulic system as follows.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600615" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600615" filename="../figg16/g1600615.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 15. Left Side Cab Latch (with Bleeder Screw) and Right Side Cab Latch</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the pump lever still in the RAISE position, have the assistant pump the handle. While
                the pump handle is in the downward stroke motion, open the bleeder screw until the pump handle comes to
                the end of the downward stroke, then close the bleeder screw.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat this procedure for 3 or 4 strokes of the pump then check and fill pump reservoir with
                fluid.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Repeat steps 2 and 3 until approximately 3 or 4 ounces of fluid have been bled from the
                system.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <para>Be sure that the pump reservoir is checked and filled to proper fluid level while bleeding the system.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the safety prop. Put pump control lever in DOWN position. Pump cab down. Be sure cab
                latches lock onto the pads. If latches do not lock automatically, lift the cab latch lever by hand. This
                action should lock the latch.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Place pump control lever momentarily in the RAISE position and then back to the DOWN
                position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check and fill reservoir to proper fluid level, which is to the bottom of the fill screw
                hole.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Raise and lower cab to check operation.</para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If cab latches do not lock properly, lubricate the latch assembly with engine oil.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_11.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006_13.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16006.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
