<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>New Vehicle Processing Manual - CF 500, CF 600 Heat Ventilation Air Conditioning (HVAC) System - SERVICE
        PROCEDURES - LEAK DETECTION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1603015" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="2">
        <title>LEAK DETECTION</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <table id="t1200010">
                <title>Special Tools</title>
                <tgroup cols="2">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.02*"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="0.98*"/>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603003.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitheight="96px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Electronic Leak Detector</para>
                                <para>ZTSE4617</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <graphic filename="../figG16/G1603014.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                         scalefitwidth="96px"/>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Ultraviolet (UV) Leak Detector Kit</para>
                                <para>ZTSE4618</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603004.xml" xrefid="hl1603004">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                        read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                        could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
                <caution>
                    <para>Good ventilation is necessary in the area where electronic A/C leak testing is to be carried
                        out. If the surrounding air is contaminated with refrigerant gas, the leak detector will
                        indicate this gas all the time. Odors from other chemicals such as antifreeze, diesel fuel, disc
                        brake cleaner or other cleaning solvents can cause the same problem. Using a fan to ventilate
                        the area to be tested before proceeding with the leak detection procedure is helpful in removing
                        small traces of contamination from the air, but the fan should be turned off during actual
                        testing.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>Refrigerant leaks are often indicated by an oily residue at the point of the leak.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>While performing a leak check, the system pressure should be between 413-551 kPa (60-80 psi)
                        at 24&#176;C (75&#176;F) with the engine off.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>If a refrigerant leak is detected:</para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Determine the leaking component.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Recover the refrigerant. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603003.xml" xrefid="hl1603003">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Make the necessary repairs.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Evacuate, leak test, and recharge the system. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603005.xml" xrefid="hl1603005">EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1603020">
            <title>Electronic Leak Detectors</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>In terms of sensitivity and safety, the electronic leak detector is excellent for finding both slow
                and major system leaks. Ensure that the detector being used is intended for use with R134a refrigerant.
                Many leak detectors intended for use with R-12 cannot detect R134a leaks.
            </para>
            <para>The unit is a hand-held device having a flexible probe used to seek out refrigerant leaks. An audio
                leak indicator signals a warning in the presence of a leak.
            </para>
            <para>Before starting to look for leaks, it is recommended to clean away all oil or grease, and blow away
                refrigerant residue from fittings and A/C components. All suspected areas should be cleaned using soap
                and water, not a solvent.
            </para>
            <para>It is important to become familiar with the leak detector instructions for the detector being used.
                The speed at which the probe is moved over the component being checked is very important in locating
                larger than permissible leaks. Leak check procedure should be in accordance with SAE J1628.
            </para>
            <para>A detected leak should be a flow of refrigerant, not a residual condition of refrigerant that is
                trapped under an oil film, etc. A detected leak rate in excess of 1.0 oz./year is unacceptable.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Ultraviolet Lamp Leak Testing</title>
            <para>An alternate method to electronic leak testing is ultraviolet light. A phosphor dye can be injected
                into the system that will produce a bright yellow-green trace at the leak, when illuminated by an
                ultraviolet (UV) lamp. The ZTSE4618 kit provides the UV lamp used to illuminate the suspected leaks. The
                kit also contains connection hoses and a dye injector, as well as, eyeglasses used to enhance the effect
                of the UV light on the dye.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The location of leaks can be pinpointed by the bright yellow-green glow of the fluorescent dye
                        under a UV lamp. Since more than one leak can exist, make sure to inspect each component, line
                        and fitting in the refrigerant system for a leak.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>It has been discovered during the use of UV light, and phosphor dyes, that other types of leaks may
                also appear as a yellow-green trace when the UV light shines on them. If an UV lamp is used for leak
                detection, it is recommended that an electronic leak detector also be used to verify that any detected
                leaks are, in fact, refrigerant leaks. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl1603020">ELECTRONIC LEAK DETECTORS</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603018.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030_HL1603006.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16030.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
