<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - COMPONENTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="4">
        <title>COMPONENTS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16025_3.xml" xrefid="f1602502">Figure 2</hotlnk>
                for locations of the components described in the following paragraphs
                <xref refid="f1602502"/>.
            </para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Compressor and Clutch</title>
            <para>The system uses a Sanden Model SD7H15 compressor configured with a proprietary International rear-port
                head to accommodate the new "C-plate" block-style fittings. It is mounted on the engine and is
                belt-driven through an electromagnetic clutch which acts to engage (turn ON) or disengage (turn OFF) the
                compressor in response to the air conditioning system controls (HVAC control panel and RCD system). When
                engaged, the clutch armature assembly is magnetically drawn to the pulley assembly on the compressor
                shaft, thereby engaging the clutch and allowing the drive belt to drive the compressor. A pressure
                relief valve on the compressor offers protection to the compressor in extreme high pressure conditions.
            </para>
            <para>These A/C system refrigerant and oil specifications are listed in
                <hotlnk xrefid="t1602502">Table 1</hotlnk>. In addition, a label located on the compressor lists the
                recommended type of refrigerant and oil to be used in the system, as well as the system oil capacity.
            </para>
            <table id="t1602502" tblwidth="pg-wide">
                <title>A/C System Refrigerant and Oil Specifications</title>
                <tgroup cols="4">
                    <colspec colname="col1" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col2" colwidth="1.53in"/>
                    <colspec colname="col3" colwidth="1.47in"/>
                    <colspec colname="COLSPEC0" colwidth="1.50in"/>
                    <thead>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" align="center">
                                <para>REFRIGERANTTYPE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" align="center">
                                <para>REFRIGERANTCHARGE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" align="center">
                                <para>REFRIGERANTOIL TYPE</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" align="center">
                                <para>REFRIGERANTOIL CAPACITY</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody>
                        <row>
                            <entry colname="col1" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>R-134a</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col2" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>30 oz.</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="col3" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>PAG oil</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry colname="COLSPEC0" valign="bottom" align="center">
                                <para>300 cc</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Condenser</title>
            <para>The air conditioning condenser is located at the front of the vehicle between the engine radiator and
                the grille. The condenser is a heat exchanger made of fin and tube construction, with "C-plate"
                block-style inlet and outlet fittings.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pressure Transducer</title>
            <para>The pressure transducer (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602507">Figure 7</hotlnk>) is a pressure-sensing device threaded into the refrigerant
                line between the condenser output and the orifice tube near the evaporator input. The transducer
                provides an electrical signal to the RCD system which monitors and controls the operation of the A/C
                system. The refrigerant system does not have to be discharged to replace the pressure transducer.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602507" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602507.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 7. Pressure Transducer</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Orifice Tube (Evaporator Input Orifice)</title>
            <para>The orifice tube (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602508">Figure 8</hotlnk>) is located inside the inlet A/C line to the evaporator
                core. The orifice tube is directional. The end nearest to the O-ring must be inserted into the A/C line
                first. The orifice tube inserts snugly into the A/C line and contains a calibrated opening that allows a
                measured flow of the high pressure liquid refrigerant into the evaporator during the cooling cycle. The
                orifice tube can be replaced without replacing the evaporator inlet line.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602508" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602508.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="352px"
                         scalefitheight="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Orifice Tube (Clutch Cycling Orifice Tube)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Evaporator</title>
            <para>The evaporator core is located in the evaporator housing mounted on the engine side of the dash panel.
                The core is a cooling assembly made of plate and fin construction, with "C-plate" block-style inlet and
                outlet fittings. Drain valves for both condensate and rain water are incorporated into the bottom of the
                evaporator housing. Service access for the air filter is through the large outside air inlet in the cowl
                tray and the top surface of the evaporator housing.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Accumulator</title>
            <para>The accumulator is a canister mounted to the evaporator housing on the dash panel. A desiccant inside
                the accumulator is used to absorb moisture from the refrigerant. The desiccant also contains a dye to
                allow easier detection of refrigerant leaks. The evaporator output thermistor is mounted in the top of
                the accumulator where it can monitor the temperature of the refrigerant exiting the evaporator.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Thermistors (Evaporator Inlet and Outlet)</title>
            <para>A thermistor (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602509">Figure 9</hotlnk>) is mounted in the evaporator input line immediately after
                the orifice tube. This thermistor senses the temperature of the refrigerant entering the evaporator. As
                mentioned in the previous paragraph, another thermistor is mounted to the top of the accumulator to
                sense the refrigerant temperature at the evaporator outlet. The resistance value of each thermistor is
                determined by the temperature of the refrigerant at its location. The resistance values of these
                thermistors are monitored by the RCD system which is used to control A/C system operation and detect
                system faults. The refrigerant system must be discharged before removing and replacing either
                thermistor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602509" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602509.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"
                         scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Thermistor</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HVAC Plumbing</title>
            <para>New International "C-plate" style block fittings are utilized on all refrigerant line connections in
                the A/C system. This fitting incorporates a secondary moisture and dirt seal within a unique plate
                inserted into the block fitting. The primary O-ring seal has a larger cross section for improved sealing
                as well. Refrigerant hoses are constructed from steel tubing coupled to Goodyear Galaxy hose. This nylon
                barrier type of hose prevents the refrigerant from escaping through the walls of the hose into the
                atmosphere. When servicing air conditioning systems, use only replacement hoses approved for air
                conditioning systems.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Cooling Fan Drive Solenoid Valve</title>
            <para>On some models the cooling fan clutch is operated by compressed air. The air is controlled by a
                solenoid valve that is normally operated by the engine cooling system; however, when the HVAC pressure
                transducer detects a high discharge pressure, the ESC sends a signal to the engine controller to engage
                the cooling fan drive.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Heater Core</title>
            <para>The heater core is located in the heater housing mounted in the cab under the right side of the
                instrument panel. The heater core is a heating assembly made of fin and tube construction, with inlet
                and outlet fittings for connecting the heater hoses from the engine cooling system. The inlet and outlet
                fittings protrude through the cowl directly above the evaporator housing. Engine coolant flows through
                the heater core at all times. The temperature of the air output by the heating/air conditioning system
                is determined by diverting more or less of the input air through the heater core. The heater core is
                serviced from inside the cab.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blower Assembly</title>
            <para>The blower assembly is located in the blower scroll housing (part of the heater unit), mounted in the
                cab under the right side of the instrument panel. The blower assembly used in the heater or heater-air
                conditioning system consists of a permanent magnet motor attached to a balanced 'squirrel-cage' fan
                unit. The motor speed is controlled by the left knob on the HVAC control panel on the instrument panel.
                The blower provides air circulation through the heater core and evaporator, and delivery of the treated
                air throughout the cab interior.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Linear Power Module</title>
            <para>The Linear Power Module (LPM) (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602510">Figure 10</hotlnk>) is mounted to the blower scroll housing (part of the
                heater unit), located in the cab under the right side of the instrument panel. The LPM is used to
                provide seven blower speed settings, and is controlled by the left knob (blower speed control) on the
                HVAC control panel. The LPM establishes the blower speed by reading the HVAC control panel output signal
                (0 to 4.75 Vdc), based on the setting of the blower speed control knob. The LPM responds by acting as a
                variable resistance between the blower motor and ground. As the blower speed control is turned cw, the
                apparent resistance to ground decreases, the voltage across the blower motor increases, and the blower
                speed increases.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1602510" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602510.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="472px"
                         scalefitheight="352px"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Linear Power Module</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HVAC Control Panel</title>
            <para>The HVAC control panel is located at the top of the center console of the instrument panel. The
                control panel consists of three knobs actuating three long life potentiometers. Internally, the control
                panel contains circuitry that electronically controls the blower motor speed and the three air door
                actuator motors. The blower speed control is detented to provide seven distinct blower speeds, in
                addition to the OFF position. The temperature control has fifteen detents. The mode control is used to
                select the HVAC operating mode, indicated by seven mode icons and five dots (for 'in-between' modes).
                The 'heat only' system has five mode icons, and four dots for 'in-between' modes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
