<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - PAINT PROBLEMS - APPLICATION
        PROBLEMS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
        <title>APPLICATION PROBLEMS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The most common application problems are:</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Blushing</title>
            <para>This term applies to the milky haze or mist that appears in a paint finish. It is usually caused by
                the trapping of moisture droplets in the paint on wet or humid days. Blushing can be avoided by using a
                slow drying thinner or by lowering the gun air pressure slightly. Most blushing can be spotted during
                painting. To correct the problem, add retarder to the paint mixture and respray. If blushing is spotted
                after painting, sand to eliminate it and recoat.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Dirt in Finish</title>
            <para>Dirt can be blown into the paint very easily when the painting work area and vehicle are not properly
                cleaned before painting. If dirt does get into the finish, it should be rubbed out with a rubbing
                compound or sanded out if the dirt is deep in the finish.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fisheye</title>
            <para>A very common problem for all painters, fisheyes are the "holes" in the paint film which allow the
                underlying finish to be seen. Normally this problem is due to the incorrect cleaning of the surface and
                the presence of wax silicones. If the paint starts to fisheye while painting, either clean the paint off
                while wet and thoroughly clean the surface with a wax and grease remover, or, after the paint coat has
                set up, apply another coat containing the recommended amount of "fisheye eliminator" available from most
                paint manufacturers.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Mottling</title>
            <para>This problem is characterized by a spotty or streaked appearance in a metallic paint finish. Mottling
                is caused by the metal flakes floating together after application due to inadequate mixing, excess
                solvent, or by holding the gun too close to the paint surface during spraying. If mottling occurs, allow
                the paint to set up and then apply a drier coat, or increase the distance of the gun to the paint
                surface. Badly mottled finishes may need to be sanded down and repainted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Orange Peel</title>
            <para>Orange peel has the appearance of a bumpy surface, much like the skin of an orange. It is caused by
                improper paint flow to the wrong spray technique or air/paint mixture, high air temperature, too little
                solvent in the paint, or poorly mixed paint. Orange peel can be prevented by adjusting the solvent mix
                to compensate for high temperature or rapid drying time and by adjusting the air mixture and spray
                pattern. In extreme cases, paint may need to be sanded and resprayed.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Pinholing</title>
            <para>Tiny holes may appear in a finish due to several different reasons such as applying paint over a moist
                surface, contaminants in paint or air lines, improper sealing of primer or plastic filler/putty areas,
                excessively heavy or wet paint coats, or poor spray technique, all of which tend to trap moisture or
                solvent under the paint finish. Review painting conditions and techniques if pinholing occurs during
                painting. Severe cases should be sanded down and repainted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Runs and Sags</title>
            <para>Often caused by applying too much paint at once, runs and sags may also appear when the paint contains
                too much solvent, when the air/paint mixture of the gun is incorrect, or when the gun is held too close
                to the paint surface. Runs and sags must be sanded out and the surface refinished.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Streaking</title>
            <para>Seen as a zebra-like effect, streaking is caused by tilting the spray gun during paint application
                instead of keeping the gun parallel to the surface. Mild streaking can be blended into additional cover
                coats, but heavy streaking requires sanding and compounding and sometimes repainting.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Wrinkling</title>
            <para>This condition is caused by unequal drying of the paint finish, usually due to excessively thick or
                solvent heavy paint coats, varying temperatures during paint application, or too many paint coats.
                Wrinkled paint must be removed and the surface repainted.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_17.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_19.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
