<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">

    <svcsubproc>
        <title>Installation (Unobstructed Access)</title>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>For proper rear window removal and installation, you will need the International&#174; Bonded
                    Windshield Tool Kit ZTSE4470. This kit comes complete with a toolbox and all the tools required to
                    remove and install bonded windshields. To order, call toll free in U.S. and Canada 1-800-520-2584 or
                    Fax 1-800-578-7375. For additional materials contact International&#174; dealer for service parts.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>For rear window glass installation, use the Windshield Replacement Kit 2592784C91. A pneumatic or
                    electric caulking gun is required for application of the adhesive.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603812" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603812.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 27. Windshield Replacement Kit</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. 43532 BODY PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. 43518 CLEAR GLASS PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>3. 43520A BLACK-OUT GLASS PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BETASEAL EXPRESS ONE-PART URETHANE ADHESIVE</callout1>
                <callout1>5. CARTRIDGE TIPS</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <para>The windshield replacement kit includes the following components:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>43532 Body Primer</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>43518 Clear Glass Primer</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>43520A Black-Out Glass Primer</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Betaseal Express One-Part Urethane Adhesive</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Cartridge Tips</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>These materials must be used on or before the expiration date marked on the container. Please
                    refer to the individual containers for expiration dates.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Additional materials needed include the following:</para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>Essex&#174; GC800 Glass Cleaner</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>White or Brown Paper Towels</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Pneumatic or Electric Caulking Gun</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Wear protective work gloves when handling the rear window glass. Also wear appropriate protective
                    gloves when using any of the Betaseal system chemicals from the Essex&#174; windshield installation
                    kit.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <randlist type="bullet">
                    <item>
                        <para>Use only heat-treated glass (AS-2 per ANSI Z26.1 - latest revision).</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Before installing new rear window glass, wipe off any water remaining around rear window
                            fence and surrounding cab area with a lint-free cloth.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </randlist>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dry-fit the rear window glass in the window fence to ensure it fits properly. Align window
                locator tabs between window locators on the cab and ensure window spring clip is inside the top of the
                window fence.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">While the rear window glass is in place, attach a piece of tape (as a reference mark) across
                the top and bottom, center portion of rear window glass and cab. Use a utility knife and cut the tape
                between the cab and rear window glass.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove rear window glass and place it on a suitable padded work stand.</para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603813" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603813.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 28. Removing Old Adhesive</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. OLD ADHESIVE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. REAR WINDOW FENCE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. GASKET CHISEL</callout1>
                <callout1>4. OLD ADHESIVE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a gasket chisel, remove old adhesive from rear window fence. Leaving a thin layer 5/64
                to 1/8 in. (2 to 3 mm) thick of old adhesive is acceptable. While removing old adhesive, try to maintain
                a consistent thickness on the windshield fence.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove any dirt or water remaining from rear window removal with a brush or clean, lint-free
                cloth.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603814" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603814.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 29. Applying Body Primer</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. 43532 BODY PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. APPLICATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. WINDSHIELD FENCE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shake 43532 body primer container for at least one minute.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply 43532 body primer with a clean, dry applicator to cover scratches and bare metal on
                the rear window fence. DO NOT apply 43532 body primer over old urethane adhesive left on rear window
                fence. Allow primer to dry for 6 to 10 minutes minimum after application.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603826" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603826.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 30. Removing Flash</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. BONDING SURFACE</callout1>
                <callout1>2. RAZOR BLADE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using a razor blade, if necessary, and plastic scrubbing pad, remove any flash from bonding
                surface of new rear window. Clean new, rear window thoroughly with Essex&#174; glass cleaner GC800 and
                dry thoroughly with paper towels. Ensure rear window is completely clean and dry before proceeding.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Read next step thoroughly and completely to ensure the correct application and removal of the
                    43518 clear glass primer.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603827" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603827.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 31. Applying Clear Glass Primer</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. 43518 CLEAR GLASS PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. APPLICATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. REAR WINDOW GLASS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. WHITE OR BROWN PAPER TOWEL</callout1>
                <callout1>5. BONDING SURFACE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shake 43518 clear glass primer container for at least one minute.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply 43518 clear glass primer with a clean, dry applicator to the rear window glass bonding
                surface only.
                <emph type="bold">NOTE - If clear glass primer is applied to clear glass surface, glass will haze.
                </emph>
                Immediately wipe clear glass primer off bonding surface by following 8 to 10 inches (20 to 25 cm) behind
                the applicator with a white or brown paper towel.
                <emph type="bold">DO NOT</emph>
                use a cloth shop towel. After completing first application of clear glass primer, repeat application and
                removal process.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603828" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603828.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 32. Applying Black-Out Glass Primer</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. 43520A BLACK-OUT GLASS PRIMER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. APPLICATOR</callout1>
                <callout1>3. WINDOW GLASS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. BONDING SURFACE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shake 43520A black-out glass primer container for at least one minute.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply 43520A black-out glass primer with a clean, dry applicator to the windshield bonding
                surface. Allow primer to dry to a tack-free condition for 6 to 10 minutes minimum after application.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Once the rear window glass has been primed, ensure there is no contact with bonding surface, as
                    oil from skin will affect bonding performance. If the rear window glass is not bonded properly, the
                    cab strength and safety would be compromised. If contact with bonding surface has occurred, repeat
                    the cleaning process and reapply 43520A black-out glass primer and allow it to dry for 6 to 10
                    minutes before applying Betaseal Express one-part urethane adhesive .
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603818" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603818.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 33. Adhesive Tube and Cartridge Tip</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. TRIM DIMENSIONS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CARTRIDGE TIP</callout1>
                <callout1>3. ADHESIVE TUBE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure, mark, and trim the cartridge tip to trim dimensions shown for proper adhesive
                application.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach cartridge tip to adhesive tube.</para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Application of adhesive bead on new rear window glass shall be 0 to 5/64 in. (0 to 2 mm) from
                    encapsulation edge and be at least 5/8 to 3/4 inch (16 to 19 mm) high and 3/8 to 1/2 inch (10 to 13
                    mm) wide maximum.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603829" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603829.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 34. Applying Adhesive to Rear Window Glass</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. PNEUMATIC OR ELECTRIC CAULKING GUN</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CARTRIDGE TIP</callout1>
                <callout1>3. ADHESIVE</callout1>
                <callout1>4. PLASTIC OR WOOD TONGUE DEPRESSOR</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Holding pneumatic or electric caulking gun as close to a 90-degree angle as possible, start
                applying adhesive at the center of the bottom edge of the rear window glass. Apply a uniform bead all
                the way around the rear window glass, overlapping the adhesive at the seam slightly. Use a plastic or
                wood tongue depressor to smooth or even out adhesive as required before installing rear window glass.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603830" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603830.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 35. Installing Rear Window Glass</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. TAPE MARKS</callout1>
                <callout1>2. REAR WINDOW</callout1>
                <callout1>3. TAPE MARKS</callout1>
                <callout1>4. CAB</callout1>
                <callout1>5. WINDOW LOCATOR TABS</callout1>
                <callout1>6. WINDOW LOCATORS ON CAB</callout1>
                <callout1>7. WINDOW SPRING CLIP</callout1>
                <callout1>8. WINDOW FENCE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Align rear window with tape marks on rear window and cab. Align window locator tabs between
                window locators on cab. Ensure window spring clip is inside the top of the window fence.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the aid of an assistant, gently push on the rear window glass all around the outer
                edges to seat it properly against the window fence.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1603831" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603831.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 36. Taping Rear Window Glass in Place</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. REAR WINDOW</callout1>
                <callout1>2. TAPE</callout1>
                <callout1>3. BACKSIDE OF CAB</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tape the rear window to the backside of the cab in four locations while adhesive cures.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the adhesive has cured, remove all pieces of tape and clean the rear window and
                surrounding areas.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>While putting the seats back into the cab, be careful not to hit the rear window glass while the
                    adhesive is curing. This may cause rear window glass to not seal properly and could cause leaking.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If rear bench seat was removed, install the rear bench seat. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16038_X1603804.xml" xrefid="x1603804">
                    <emph type="bold">REAR BENCH SEAT</emph>
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x1603804"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If front seats were removed, install the front seats. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16038_X1603805.xml" xrefid="x1603805">
                    <emph type="bold">FRONT SEATS</emph>
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="x1603805"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcsubproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16038.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
