<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a) - REMOVE
        AND INSTALL - COMPRESSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601703" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="0">
        <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The fittings on the service hoses for R-134a air conditioning systems are standard Metric SAE
                        quick connect fittings that will work only on R-134a air conditioning systems service ports.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from both service ports.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the recovery/recycling station hoses to the service ports, making sure that the
                    hand valves on the recovery/ recycling station are fully closed by turning them clockwise.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Start with the blue manifold suction hose and connect it to the compressor suction (low
                    pressure) service port. Connect the red hose to the high pressure discharge service port.
                </para>
                <para>Turn the Metric SAE quick-connect valves on the red and blue hoses completely off (turn
                    clockwise).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Service ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not visible,
                            you can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter system hose
                            connected to the compressor.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">DO NOT OPEN the valves on the Metric SAE quick connect fittings until they are connected
                    to the service ports on a vehicle.
                </para>
                <para>Turn the Metric SAE quick-connect valves on the red and blue hoses completely on (turn
                    counterclockwise).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open both valves of the recovery/ recycling station. Turn the main power switch on and
                    press the compressor start switch. The recovery/recycling Station will automatically shut off when
                    the refrigerant in the system has been exhausted to the storage tank.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After the recovery/recycling station has shut off, close both valves on the
                    recovery/recycling station and on the metric SAE quick connect fittings at the compressor. Remove
                    the blue and red hoses from the service ports on the compressor.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the high and low pressure hoses from the compressor. Cap the end of both
                    lines to keep foreign material and moisture from entering the system.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slack off on the belt tensioner and remove the compressor drive belt. Disconnect the
                    clutch electrical connector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the four (4) bolts that secure the compressor to its bracket and remove the
                    compressor from the vehicle.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When removing compressor, be certain to seal all openings to prevent entry of dirt and
                            moisture.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not invert the compressor beyond a horizontal position during compressor removal or
                            installation as refrigerant oil will leak into the suction cavity. This will result in the
                            piston drawing the oil into the cylinder and damaging the compressor during initial
                            operation after installation.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Not all parts of the compressor are serviceable. The clutch assembly is replaced as a unit
                            and the compressor seal and valve assemblies are supplied as service kits. More extensive
                            service requirements may necessitate replacement of the compressor.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the compressor on the mounting bracket and insert the four mounting bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the compressor drive belt, align the clutch drive pulley with the accessory
                    drive pulley or water pump pulley and tension the belt as specified in
                    <hotlnk document="s16017x_13.xml" xrefid="hl1601702">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the compressor mounting bolts to 20 to 25 ft-lbs. (27 to 34 N&#183;m) and
                    install supporting braces if applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Re-install the low and high pressure hoses to the top of the compressor. Be sure to use
                    new O-rings, lubricated in mineral oil.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge the air conditioning system as specified in GROUP 16 - AIR CONDITIONING THEORY,
                    DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_HL1601704.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
