<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a) - REMOVE
        AND INSTALL - VALVE PLATE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="4">
        <title>VALVE PLATE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>The cylinder head is made of aluminum and care should be taken when removing it not to damage
                        the sealing surfaces.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the screws in head (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601715">Figure 15</hotlnk>) and remove the valve plate and head from the cylinder
                    by prying or tapping under the ears which extend from the valve plate. If the head and valve plate
                    adhere, hold the head and tap the valve plate ears away from the head with a soft hammer
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601715" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601715" filename="../figg16/g1601715.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Remove Screws In Head</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not hit or tap the head to separate the head and valve plate because damage to the head
                            may result.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All gasket material adhering to the head, valve plate, or crankcase should be carefully
                    removed in such a manner that the machined sealing surfaces are not scratched or nicked.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Valves and valve plates are furnished only as a complete assembly.</para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a thin film of clean mineral oil on the area of the crankcase to be covered by the
                    crankcase gasket. Place the cylinder gasket in position on the cylinder so the dowel pins in the
                    crankcase go through the dowel pin holes in the cylinder gasket.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a thin film of clean mineral oil to the top and bottom valve plate areas to be
                    covered by gaskets. Place the valve plate in position on the cylinder gasket so the discharge valve
                    assemblies (i.e., the smaller diameter assemblies with the restrainer over the valve reed) are
                    facing up and the locating dowel pins go through the dowel pin holes in the valve plate (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601716">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601716" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601716" filename="../figg16/g1601716.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Place Head Gasket In Position</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the head gasket, with the bead facing up, in position on the valve plate so the
                    dowel pins go through the dowel pin holes in the gasket (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601716">Figure 16</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply a light film of clean mineral oil on the machined surface of the cylinder head
                    which matches the head gasket. Place the head on the cylinder head gasket so the dowel pins go into
                    the dowel pin holes in the head.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Insert the head screws and run in all the screws (by hand) until the heads make contact.
                    Tighten the head screws (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601717">Figure 17</hotlnk>) to 17 to 25 ft-lbs. (23.0 to 33.9 N&#183;m) in
                    sequence shown in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601718">Figure 18</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601717" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601717" filename="../figg16/g1601717.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. Tighten Head Screws</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601718" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601718" filename="../figg16/g1601718.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="312px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18. Tighten In Proper Sequence</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
