<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>REPAIR INSTRUCTIONS FOR FIBERGLASS AND PLASTIC (ABS) MATERIAL - PLASTIC (ABS) - REPAIR PROCEDURE</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="3">
        <title>REPAIR PROCEDURE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Identify Nature of Damage</title>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Minor scratches, abrasions</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Small cracks or gouges</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Major damage (holes with loose or missing pieces)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Structural damage (to the mounting system or to accessory attachment surface)</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Stress lines</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Prepare Damaged Area</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove all parts and accessories interfering with the area to be repaired. Clean the
                    repair area with Sikkens No. M600 Wax and Grease Remover, or equivalent, to remove all surface
                    residue, then wipe dry.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Grind and sand the area prior to repair if necessary. Care must taken to keep the
                    grinder or sander in constant motion to prevent heat build up. Blow the area clean.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>FIBERGLASS ABS PLASTIC REPAIRS - To avoid breathing dust and fumes, wear approved
                            protective equipment. Breathing fiberglass ABS plastic dust and/or fumes can be hazardous to
                            your health.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>1. OSHA standards should be consulted with respect to mandatory requirements as well as
                            suggested procedures to minimize exposure. (Reference: Title 29, Code of Federal
                            Regulations, Section 1910, 1001.)
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>2. Whenever possible work on fiberglass and ABS plastics in a separate area away from
                            other operations.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>3. Always wear a respirator approved by NIOSH or MSHA during all fiberglass or ABS plastic
                            repairs.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>4. Worker clean-up. Wash your hands before eating, drinking or smoking.</para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Repair Minor Scratches or Abrasions</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1600358">Figure 58</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1600358" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1600358" filename="../figg16/G1600358.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 58. Minor Scratches</caption>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clean the area with Sikkens No. M600 surface cleaner, or equivalent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Scuff the damaged area with a Scotch Brite No. 7447 Red Pad, then clean the area.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Paint with Sikkens Autocryl Filler, Autocryl Color and Matting Clear.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Repair Small Cracks or Gouges</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill a small hole at each end of the crack to stop crack extension.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Form a V-groove the length of the damage using a burr bit on a drill or equivalent (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1600359">Figure 59</hotlnk>). The sides of the "V" should be tapered no more than
                    45 degrees.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1600359" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1600359" filename="../figg16/G1600359.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 59. Form V-Groove the Length of Damage</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Care should be taken when grooving the damaged area. The bumper end caps and the side
                            skirts are .125 inch thick. Small cracks or gouges can become major repairs. This is because
                            large cracks will result when too much material is removed during the repair.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Scuff the area about 1/2 inch (13 mm) larger than the damaged area with Scotch Brite No.
                    7447 Red Pad.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">The damaged area is then filled with hot melt adhesive, epoxy adhesive/filler, or sealed
                    using the hot welding technique.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After drying and cooling, the patched area is sanded to match the surrounding area and
                    is ready for finish.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl160031a">
            <title>Major Repairs (Holes With Loose or Missing Pieces)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Cut out the damaged area. If the damage is only on the outside wall of a double walled
                    panel, cut a hole large enough in the rear wall to allow a patch one inch (25 mm) larger than the
                    surface hole to pass through.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Apply the surface patch to the inside of the outer wall with epoxy adhesive. Apply a
                    patch to the outside of the inner wall using the same technique. Make sure each patch is overlapping
                    the edge of the hole by approximately 1/2 inch (13 mm) all around.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Fill the outer patched surface with epoxy adhesive/filler, then sand with coarse (No.
                    40) grit sand paper to match the surrounding contour.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Finish sand and feather edge with No. 220/360 grit sand paper. The area is now ready for
                    finishing.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Structural Repairs</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare and patch the damaged area the same as
                    <hotlnk xrefid="hl160031a">Major Repairs</hotlnk>.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Components such as bracket mounts, etc. can be fabricated from sheet stock using standard
                            shop tools, a heat gun and adhesives (
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1600360">Figure 60</hotlnk>).
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f1600360" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1600360" filename="../figg16/G1600360.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 60. Bracket Mounts, Etc. Can Be Fabricated From Sheet Stock</caption>
                    <calloutgroup>
                        <callout1>1. FASTENING FLANGE</callout1>
                        <callout1>2. MOUNTING SURFACE</callout1>
                    </calloutgroup>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use epoxy adhesive/filler to attach the components. Reinforcements will be important in
                    these situations because of stress and vibration experienced in these areas.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_16.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003_18.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
