<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SYSTEM MAINTENANCE - PRE-SEASON SERVICING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390601" svcproctype="pm" graphiccount="0">
        <title>PRE-SEASON SERVICING</title>
        <para>Experience has shown that many unsatisfactory conditions incurred with heating and air conditioning
            systems result from lack of regular maintenance. Preventive maintenance and cleanliness of all components
            within the system are extremely important. A complete step-by-step pre-season checkout of the air
            conditioner/heater system will substantially increase satisfactory operation during the operating season.
        </para>
        <para>Perform the following procedures:</para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the mounting fasteners of each component for looseness.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check condition, tension and alignment of all drive belts. Refer to GROUP 12- ENGINE section
                in the Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check condition of heater hoses and engine cooling system hoses. Replace if necessary.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the vehicle coolant level is correct.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check refrigerant hose retention and condition. Look for cracks, chafing, or other damage.
                Inspect all tubing and hoses for dirty or loose connections. All connections must be clean and tight.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>If a patch of oily residue is found at or near a connection it may indicate a refrigerant leak.
                    Note its location in case a system operational test indicates a refrigerant leak or a low
                    refrigerant condition.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Cleanliness of the air conditioner components cannot be over-emphasized. Lack of proper attention
                    in this area is one of the major causes of costly and unsatisfactory unit operation.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Never force the fresh/recirculate air door open. If the door position must be changed; turn on
                    key, set mode control to FLOOR, turn off key. Forcing the door will result in a broken door shaft
                    and a costly repair.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the filter elements in the evaporator housing and the housing air intake. If the
                vehicle is equipped with a sleeper HVAC system, check the rear system filter element. Clean or replace
                filter elements if necessary. To access the filter in the front evaporator housing, refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390805.xml" xrefid="hl160390805">REMOVE AND INSTALL, AIR FILTER</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl160390805"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>When using a pressure washer to clean any heat exchanger (radiator, condenser, evaporator, or
                    charge air cooler); use caution and maintain distance from the component with the pressure washer.
                    Do not spray the component fins at an angle as fin damage may occur and reduce efficiency.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Clean all foreign material from condenser and radiator fins. As often as necessary, spray
                water through the condenser towards the radiator and through the radiator towards the condenser to flush
                debris from the fins. If necessary, spray the component with a cleaning solution, allow to soak 20 - 30
                minutes, then rinse with clean water.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate front air conditioner system and check operation of controls.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check operation of front blower (airflow matches selected blower speed).</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the front system is cooling properly in the A/C modes and heating properly in
                the heat modes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the vehicle is equipped with a sleeper HVAC system, proceed to step 14; otherwise,
                continue to the next step.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use Diamond Logic Builder (DLB) and the electronic service tool to verify that no HVAC
                Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC's) are currently stored in the system. For complete information on viewing
                DTC's refer to the applicable Electrical Troubleshooting Guide, on ISIS.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no DTC's are present and the system is operating correctly, the pre-season check is
                completed.
            </para>
            <para>If the system appears to be malfunctioning refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390700.xml" xrefid="hl160390700">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl160390700"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the vehicle engine is running.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the
                <emph type="boldundersc">front</emph>
                HVAC control panel, set the blower speed control to midrange, and the mode control to a
                <emph type="bold">non-A/C</emph>
                mode.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>In the following steps, bar graphs representing the set points of the blower speed and temperature
                    controls should be displayed in the message display area of the gauge cluster. The bar graphs are
                    displayed only during, and for several seconds after, actuation of the controls. If the vehicle is
                    equipped with a DIGITAL rear HVAC control panel, the bar graphs will also be displayed at that
                    location.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate the blower speed controls for the sleeper HVAC system (rear control panel
                <emph type="bold">and</emph>
                instrument panel switches), and verify that the system responds correctly. Leave the rear blower speed
                set to mid-range.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the sleeper temperature rocker switch on the instrument panel, adjust the temperature
                set point to its highest setting, and verify that warm air is output from the sleeper vents.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Using the sleeper temperature control on the rear control panel, adjust the temperature set
                point to its lowest (coldest) setting. Verify that within 2 minutes the A/C compressor is energized and
                cool air is output from the sleeper vents.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use Diamond Logic Builder (DLB) and the electronic service tool to verify that no HVAC
                Diagnostic Trouble Codes (DTC's) are currently stored in the system. For complete information on viewing
                DTC's refer to the applicable Electrical Troubleshooting Guide, on ISIS.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If no DTC's are present and the system is operating correctly, the pre-season check is
                completed.
            </para>
            <para>If the system appears to be malfunctioning refer to the
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390700.xml" xrefid="hl160390700">DIAGNOSIS AND TROUBLESHOOTING</hotlnk>
                section
                <xref refid="hl160390700"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390600.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_20.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
