<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - HVAC CONTROL HEAD CIRCUITS - Extended Description
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Extended Description</title>
        <para>The HVAC control head connector terminal A1 is supplied switched ignition voltage, via circuit A75C, from
            a cab power distribution panel fuse (F6 - Early Prod. or F19 - Late Prod.). HVAC control head connector
            terminal A2 is supplied Battery voltage, via circuit A73B, from a cab power distribution panel fuse (F22 -
            Early Prod. or F10 - Late Prod.). HVAC control head connector terminal B6 is supplied ground from ground
            stud (1851), via circuits A11-GA and A74-G.
        </para>
        <para>Voltage for the control head lighting is supplied to control head connector terminal A12 from the
            Electronic Gauge Cluster (EGC) connector (1500) terminal 1.
        </para>
        <para>When the mode selection requires the control head to request AC compressor turn on, the control head
            places a ground on terminal A4 of connector (1200). This signal is routed by circuit A77 to the ESC at
            connector (1600) terminal 7.
        </para>
        <para>The HVAC control head sends a digital diagnostic signal to the ESC indicating the operating status of the
            control head and the circuits monitored by the control head. This signal is output from terminal A9 of
            connector (1200) and is routed by circuit A75A to ESC connector (1600) terminal 8.
        </para>
        <para>For more information about other control head circuits:
            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602563.xml" xrefid="hl1602563">MODE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT</hotlnk>,
            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602565.xml" xrefid="hl1602565">BLOWER MOTOR CIRCUIT</hotlnk>,
            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602564.xml" xrefid="hl1602564">TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT</hotlnk>, or
            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602562.xml" xrefid="hl1602562">RECIRCULATION ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT</hotlnk>,
            refer to the section covering that circuit.
        </para>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_65.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_67.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
