<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL LEVEL
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602557" svcproctype="check" graphiccount="3">
        <title>CHECKING COMPRESSOR OIL LEVEL</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not remove the oil fill plug to check the oil level in the refrigerant compressor after the A/C
                    system has been charged with refrigerant. The crankcase side of the compressor is under pressure and
                    personal injury may result.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <para>It is not possible to check the oil level in the compressor on an A/C system that is under system
            pressure. If it is suspected that there is not enough oil in the A/C system, it will be necessary to remove
            all of the oil currently in the system and refill the system with a full oil charge.
        </para>
        <para>The compressor oil level can be accurately checked only by removing the compressor from the vehicle and
            draining the oil into a calibrated container.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Verify that the system is discharged.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the compressor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the oil plug and drain as much oil as possible into a suitable calibrated container
                (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602545">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1602545" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602545.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="152px"/>
            <caption>Figure 46. Drain as Much Oil as Possible</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the caps (if present) from the suction and discharge ports.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Drain remaining compressor oil from the suction and discharge ports, into the calibrated
                container, while turning the shaft (clockwise only) by hand or with a socket wrench on the armature
                retaining nut (refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602546">Figure 47</hotlnk>). Replace the caps on the suction and discharge ports.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1602546" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602546.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="232px"/>
            <caption>Figure 47. Drain Oil While Turning Shaft</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure and record the amount of oil drained from the compressor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the oil for signs of contamination such as discoloration or foreign material.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the oil shows signs of contamination, replace the compressor.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If the oil is not contaminated, add the correct amount of new oil to the compressor as
                determined by the
                <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602526.xml" xrefid="hl1602526">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl1602526"/>. Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602547">Figure 48</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1602547" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1602547.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                     scalefitheight="192px"/>
            <caption>Figure 48. Add New Oil to Compressor</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install oil fill plug taking care not to twist the O-ring seal. Replace the O-ring if
                damaged. Torque oil plug to 15-20 N.m (11-15 lbf-ft). Do not over-tighten plug to stop a leak. Stop
                leaks first by fixing any seat damage, removing dirt and installing a new O-ring.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602526.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602534.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
