<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>SERVICING PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <para>R-12 and HFC-134A are classified as safe refrigerants; however, certain precautions must be observed
                to protect the parts involved and to prevent personal injury to service personnel.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>One of the most important measures to be taken while servicing air conditioning systems is
                        constant and adequate eye protection. Safety goggles or other adequate eye protection must be
                        worn. The temperature of liquid refrigerant is -15.7&#176;C (-100&#176;F). Serious injury or
                        blindness will result from refrigerant contacting the eyes.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>If the refrigerant should contact the eyes, DO NOT rub them. Splash the eyes with cold water to
                gradually get the temperature above the freezing point. See a doctor immediately.
            </para>
            <para>Should liquid refrigerant come in contact with the skin, the resulting injury should be treated the
                same as though the skin has been frostbitten or frozen.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not smoke or allow any type of fire or flame in the immediate area while servicing the air
                        conditioning system. Refrigerant is not combustible; however, in the presence of heat it changes
                        to phosgene, a poisonous gas. Inhalation can cause death or serious injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always use approved refrigerant recycling equipment when working with R-12 and HFC-134A. The
                        refrigerant evaporates very quickly and may displace the oxygen surrounding the work area
                        creating the hazard of suffocation or brain damage, especially in small or enclosed areas.
                        Federal and State laws require that R-12 refrigerant be recovered and recycled to help protect
                        the environment.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Never weld, solder, steam clean or use excessive heat on any of the air conditioning lines or
                        equipment while the system is charged. Heat applied to any part will cause the pressure within
                        the system to become excessive, which may result in an explosion and possible personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be certain that pressurized refrigerant containers are not exposed to open flame or
                        temperatures above 125&#176;F (51&#176;C). Do not discard empty refrigerant containers where
                        they are likely to be subjected to the heat of trash burners, etc.; they may explode, resulting
                        in personal injury or possible death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Always use correct replacement refrigerant hoses. Do not use hoses other than those specified
                        for the system being serviced. The use of improper hoses may cause a hose rupture, which may
                        result in personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_7.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_9.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
