<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - GENERAL DESCRIPTION - REAR HVAC system - SYSTEM
        DESCRIPTION - REAR HVAC SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390301" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SYSTEM DESCRIPTION - REAR HVAC SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (General)</title>
            <para>The rear HVAC system operates in a recirculate mode 100% of the time. The blower assembly draws air
                into the unit through the air intake at the front bulkhead of the bunk. A filter, located at the air
                intake, is accessible when the bunk is raised. Air from the blower is conditioned by forcing it though
                the evaporator core; and, depending on the temperature setting, the heater core. Conditioned air is
                output from the rear HVAC unit through an under bunk floor outlet; and through the main outlet duct,
                which is connected to the sleeper duct system.
            </para>
            <para>The temperature of the air output from the rear HVAC unit is determined by the position of the
                temperature blend door. The electrically actuated door diverts air from the blower assembly, either
                through the heater core, or around it, as determined by the rear HVAC controller. Inputs to the
                controller include; the temperature control on the rear HVAC control panel, the SLPR TEMP switch on the
                instrument panel, and the discharge duct temperature sensor. The controller sets the temperature setting
                of the sleeper HVAC system according to whichever sleeper temperature control was adjusted last. This
                allows the sleeper temperature to be controlled by either the sleeper control panel or the switch in the
                instrument panel. When either sleeper temperature control is adjusted, it is sensed by the rear HVAC
                controller, and it becomes the active control. The rear controller then adjusts the temperature blend
                door to match the setting of that control. Engine coolant flows through the heater core at all times
                (unless the vehicle is equipped with a heater shutoff valve).
            </para>
            <para>The speed of the rear system blower motor, which controls the volume of air moved through the rear
                HVAC system, is also determined by the rear HVAC controller. The blower speed inputs to the controller
                include; the fan speed control on the rear HVAC control panel, the SLPR FAN switch on the instrument
                panel, and the engine controller (via the body controller). The controller sets the blower speed of the
                sleeper HVAC system according to whichever sleeper blower speed control was adjusted last. This allows
                the sleeper blower speed to be controlled by either the sleeper control panel or the switch in the
                instrument panel. When either blower speed control is adjusted, it is sensed by the rear HVAC
                controller, and it becomes the active control. The rear controller then adjusts the sleeper blower speed
                to match the setting of that control.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (Air Conditioning)</title>
            <para>In the A/C mode the air is pushed by the blower assembly, through the evaporator core, to the
                temperature blend air door. Normally, in this mode, the door diverts all or most of the air around the
                heater core and out to the sleeper duct system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Distribution (Heat)</title>
            <para>In the Heat mode the air is pushed by the blower assembly, through the evaporator core, to the
                temperature blend air door. In this mode, the door diverts all or most of the air through the heater
                core and out to the sleeper duct system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>A/C Refrigerant Flow - Sleeper A/C System</title>
            <para>The addition of the sleeper A/C system does not change the operation of the front (cab) A/C
                refrigerant system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390201.xml" xrefid="hl160390201a">A/C REFRIGERANT FLOW - FRONT A/C
                    SYSTEM</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>In general, the air conditioning mode is automatically requested by the sleeper HVAC controller
                whenever the active temperature control for the sleeper system is set to a temperature that is lower
                than the current temperature sensed by the rear HVAC unit. Upon receiving the A/C request, the body
                controller will energize the A/C compressor if all requirements are met. For example, to energize the
                A/C compressor, the blower control on the front HVAC control panel must NOT be set to OFF. The
                electrical control systems are covered in the applicable ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS manual and/or
                ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING guide listed in ISIS.
            </para>
            <para>The rear thermostatic expansion valve and evaporator core are connected in parallel with the filter
                drier, expansion valve, and evaporator core of the front A/C system (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1603916">Figure 16</hotlnk>). With the A/C compressor energized, the rear expansion
                valve regulates the amount of refrigerant that it passes to the evaporator core. While leaving the
                expansion valve, the refrigerant starts to expand, entering the evaporator core as a low pressure, low
                temperature liquid. Within the evaporator core, the lower pressure permits the liquid refrigerant to
                boil or evaporate, changing its state from a liquid to a low pressure/low temperature vapor; and
                absorbing heat from the evaporator core and the air surrounding it. Cooling of the sleeper's interior
                takes place as the refrigerant vapor passes through the evaporator and absorbs heat from the sleeper air
                pushed through the evaporator core by the system blower. The refrigerant exits the evaporator outlet as
                a low pressure/low temperature vapor and is drawn through the low pressure side of the expansion valve
                by the suction created by the compressor.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1603916" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603916.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 16. A/C Refrigerant Flow Diagram (with Sleeper System Shown)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390300.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390302.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
