<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - TROUBLESHOOTING QUICK TIPS - COMMON CONDITIONS THAT CAUSE POOR
        OR NO A/C OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc graphiccount="0">
        <title>COMMON CONDITIONS THAT CAUSE POOR OR NO A/C OPERATION</title>
        <para>This section lists some of the more common conditions encountered with malfunctioning HVAC systems.</para>
        <seqlist>
            <item>
                <para>If the AC Request line (wire A77) is open from the HVAC control head to the ESC, the A/C system
                    will not operate and a DTC will not be set by the ESC.
                    <emph type="bold">Check for this condition using the EZ-Tech (see
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602571.xml" xrefid="hl1602571">SECTION 20.3</hotlnk>
                        or
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602560.xml" xrefid="hl1602560">SECTION 9</hotlnk>).
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If a thermistor value is displayed as 0 (zero) in the diagnostic software, check the thermistor
                    wiring for an open circuit. (This could also be caused by corrosion on the thermistor connector
                    contacts.) Note the thermistor DTC, if one is set; then, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602566.xml" xrefid="hl1602566">SECTION 15</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602566"/>
                    to troubleshoot the thermistor circuits.
                </para>
                <para>
                    <emph type="bold">NOTE: If the electrical connection to either thermistor is suspected of being
                        intermittent, perform the
                        <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602573.xml" xrefid="hl1602573">THERMISTOR CONNECTOR REPAIR</hotlnk>
                        procedures
                        <xref refid="hl1602573"/>.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>If the thermistor value is displayed as NA in the diagnostic software, check the thermistor wiring
                    for a short to ground. Note the thermistor DTC, if one is set; then, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602566.xml" xrefid="hl1602566">SECTION 15</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602566"/>
                    to troubleshoot the thermistor circuits.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>The high head pressure DTC (613-14A-1-10) will activate when the pressure transducer measures 400
                    psi if vehicle speed is over 20 mph. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602568.xml" xrefid="hl1602568">SECTION 8.1</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602568"/>
                    for a more complete understanding of the pressure transducer circuit. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602549.xml" xrefid="t1602512">TABLE 12</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t1602512"/>
                    to troubleshoot a high head pressure condition.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>On some vehicles it was possible for DTC 613-14A-1-6 (Marginal Charge) to be set and latched when
                    there was no malfunction. With the current ESC software version, this is now an invalid code. If
                    this code is being displayed, refer to DTC 613-14-1-6 in
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_18.xml" xrefid="t1602504">TABLE 3</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="t1602504"/>
                    for instructions on how to proceed.
                </para>
                <para>To clear a latched, active HVAC code (such as 613-14A-1-6):</para>
                <seqlist style="arabic">
                    <item>
                        <para>Turn the HVAC Fan control to OFF.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Using the Cruise Control switches place the ESC into diagnostic mode to display the DTC's.
                            Refer to
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_18.xml" xrefid="hl1602542">DIAGNOSTIC TROUBLE CODES</hotlnk>
                            <xref refid="hl1602542"/>.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clear the inactive DTC's.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Cycle the ignition switch off and then back on.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Place the ESC into the diagnostic mode again. The HVAC code should now be inactive.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Clear the inactive DTC's.</para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Excessive oil in the system will cause the system to not operate properly, and too little oil can
                    damage the compressor. When performing any service that requires charging the system, carefully
                    follow the procedures in
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602526.xml" xrefid="hl1602526">SECTION 7.10</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602526"/>
                    to insure that the correct quantity of oil is maintained in the system.
                </para>
            </item>
        </seqlist>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602570.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602571.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
