<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - BASIC
        PRINCIPLES
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>BASIC PRINCIPLES</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>For vehicles built before the dates specified in this section, refer to
                        <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16012v.htm" bookname="s16012v">s16012</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING
                        BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM)
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
            <title>HEAT</title>
            <para>The word
                <emph type="bold">heat</emph>
                may be defined in many ways. The definition best suited for refrigerant service is that heat is a form
                of energy which can be transferred from one place to another. This transfer, however, cannot take place
                unless there is a difference in temperature between the two places.
            </para>
            <para>Everything in nature contains heat. Some things contain more heat than others, but all contain heat.
                Heat cannot be created or destroyed, but it can be moved from one place to another or from one form of
                energy to another form of energy. Heat energy travels in one direction only: from a warmer object to a
                cooler object. This movement of heat takes place in one of three ways: convection, conduction or
                radiation.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Convection</emph>
                means that heat transfer is taking place as a result of the circulation of a fluid. The cooling system
                in a truck is a good example of convection cooling. The coolant (water and anti-freeze) in the cooling
                system removes the heat created by the engine by carrying it from the engine block to the radiator. The
                heat is then dissipated into the surrounding air.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Conduction</emph>
                means that heat is being transferred through a solid. For example, when food is frying in a pan, heat
                from the burner is conducted through the metal of the pan to the food.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Radiation</emph>
                means that heat is being transferred through a medium and the medium does not become hot. An example of
                this is the way people acquire sunburns at the beach. Part of the heat from the sun is transmitted to
                the skin through the air.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
