<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM (REFRIGERANT RECOVERY)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601915" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM (REFRIGERANT RECOVERY)</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml" xrefid="hl1601912">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                    read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                    could lead to serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <important>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </important>
            <important>
                <para>If the system is being discharged because a leak is suspected, the leak must be located before
                    discharging the system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601922.xml" xrefid="hl1601922">LEAK DETECTION</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>The locations of the A/C system high pressure and low pressure service ports vary by vehicle model
                    and year. The high pressure service port is located on the compressor's high pressure discharge line
                    between the compressor and the expansion valve. Typical locations are on the receiver-dryer or on
                    the compressor. The low pressure port is located on the compressor suction line, between the
                    expansion valve and the compressor.
                </para>
                <para>Discharge and suction ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not
                    visible, you can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter hose connected to
                    the compressor.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601925.xml" xrefid="f1601956">Figure 41</hotlnk>.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Empty the 'recovered oil' catch bottle on the recovery station. This will make it easier to
                determine the amount of oil recovered during the refrigerant recovery procedure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from both service ports.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station and hose fittings, verify that all valves are closed. The valves at
                the recovery station must be set to the CLOSED position. The valves at the quick connect fittings must
                be set fully counter-clockwise (CCW).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the recovery station to the system as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    hose to the low pressure service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    hose to the high pressure service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open (turn clockwise) the valves on the Metric SAE quick connect fittings connected to the
                service ports on the vehicle.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set both hand valves on the recovery station to the RECOVERY/VACUUM position.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the recovery station main power switch on and press the RECOVER button. The recovery
                station will automatically shut off when the refrigerant in the system has been exhausted to the storage
                tank.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close the quick connect valves, and set both valves on the recovery station to the CLOSED
                position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When recovering refrigerant by use of a recovery station, system oil is separated from the
                refrigerant during the recovery cycle. When the refrigerant recovery operation is complete, the recovery
                station will drain the oil into the station's calibrated catch bottle. The amount of oil recovered may
                be used to determine the amount of NEW oil that must be added back to the A/C system. Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601911.xml" xrefid="hl1601911">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the
                <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                and
                <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                hoses from the service ports on the refrigerant compressor.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Work may now begin on the air conditioning system.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601925.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601913.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
