<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - SERVICE HINTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SERVICE HINTS</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note cable routings during removal. Where necessary, cables should make sweeping curves.
                Sharp bends tend to increase resistance to bowden wire movement and sometimes cause kinks, which render
                the cable inoperative.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is most important that all refrigerant hose, O-rings, and tubing fittings be lubricated
                with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                refrigerant oil and tightened as specified in the torque chart of this section and the Air Conditioning
                - Heating Service Section for the particular vehicle. Use only a torque wrench known to be correct.
                Always use a back-up wrench when loosening or tightening fittings.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>DO NOT use oil approved for HFC-134A air conditioning systems to lubricate fittings and
                        O-rings on R-12 or HFC-134A systems. The oil absorbs too much moisture which may corrode the
                        fittings and make them difficult to disassemble. Use mineral-based oil (R-12 oil) to lubricate
                        fittings and O-rings on both types of systems.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver/dehydrator unit on any system which is opened for more than a very
                short period, when the system is flushed and/or when the compressor is replaced.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Be certain that the evaporator core temperature control sensing capillary tube is properly
                inserted into the evaporator core.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The expansion valve refrigerant temperature sensing tube must be securely attached to the
                evaporator refrigerant outlet tube. Also, the temperature sensing bulb and expansion valve must be
                tightly wrapped with insulating tape to prevent the ambient temperature from affecting correct sensing
                of the temperature or the refrigerant leaving the evaporator.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and strap locks must be reinstalled in their
                original positions (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601219">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601219" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601219" filename="../figg16/G1601219.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"
                         scalefitheight="232px" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 19. Re-install Clamps in Original Position</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be flushed as described in this section any time the
                compressor is replaced due to internal failure.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The compressor oil level must be checked and replaced as specified in the applicable
                compressor service section. Refer to GROUP 16, AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH in the CTS-5000
                Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing openings should be immediately capped or plugged during
                removal and remain so until reinstallation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other foreign
                material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried in the system to the right place.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Refrigerant must be recovered from the air conditioning system before any components of the
                        system are removed or replaced. Removing components while pressure is in the system will cause
                        personal injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
