<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - EVACUATING THE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601206" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>EVACUATING THE SYSTEM</title>
        <para>Whenever the air conditioning system has been opened, the system must be completely evacuated of air and
            moisture before being recharged.
        </para>
        <para>Outlined below is the procedure for evacuating the system using the OEM-1387 Charging Station for R-12 air
            conditioning systems, and OEM-1416 for HFC-134A air conditioning systems. On the HFC-134A charging station,
            make sure the valves on the red and blue hoses at the metric SAE quick-disconnect fittings are closed.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the Charging Station to the compressor service ports as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Close all the valves on the Charging Station (turn fully clockwise).</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    suction gauge hose (low pressure) to the compressor suction service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    discharge gauge hose (high pressure) to the compressor discharge service port.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">yellow</emph>
                    hose from the center fitting on the manifold to the vacuum pump suction fitting on the charging
                    station.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Open manifold suction and discharge gauge valves (turn fully counter- clockwise).</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">On HFC-134A metric SAE quick- disconnect fittings, turn the valves on the red and blue
                    hoses completely on (turn counterclockwise).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Start vacuum pump and
                <emph type="bold">SLOWLY</emph>
                open pump shutoff valve.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After suction gauge on manifold shows that vacuum is being established in the system, open
                vacuum gauge valve on the charging station and continue to operate the vacuum pump for ten (10) minutes.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close pump shutoff valve and observe vacuum gauge for one minute. The meter should not
                indicate a rise of more than 5 millimeters of mercury. If the gauge rises more than 5 millimeters of
                mercury in one (1) minute, the system has a leak which must be repaired. If there is no leak, proceed to
                step 5.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open pump shut-off valve and continue to operate vacuum pump for an additional twenty (20)
                minutes. Then close the pump shut-off valve and observe vacuum gauge. It the meter stays below 4
                millimeters of mercury for two (2) minutes, the system is ready to be charged.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the vacuum pump still operating, close both manifold gauge valves, pump shut-off and
                vacuum meter valves. Turn off vacuum pump.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Do not disconnect the manifold gauge hoses from the compressor service ports before charging
                        the system.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
