<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>No Idle APU/HVAC System - SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602539" svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>SAFETY PRECAUTIONS</title>
        <para>You must understand all procedures and instructions before you begin maintenance and service procedures.
        </para>
        <para>You must follow your company's maintenance and service guidelines.</para>
        <para>You must use special tools, when required, to avoid personal injury and damage to components.</para>
        <para>Throughout this manual you will find Cautions and Warnings:</para>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Cautions will advise you of the proper care to be taken to avoid damage to your vehicle or
                    property.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Warnings advise you of hazards, the consequences and what to do to avoid them, not only to avoid
                    damage to your vehicle or property, but also to help prevent situations and occurrences which could
                    result in personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Shock and entanglement hazard. Disable the starting circuit by removing the starter and fuel
                    solenoid relays (Relay 1 and Relay 3) before servicing. Failure to follow this warning can result in
                    property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent auto-restart when using the manual stop lever on the engine, the Starter and Fuel
                    Solenoid relays must be removed immediately after shutdown. Failure to follow this warning could
                    result in property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <figure id="f1603740" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603740.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="432px"
                     scalefitheight="272px"/>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, park the vehicle on a flat level surface, set
                    the parking brake, chock the wheels and turn the ignition off.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Shock Hazard. Only trained technicians should service the high voltage components in this unit.
                    High voltage circuits and components contain voltage levels that may cause equipment damage,
                    electrical shock and/or deadly electrocution if handled incorrectly.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Exhaust gases from engines contain hazardous compounds. Do not operate engines in enclosed areas
                    without abundant forced ventilation (with garage doors and windows wide open). Maintain exhaust
                    system in good operating condition. Breathing exhaust gases could result in personal injury or
                    death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Always use floor stands top support the vehicle before working under it. Using only a jack could
                    allow the vehicle fall causing property damage, personal injury or death.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To avoid property damage, personal injury or death, take care when performing any maintenance or
                    making any check or repair. Some of the materials in this vehicle may also be hazardous if used,
                    serviced or handled improperly. If you have any questions pertaining to service, have the work
                    performed by a skilled technician.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent serious eye injury, always wear safe eye protection when you perform vehicle
                    maintenance or service.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16037_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16037_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16037.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
