<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - PAINT AND REFINISHING - SIKKENS TECHNICAL DATA SHEETS -
        SIKKENS DEGREASERS AND CLEANERS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1600201" svcproctype="inspect" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SIKKENS DEGREASERS AND CLEANERS</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Technical Data Sheet</para>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>Degreasers are solvents especially formulated to remove grease and other contaminants from bare metal,
                existing finishes, plastics, etc. Sikkens has three types of degreasers available to best suite your
                shop and the substrate to be degreased:
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>Sikkens Wax and Grease Remover M600</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Sikkens Anti-Static Degreaser</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Aquaprep (waterbased)</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Before You Degrease</title>
            <para>The purpose of cleaning and degreasing is to remove residual grease, oil, wax, silicones, road dirt
                and sand, etc. If this is omitted, then residual dirt will migrate into the fine scratches left during
                the sanding process. Possible silicone fish eyes and adhesion of the paint system subsequently applied
                to the contaminated surface will be poor and the finish may blister or delaminate in a very short time.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Always wash the car thoroughly to remove as much contamination as possible and to
                    eliminate as much dirt as possible.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Always wear gloves when degreasing. This will accomplish two things:</para>
                <seqlist>
                    <item>
                        <para>Eliminate solvent being absorbed into your hands.</para>
                    </item>
                    <item>
                        <para>Prevent salts and oils on your hands from contaminating the surface to be refinished.
                        </para>
                    </item>
                </seqlist>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Application</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Wax and Grease Remover M600 is a very good general purpose degreaser. It is suitable for
                    cleaning and degreasing bare metal, existing finishes, primer surfacers, etc. It is the least
                    aggressive of the Sikkens solvent based degreasers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Anti-Static Degreaser is an aggressive greaser for cleaning bare metal and also removes
                    the static charge from raw plastic parts and fiberglass. This product is too aggressive for lacquers
                    but can be used on non-reversible existing finishes. Always check the reversibility of the substrate
                    before degreasing with this product.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Solvent based degreasers may not be legal for use in VOC regulated areas. Always check
                            local regulations.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Aquaprep is a waterbased cleaner/degreaser that may be used on all substrates. Aquaprep
                    will better remove water soluble contaminants (such as tree sap or sweat and salts from your hands)
                    than solvent based degreaser. Because of its extremely low VOC content, this product can be used in
                    most VOC regulated areas.
                </para>
                <para>Aquaprep can be wiped on or may be misted on with the use of a pump spray bottle. Allow the
                    solution to remain on the surface for two or more minutes to loosen and float contaminates. Wipe
                    with clean, dry towels. For difficult areas or stronger cleaning, repeat this process. The surface
                    may be rinsed with clean water if desired.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Degreasing Technique</title>
            <para>When a repair is to be made or a finish is to be recoated, the first thing to do after washing the car
                is to clean and degrease the body panel under treatment. Wet a clean cloth with one of the above three
                products and clean/degrease the surface under treatment. Immediately thereafter, wipe the surface dry
                with clean, dry cloths. Always use two cloths, as one cloth will merely shift rather than remove dirt
                and grease.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Replace cloths being used for degreasing and cleaning regularly by clean ones. Always place
                        used degreasing rags in a sealed container that meets local requirements to avoid the risk of
                        spontaneous combustion fire.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Unsanded Existing Finishes</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Water - Wash down the vehicle with detergent and warm water. This will dissolve water
                    soluble contaminants, ie., bird droppings, tree sap, etc.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">M600, Anti-Static Degreaser, Aquaprep - Wash down area to be repaired with one of the
                    degreasers and cleaners. This will remove any contaminant that cannot be removed with water.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a clean towel, dry off the degreaser and cleaner before it has time to evaporate.
                    --Always use one fresh towel for washing down and one fresh dry towel for wiping dry. --Replace
                    towels regularly.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>For surity against water soluble contaminant remaining, apply Aquaprep to the surface
                            prior to topcoating.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                    <note>
                        <para>Never allow the degreaser and cleaner to evaporate, the contaminate will remain. Wipe the
                            surface dry with a clean towel before the degreaser is allowed to evaporate.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                    <para>
                        <title>Sanded Existing Finishes</title>Repeat Steps 2 and 3 one more time after sanding and
                        prior to topcoating.
                    </para>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Untreated Plastic Parts</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Water - Wash down the unpainted plastic part with warm water and detergent.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Anti-Static Degreaser - Wash down plastic part with Anti-Static Degreaser. The stronger
                    solvent in Anti-Static Degreaser removes mold release agents.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With a clean towel, dry off the Anti-Static Degreaser before it has time to evaporate.
                    After this treatment, the surface is also rendered anti-static.
                </para>
                <para>Anti-Static Degreaser should also be used on painted plastic parts. Follow the same procedure for
                    unpainted plastic parts.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>The use of Aquaprep must replace Anti-Static Degreaser in areas where the use of low VOC
                            products are mandated.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Bare Metal</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">M600, Anti-Static Degreaser, Aquaprep - Wash down the metal with one of the degreasers
                    and cleaners. This will ensure that the stubborn contaminants will be removed during final
                    degreasing and cleaning.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>With all cleaning and degreasing activities: once the vehicle has been cleaned, it must
                            never be touched with the bare hand; as salts, moisture and oils can be transferred to the
                            prepared surface which may result in adhesion or blistering problems. It is particularly
                            important that hand protecting barrier creams are never used near an automobile that is to
                            be refinished.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Special Instruction for Cleaning and Degreasing of Truck Body Constructions</title>
            <para>It is important to prevent dirt residues from getting into construction grits of vans, trucks, etc.
                during cleaning and degreasing. They might cause adhesion problems when the paint is applied. Vertically
                fitted parts should, therefore, first be cleaned and degreased from the bottom upwards and subsequently
                from the top downwards.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Degreasing and Condensation on Metal Surfaces</title>
            <para>After a surface has been cleaned and degreased, the solvent will evaporate. The heat needed for
                evaporation is withdrawn from that surface, making it colder than the surrounding atmosphere, which
                results in (often not visible) condensation on the surface. Allow the moisture sufficient time to
                evaporate. The first coat of paint can be applied as soon as the surface has regained the temperature of
                the surrounding atmosphere. Earlier application of the coat may lead to adhesion problems.
            </para>
            <para>The same problem may arise if a vehicle is transferred from a cold room to a warm one, or from
                outdoors to indoors. Allow vehicles a minimum of one hour to acclimatize. Double-walled vehicles (and
                certainly insulated ones) require some hours to acclimatize.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Stock Keeping: Container Size</title>
            <para>Sikkens M600: I gallon and 5 gallons; Anti-Static Degreaser: 5 liters; Aquaprep: I gallon</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Minimum Shelf Life</title>
            <para>2 years if stored in original container at room temperature. Keep Aquaprep from freezing.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Aspects: Flashpoints (Closed Cup)</title>
            <para>Sikkens M600: &#60;21&#176;C; Anti-Static Degreaser: &#60;21&#176;C; Aquaprep: &#60;21&#176;C</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>VOC Content</title>
            <table id="t1600204">
                <title>VOC Content</title>
                <tgroup cols="3">
                    <colspec colnum="1" colname="1" colwidth="2.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="2" colname="2" colwidth="1.5in"/>
                    <colspec colnum="3" colname="3" colwidth="1.5in" colsep="1"/>
                    <thead valign="top">
                        <row>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Type</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>Lbs/gal</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>grams/liter</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </thead>
                    <tbody valign="top">
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Sikkens M600</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6.38</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>765</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Anti-Static Degreaser</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>6.43</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>772</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                        <row rowsep="1">
                            <entry>
                                <para>Aquaprep</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>&#60;1.4</para>
                            </entry>
                            <entry>
                                <para>15</para>
                            </entry>
                        </row>
                    </tbody>
                </tgroup>
            </table>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Warnings</title>
            <para>This material is designed for application only by trained professional personnel using proper
                equipment and is not intended for sale to the general public. READ AND UNDERSTAND THE MATERIAL SAFETY
                DATA SHEET BEFORE USING THIS PRODUCT.
            </para>
            <para>Isolate from heat, electrical equipment, sparks, and open flame. Vapor may cause flash fires. Use with
                adequate ventilation. Do not breathe vapors or spray mist. Use NIOSH/MSHA approved respirator during any
                contact with this product. Follow manufacturer's directions for respirator selection and use. In
                confined areas, use NIOSH/MSHA approved airline respirator or hood.
            </para>
            <para>Avoid contact with eyes, skin, and clothing. Wear personal protective equipment as outlined in the
                Aerial Safety Data Sheet. Wash thoroughly with soap and water in case of any contact. When a finish,
                exhaust all vapors in a safe manner. Product produced from welding or cutting the dried finish should be
                avoided.
            </para>
            <para>Keep container tightly closed when not in use. In case of spillage, absorb with inert material and of
                in accordance with applicable regulations. Paint arrestors (spray booth filters), sanding dust, rags,
                paint strainers, etc., may be considered as hazardous waste and must be disposed of in accordance with
                applicable regulations.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>First Aid</title>
            <para>In case of eye contact, flush immediately with plenty of water for at least 15 minutes and get
                attention; for skin, wash thoroughly with soap and water. If affected by inhalation of vapor or-by mist,
                remove to fresh air, get medical attention. If swallowed, get medical attention.
            </para>
            <para>The contents of this package must be blended with other components before the product can be used.
                Before opening packages, read all warning labels and the Material Safety Data Sheet and follow all
                precautions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Notice</title>
            <para>Reports have associated repeated and prolonged occupational overexposures to solvents with permanent
                brain nervous system damage. Intentional misuse by deliberately concentrating and inhaling contents may
                be harmful or fatal.
            </para>
            <para>If the Material Safety Data Sheet lists any product being used as containing heavy meal compounds
                (Numbers 26,27,28,38,48,53,54,73,79), inform your hazardous waste management company.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Disclaimer</title>
            <para>The technical information and suggestions for use made herein are based on Akzo Coatings Inc. research
                and experience and are believed to be reliable, but such information and suggestions do not constitute a
                warranty.
            </para>
            <para>Since Akzo Coatings Inc. has no control over the conditions under which the product is transported,
                stored, handled, used or applied, buyers must determine for themselves, by preliminary tests or
                otherwise, the suitability of the product for their purposes.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_26.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002_28.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16002.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
