<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - INSTALL - CAB DOOR
        WINDOW REGULATOR ARM ASSEMBLY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CAB DOOR WINDOW REGULATOR ARM ASSEMBLY</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Cab Door Window Regulator Arm Assembly on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f16033145">Figure 145</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position window regulator arm (Item 1) in behind the modular door hardware assembly
                    (Item 2), line up the hole in the window regulator arm with the hole in the modular door hardware
                    assembly. Install window regulator arm assembly shaft (Item 3) through the modular door hardware
                    assembly into the window regulator arm. Using a flat blade screw driver (Item 4) in the slot of the
                    window regulator arm assembly shaft, rotate it clockwise to lock it in the window regulator arm,
                    driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f16033145" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G16026c3.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="320px"
                         scalefitheight="392px"/>
                <caption>Figure 145. Window Regulator Arm and Window Regulator Arm Assembly Shaft</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. WINDOW REGULATOR ARM</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. MODULAR DOOR HARDWARE ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. WINDOW REGULATOR ARM ASSEMBLY SHAFT</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. FLAT BLADE SCREW DRIVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_33.xml" xrefid="f1603353">Figure 53</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603353"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install window regulator assembly coil spring (Item 2) into slot of window regulator arm
                    assembly shaft (Item 5), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>To avoid personal injury, be sure to use an appropriate tool and use care when installing the
                        window regulator assembly coil spring behind the retaining tab on the modular door hardware
                        assembly per Step 3, since the window regulator assembly coil spring will be loaded during
                        installation.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the window regulator assembly coil spring (Item 2) is installed properly on the
                    window regulator arm assembly shaft (Item 5). Using an appropriate tool, rotate window regulator
                    assembly coil spring clockwise around to the retaining tab (Item 3) on the modular door hardware
                    assembly (Item 4) and position behind retaining tab, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Rotate inner cab door handle (Item 1) back down over the window regulator assembly coil
                    spring (Item 2), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_33.xml" xrefid="f1603352">Figure 52</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603352"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position both retaining tabs (Item 3) on the inner cab door handle (Item 2) into the
                    slots in the modular door hardware assembly (Item 4) and slide inner cab door handle to the left to
                    secure retaining tabs in place, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the inner cab door handle (Item 2) is positioned properly. Install torx head bolt
                    (Item 1) securing inner cab door handle to the modular door hardware assembly (Item 4), driver side
                    shown. Tighten to 71 to 88.5 Lbf-in (8 to 10 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_25.xml" xrefid="f1603339">Figure 39</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603339"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower cab door glass (Item 1) to the bottom of cab door (Item 2).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Working through the cab door access opening (Item 5), carefully push window regulator
                    arm (Item 7) into the cab door window slide block (Item 9) in the cab door window slide rail (Item
                    10), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_25.xml" xrefid="f1603341">Figure 41</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603341"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If vehicle is equipped with manual door window, temporarily place the window regulator
                    handle (Item 1) on the window regulator handle shaft (Item 2) and raise and lower cab door glass
                    (Item 3) in the cab door (Item 4). Make sure cab door glass goes up and down smoothly without
                    binding before continuing. Once it is determined the cab door glass goes up and down properly,
                    remove window regulator handle and continue to next step, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_25.xml" xrefid="f1603339">Figure 39</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603339"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If vehicle is equipped with electric door window, temporarily hold cab door trim panel
                    (Item 4) up to the cab door (Item 2) and connect electric connectors
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603304.xml" xrefid="f1603335">(Item 3, Figure 35)</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="f1603335"/>
                    and use electric window switch panel (Item 3) to raise and lower cab door glass (Item 1) in the cab
                    door. Make sure cab door glass goes up and down smoothly without binding before continuing. Once it
                    is determined the cab door glass goes up and down properly, disconnect electric connector to cab
                    door trim panel and continue to next step, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cab door window electric motor, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603340.xml" xrefid="x1603340">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOOR WINDOW ELECTRIC MOTOR</emph>
                        <xref refid="x1603340"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing cab door window electric motor, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door Window Electric Motor on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cab door vapor barrier, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603335.xml" xrefid="x1603335">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOOR VAPOR BARRIER</emph>
                        <xref refid="x1603335"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . If cab door is equipped with electric door window and locks, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door Vapor Barrier with Electric Door Window and Locks on Daycab and
                        Sleeper Cab
                    </emph>
                    . If cab door is equipped with manual door window and locks, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door Vapor Barrier with Manual Door Window and Locks on Daycab and
                        Sleeper Cab
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cab door trim panel, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603334.xml" xrefid="x1603334">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOOR TRIM PANEL</emph>
                        <xref refid="x1603334"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . If cab door is equipped with electric door window and locks, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door Trim Panel with Electric Door Window and Locks on Daycab and
                        Sleeper Cab</emph>. If cab door is equipped with manual door window and locks, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door Trim Panel with Manual Door Window and Locks on Daycab and
                        Sleeper Cab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side cab door window regulator arm and window
                    regulator arm assembly shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603340.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603341.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
