<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - BEFORE 01/01/1993 (R-12) - REMOVE
        AND INSTALL - COMPRESSOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="7">
        <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Before starting removal of the compressor, the refrigerant must be recovered from the
                    system. A Recovery/ Recycling Station or equivalent is required for this operation.
                </para>
                <para>The manifold gauge set and/or recovery/recycling station and service hoses
                    <emph type="bold">MUST BE DEDICATED</emph>
                    to and used only on one of the two types of refrigerant. If the oil that is in the hoses and gauges
                    used to service an R-12 charged air conditioning system is introduced into an HFC-134A charged air
                    conditioning system, the oil from the R-12 manifold gauge set and hoses will cause the HFC-134A
                    system to function poorly and eventually may cause compressor failure. The same thing will happen if
                    HFC-134A oil is introduced into an R-12 system.
                    <emph type="bold">Do not use the same manifold gauge set, recovery/recycling station and service
                        hoses on both R-12 and HFC-134A SYSTEMS.
                    </emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the caps from the compressor service ports and connect the Manifold and Gauge
                    Set. Make sure that both hand valves are fully off by turning each one fully clockwise. Start with
                    the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    manifold suction gauge hose and connect it to the compressor suction service port. Connect the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    hose from the manifold discharge gauge to the high pressure discharge service port.
                </para>
                <para>On HFC-134A Metric SAE quick- disconnect fittings, turn the valves on the red and blue hoses
                    completely off (turn clockwise).
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Service ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not visible,
                            you can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter system hose
                            connected at the compressor.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>The fittings on the service hoses for HFC-134A air conditioning systems are standard
                            Metric SAE quick- disconnect fittings that will work only on HFC-134A air conditioning
                            systems.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect hose (
                    <emph type="bold">Yellow</emph>) to center fitting on the manifold and position opposite end of hose
                    to the inlet of the Recovery/ Recycling Station.
                </para>
                <para>On HFC-134A Metric SAE quick- disconnect fittings, turn the valves on the red and blue hoses
                    completely on (turn counterclockwise).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open both valves of the manifold. Turn the main power switch on and press the compressor
                    start switch. The Recovery/ Recycling Station will automatically shut off when the refrigerant in
                    the system has been exhausted to the storage tank.
                </para>
                <specpara>
                    <warning>
                        <para>Be certain that the yellow system service hose is firmly attached to the inlet of the
                            Recovery/ Recycling Station. Refrigerant can be hazardous if inhaled.
                        </para>
                    </warning>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not vent refrigerant into the atmosphere. The use of R-12 is a worldwide environmental
                            concern. Legislation has been enacted that makes the use of Recovery/Recycling Stations
                            mandatory. Because of the absence of chlorine in the molecular structure of HFC-134A, the
                            use of HFC-134A refrigerant will not have any harmful effects on the ozone layer of the
                            atmosphere. Because there is not enough evidence to determine the "greenhouse" effect of
                            HFC-134A, recycling of HFC-134A is recommended.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the refrigerant has been recovered, remove the compressor by removing the
                    refrigerant hoses and service port gaskets. Then loosen the four mounting bolts, and remove the
                    drive belt and the electric clutch wire from the connector.
                </para>
                <para>The compressor can now be removed from the vehicle. Compressor mounting brackets vary from one
                    vehicle to another (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601304">Figure 4</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601305">Figure 5</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601306">Figure 6</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601307">Figure 7</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601308">Figure 8</hotlnk>,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601309">Figure 9</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601310">Figure 10</hotlnk>); however, the compressor always has a four-bolt
                    mounting and almost always a supporting brace.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601304" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601304" filename="../figg16/G1601304.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 4. Compressor Mounting Caterpillar 3406 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601305" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601305" filename="../figg16/G1601305.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 5. Compressor Mounting International DT/DTA Engines</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601306" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601306" filename="../figg16/G1601306.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 6. Compressor Mounting Caterpillar 3176 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601307" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601307" filename="../figg16/G1601307.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 7. Compressor Mounting International 7.3 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601308" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601308" filename="../figg16/G1601308.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Compressor Mounting Cummins N-14 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601309" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601309" filename="../figg16/G1601309.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Compressor Mounting Detroit Diesel Series 60 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601310" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601310" filename="../figg16/G1601310.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                             scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="272px"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. Compressor Mounting Cummins L-10 Engine</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <important>
                        <para>When removing the compressor, be certain to seal all openings to prevent entry of dirt and
                            moisture.
                        </para>
                    </important>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Do not invert the compressor beyond a horizontal position during compressor removal or
                            installation as refrigerant oil will leak into the suction cavity. This will result in the
                            piston drawing the oil into the cylinder and damaging the compressor during initial
                            operation after installation.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>Not all parts of the compressor are serviceable. The clutch assembly is replaced as a unit
                            and the compressor seal and valve assemblies are supplied as service kits. More extensive
                            service requirements may necessitate replacement of the compressor.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the compressor on the mounting bracket and insert the four retaining bolts.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the compressor drive belt, align the clutch drive pulley with the accessory
                    drive pulley or water pump pulley and tension the belt as specified in
                    <hotlnk document="s16013j_HL1601301.xml" xrefid="hl1601301">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten the compressor mounting bolts to 20 to 25 ft-lbs. (27 to 34 N&#8226;m) and
                    install supporting braces if applicable.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the service port gaskets and refrigerant hoses.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge the air conditioning system as specified in GROUP 16 - AIR CONDITIONING THEORY,
                    DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16013j_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16013j_HL1601302.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16013j.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
