<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - ADDING REFRIGERANT TO THE SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="fill" graphiccount="0">
        <title>ADDING REFRIGERANT TO THE SYSTEM</title>
        <para>When the air conditioning system is low on refrigerant, it can be refilled using a charging station as
            outlined below.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the charging station to the compressor as follows:</para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Close the manifold suction (blue) and discharge (red) valves (turn fully clockwise).
                </para>
                <para>On the HFC-134A station, turn the metric quick-disconnect valves on the blue and red hoses off
                    (turn clockwise).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove cap from the compressor suction service port and connect the manifold suction
                    gauge hose (blue).
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Remove cap from the compressor discharge service port and connect the manifold discharge
                    gauge hose (red).
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fill the charging station with or meter the proper amount of refrigerant (follow equipment
                maker's instructions).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the service hose (yellow) from the center manifold to the valve on top of the
                charging station.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Open refrigerant supply valve on the charging station.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Set air conditioning controls at maximum cooling (A/C lever at "COLD," blower switch on
                "High"). Open the cab doors.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Run the engine at high idle speed.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">SLOWLY open suction valve to add refrigerant to the system. Observe the sight glass and add
                refrigerant until no foaming or bubbles appear in the sight glass. Continue adding refrigerant until 16
                oz. (.5 kg) has been added to the system after the sight glass has cleared. DO NOT OVERCHARGE SYSTEM.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not allow refrigerant to enter the compressor as a liquid as it will cause severe damage to
                        the compressor.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Close suction gauge valve and close refrigerant supply valve on the charging station.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Perform
                <hotlnk document="s16012v_4.xml" xrefid="hl1601204">SYSTEM PRESSURE CHECK</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After pressure test is completed, disconnect manifold gauge hoses from compressor service
                ports. Install protective caps on each service port.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check air conditioning system for refrigerant leaks using an electronic leak detector.
                Follow equipment manufacturer's instructions.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_12.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_14.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
