<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - INSTALL - CAB DOOR
        HINGE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAB DOOR HINGE</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Cab Door Hinge on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_19.xml" xrefid="f1603329">Figure 29</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603329"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <para>The cab door is mounted on upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) located on the cab hinge
                pillar (Item 3). Cab door adjustment is provided by enlarged holes in front cab door hinge mounting
                holes. If cab door hinges are removed from the cab, upper and lower hinges can be interchanged.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) onto cab hinge pillar
                    (Item 3), use markings at upper and lower hinge position on cab hinge pillar to help position cab
                    door hinges properly on the cab hinge pillar.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position lower cab door hinge (Item 2), using markings on cab hinge pillar (Item 3).
                    Install two hex bolts with washers (Item 4) through lower cab door hinge and thread into the cab
                    hinge pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position upper cab door hinge (Item 1), using markings on cab hinge pillar (Item 3).
                    Install one hex bolt with washer (Item 4) through mounting hole nearest cab door opening and one hex
                    flanged locking bolt (Item 5) through forward mounting hole of the upper cab door hinge and thread
                    into the cab hinge pillar, driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After installing upper and lower cab door hinges (Items 1 and 2) on cab hinge pillar
                    (Item 3), install the cab door onto cab door hinges. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603333.xml" xrefid="x1603333">
                        <emph type="bold">CAB DOORS</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="x1603333"/>. For installing cab door, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Cab Door on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to remove upper and lower passenger side cab door hinges.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603333.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_76.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
