<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1602564">
        <title>TEMPERATURE ACTUATOR MOTOR CIRCUIT</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CIRCUIT FUNCTIONS</title>
            <figure id="f1602564" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602564.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                         scalefitheight="272px"/>
                <caption>Figure 66. Temperature Door Actuator Motor Function Diagram</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. TEMPERATURE DOOR ACTUATOR MOTOR
                        <callout2>LOCATED ON CAB BLOWER HOUSING</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                    <callout1>2. TEMPERATURE SELECT CONTROL
                        <callout2>LOCATED ON HVAC CONTROL HEAD</callout2>
                    </callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <para>The
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1602564">TEMPERATURE DOOR ACTUATOR MOTOR</hotlnk>
                controls a temperature blend air door that regulates the temperature of the air discharged from the
                vents. The temperature blend door determines what portion of the system input air is deflected through
                the heater core depending on the setting of the temperature control (center knob) on the HVAC control
                panel. As the temperature control is rotated clockwise more air is deflected through the heater core,
                increasing the temperature of the system output air entering the cab. The temperature control has
                fifteen detents.
            </para>
            <para>When the temperature control setting is changed, the control head will apply a drive voltage to the
                temperature door actuator motor causing it to turn the temperature blend door to the desired position.
                Circuitry within the control head senses when the door reaches the correct position, and stops
                outputting the drive voltage.
            </para>
            <para>Because the actuator motor can be driven in either direction the drive voltage can be of either
                polarity. In order to position the doors correctly, circuitry within the control head keeps track of the
                actuator position at all times based on a known starting position. It can then drive the actuator to any
                position by applying a drive voltage of the correct polarity, and sensing (counting) the number of
                actuator motor revolutions through the actuator circuits. To establish a known starting position, the
                control head runs the actuator and door through a calibration procedure when battery voltage is first
                applied to the HVAC control head, and then at regular intervals during normal operation.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_79.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_81.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
