<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - SERVICE PROCEDURES FOR R-134a - CHARGING THE AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM (FULL CHARGE)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390907" svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM (FULL CHARGE)</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390901.xml" xrefid="hl160390901">SERVICE WARNINGS
                        <xref refid="hl160390901"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Failure to read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with
                    refrigerant could lead to serious personal injury.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <warning>
                <para>Do not remove the compressor oil fill plug to check the oil level in the refrigerant compressor
                    while the A/C system is charged with refrigerant. The crankcase side of the compressor is under
                    pressure and personal injury may result. It is not possible to check the oil level in the compressor
                    on an A/C system that is under system pressure.
                </para>
            </warning>
            <caution>
                <para>Use only new or recycled R-134a refrigerant; not any of the so called "direct replacement"
                    refrigerants. Use of equipment dedicated for R-134a is necessary to reduce the possibility of oil
                    and refrigerant incompatibility concerns.
                </para>
            </caution>
            <caution>
                <para>When charging the A/C system the refrigerant tank must be kept upright. If the tank is not in the
                    upright position, liquid refrigerant may enter the system and cause compressor damage.
                </para>
            </caution>
            <note>
                <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here, the
                    function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If you are
                    performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown, refer to the
                    manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                </para>
            </note>
            <note>
                <para>If recycled refrigerant is to be used, follow the instructions supplied with the recycling
                    equipment to purge the air from the refrigerant before charging the system.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <para>Perform the Charging procedures, using new or recycled refrigerant, only after the following actions have
            been completed:
        </para>
        <randlist type="bullet">
            <item>
                <para>System components repaired and/or replaced.</para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>System flushed or purged
                    <emph type="bold">(if required)</emph>.
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>Refrigerant oil added (
                    <emph type="bold">only</emph>
                    if oil was added directly to the compressor, see
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390910.xml" xrefid="hl160390910">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </item>
            <item>
                <para>System completely evacuated.</para>
            </item>
        </randlist>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>If the equipment being used adds system refrigerant oil during the evacuation/charging procedure,
                    you must first determine the amount of oil to be added (refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390910.xml" xrefid="hl160390910">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>),
                    <xref refid="hl160390910"/>. Then follow the instructions furnished with the recovery station, or
                    refrigerant oil injector tool, to add the correct amount of
                    <emph type="bold">NEW</emph>
                    oil to the system during this procedure.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The recovery station
                <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                (suction) and
                <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                (discharge) hoses should still be connected as they were during the evacuation operation.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">If necessary, add oil to return the system oil capacity to its correct level (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390910.xml" xrefid="hl160390910">OIL FILL GUIDELINES</hotlnk>),
                <xref refid="hl160390910"/>. To add oil during the evacuation/charging process, follow the instructions
                furnished with the recovery station, or refrigerant oil injector tool.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Due to the density of R-134a, the amount of refrigerant required to charge a typical air
                    conditioning system has been reduced. Overcharging the system will result in excessively high head
                    pressures during operation and may damage the compressor. Be sure to check specifications on the
                    vehicle being serviced. This information is often located on a label on the refrigerant compressor.
                </para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Determine the amount of refrigerant needed to charge the A/C system. This information can be
                found in the
                <hotlnk document="s16039_80.xml" xrefid="t1603922">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                section of this manual
                <xref refid="t1603922"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Following the instructions provided with the recovery station; set the recovery station to
                charge the system with the specified amount of refrigerant.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">On the recovery station, set the low side valve to CLOSED, and the high side valve to
                CHARGE.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Press the CHARGE button to start the charge procedure. When the system is fully charged, the
                recovery station will turn off.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Complete the charging procedure by setting both hand valves on the recovery station to the
                CLOSED position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Before disconnecting the recovery station from the A/C system, perform
                <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390704.xml" xrefid="hl160390704">A/C SYSTEM PERFORMANCE TEST PROCEDURE
                </hotlnk>
                <xref refid="hl160390704"/>.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">After the pressure test is completed, stop the engine and close the valves on the
                quick-disconnect fittings (turn fully ccw) at the vehicle A/C service ports.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the
                <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                and
                <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                hose quick-disconnect fittings from the vehicle service ports.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the protective caps on both of the vehicle service port fittings.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390906.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_73.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
