<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE
        (WITH R-12 REFRIGERANT SYSTEM) - REFRIGERANT SYSTEM SERVICE - FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="drain" graphiccount="0">
        <title>FLUSHING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>R-12 Charged Air Conditioning Systems</title>
            <para>The flushing of refrigerant lines and parts in R-12 charged air conditioning systems is done with R-11
                refrigerant. This refrigerant is used because it remains liquid at room temperatures and pressures.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not use any solvents other than R-11 for flushing refrigerant lines and parts of R-12
                        charged air conditioning systems. The reaction of other solvents with refrigerant will cause
                        sludge, which will damage some parts and be much more difficult to flush from the system.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>Special refrigeration system flushing equipment is available from various air conditioning equipment
                manufacturers for R-12 charged air conditioning systems. This equipment employs a continuous circulation
                flushing method to thoroughly and quickly clean a badly contaminated system without removing the major
                system components.
            </para>
            <para>If this equipment is used, carefully follow the equipment manufacturer's recommended procedures for
                equipment use and system flushing.
            </para>
            <para>If special equipment is not available, the system may be flushed using the following procedures.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>R-11, like R-12, is a chloroflurocarbon and is covered under the same regulations. R-11 must
                        be handled with the same cautions and may not be vented to the atmosphere. While R-11 is a
                        liquid at normal room temperatures, it evaporates very quickly; therefore, it must be stored and
                        recovered in sealable containers.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <para>
                <title>Flush the Evaporator</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recover the refrigerant from the system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove high and low side hoses from compressor and place covers over valve ports to
                    prevent the entrance of moisture.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove expansion valve. Clean out with a small charge of liquid R-11.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect length of heater hose to the expansion valve connection of the evaporator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From service line components, fabricate a short refrigerant line to connect between the
                    evaporator suction line and the manifold gauge set suction valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the manifold suction valve and discharge valves. (Turn fully clockwise.)</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the service hose from the center manifold fitting to the valve on top of the
                    charging cylinder of R-11 refrigerant.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Open the refrigerant supply valve on top of the charging cylinder.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open the suction gauge valve and allow liquid refrigerant to flow through the
                    evaporator to a sealable container. Allow at least one pound of R-11 to pass through the evaporator.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the refrigerant supply valve on top of the charging cylinder.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the fabricated refrigerant line from the evaporator suction line.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the hose from the evaporator inlet and reinstall the expansion valve to the
                    evaporator line only.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>
                <title>Flush the Condenser</title>
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard the receiver/ dehydrator.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From service hose components, fabricate a short refrigerant line to connect between the
                    condenser inlet (compressor discharge) line and the gauge manifold discharge valve hose.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect a piece of heater hose to the condenser outlet line. Insert the other end of the
                    hose into a sealable container.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Make certain that manifold suction and discharge valves on the gauge manifold are closed
                    (turn fully clockwise). Open the refrigerant R-11 charging cylinder valve (still connected to the
                    center manifold on the gauge manifold).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slowly open discharge valve on gauge manifold to allow the liquid refrigerant to flow
                    through the condenser to a sealable container. Allow at least one pound of refrigerant to flow
                    through the condenser.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Close the refrigerant supply line.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the fabricated refrigerant line from the condenser inlet line. Remove the hose
                    from the outlet line.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a small amount of R-11 to flush the line which connects the receiver/ dehydrator to
                    the expansion valve.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new receiver/dehydrator and re-connect the air conditioning system.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the manifold gauge set and charge with one pound of R-12 refrigerant as
                    described in this section.
                    <emph type="bold">(Do not evacuate the system until after the leak test.)</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Leak test all connections with a leak detector. If OK, then proceed with Step 12. If not
                    OK, repair the leak and then go on to Step 12.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Evacuate and charge the system with R-12. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16012v_12.xml" xrefid="hl1601207">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING SYSTEM (FULL
                        CHARGE)</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Allow the system to run for ten minutes and perform oil level checks.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Perform
                    <hotlnk document="s16012v_4.xml" xrefid="hl1601204">SYSTEM PRESSURE CHECK</hotlnk>
                    of the refrigerant system to assure quality cooling performance.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>HFC-134A Charged Air Conditioning Systems</title>
            <para>At the present time, there is no flushing agent for HFC-134A charged air conditioning systems. R-11
                and any other flushing solution that is currently used to flush R-12 charged air conditioning systems
                <emph type="bold">CANNOT</emph>
                be used to flush HFC-134A systems. The residue left by these flushing products will destroy the
                lubrication properties of the oil used in HFC-134A systems.
            </para>
            <para>The only procedure presently available to flush an HFC-134A charged air conditioning system is to
                pressure flush with HFC-134A refrigerant using a recycling system to capture the HFC-134A flushed
                through the system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16012v.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
