<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Cab - Safety Belt System - Description and Operation</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Belt System</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>All safety belt assemblies including retractors, belt tension sensor (BTS), if equipped,
                        buckles, shoulder belt height adjusters (if equipped), child safety seat tether attachments and
                        attaching hardware should be inspected after any collision. All new belt assemblies should be
                        installed unless a qualified technician finds the assemblies show no damage and operate
                        correctly. Belt assemblies not in use during a collision should also be inspected and new
                        assemblies installed if either damage or incorrect operation is noted.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Each seating position in the vehicle has a specific safety belt assembly which consists of one
                        buckle and one tongue. The safety belt assembly is designed to be used as a pair and is not to
                        be used across seating positions.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>New safety belt buckles, height adjusters, center adjust tongues, and belts and retractors can
                        be installed separately. However, if a safety assembly was in use during a collision, a new belt
                        and retractor must be installed as well as the center adjust tongue, and belt and buckle
                        assembly or the center adjust tongue, and the cable and buckle assembly. When installing new
                        safety belts and buckles, height adjusters, safety cables and buckles, center adjust tongues,
                        and belt and retractors, use only the parts specified in the Ford Master Parts Catalogs for the
                        make and model of the vehicle being repaired. Safety belt assemblies must not be interchanged
                        between vehicle models.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The active restraint system consists of the following:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>Driver, center and passenger safety belt buckles, attached to the floor pan.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Driver and passenger safety belt retractors, located on the B-pillar behind the safety belt
                        retractor trim panel covers.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The outboard safety belt for the driver and passenger seat is a continuous-loop 3-point system. The
                combination lap and shoulder belt (continuous-loop) uses a common slip tongue.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Vehicle-Sensitive (Emergency) Locking Mode</title>
            <para>The emergency locking retractor (ELR) mode will allow the occupant freedom of movement, locking tight
                only on hard braking, hard cornering or an impact of approximately 8 km/h (5 mph). The ELR mode helps to
                reduce the forward movement of the driver and passengers. The ELR mode is continuously in operation at
                all seating positions.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Energy Management Retractor</title>
            <para>The driver and front outboard passenger seat belt systems have a safety belt system with an energy
                management feature at the front seating positions to help further reduce the risk of injury in the event
                of a head-on collision.
            </para>
            <para>The energy management retractor feature is designed to pay out webbing in a controlled manner. This
                feature is designed to help reduce the belt force acting on an occupant's chest.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Fastening Safety Belts</title>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Do not introduce slack into the safety belt system because the belt locks upon impact where it
                        is positioned. Use the shoulder safety belt on the outside shoulder only. Never wear the
                        shoulder safety belt under the arm. Never swing the shoulder safety belt around the neck over
                        the inside shoulder. Never use a single belt for more than one person. Make sure the lap portion
                        of the belt is fitted snugly and as low as possible around the hips, not the waist. Failure to
                        follow these precautions could increase the chance and severity of injury in a collision.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <para>Always follow the preceding safety precautions when fastening the safety belts.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Belt Extension Assembly</title>
            <para>In certain cases, the safety belt may be too short even when it is fully extended. About 20 cm (8 in)
                can be added to the belt length by using a safety belt extension. Safety belt extensions are available
                at no cost from any Ford or Lincoln-Mercury dealer parts department. Safety belt extensions are only
                available with black webbing.
            </para>
            <para>Use only extensions manufactured by the same supplier as the safety belt. Manufacturer identification
                is located at the end of the webbing on the label. Also, use the safety belt extension only if the
                safety belt is too short for you when fully extended. Do not use an extension to change the fit of the
                shoulder belt across the torso.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Safety Belt Warning System - Driver Safety Belt</title>
            <para>The driver safety belt incorporates a safety belt warning indicator switch, warning indicator and
                chime. The warning indicator and chime are reminders to fasten the safety belt.
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>If the driver safety belt is not buckled before the ignition switch is turned to the ON
                        position, the safety belt indicator light illuminates for 1 to 2 minutes and the warning chime
                        sounds for 4 to 8 seconds.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the driver safety belt is buckled while the safety belt indicator light is on and the
                        warning chime is sounding, the warning light and warning chime turn off.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>If the driver safety belt is buckled before the ignition switch is turned to the ON position,
                        the safety belt indicator light and warning chime remain off.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_X5012036.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_16.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
