<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - INSTALL - CAB COWL
        TRAY
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1603354" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAB COWL TRAY</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Cab Cowl Tray on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603324.xml" xrefid="f1603390">Figure 90</hotlnk>
                <xref refid="f1603390"/>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the hole in the passenger side of the cowl tray (Item 2) over the antenna (Item
                    4), lower cowl tray into position at cab cowl.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide the holes in the cowl tray (Item 2) over both driver and passenger side wiper
                    pivot posts (Item 15).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide mounting holes of cowl tray (Item 2) at the bottom of both driver and passenger
                    side over the mounting studs (Item 14) on the cab cowl. Make sure that the plastic bracket on the
                    passenger side of the cowl tray slides in behind the mounting bracket (Item 6, view arrow C) and
                    that the plastic bracket (Item 8, view arrow C) at the lower front of the cowl tray is in place at
                    the evaporator box (Item 9) of AC unit.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hex flanged nut (Item 12, view arrow B) under cowl tray (Item 2, view arrow B)
                    on driver side. Tighten to 16 Lbf-ft (22 N&#8226;m), DO NOT exceed 18 Lbf-ft (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hex flanged nut (Item 13, view arrow D) under cowl tray (Item 2, view arrow D)
                    on passenger side. Tighten to 16 Lbf-ft (22 N&#8226;m), DO NOT exceed 18 Lbf-ft (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hex flanged bolt (Item 10, section A - A) into center mounting bracket (Item 11,
                    section A - A) at the center of cowl tray (Item 2, section A - A). DO NOT over tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install torx pan head screw (Item 8, view arrow C) through cowl tray mounting bracket
                    (Item 7, view arrow C) at the lower front of the cowl tray (Item 2, view arrow C) into evaporator
                    box (Item 9) of AC unit. DO NOT over tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install hex flanged bolt (Item 5, view arrow D) through mounting bracket (Item 6, view
                    arrow D) into u-shaped speed nut (Item 15) on plastic bracket under cowl tray (Item 2) on passenger
                    side. DO NOT over tighten.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Slide rubber seal (Item 3, view arrow E) down over antenna (Item 4, view arrow E) on
                    passenger side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install washer hose (Item 1, view arrow A) onto fitting under cowl tray (Item 2, view
                    arrow A) on driver side.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">After installing cowl tray, install driver and passenger side windshield wiper arm and
                    blade assembly. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603353.xml" xrefid="x1603353">
                        <emph type="bold">WINDSHIELD WIPER ARM AND BLADE ASSEMBLY</emph>
                        <xref refid="x1603353"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing driver and passenger side windshield wiper arm and blade assembly, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Windshield Wiper Arm and Blade Assembly on Daycab and Sleeper Cab</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower tilt hood to closed position and latch hood on both sides.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turn wipers on to high speed and activate windshield washer to check for proper
                    operation. Adjust position of windshield wiper arm and blade assembly if required to obtain proper
                    wiper operation.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_X1603353.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_112.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
