<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - AERODYNAMIC PANELS - ROOF AIR DEFLECTOR - PRO SLEEPER&#174;
        AERODYNAMIC DEFLECTOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="16">
        <title>PRO SLEEPER&#174; AERODYNAMIC DEFLECTOR</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Description</title>
            <para>In July, 1994, International introduced a flat top and high roof PRO SLEEPER&#174;. The roof deflector
                assembly for each tractor will be shipped to the dealer directly from the deflector manufacturer
                unpainted. It will be the dealer's responsibility to paint and install the roof deflector assembly.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc id="hl1601002">
            <title>Low Roof</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Prepare the outer surface of the air deflector and air deflector extenders for painting
                    as explained in GROUP 16 - PAINTING in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Paint the air deflector and side deflectors the finish color before installation. The
                    inside of the air deflector and back side of the air deflector extenders and the antenna mount (if
                    included) do not require a class 1 finish.
                </para>
                <para>Also paint the 8 star bolt assemblies, and 2 "L" brackets the finish color.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Completely cover the roof of the cab with blankets or tarps to protect the roof from
                    being damaged during the installation procedure. Also cover the air horn(s). Care must be taken not
                    to damage the air horn(s) during the air deflector installation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cab drag link airshield brace from the air deflector middle and rear mounting
                    brackets on both sides of the vehicle (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601008">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Reinstall the bolt that secures the middle mount to
                    the cab roof. Tighten finger tight.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601008" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601008" filename="../figg16/G1601008.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 8. Low Roof</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the air deflector on the air deflector front mounting bracket tabs (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601009">Figure 9</hotlnk>), then slide the air deflector back against the air
                    deflector rear mounting brackets (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601009">Figure 9</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601009" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601009" filename="../figg16/G1601009.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 9. Air Deflector On Brackets</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the cab drag link airshield brace between the middle mounting bracket and the
                    air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601008">Figure 8</hotlnk>). Install and tighten the bolt on the middle mount
                    finger tight.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install two 3/8"x 1-1/2" hex hd. bolts and 3/8" flat washers through the two holes in
                    the air deflector rear mounting bracket, through the rear of the air deflector and cab drag link
                    airshield brace on both sides of the vehicle (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601009">Figure 9</hotlnk>). Install a 3/8" nylon insert locknut and 3/8" flat
                    washer on each bolt. Tighten the locknuts until they are snug and the air deflector is against both
                    air deflector rear mounting brackets.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the air deflector resting on the front mounting tabs, measure the clearance between
                    the front of the air deflector and the cab roof. The clearance across the front should be 3/4 of an
                    inch (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601010">Figure 10</hotlnk>). If it's not close to 3/4 of an inch, block the front
                    of the air deflector up to obtain the correct clearance. Be sure the measurement is the same across
                    the front of the air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601010">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601010" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601010" filename="../figg16/G1601010.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 10. Clearance Across Front</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <note>
                        <para>If you plan on installing more than one set of PRO SLEEPER air deflector assemblies, it is
                            recommended that metal templates be made from the drawings
                            <hotlnk xrefid="f1601011">Figure 11</hotlnk>.
                        </para>
                    </note>
                </specpara>
                <figure id="f1601011" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601011" filename="../figg16/G1601011.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 11. Mounting Bracket Templates</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place the drilling templates in position on the tabs of the air deflector front mounting
                    bracket as illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601012">Figure 12</hotlnk>. Be sure the slot in the template is resting on the tab
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601012">Figure 12</hotlnk>). Tape the template in this position.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601012" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601012" filename="../figg16/G1601012.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 12. Slot In Template Resting On Tab</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill a 1/8 inch pilot hole through the air deflector in both positions indicated on the
                    template.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the template and drill a 13/32 inch hole through the air deflector in both pilot
                    hole locations.
                </para>
                <para>Care should be taken not to damage the threads in the air deflector front mounting bracket when
                    the drill passes through the fiberglass material of the air deflector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a 3/8" x 1-3/4" Star Drive bolt assembly in both holes and tighten finger tight
                    (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601013">Figure 13</hotlnk>). If the bolts are difficult to install, run a 3/8"-16
                    tap in the holes to clean up the threads.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601013" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601013" filename="../figg16/G1601013.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 13. Air Deflector Middle Mounting Brackets</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 9 through 12 on the opposite side of the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the middle mounting bracket is against the inside of the air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601013">Figure 13</hotlnk>) and use the 1/8" pilot drill to drill a hole (from the
                    inside) at each bolt hole location in both air deflector middle mounting brackets (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601013">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the outside of the air deflector, drill a 13/32" hole at each 1/8" pilot hole
                    location.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install, from the outside, a 3/8" x 1-3/4" Star Drive bolt assembly through the air
                    deflector and mounting bracket. Secure with a flat washer and 3/8"-16 nylon insert locknut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601013">Figure 13</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all air deflector front and middle Star Drive bolts assemblies and the middle
                    mounting bracket mounting bolt to 31 ft-lbs. (42 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Deflector Extender Assembly</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two 3/8 inch bolts from the rear mounting bracket, through the rear of the
                    air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601014">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601014" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601014" filename="../figg16/G1601014.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 14. Air Deflector Extender Assembly</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the right air deflector extender to the right rear of the roof air deflector so
                    the bottom two holes in the side deflector line up with the two lower holes in the air deflector
                    rear mounting bracket (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601014">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the two 3/8 inch bolts, flat washers and nuts removed in step one in these
                    holes (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601014">Figure 14</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the side deflector so it is flush with the side and top of the roof air
                    deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601015">Figure 15</hotlnk>). Hold in place with a "C" clamp (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601014">Figure 14</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601015">Figure 15</hotlnk>). Tighten the two lower nuts to 31 ft-lbs. (42 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601015" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601015" filename="../figg16/G1601015.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 15. Side Deflector Flush With Roof Air Deflector</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the holes in the mounting flange of the air deflector extender as a template and
                    drill a 11/32 inch hole through the roof air deflector at each hole location (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601015">Figure 15</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">From the air deflector extender side, install a 5/16" x 1" hex hd. bolt and 5/16 inch
                    flat washer through each hole. Install a 5/16 inch flat washer and nylon insert lock nut on each
                    bolt (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601015">Figure 15</hotlnk>). Tighten to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m). Remove the "C"
                    clamp.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat steps 1 through 6 on the left air deflector extender.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the "L" bracket on the inside of the lower side air deflector and up against
                    the bottom of the air deflector extender as illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601016">Figure 16</hotlnk>
                    Secure in place with two 5/16"-18 x 1" hex hd. bolts and 5/16" lock washers. Tighten hand tight.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601016" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601016" filename="../figg16/G1601016.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 16. Position "L" Bracket</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the hole on the side of the "L" bracket that is against the bottom of the upper air
                    deflector extender as a guide to drill a 11/32" hole through the bottom of the upper side mounted
                    air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601016">Figure 16</hotlnk>). Secure the "L" bracket to the upper air deflector
                    extender with a 5/16"-18 x 1" hex hd. bolt, flat washer, lock washer and hex nut through this hole
                    with the head of the bolt and a flat washer against the upper air deflector extender (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601016">Figure 16</hotlnk>). Tighten the fasteners to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Satellite Antenna Mount (If Required)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 7th and 8th bolts (from the bottom going up) that secure the air deflector
                    extender to the roof air deflector and discard.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place antenna mount against side deflector and align with the holes of the bolts removed
                    in step one (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601017">Figure 17</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601017" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601017" filename="../figg16/G1601017.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 17. Align Antenna Mount</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a 5/16" x 1-1/4" hex hd. bolt and 5/16 inch flat washer through these holes into
                    the roof air deflector. Install a 5/16 inch flat washer and locknut on each bolt (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601017">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Tighten to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill a 11/32 inch hole through the roof air deflector using the outermost hole in the
                    antenna mount as a guide (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601017">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Install a 5/16" x 1-1/4" hex hd. bolt and 5/16 inch
                    flat washer through this hole into the roof air deflector. Install a 5/16 inch flat washer and
                    locknut on the bolt. Tighten to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Drill two 11/32 inch holes through the side air deflector extender using the holes in
                    the antenna mount that contact the air deflector extender as a guide (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601017">Figure 17</hotlnk>). Install 5/16" x 1-1/4" button hd. capscrews and 5/16
                    inch flat washers through the holes in the air deflector extender into the antenna mount. Install
                    5/16 inch flat washers and locknuts on the bolts. Tighten to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 5th 5/16" bolt from the bottom that secures the air deflector extender to the
                    roof air deflector (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601018">Figure 18</hotlnk>and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601019">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601018" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601018" filename="../figg16/G1601018.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 18. Secure Brace</caption>
                </figure>
                <figure id="f1601019" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601019" filename="../figg16/G1601019.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 19. Use Bolts Provided</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the top of the brace to the bottom of the antenna mount in the hole provided with
                    a 5/16"x 1-1/4" hex hd. bolt on a 72" and a 5/16" x 2" hex hd. bolt and a spacer on a 51", 2 flat
                    washers and lock nut (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601018">Figure 18</hotlnk>
                    and
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601019">Figure 19</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the bottom of the antenna mount brace to the air deflector extender in the hole
                    where the bolt was removed, with the bolt removed in step 6 (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601018">Figure 18</hotlnk>). Tighten both bolts to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Satellite Antenna (If Required)</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install antenna to the antenna mount per the antenna manufacturers instructions.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Run cable using "P" clamps or wire ties as required to insure that they do not vibrate,
                    especially next to the antenna plugs.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check antenna operation per manufacturer's instructions.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Flexible Cab Trim Molding</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold the flexible cab trim molding in position against the rear edge of the air
                    deflector extender assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601020">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601020" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601020" filename="../figg16/G1601020.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 20. Flexible Cab Trim Moulding</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install No. 10 fasteners starting from the center and working out toward each end as
                    illustrated in
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601020">Figure 20</hotlnk>. Snug up each fastener. Align the forward edge of the
                    flexible molding flush with the outside trailing edge of the air deflector extender assembly.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten all fasteners from the center out to 6 ft-lbs. (8 N&#8226;m). Do not over
                    tighten as distortion of the flexible molding and retainer may result.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Drilling Templates</title>
            <para>It will be necessary to create metal templates to use as a guide to drill the front bracket mounting
                holes in the air deflector (step 9 under
                <hotlnk xrefid="hl1601002">LOW ROOF</hotlnk>). One template can be made using the right side
                measurements. Reverse the right template to use it on the left side.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>High Roof</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the 5/16"-18 torx hd. capscrews installed around the high roof (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601021">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601021" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601021" filename="../figg16/G1601021.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 21. High Roof - Remove Capscrews</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully set the roof air deflector on the roof so that the holes in the air deflector
                    line up with the holes in the roof (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601022">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601022" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601022" filename="../figg16/G1601022.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 22. Align Holes</caption>
                </figure>
                <specpara>
                    <caution>
                        <para>Care should be taken not to mar the paint on the roof during air deflector installation.
                        </para>
                    </caution>
                </specpara>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reinstall the 5/16"-18 torx hd. capscrews that were removed in step 1 to secure the air
                    deflector to the roof (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601022">Figure 22</hotlnk>). Tighten to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Air Deflector Extender Installation</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the left and right flexible cab trim molding to the rear of both air deflector
                    extenders. Position the flexible trim flush with the top of the air deflector extender. Secure the
                    trim in position with one #10-16 x 1-1/4" self-drilling pan hd. screw in the center of the molding.
                    Tighten the screws to 6 ft-lbs. (8 N&#8226;m).
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT OVER TIGHTEN.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Hold the air deflector extender in position against the back of the roof air deflector
                    with "C" clamps. Position the extender so it is even with the top and flush with the outer edge of
                    the roof air deflector.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use the three holes in the extender as a template and drill 11/32" holes through the
                    roof air deflector in these locations.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the air deflector extender to the back of the roof air deflector with three
                    5/16"-18 x 1-1/4" bolts, 5/16" flat washers, special washers and lock nuts in the three drilled
                    holes as illustrated in view B-B,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601023">Figure 23</hotlnk>. Tighten the fasteners to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                    Repeat this procedure on the opposite side of the roof air deflector.
                </para>
                <figure id="f1601023" figsize="col-wide">
                    <graphic id="g1601023" filename="../figg16/G1601023.webp" type="webp"/>
                    <caption>Figure 23. Air Deflector Extender Installation</caption>
                </figure>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the roof fairing extender brace between the rear of the roof air deflector and
                    the air deflector extender as illustrated in views A-A and C-C,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601023">Figure 23</hotlnk>. Tighten fasteners to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the side rear upper air deflector mounting brackets between the upper and lower
                    side mounted air deflectors with 5/16"-18 x 1" SST hex hd. bolts and 5/16" lock washers as
                    illustrated in view "D",
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1601023">Figure 23</hotlnk>. Tighten all fasteners to 18 ft-lbs. (24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">At the lower end of the angle bracket on the air deflector extender is a hole. Make sure
                    the lower end of the extender is flush with the outside of the roof air deflector and install a
                    #10-16 x 1-1/4" self-drilling pan hd. screws in this hole, into the back of the fiberglass roof.
                    Tighten to 6 ft-lbs. (8 N&#8226;m).
                    <emph type="bold">DO NOT OVER TIGHTEN.</emph>
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat this procedure on the opposite side of the roof air deflector.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16010.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
