<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - AIR
        CONDITIONING SYSTEM SERVICE - RECOVERY/RECYCLING/CHARGING STATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1601925" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="1">
        <title>RECOVERY/RECYCLING/CHARGING STATION</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601956">Figure 41</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601956" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1601975.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                <caption>Figure 41. Recovery Station (Shown Connected to a CCI Compressor)</caption>
            </figure>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Before doing any of the work below, read the
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601912.xml" xrefid="hl1601912">SERVICE WARNINGS</hotlnk>. Failure to
                        read the Service Warnings and to be aware of the dangers involved when working with refrigerant
                        could lead to serious personal injury.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>To prevent damage to the test equipment, make sure test equipment is clear of all moving parts
                        in the engine compartment.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>The fittings on the service hoses for R-134a air conditioning systems are standard Metric SAE
                        quick connect fittings (
                        <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601907.xml" xrefid="f1601940">Figure 40</hotlnk>) that will work
                        only on R-134a air conditioning system service ports.
                    </para>
                </important>
                <important>
                    <para>Although your service equipment may appear physically different from the equipment shown here,
                        the function of the equipment used to perform each service procedure is basically the same. If
                        you are performing these service procedures using service equipment different from that shown,
                        refer to the manufacturer's instructions supplied with that equipment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The locations of the A/C system high pressure and low pressure service ports vary by vehicle
                        model and year. The high pressure service port is located on the compressor's high pressure
                        discharge line between the compressor and the expansion valve. Typical locations are on the
                        receiver-dryer or on the compressor. The low pressure port is located on the compressor suction
                        line, between the expansion valve and the compressor.
                    </para>
                    <para>Discharge and suction ports are usually marked on the compressor head. If the marking is not
                        visible, you can identify the suction (low pressure) side by the larger diameter hose connected
                        to the compressor.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the protection caps from both service ports on the vehicle.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">On the recovery station and hose fittings, verify that all valves are closed. The valves
                    at the recovery station must be set to the CLOSED position. The valves at the quick connect fittings
                    must be set fully counter-clockwise (CCW).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the recovery station to the system as follows:</para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the
                        <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                        hose to the low pressure service port.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect the
                        <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                        hose to the high pressure service port.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>During system
                        <emph type="underscr">diagnostic tests</emph>, DO NOT OPEN either hand valve on the recovery
                        station for any reason. Equipment can be damaged, and personal injury can result. During
                        <emph type="underscr">service procedures</emph>, DO NOT OPEN the valves on the recovery station,
                        or the valves on the Metric SAE quick connect fittings, until instructed to do so in the
                        procedures.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Before opening the valves on the Metric SAE quick connect fittings, the fittings must be
                        connected to the service ports on the vehicle.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <para>Once the quick connect fittings are attached to the service ports, turning the knob
                <emph type="bold">clockwise</emph>
                (CW) pushes an internal pin down
                <emph type="bold">to open</emph>
                the service port valve (refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601907.xml" xrefid="f1601940">Figure 40</hotlnk>). Turning the knob CCW
                raises the pin, closing the service port valve. Once closed the quick-disconnect fitting can be removed
                without venting refrigerant from the system.
            </para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Be sure the valves on the Metric SAE quick connect fittings at the service ports on the
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    hoses are closed (fully CCW).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Verify that both valves on the recovery station are set to the CLOSED position.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the
                    <emph type="bold">blue</emph>
                    and
                    <emph type="bold">red</emph>
                    hoses from the vehicle service ports.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601907.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_HL1601915.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
