<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTIC SYSTEM (APAds&#8482;) DESCRIPTION, OPERATION, TROUBLESHOOTING,
        REMOVE, INSTALL, AND ELECTRICAL CIRCUIT DIAGRAMS MAINTENANCE MANUAL - DESCRIPTION - AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION
        AND DIAGNOSTICS SYSTEM (APADS)
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="1">
        <title>AIR CONDITIONING PROTECTION AND DIAGNOSTICS SYSTEM (APADS)</title>
        <para>The air conditioning protection and diagnostics system (APADS) is an sealed electronic,
            microprocessor-controller based device. It is part of a family of controller products specifically designed
            to reduce the air conditioning maintenance costs in the vehicular heating, ventilation and air conditioning
            (HVAC) systems by increasing the life of the major system components and aiding in the diagnosis of system
            faults. With APADS, air conditioning reliability is improved by actively monitoring the system conditions,
            and controlling the refrigerant compressor clutch and the ON/OFF fan drive solenoid.
        </para>
        <para>APADS is composed of an electronic control module and two "smart" pressure switches. The APADS control
            module monitors inputs from the two "smart" pressure switches and the vehicle's thermostatic switch. The
            main feature of APADS is that it identifies A/C problems before they become major repairs. Simple,
            easy-to-read LED blink codes communicate specific fault codes that warn of existing or impending problems.
            This makes troubleshooting the A/C system faster and easier for the technician.
        </para>
        <para>This increases the life of system components and prevents compressor damage, APADS keeps trucks on the
            road longer and significantly reduces A/C maintenance costs.
        </para>
        <para>Refer to
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1602202">Figure 2</hotlnk>
        </para>
        <figure id="f1602202" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602202.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. APADS Control Module and Wiring Harness</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16022y.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
