<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 AND 8600 MODELS - INSTALL - CAB DOORS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="x1602923" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CAB DOORS</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Front Cab Door on Standard Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 and 8600 Models,
                Extended Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500 and 8600 Models and Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600
                Models
            </title>
            <para>Doors are of all steel-welded construction. The front cab door is mounted on hinges located on the
                front cab door hinge pillar and door adjustment is provided by enlarged holes in front cab door hinge.
                Door check stop is located just below upper hinge on the front cab door hinge pillar. Front cab door
                latch striker pin is also adjustable on front cab door lock pillar. Service on the door and its
                components are covered in sections which follow.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602939">Figure 39</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a sling or padded chain through top of window opening and attach sling to an
                    overhead hoist to support front cab door. Move front cab door (Item 6) from a padded work bench or
                    other suitable support covered with a material that protected painted surfaces of the door.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the front cab door (Item 6) is positioned at the cab. Carefully install the wiring
                    harness and connectors of front cab door through front cab door hinge pillar into the cab and pull
                    them through as far as they will go, as the cab door is placed on the hinges.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the wiring harness and connectors are installed into the cab. Slide four threaded
                    studs (Item 5) of front cab door (Item 6) into mounting holes of upper and lower front cab door
                    hinges (Items 7 and 8), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install four hex nuts with washers (Item 4) onto threaded studs (Item 5) of front cab
                    door (Item 6), driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position front cab door check link (Item 2) into front cab door check bracket (Item 3).
                    Install front cab door check stop pin (Item 1), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602938">Figure 38</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the front cab door is installed onto the cab. Reach up under the instrument panel
                    to the left of the steering wheel and connect CB radio cable connector (Item 1), electric window and
                    electric door lock wiring harness connector (Item 2) and lighted, heated or electric mirror wiring
                    harness connector (Item 3), if so equipped, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602937">Figure 37</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Reach up under the instrument panel and push the cab door wiring harness (Item 1) and
                    connectors (Item 2) up under the instrument panel, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602936">Figure 36</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install door wiring harness rubber boot (Item 1) onto the cab hinge pillar (Item 2),
                    driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side front cab door.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Rear Cab Door on Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and 7600 Models</title>
            <para>Doors are of all steel-welded construction. The rear cab door is mounted on hinges located on the cab
                B pillar and door adjustment is provided by enlarged holes in rear cab door hinge. Rear cab door check
                stop is located just below upper rear cab door hinge on the cab B pillar. Rear cab door latch striker
                pin is also adjustable on rear cab door lock pillar. Service on the door and its components are covered
                in sections which follow.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602944">Figure 44</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Use a sling or padded chain through top of window opening and attach sling to an
                    overhead hoist to support rear cab door. Move rear cab door (Item 6) from a padded work bench or
                    other suitable support covered with a material that protected painted surfaces of the door.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the rear cab door (Item 6) is positioned at the cab. Carefully install the wiring
                    harness and connector of rear cab door through rear cab door B pillar into the cab and pull them
                    through as far as they will go, as the cab door is placed on the hinges.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the wiring harness and connector is installed into the cab. Slide four threaded
                    studs (Item 5) of rear cab door (Item 6) into mounting holes of upper and lower rear cab door hinges
                    (Items 7 and 8), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install four hex nuts with washers (Item 4) onto threaded studs (Item 5) of rear cab
                    door (Item 6), driver side shown. Tighten to 14 to 18 Lbf-ft (19.6 to 24 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position rear cab door check link (Item 2) into rear cab door check bracket (Item 3).
                    Install rear cab door check stop pin (Item 1), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602943">Figure 43</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the rear cab door is installed onto the cab. Connect cab door light switch
                    connector (Item 3) to cab wiring harness light switch connector (Item 4), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect cab wiring harness electrical connector (Item 1) to cab door wiring harness
                    electrical connector (Item 2), driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602942">Figure 42</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses unless otherwise noted.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position B pillar trim panel (Item 3) inside cab at the cab B pillar. Lift seat belt
                    retractor cover
                    <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602941">(Item 2, Figure 41)</hotlnk>
                    and rear door seal plate
                    <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602941">(Item 4, Figure 41)</hotlnk>
                    up enough to allow installation of B pillar trim panel behind and underneath it.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Once the B pillar trim panel (Item 3) is positioned properly against the cab B pillar,
                    install six push-in fasteners (Item 2) through the B pillar trim panel into cab B pillar, driver
                    side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602941">Figure 41</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install push-in fastener (Item 1) securing the seat belt retractor cover (Item 2) to the
                    seat belt retractor bracket, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install torx head screw (Item 3) nearest the B pillar securing the rear door seal plate
                    (Item 4) to the cab floor, driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602940">Figure 40</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install a new torx head bolt (Item 1) and secure shoulder belt D - ring (Item 2) to the
                    B pillar trim panel (Item 3), driver side shown. Tighten to 25 to 35 Lbf-ft (34 to 47.5 N&#8226;m).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602903.xml" xrefid="f1602936">Figure 36</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install door wiring harness rubber boot (Item 1) onto the cab hinge pillar (Item 2),
                    driver side shown.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Repeat procedure to install passenger side rear cab door.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_74.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_76.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
