<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CF 500, CF 600 Cab - Glass, Frames and Mechanisms - Glass, Frames and Mechanisms Description and Operation
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="0">
        <title>Glass, Frames and Mechanisms Description and Operation</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power Window System</title>
            <para>
                <title>Features and Operation</title>
            </para>
            <para>If equipped with power windows, the window control switch:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>will operate the power windows only when the ignition switch is in the ON or ACC position.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>is located on each front door trim panel.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>may be used to raise or lower the driver and passenger side windows from the LF window control
                        switch, or the passenger window from the passenger switch.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>for the LH window, includes a one-touch down (OTD) feature for the driver door window, which
                        is activated by pressing the LH window control switch to the 2nd detent position, then releasing
                        it.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>can partially lower the driver side window when the LF window control switch is depressed to
                        the 1st detent.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>will completely lower the driver side window when the LF window control switch is fully
                        depressed and then released (2nd detent).
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Power Window System - Modes of Operation</title>
            <para>There are 2 modes of operation for the power window system.</para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Manual Mode</emph>
            </para>
            <para>When the LH front window control switch is pressed to the 1st detent, the LH front window will move
                down until 1 of the following conditions are met:
            </para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The LH front window control switch has been released from the 1st detent.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The LH front window control switch is pushed to the OTD position (2nd detent), causing the LF
                        window to enter auto mode.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Auto Mode</emph>
            </para>
            <para>Auto mode provides the OTD feature. The OTD feature is activated when the LH window control switch for
                the LH window is pressed to the 2nd detent.
            </para>
            <para>Auto mode will be terminated when any of the following conditions are met:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>The LH window control switch is pushed to the UP position</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The LH window control switch is released (OFF position) and then moved to the DOWN position
                        (1st detent) or OTD position (2nd detent)
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>The delayed accessory relay is active</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
            <para>The OTD feature is integral to the LH front window control switch assembly.</para>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Rear Window Glass</title>
            <para>The rear glass:</para>
            <randlist type="bullet">
                <item>
                    <para>is standard tempered safety glass.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>is fixed to the rear of the cab with a formed weatherstrip.</para>
                </item>
            </randlist>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_X5011148.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032_21.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16032.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
