<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL - ACTUATOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND
        DOOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390815" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ACTUATOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Accessing the temperature blend door actuator may require the removal of trim panels not described in
                this manual. Refer to the appropriate CAB section(s) in Group 16 of the Master Service Manual for
                additional procedures.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1603938">Figure 38</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following Remove and Install procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove fuse panel cover from passenger side instrument panel by pulling top of cover
                    away from IP to release spring clips, then lift cover up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove trim panels, as necessary, to gain access to mounting screws for heater trim
                    cover (4, Figure 38).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove nine screws from heater trim cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove heater trim cover by pulling it straight back.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect electrical plug connected to temperature blend door actuator (6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove two screws securing actuator to blower scroll housing (3), and pull actuator
                    straight off of temperature blend door shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, never force the actuator drive collar into position. If the drive
                        collar position must be changed, follow the following procedures. Forcing the drive collar may
                        result in a broken actuator.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install actuator by rotating door until flats on door shaft align with actuator drive
                    collar, if possible, then carefully slip the actuator onto end of door shaft so that mounting holes
                    are properly aligned. If actuator drive collar must be moved to allow alignment:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place actuator into its approximate position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">To rotate drive collar, connect a 9 Volt battery across the active pins of the
                        actuator connector (check mating connector if necessary). (Reverse connection to rotate drive
                        collar in opposite direction.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Allow drive collar to rotate until it is aligned with door shaft, and actuator
                        mounting screws can be inserted. Then, disconnect battery.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure actuator to blower scroll housing (3, Figure 38) using two screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect electrical control plug to temperature blend door actuator (6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure heater trim cover (4) to heater housing with nine screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603938" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1603938.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="502px"/>
                <caption>Figure 38. Heater Unit Exploded View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEATER HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HEATER CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BLOWER SCROLL HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HEATER TRIM COVER</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. BLOWER WIRE HARNESS</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ACTUATOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. LINEAR POWER MODULE (BLOWER SPEED CONTROL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. BLOWER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. ACTUATOR, MODE CONTROL DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. LINEAR POWER MODULE COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install all additional trim panels removed to gain access to heater trim cover.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install fuse panel cover by inserting two tabs at bottom of cover into sockets in IP;
                    then press top of cover toward IP to engage spring clips.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step the actuator may also be recalibrated by disconnecting the vehicle
                        battery for 15 seconds; however, this method may result in disrupting other electrical equipment
                        (radio presets, etc.).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recalibrate temperature blend door by disconnecting HVAC control panel assembly for at
                    least 15 seconds. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390821.xml" xrefid="hl160390821">HVAC CONTROL PANEL ASSEMBLY, REMOVE
                        AND INSTALL
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390821"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390814.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390816.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
