<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC) SYSTEM - ProStar - REMOVE AND INSTALL - AIR CONDITIONER
        (EVAPORATOR) HOUSING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl160390810" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="3">
        <title>AIR CONDITIONER (EVAPORATOR) HOUSING</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>Removal and installation of the evaporator housing requires the removal of other assemblies (such as
                cab cowl tray). The assemblies that must be removed vary by vehicle model and engine combinations. Refer
                to the appropriate section(s) in the Master Service Manual for additional procedures.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If you were referenced to this procedure from the heater housing removal procedure; note that
                        on some vehicles it may be possible to unmount the evaporator housing and move it away from the
                        cowl enough to remove the heater housing mounting nuts (located behind the evaporator housing),
                        WITHOUT disconnecting the A/C lines. Inspect the vehicle being serviced and review the following
                        procedure to determine if complete removal of the evaporator housing is necessary. If it is
                        determined that disconnection of the A/C lines is unnecessary, review the following procedures
                        and perform only the steps required to remove the evaporator housing from the cowl. If this
                        method is followed, it will still be necessary to unclamp A/C lines to allow movement. When
                        positioning the evaporator housing out of the way DO NOT kink the A/C lines.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove cab cowl tray.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Discharge A/C system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390905.xml" xrefid="hl160390905">DISCHARGING THE SYSTEM</hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390905"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring to thermistors (2 and 5,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603932">Figure 32</hotlnk>) and remove strap locks, as necessary, to allow
                    connectors to be moved out of the way.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unclip or remove clamps securing condenser-to-evaporator line (10) to evaporator housing
                    (9).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect end of condenser-to-evaporator line from filter-drier (6).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Unclip clamps and/or strap locks securing evaporator-to-compressor line (7) to cowl.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect end of evaporator-to-compressor line from outlet thermistor line (5).</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603932" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603932.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Evaporator Housing (Shown with Cowl Tray Removed)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EVAPORATOR INLET LINE (INCLUDES INPUT THERMISTOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INPUT THERMISTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. EVAPORATOR OUTLET LINE (INCLUDES LOW SIDE SERVICE PORT)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. THERMOSTATIC EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. OUTPUT THERMISTOR LINE (INCLUDES OUTPUT THERMISTOR)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. FILTER-DRIER</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. EVAPORATOR-TO-COMPRESSOR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. HEATER HOSES</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. CONDENSER-TO-EVAPORATOR LINE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect wiring connector to actuator motor for fresh/recirc air door (16,
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603933">Figure 33</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603933" figsize="full-pg">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603933.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 33. Evaporator Housing Mounting and Components</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. EVAPORATOR INLET LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. INPUT THERMISTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BOTTOM LOCKING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. THERMOSTATIC EXPANSION VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. TOP LOCKING PLATE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. T30 TORX HEAD SCREW</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. OUTPUT THERMISTOR LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. OUTPUT THERMISTOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. 3 MM ALLEN HEAD CAPSCREW (2)</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. EVAPORATOR OUTLET LINE</callout1>
                    <callout1>11. FILTER-DRIER</callout1>
                    <callout1>12. EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>13. GASKET/SEAL, AIR INTAKE</callout1>
                    <callout1>14. GASKET, EVAPORATOR HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>15. RECIRCULATE/FRESH AIR DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>16. ACTUATOR, RECIRC DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>17. DRAIN TUBES</callout1>
                    <callout1>18. EVAPORATOR CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>19. BOLTS, FILTER-DRIER MTG</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove four nuts securing evaporator housing (12, Figure 33) to mounting studs on
                    cowl.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully remove evaporator housing from cowl.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The need to perform additional steps is determined by the specific repair being performed.
                        Perform only the following steps that are required to transfer parts to a replacement housing or
                        to replace parts within the removed housing.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">To remove recirc door actuator (16, Figure 33), remove two screws securing actuator to
                    evaporator housing (12).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove drain tubes (17, Figure 33) from evaporator housing.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove filter-drier, expansion valve, and associated a/c lines, as an assembly (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1603934">Figure 34</hotlnk>), as follows.
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove screw securing filter-drier inlet line clamp to evaporator housing.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Remove nuts securing evaporator inlet and outlet lines (1 and 10, Figure 33) to the
                        evaporator core inlet and outlet fittings.
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">While supporting filter-drier (11, Figure 33), remove two mounting bolts (19)
                        securing filter-drier to evaporator housing.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>While separating evaporator housing be careful not to damage fins or fittings on evaporator
                        core.
                    </para>
                </caution>
                <note>
                    <para>The housing halves normally snap together and are secured with one screw (hi-lo thread);
                        however, mounting tabs are provided to allow assembling the halves with additional hi-lo thread
                        screws if the plastic snaps are damaged during disassembly. The mounting tabs are designed
                        specifically to use only hi-lo thread screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Separate housing halves by removing one or more hi-lo thread screws, releasing snap
                    tabs, and pulling halves straight away from each other.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove and discard mounting gaskets (13 and 14, Figure 33) if they are damaged during
                    separation.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With housing separated, the evaporator core and/or fresh/recirculate air door may be
                    removed.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>When replacing a damaged fresh/recirc air door verify that no parts remain lodged in the
                        housing or evaporator core.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When replacing a damaged evaporator housing (or housing half), transfer all good
                    components (evaporator core, fresh/recirculate door, door actuator, and drain tubes) from the
                    damaged housing to the new housing.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1603934" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1603934.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitheight="192px"/>
                <caption>Figure 34. Filter-Drier, Expansion Valve, and Associated A/C Lines</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Depending on the level of disassembly required for the repair, some of the following steps may
                        not be necessary for each installation.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If refrigerant system is to be flushed or purged, perform that operation before
                    reassembling the system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390909.xml" xrefid="hl160390909">PURGING OR FLUSHING THE AIR
                        CONDITIONING SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390909"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">When installing a new evaporator housing or reinstalling a housing that was removed for
                    service, verify that all internal components (evaporator core and fresh/recirculate door) are
                    installed in the housing before joining the housing halves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The housing halves normally snap together and are secured with one screw (hi-lo thread);
                        however, mounting tabs are provided to allow assembling the halves with additional hi-lo thread
                        screws if the plastic snaps are damaged during disassembly. The mounting tabs are designed
                        specifically to use only hi-lo thread screws.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Join housing halves by using snap tabs and one screw. If any snap tabs have been
                    damaged, use additional hi-lo thread screws in the molded joining tabs to securely join housing
                    halves.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, never force the actuator drive collar into position. If the drive
                        collar position must be changed, perform the following procedures. Forcing the drive collar may
                        result in a broken actuator.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If fresh/recirculate air door actuator (16, Figure 33), was previously removed, install
                    actuator by rotating door until flats on door shaft align with actuator hub, if possible. If
                    actuator drive collar must be moved to allow alignment:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place actuator into its approximate position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect a 9 Volt battery across pins A and F of actuator connector, to rotate drive
                        collar. (Reverse connection to rotate drive collar in opposite direction.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Allow drive collar to rotate until it is aligned with door shaft, and actuator
                        mounting screws can be inserted. Then, disconnect battery.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure actuator to evaporator housing with two screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install drain tubes (17, Figure 33).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a new gasket/seal (14, Figure 33), install evaporator housing (12) onto mounting
                    studs located on cowl using four nuts. Tighten to 5,400 to 7,600 N.mm (47.5 to 67.5 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following steps the filter-drier, expansion valve, and their associated a/c lines are
                        treated as an assembly. When installing this assembly care must be taken to align connections
                        properly and to not place undue stress on a/c line connections. Once the filter-drier mounting
                        bolts are loosely installed to support the assembly, the a/c line connections should be torqued
                        to provide proper joining and alignment, before tightening the filter-drier mounting bolts.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Always lubricate O-rings on fittings with mineral-based oil during installation.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place new O-rings and C-plates on evaporator inlet and outlet lines (1 and 10, Figure
                    33).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place filter-drier/expansion valve assembly (Figure 34) into its approximate position by
                    inserting evaporator inlet and outlet lines into evaporator core inlet and outlet fittings; AND
                    loosely installing the two filter-drier mounting bolts (19, Figure 33). (Filter-drier mounting bolts
                    must be loose enough to allow proper alignment of evaporator inlet and outlet fittings while
                    supporting the weight of the filter-drier.)
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install nuts securing evaporator inlet and outlet lines to the evaporator core inlet and
                    outlet fittings. Tighten to 19,000 to 21,000 N.mm (170 to 190 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tighten two mounting bolts securing filter-drier to evaporator housing. Tighten to
                    11,000 to 11,600 N.mm (97 to 103 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure filter-drier inlet line clamp to evaporator housing using one screw.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a new O-ring and C-plate connect end of evaporator-to-compressor line (7, Figure
                    32) to outlet thermistor line (5). Tighten to 19,000 to 21,000 N.mm (170 to 190 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure evaporator-to-compressor line to cowl using existing clamp(s).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Using a new O-ring and C-plate connect end of condenser-to-evaporator line (10, Figure
                    32) to filter-drier inlet fitting. Tighten to 19,000 to 21,000 N.mm (170 to 190 lbf-in).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure condenser-to-evaporator line to evaporator housing (9, Figure 32) using existing
                    clamps.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring to thermistors (2 and 5, Figure 32) and secure wires in original position
                    using strap locks.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect wiring connector to actuator motor (16, Figure 33) for fresh/recirc air door.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>In the following step the actuator may also be recalibrated by disconnecting the vehicle
                        battery for 15 seconds; however, this method may result in disrupting other electrical equipment
                        (radio presets, etc.).
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recalibrate fresh/recirc air door by disconnecting HVAC control panel assembly for at
                    least 15 seconds. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390821.xml" xrefid="hl160390821">HVAC CONTROL PANEL ASSEMBLY, REMOVE
                        AND INSTALL
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390821"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recharge A/C system. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390907.xml" xrefid="hl160390907">CHARGING THE AIR CONDITIONING
                        SYSTEM
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl160390907"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install cab cowl tray/HVAC air inlet.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390809.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039_HL160390811.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16039.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
