<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - BEFORE 01/01/1993 (R-12)</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsection id="s16013j" svcsectype="prodspec" division="truck" formnum="CTS-5068J" date="03/31/1996">
        <title>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - BEFORE 01/01/1993 (R-12)</title>
        <apply>
            <configure>
                <truckmodelgroup/>

                <truckmodel>5000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/30/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9200
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/30/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9300
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/30/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9400
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>11/30/1992</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>2000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>4000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>8000
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9600
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
                <truckmodel>9700
                    <daterange>
                        <enddate>01/01/1993</enddate>
                    </daterange>
                </truckmodel>
            </configure>
        </apply>
        <description>
            <geninfo>
                <lev1>
                    <para>To meet the Federal Government's scheduled phase-out of CFC-12 (R-12) refrigerant,
                        International will start building vehicles charged with the new refrigerant HFC-134A on the
                        following dates:
                    </para>
                    <para>5000, 9200, 9300, 9400 Series on November 30, 1992.</para>
                    <para>2000, 4000, 8000, 9600, 9700 Series on January 1, 1993.</para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
                    <para>The compressor is a two-cylinder reciprocating unit (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601301">Figure 1</hotlnk>). It is belt driven through a magnetic clutch
                        located on the compressor crankshaft.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1601301" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1601301" filename="../figg16/g1601301.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="532px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 1. Refrigerant Compressor and Clutch</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. CLUTCH COMPRESSOR DRIVE</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. PORT CAPS (KEEP IN PLACE WHEN LINES ARE DISCONNECTED)</callout1>
                            <callout1>4. OIL FILL PLUG</callout1>
                            <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The functions of the compressor are to push the refrigerant through the air conditioning
                        system, and compress and superheat the heat-saturated refrigerant returned from the evaporator.
                    </para>
                    <para>The compressor crankcase, cylinder head, pistons, connecting rods, bearing housing, valve
                        plate and base plate are die cast aluminum. The crankshaft is cast iron as are the cylinder
                        liners, which are permanently cast into the crankcase.
                    </para>
                    <para>The lubrication system uses the existing pressure differential between the suction intake and
                        the crankcase to provide lubricating oil to bearings and internal components. An oil plug on
                        each side of the crankcase permits oil checking regardless of compressor mounting.
                    </para>
                    <para>With the introduction of HFC-134A refrigerant, the high pressure relief valve is moved from
                        the receiver-dryer to the compressor on production vehicles (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601301">Figure 1</hotlnk>). Replacement receiver-dryers will have a pressure
                        relief valve.
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>MAGNETIC CLUTCH</title>
                    <para>The compressor magnetic clutch is secured to the compressor crankshaft (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601302">Figure 2</hotlnk>). The purpose of the clutch is to engage and
                        disengage the belt drive as necessary to maintain desired interior cab temperature.
                    </para>
                    <figure id="f1601302" figsize="col-wide">
                        <graphic id="g1601302" filename="../figg16/g1601302.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                                 scalefitwidth="248px" scalefitheight="232px"/>
                        <caption>Figure 2. Compressor Clutch</caption>
                        <calloutgroup>
                            <callout1>1. PULLEY ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                            <callout1>2. FIELD COIL</callout1>
                            <callout1>3. COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                        </calloutgroup>
                    </figure>
                    <para>The primary components of the clutch are: the pulley assembly, which contains the clutch disc
                        and bearing and is mounted on the crankshaft, and the stationary field coil, mounted on the
                        compressor housing (
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1601302">Figure 2</hotlnk>).
                    </para>
                </lev1>
                <lev1>
                    <title>OPERATION</title>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>COMPRESSOR</title>
                        <para>The compressor is driven by the vehicle engine and operates on demand by the air
                            conditioning system through the magnetic clutch. During the down stroke a slight vacuum is
                            created between the top of the piston and the cylinder head causing the inlet valve to open.
                            Refrigerant at a pressure of 12 to 50 psi is drawn into the cylinder. As the piston begins
                            its upward stroke, the refrigerant that was drawn into the cylinder on the down stroke is
                            being compressed. Pressure on the inlet valve allows it to close. The piston continues its
                            upward stroke and refrigerant now compressed to 120-300 psi pushes the outlet valve open.
                            Refrigerant flows through the open valve into the air conditioning system.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                    <lev2>
                        <title>MAGNETIC CLUTCH</title>
                        <para>During operation, electrical current flows into the field coil. The energized field coil,
                            acting as an electromagnet, holds the clutch plate in contact with the pulley, setting the
                            compressor in motion. When the cab interior reaches the desired temperature, the field coil
                            is de-energized, the clutch plate is released from the pulley, and compressor operation
                            stops.
                        </para>
                    </lev2>
                </lev1>
            </geninfo>
        </description>
    </svcsection>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="2">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16013j_2.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16013j.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
