<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 AND 8600 MODELS - INSTALL - REAR INTERIOR TRIM PANEL</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="0">
        <title>REAR INTERIOR TRIM PANEL</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install Rear Interior Trim Panel on Standard Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500 and 8600
                Models, Extended Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 8500 and 8600 Models and Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500
                and 7600 Models
            </title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The step below shows installing both driver and passenger side corner and side interior trim
                        panels after installing rear interior trim panel. If one or the other of the corner and side
                        interior trim panels was not removed during the removal step, you will need only to reinstall
                        the side and corner interior trim panel that was removed.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s160295_47.xml" xrefid="f16029107">Figure 107</hotlnk>
                for Items in parentheses.
            </para>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Place rear interior trim panel (Item 3) inside the cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position rear interior trim panel (Item 3) over mounting holes in cab back panel and
                    install five push-in fasteners (Item 2) across the top of the rear interior trim panel. Make sure
                    floor mat is properly fitted around rear interior trim panel at the bottom.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install passenger and driver side corner and side interior corner trim panel, refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602936.xml" xrefid="x1602936">
                        <emph type="bold">CORNER AND SIDE INTERIOR TRIM PANEL</emph>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . For installing passenger and driver side corner and side interior trim panel into standard cab,
                    refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Corner and Side Interior Trim Panel on Standard Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500,
                        7600, 7700, 8500 and 8600 Models</emph>. For installing passenger and driver side corner and
                    side interior trim panel into extended cab, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Corner and Side Interior Trim Panel on Extended Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500,
                        7600, 8500 and 8600 Models</emph>. For installing passenger and driver side corner and side
                    interior trim panel into crew cab, refer to
                    <emph type="bold">Install Corner and Side Interior Trim Panel on Crew Cab for 7300, 7400, 7500 and
                        7600 Models</emph>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_101.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295_X1602937.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s160295.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
