<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING BASIC THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE (with R-134a Refrigerant System) - DESCRIPTION
        OF SYSTEM COMPONENTS - COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="describe" graphiccount="3">
        <title>COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <para>The compressor is mounted on the engine and is belt-driven through an electromagnetic clutch which
                acts to engage (turn ON) or disengage (turn OFF) the compressor in response to the air conditioning
                system controls.
            </para>
            <para>When engaged, the clutch armature assembly is magnetically drawn to the pulley assembly on the
                compressor shaft, thereby engaging the clutch and driving the compressor.
            </para>
            <para>The suction side of the compressor draws low pressure refrigerant vapor (5 to 50 psi) from the
                evaporator (low pressure side of system). The compressor then compresses the refrigerant vapor and
                discharges it at increased temperature and pressure (120 to 300 psi) through the high side line which
                connects the compressor to the condenser (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601909">Figure 8</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601909" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601909" filename="../figg16/G1601909a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 8. Refrigerant Vapor is Compressed and Discharged (CCI Type Compressor Shown)</caption>
            </figure>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>TWO-CYLINDER CCI COMPRESSOR</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601908">Figure 9</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Before 11/1/02, a two-cylinder, CCI compressor was used. In this compressor, each piston is actuated
                via its connecting rod, in response to crankshaft rotation.
            </para>
            <para>An internal lubricating system uses the suction side intake crankcase pressure differential to coat
                internal parts with a thin film of oil. This lubrication also travels along with the refrigerant
                throughout the air conditioning system to lubricate various system components.
            </para>
            <para>Refer to the
                <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16017x.htm" bookname="s16017x">s16017</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING
                COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH Service Manual Section in the Master Service Manual for greater detail on these
                units.
            </para>
            <para>A pressure relief valve was located on the receiver-dryer on earlier systems. The pressure relief
                valve is located on the compressor on later systems. This offers better protection to the compressor in
                extreme high pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The label on the clutch side of the compressor (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601908">Figure 9</hotlnk>) lists the type of refrigerant and oil used in the system
                and the refrigerant charge quantity recommended by International.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601908" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1601908" filename="../figg16/G1601908a.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1"
                         scalefitwidth="408px"/>
                <caption>Figure 9. Two-Cylinder CCI Compressor and Clutch - (Used Before 11-1-02)</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COMPRESSOR DRIVE CLUTCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. PORT CAPS (KEEP IN PLACE WHEN LINES ARE DISCONNECTED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. OIL FILL PLUG</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. LABEL</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>SEVEN-CYLINDER SANDEN COMPRESSOR</title>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1601954">Figure 10</hotlnk>.
            </para>
            <para>Since 11/1/02, a Sanden, seven-cylinder 'wobble plate' compressor has been used. These compressors use
                'peanut' style fittings on the A/C lines. Prior to this date, the Sanden compressor was available only
                as an option. The earlier version of the Sanden compressor used standard threaded fittings on the A/C
                lines. In this compressor, each piston is actuated via its connecting rod, in response to the action of
                a wobble plate. A pressure relief valve is located on the compressor to provide protection to the
                compressor in the event of extreme high pressure.
            </para>
            <para>The compressor, and the other system components, are lubricated by the lubrication that travels along
                with the refrigerant throughout the air conditioning system. The label on the compressor lists the type
                of refrigerant and oil used in the system, and the refrigerant charge quantity recommended by
                International.
            </para>
            <para>The Sanden compressor and clutch are to be replaced as an assembly. Additional service information for
                this compressor is found in this manual.
            </para>
            <figure id="f1601954" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/G1601973.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px"/>
                <caption>Figure 10. Typical Seven-Cylinder Sanden Compressor and Clutch (Version with 'Peanut' Style
                    Fittings Shown)
                </caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. REFRIGERANT COMPRESSOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. COMPRESSOR DRIVE CLUTCH</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. OIL FILL PLUG</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PORT CAPS (KEEP IN PLACE WHEN LINES ARE DISCONNECTED)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. HIGH PRESSURE RELIEF VALVE</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_9.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019_11.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16019.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
