<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING COMPRESSOR AND CLUTCH, TWO CYLINDER RECIPROCATING TYPE - After 01/01/1993 (R-134a) -
        LUBRICATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1601706">
        <title>LUBRICATION</title>
        <svcproc svcproctype="check" graphiccount="0">
            <title>REFRIGERANT OIL</title>
            <para>Effective approximately February 1, 1995, all refrigerant compressors used in truck production are
                filled with Lubrizol LZ-2916 Ester Oil. If adding oil is necessary when servicing the air conditioning
                system, and the compressor is filled with PAG oil, we recommend that the PAG oil be drained from the
                compressor and refilled with Lubrizol LZ-2916 Ester Oil.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>The label on the refrigerant compressor specifies the type of oil it is filled with.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>If the compressor is refilled with Lubrizol LZ-2916 Ester oil, it is recommended that the oil
                        identification on the label on the compressor be changed to reflect the change in oil.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>Refer to
                <hotlnk document="s16017x_13.xml" xrefid="hl1601702">SPECIFICATIONS</hotlnk>
                for the amount of Ester oil for the system.
            </para>
            <para>Ester oil is compatible with mineral and PAG oil. When changing from mineral or PAG oil to Ester oil,
                it is not necessary to flush the system unless it is contaminated.
            </para>
            <para>
                <emph type="bold">Be sure to observe the following:</emph>
            </para>
            <seqlist>
                <item>
                    <para>PAG oil can never be mixed with mineral oil and can only be used in R-134a systems.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Mineral oil can never be mixed with PAG oil and can only be used in R-12 systems.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Lubrizol LZ-2916 Ester oil can be mixed with either mineral or PAG oil. It is permissible to
                        add Ester oil in small amounts to systems filled with either PAG or mineral oil.
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Keep spare refrigerant oil in a sealed container. The oil draws moisture and will become
                        moisture contaminated if exposed to the atmosphere for any period of time.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x_12.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16017x.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
