<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>AIR CONDITIONING - HEATER SYSTEM: 5000i, 9100i, 9200i, 9400i, 9900i MODELS - Starting 03/01/1999 - SERVICE
        HINTS
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="repair" graphiccount="0">
        <title>SERVICE HINTS</title>
        <para>Special attention to the following during component remove and install will aid in avoiding unnecessary
            and time-consuming problems.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Note electrical connections during removal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">It is most important that all refrigerant hose, O-rings, and tubing fittings be lubricated
                with
                <emph type="bold">MINERAL-BASED</emph>
                refrigerant oil and tightened as specified in the
                <hotlnk document="s16023_X1602321.xml" xrefid="x1602321">TORQUE CHART</hotlnk>. Use only a torque wrench
                known to be correct.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Always use a back-up wrench when loosening or tightening fittings.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Replace the receiver-dehydrator unit on any system which is opened for more than a short
                period (&#60;30 minutes), when the system is flushed, and/or when the compressor is replaced for an
                internal failure, causing system contamination.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All refrigerant hose and tubing support clamps and stay locks must be re-installed in their
                original position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The air conditioning system must be purged and flushed, as described in
                <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16019.htm" bookname="s16019">s16019</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING BASIC
                THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual, any time the compressor is replaced
                due to an internal failure, causing system contamination.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">The compressor oil level must be checked and replaced as specified in
                <exhotlnk document="../s16/s16019.htm" bookname="s16019">s16019</exhotlnk>, AIR CONDITIONING BASIC
                THEORY, SYSTEM DIAGNOSIS AND SERVICE in the Master Service Manual.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">All A/C component and refrigerant line openings should be immediately covered or plugged
                during removal and remain so until re-installation to prevent the entry of dirt, moisture and other
                foreign material. Even the slightest particle can cause problems if carried to a vulnerable place within
                the system.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023_13.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16023.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
