<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>CAB: DAYCAB AND SLEEPER CAB for ProStar, ProStar Premium, and ProStar Limited Models - ADJUSTMENTS - Daycab
        Ride Height
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="2">
        <title>Daycab Ride Height</title>
        <specpara>
            <warning>
                <para>To prevent property damage or personal injury, park the vehicle on a level surface, set the
                    parking brake, chock the wheels, and turn the engine off.
                </para>
            </warning>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">These procedures are to provide instructions and specifications for setting the desired cab
                ride height. Before starting the adjustment procedure, be sure that the following conditions are met or
                performed.
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Park the chassis on a flat level surface.</para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">The chassis air system should be within the normal operating range of 100 to 120 psi.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">Ensure that all cab mounting, hood mounting, muffler mounting components, and air
                    cleaner mounting components are correctly installed to ensure free (unobstructed) movement of the
                    cab.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">There must not be any occupants in the cab and no change in cab weight during the
                    adjustment procedures
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f16033e5" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g16033e5.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                     scalefitheight="248px"/>
            <caption>Figure 151. Daycab Ride Height Measurement</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. JOUNCE BUMPER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CROSSMEMBER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Measure the cab ride height between the bottom of the jounce bumper and the top of the
                crossmember. This measurement must be made between the two measuring points that are specified and must
                meet specified height of 1.79 inches (45.4 mm) for all ProStar&#8482; daycab models.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f16033e6" figsize="pg-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg16/g16033e6.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="312px"
                     scalefitheight="312px"/>
            <caption>Figure 152. Daycab Linkage Adjustment</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. VALVE LEVER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. LINKAGE SOCKET</callout1>
                <callout1>3. LINKAGE</callout1>
                <callout1>4. LOCKING CLIP</callout1>
                <callout1>5. NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>6. HEIGHT VALVE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the linkage from the ride height valve by removing the nut from the linkage
                socket and valve lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>It is very important that the height valve be cycled completely before and after any ride height
                    adjustments. Cycling of the height valve will help make the adjustment more accurate.
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Dump air from the rear cab air suspension by rotating the valve lever to the EXH (exhaust)
                position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Refill the rear cab air suspension to the proper ride height of 1.79 inches (45.4 mm) by
                rotating the valve lever to the FILL position.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the locking clip from the linkage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Turn the linkage socket clockwise to lengthen the linkage or turn the linkage socket
                counterclockwise to shorten the linkage.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>When at proper length, the linkage should connect to the valve lever without affecting the ride
                    height adjustment.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Attach the linkage socket onto the valve lever and secure with the nut. Torque nut to 8 to
                10 Lbf-ft (10.8 to 13.6 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Re-measure the cab ride height, and adjust as required. Proper ride height is 1.79 inches
                (45.4 mm) for all ProStar&#8482; daycab models.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_X16033205.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033_135.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16033.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
