<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>HEAT VENTILATION AIR CONDITIONING (HVAC), Orifice Tube System, Pre-March 2007 - 3200, 4100, 4200, 4300,
        4400, 7300, 7400, 7500, 7600, 7700, 8500, 8600 - REMOVE AND INSTALL - ACTUATOR MOTOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1602514" svcproctype="remove" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ACTUATOR MOTOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR</title>
        <svcprocinfo>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Refer to
                        <hotlnk xrefid="f1602531">Figure 32</hotlnk>
                        while performing the following Remove and Install procedures.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </svcprocinfo>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Remove</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the passenger side instrument panel cover by pulling the top of the cover away
                    from the IP to release the spring clips, then lift the cover up.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove nine screws from the heater trim cover (4).</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the cover by pulling it straight back.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the electrical plug connected to the temperature blend door actuator motor
                    (6).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the two screws securing the actuator to the blower scroll housing (3), and pull
                    the actuator (6) straight off of the temperature blend door shaft.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Install</title>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>In the following step, never force the actuator drive collar into position. If the drive
                        collar position must be changed, follow the following procedures. Forcing the drive collar may
                        result in a broken actuator.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Carefully slip the actuator (6) onto the end of the temperature blend door shaft so that
                    the mounting holes are properly aligned, if possible. If alignment is necessary:
                </para>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Place the actuator into its approximate position.</para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Connect a 9 Volt battery across pins A and F of the actuator connector, to rotate
                        the drive collar. (Reverse the connection to rotate the drive collar in the opposite direction.)
                    </para>
                </step2>
                <step2>
                    <para count="1">Allow the drive collar to rotate until it is aligned with the door shaft, and the
                        actuator mounting screws can be inserted. Then, disconnect 9 Volt battery.
                    </para>
                </step2>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the actuator to the blower scroll housing (3) using two screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the electrical control plug to the temperature blend door actuator motor (6).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Secure the heater trim cover (4) to the heater housing with nine screws.</para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1602531" figsize="pg-wide">
                <graphic filename="../figg16/g1602531.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="514px"/>
                <caption>Figure 32. Heater Unit Exploded View</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. HEATER HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. HEATER CORE</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. BLOWER SCROLL HOUSING</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. HEATER TRIM PANEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>5A. BLOWER WIRE HARNESS (EARLY PRODUCTION - 2 PIECE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5B. BLOWER WIRE HARNESS (LATE PRODUCTION - 1 PIECE)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. ACTUATOR, TEMPERATURE BLEND DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>7. LINEAR POWER MODULE (BLOWER SPEED CONTROL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>8. BLOWER ASSEMBLY</callout1>
                    <callout1>9. ACTUATOR, MODE CONTROL DOOR</callout1>
                    <callout1>10. LINEAR POWER MODULE COVER</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the passenger side instrument panel cover by inserting the two tabs at the
                    bottom of the cover into the sockets in the IP; then press the top of the cover toward the IP to
                    engage the spring clips.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Recalibrate the temperature blend door by disconnecting the HVAC control panel assembly
                    for at least 15 seconds. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602521.xml" xrefid="hl1602521">REMOVE AND INSTALL, HVAC CONTROL PANEL
                        ASSEMBLY
                    </hotlnk>
                    <xref refid="hl1602521"/>.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602512.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025_HL1602513.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s16025.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
