<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CLUTCH CONTROL LINKAGE - 5000, 9300 AND 9400 SERIES -
        ADJUSTMENT - RELEASE SHAFT YOKE TO RELEASE BEARING CLEARANCE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1100803" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>RELEASE SHAFT YOKE TO RELEASE BEARING CLEARANCE</title>
        <para>To obtain the specified release shaft yoke to release bearing housing clearance (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1100803">Figure 3</hotlnk>), adjust the control linkage as outlined below. This adjustment
            will provide the specified clutch pedal free travel.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the control rod adjusting yoke lock nut.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the cotter and yoke pins and disconnect the control rod from release shaft or the
                pedal shaft lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1100803" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1100803" filename="../figg11/G1100803.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 3. Release Shaft Yoke to Release Bearing Clearance</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>C. CLEARANCE</callout1>
                <callout1>1. LOCK NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>2. CONTROL ROD</callout1>
                <callout1>3. YOKE</callout1>
                <callout1>4. RELEASE YOKE (FORK)</callout1>
                <callout1>5. RELEASE BEARING</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the release shaft until the release shaft yoke (fork) lightly contacts the release
                bearing housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Holding the release yoke (fork) against the release bearing housing (per Step 3), adjust the
                control rod yoke until the yoke pin can be freely installed through the yoke and shaft lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">To obtain the specified clearance, lengthen the control rod by turning the yoke seven (7)
                turns counterclockwise (as viewed from the adjusting yoke end of the control rod).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the control rod yoke to the shaft lever and install the yoke pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Where possible, inspect for the specified clearance between the release shaft yoke and the
                release bearing housing with the clutch pedal against its return stop. If necessary, readjust the
                linkage to obtain the specified clearance.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the control rod yoke lock nut and install a new cotter pin.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r_4.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r_6.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
