<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CLUTCH CONTROL LINKAGE - 9600, 9700 AND 9800 SERIES -
        REPLACE - CLUTCH PEDAL SHAFT BEARING
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="1">
        <title>CLUTCH PEDAL SHAFT BEARING</title>
        <para>The procedure outlined below should be followed when replacement of the clutch pedal, clutch pedal shaft
            or pedal shaft bearings is required (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1100910">Figure 10</hotlnk>).
        </para>
        <figure id="f1100910" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1100910" filename="../figg11/G1100910.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 10. Clutch Pedal Shaft Details</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. ALIGNING WASHER (2)</callout1>
                <callout1>2. PEDAL SHAFT</callout1>
                <callout1>3. BEARING ASSEMBLY (2)</callout1>
                <callout1>4. PEDAL STOP NUT (2) AND FLAT WASHER (2)</callout1>
                <callout1>5. BOLT AND FLAT WASHER (2)</callout1>
                <callout1>6. SNAP RING</callout1>
                <callout1>7. CLUTCH PEDAL</callout1>
                <callout1>8. FLANGE BOLT AND FLANGE LOCK NUT</callout1>
                <callout1>9. BOLT AND LOCKWASHER (2)</callout1>
                <callout1>10. FLANGE BOLT</callout1>
                <callout1>11. UPPER CONTROL ROD</callout1>
                <callout1>12. CLEVIS AND COTTER PINS</callout1>
                <callout1>13. PEDAL SHAFT LEVER</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the radiator grille upper panel and radiator access panel.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tilt the cab forward (45 degrees) and secure with the safety prop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the control rod return spring.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Disconnect the upper (vertical) clutch control rod from the pedal shaft lever by removing
                the cotter and yoke pins.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the pedal shaft lever clamp bolt and aligning washer. Remove lever from pedal
                shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the yoke pin holes in the pedal shaft lever and control rod. If worn, replace parts.
                Inspect the yoke pins. Replace if worn. Lower the cab.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolts and lockwashers securing the right (inner) bearing assembly to the cab
                engine cover panel.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the bolts, nuts and lockwashers securing the left (outer) bearing assembly to the
                mounting bracket.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the pedal shaft (with pedal and bearing assemblies), taking care not to damage
                electrical wiring, air ducts, etc.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the snap ring from the left (outer) end of the shaft. Remove the bearing assemblies
                from the shaft. Discard the old bearing assemblies.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the clutch pedal clamp bolt and aligning washer. Remove the pedal from the shaft.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Inspect the pedal shaft. Replace if worn or damaged.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the clutch pedal on the pedal shaft. Align the slot of the pedal with the key slot
                in the shaft and install the aligning washer. Install the pedal clamp bolt and nut. Tighten the bolt to
                75 to 85 ft-lbs. (102 to 115 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lubricate the bearing surfaces of the bearing assemblies with a light coat of grease
                (chassis lubricant).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the new bearing assemblies on the ends of shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the snap ring on left (outer) end of the shaft.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the shaft (with pedal and bearing assemblies) in cab engine cover panel and
                mounting bracket. Be careful not to damage electrical wiring, air ducts, etc.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the bearing assembly mounting bolts, nuts and lockwashers. DO NOT tighten bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Make sure the pedal shaft pivots freely in the bearing assemblies. Tighten bearing assembly
                mounting bolts to 25 to 38 ft-lbs. (34 to 51 N&#8226;m). Recheck for free shaft rotation after
                tightening the bolts.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tilt the cab forward (45 degrees) and secure with the safety prop.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Position the pedal shaft lever on shaft. Align the slot of the lever with the key slot in
                the shaft and install the aligning washer, the lever clamp bolt and nut. Tighten the bolt to 75 to 85
                ft-lbs. (102 to 115 N&#8226;m).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the upper (vertical) control rod to the pedal shaft lever with the yoke pin. Install
                a new cotter pin.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <important>
                <para>The yoke pin must be installed so that the end with the cotter pin hole points outward (toward
                    driver's side of vehicle).
                </para>
            </important>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the return spring.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Lower the cab.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Check the clutch internal, clutch pedal, and linkage adjustments. Readjust as needed. Refer
                to
                <hotlnk document="s11009r_4.xml" xrefid="hl1100901">ADJUSTMENT
                    <xref refid="hl1100901"/>
                </hotlnk>
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the radiator access panel and radiator grille upper panel.</para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11009r_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11009r_10.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11009r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
