<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CLUTCH CONTROL LINKAGE - 9800 SERIES - REPLACE - CLUTCH
        CONTROL ROD
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="replace" graphiccount="0">
        <title>CLUTCH CONTROL ROD</title>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Upper (Vertical) Control Rod</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Remove the radiator grille upper panel, the headlamp bezels, and the radiator grille
                    lower panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the cab forward (45 degrees) and secure with the safety prop.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <warning>
                    <para>Be sure to install the safety prop when the cab is tilted 45 degrees. Failure to do so could
                        cause serious injury or death.
                    </para>
                </warning>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Working through the radiator grille opening, remove the control rod return spring (
                    <hotlnk document="s11011_1.xml" xrefid="f1101101">Figure 1</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect upper (vertical) control rod from the pedal shaft lever and relay lever by
                    removing the cotter pin yoke pins.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the yoke pin holes in the pedal shaft lever and the relay lever. If worn,
                    replace the levers. Inspect the yoke pins. Replace if worn.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble the new adjusting yoke and lock nut to the new control rod. Do not tighten the
                    nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the new control rod to pedal shaft lever with the yoke pin and install the
                    cotter pin.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">With the pedal fully returned against the pedal stop, adjust the control rod adjusting
                    yoke to align with the centerline of the cab pivot bolt (
                    <hotlnk document="s11011_4.xml" xrefid="f1101103">Figure 3</hotlnk>).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Connect the control rod to the relay lever with the yoke pin and install the cotter pin.
                    Tighten the adjusting yoke lock nut.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>All yoke pins must be installed so that the end with the cotter pin hole points outward
                        (toward the driver's side of vehicle).
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the return spring.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the clutch internal, clutch pedal and release shaft yoke to release bearing
                    clearance adjustments and readjust if needed. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s11011_4.xml" xrefid="hl110112a">ADJUSTMENT
                        <xref refid="hl110112a"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Install the radiator grille panels and headlamp bezels.</para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
        <svcsubproc>
            <title>Lower (Horizontal) Control Rod</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Tilt the cab fully forward.</para>
            </step1>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Before fully tilting the cab, be sure that the area in front of the cab is clear of anything
                        that would cause damage to the cab when it is fully tilted.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Disconnect the lower (horizontal) control rod from the relay lever and release the shaft
                    lever by removing the cotter and yoke pins. Remove the control rod from vehicle.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Inspect the yoke pin holes in the relay and release shaft levers. If worn, replace the
                    levers.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Assemble a new adjusting yoke and lock nut to a new control rod. Coat the threads of the
                    control rod, lock nut and adjusting yoke with an anti-rust compound ("Never-Seez" or equivalent).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Position the control rod assembly in the vehicle. Connect the rod assembly to the relay
                    lever and install the cotter pin.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Lower the cab.</para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the clutch internal and clutch pedal adjustments and re-adjust if needed. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s11011_4.xml" xrefid="hl110112a">ADJUSTMENT
                        <xref refid="hl110112a"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    .
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Adjust the lower control rod (release shaft yoke to release bearing clearance) and
                    connect the control rod to the release shaft lever. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s11011_4.xml" xrefid="hl1101101">RELEASE SHAFT YOKE TO RELEASE BEARING CLEARANCE
                        <xref refid="hl1101101"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    . Install the cotter pin.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcsubproc>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11011_5.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11011_7.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11011.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
