<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SPICER 15-1/2 INCH (394 MM) SOLO&#8482; CLUTCH - INSTALL -
        TRANSMISSION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc svcproctype="install" graphiccount="4">
        <title>TRANSMISSION</title>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Check wear on clutch release yoke fingers, cross shaft and cross shaft bushings. Replace if
                    necessary.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Lubricate the release bearing housing and wear pads, and cross shaft bushings prior to installing
                    the transmission. Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s11012_10.xml" xrefid="x1101201">LUBRICATION</hotlnk>.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shift the transmission into gear so the main drive gear can be rotated during installation
                to line up the driven disc splines with the transmission input shaft splines.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the clutch brake (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1101220">Figure 20</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1101220" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg11/g1101220.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 20. Install Clutch Brake</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a sling or transmission jack to support and align the transmission with the engine.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <specpara>
            <caution>
                <para>Do not let the transmission drop or hang unsupported in the driven discs.</para>
            </caution>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate the clutch release yoke rearward and center the yoke on the drive gear bearing cap.
                Hold the yoke in this position. Start the input shaft into the clutch release bearing sleeve. Slide the
                transmission forward to pick up the driven disc splines. It might be necessary to rotate the
                transmission output shaft to align the input shaft with the driven disc splines (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1101221">Figure 21</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1101221" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg11/g1101221.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 21. Align Input Shaft with Driven Disc Splines</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">When the clutch release yoke fingers pass over the release bearing assembly thrust pads,
                turn the release shaft to swing the release yoke fingers down in front of the release bearing thrust
                pads (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1101222">Figure 22</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1101222" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg11/g1101222.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 22. Turn Release Shaft to Swing Release Yoke Fingers Down</caption>
        </figure>
        <specpara>
            <note>
                <para>Interference of the release yoke fingers with the clutch cover assembly will prevent installation
                    of the transmission or cause binding of the release shaft if it is not rotated.
                </para>
            </note>
        </specpara>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Engage the clutch housing pilot into the flywheel housing and align the bolt holes. Start
                all bolts and tighten progressively around the housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect the clutch release linkage.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Adjust the linkage until the fingers of the release yoke contact the release bearing wear
                pads. Refer to Group 11- Linkage in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for the model being serviced.
                There will be zero free play at the clutch pedal when this step is completed (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1101223">Figure 23</hotlnk>).
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1101223" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic filename="../figg11/g1101223.webp" type="webp" scalefit="1" scalefitwidth="248px" resolution="150"/>
            <caption>Figure 23. Zero Free Play at Clutch Pedal</caption>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Fully depress the clutch pedal a minimum of 5 times to set the clutch and gain free play at
                the clutch pedal.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012_6.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012_8.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
