<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CLUTCH CONTROL LINKAGE - 5000, 9300 AND 9400 SERIES -
        ADJUSTMENT
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec id="hl1100802">
        <title>ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>To assure correct clutch operation and a long service life of clutch components, the clutch and the
                clutch control linkage must be properly adjusted.
            </para>
            <para>Two types of adjustments must be made:</para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Clutch internal (release bearing) adjustment</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>External (pedal and linkage) adjustment.</para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>Adjustment factors are the release bearing to clutch brake clearance (clutch internal adjustment), the
                clutch pedal height and the release shaft yoke to release bearing clearance.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <important>
                    <para>Do not change external (linkage) adjustments without first checking the clutch internal
                        adjustment.
                    </para>
                </important>
            </specpara>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Changing the external adjustment will not compensate for an improperly adjusted clutch.</para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <para>The following procedures cover only external linkage adjustments.</para>
            <para>Refer to the specific clutch section in GROUP 11 - CLUTCH in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual for
                internal adjustment procedure.
            </para>
            <para>Some clutches have a self-adjusting feature which automatically compensates for wear of the clutch
                disc facings. However, initial settings must be established by manual adjustment at the time of clutch
                or clutch control linkage service.
            </para>
            <para>To obtain proper clutch control operation, it is important that adjustment operations be performed in
                the following sequence:
            </para>
            <seqlist style="arabic">
                <item>
                    <para>Check the clutch internal (release bearing) adjustment and readjust if necessary. Refer to
                        specific clutch section in GROUP 11 - CLUTCH in the CTS-5000 Master Service Manual.
                    </para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check the clutch pedal adjustment and readjust if necessary.</para>
                </item>
                <item>
                    <para>Check the clutch release shaft yoke to release bearing clearance (clutch pedal free travel)
                        and readjust if necessary. Refer to
                        <hotlnk document="s11008r_5.xml" xrefid="hl1100803">RELEASE SHAFT YOKE TO RELEASE BEARING
                            CLEARANCE
                            <xref refid="hl1100803"/>
                        </hotlnk>
                        .
                    </para>
                </item>
            </seqlist>
            <para>After all adjustments have been made, operate the clutch pedal and check the clutch release and clutch
                brake operation. The clutch should fully release and the clutch brake should be applied before the
                clutch pedal contacts the cab insulator panel.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
            <title>CLUTCH PEDAL</title>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Check the clutch pedal height (
                    <hotlnk xrefid="f1100802">Figure 2</hotlnk>). Refer to
                    <hotlnk document="s11008r_7.xml" xrefid="hl1100801">SPECIFICATIONS
                        <xref refid="hl1100801"/>
                    </hotlnk>
                    , for proper pedal height dimension.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">If necessary, remove the sound insulator panel and adjust the pedal stop to obtain
                    specified pedal height. Install the insulator panel.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <figure id="f1100802" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1100802" filename="../figg11/G1100802.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
                <caption>Figure 2. Clutch Pedal Adjustment</caption>
                <calloutgroup>
                    <callout1>1. PEDAL FREE TRAVEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>2. CLUTCH BRAKE APPLICATION</callout1>
                    <callout1>3. TOTAL PEDAL TRAVEL</callout1>
                    <callout1>4. PEDAL HEIGHT (FROM INSULATOR PANEL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>5. PEDAL HEIGHT (FROM DASH PANEL SHEET METAL)</callout1>
                    <callout1>6. PEDAL STOP</callout1>
                </calloutgroup>
            </figure>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11008r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
