<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPICER 14-INCH (355.6 MM) STAMPED ANGLE-SPRING CLUTCH - ADJUSTMENT INSTRUCTIONS</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>ADJUSTMENT INSTRUCTIONS</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>Before making any adjustments, review the following precautions required to assure optimum clutch
                performance:
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="0">
            <title>ADJUSTMENT PRECAUTIONS</title>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Internal adjustment of the adjusting ring must be made before any linkage adjustment is
                        made.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">All internal clutch adjustments should be made with the clutch pedal down (clutch
                    released).
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Turning the adjusting ring clockwise moves the release bearing toward the transmission.
                    Turning the adjusting ring counterclockwise moves the release bearing toward the engine.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Linkage adjustment should only be performed in the following case:</para>
                <para>To compensate for linkage wear, clutch brake wear or transmission bearing cap wear; or replacement
                    of relative clutch or linkage components.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Release Travel is the total distance the release bearing moves during a full pedal
                    stroke. Release Travel of 1/2" to 9/16" is required to assure that the release bearing releases far
                    enough to allow the driven discs to spin freely, avoiding clutch drag.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Free Pedal, or the amount of play in the clutch pedal in the cab, is an indication of
                    clutch adjustment. Free Pedal of approximately 1 1/2" to 2" is optimum. Adjustment procedures should
                    begin before no Free Pedal exists.
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Free Travel is the clearance distance between the release yoke fingers and the clutch
                    release bearing wear pads. This dimension regulates the amount of Free Pedal. The optimum amount of
                    Free Travel is 1/8".
                </para>
            </step1>
            <step1>
                <para count="1">Clutch Brake Squeeze begins at that point at which the clutch brake is initially
                    engaged. Optimum Clutch Brake Squeeze should begin at 1/2" to 1" from the end of pedal stroke or
                    floor board.
                </para>
            </step1>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003_10.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003_HL110033A.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
