<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - CLUTCH CONTROL LINKAGE - 1000 SERIES - ADJUSTMENT</stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1100501" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>ADJUSTMENT</title>
        <para>To assure correct clutch operation and long service life of the clutch components, the clutch and linkage
            must be kept in proper adjustment.
        </para>
        <para>Adjustment must be made periodically to compensate for wear of the clutch disc facings (as indicated by
            reduction of pedal free travel) and at the time of clutch control linkage service.
        </para>
        <para>Adjustment factors are clutch release bearing clearance and clutch pedal free travel. Pedal free travel is
            determined by release bearing clearance.
        </para>
        <para>To obtain specified release bearing to clutch finger clearance (
            <hotlnk xrefid="f1100502">Figure 2</hotlnk>), adjust the clutch linkage as outlined. This adjustment will
            provide specified pedal free travel.
        </para>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Loosen the lower (horizontal) clutch control rod adjusting yoke lock nut.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the cotter and clevis pins and disconnect the lower control rod from the relay
                lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1100502" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1100502" filename="../figg11/g1100502.webp" type="webp" resolution="72"/>
            <caption>Figure 2. Release Bearing Clearance</caption>
            <calloutgroup>
                <callout1>1. CLUTCH FINGER</callout1>
                <callout1>2. RELEASE BEARING</callout1>
                <callout1>3. 1/8" (3 MM) CLEARANCE</callout1>
            </calloutgroup>
        </figure>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Insert a .38" (9.65 mm) spacer gauge between clutch pedal shank and pedal return stop.
                (Gauge can be made locally.)
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1 id="l1100504">
            <para count="1">Pull the lower control rod forward until the release bearing contacts the clutch fingers.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Holding the rod in the forward position (per Step 4), adjust the control rod yoke until the
                clevis pin can be freely inserted through the yoke and relay lever.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Tighten the control rod yoke lock nut and install a new cotter pin.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove the pedal spacer gauge.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Operate clutch pedal and check clutch release. Clutch should fully release before clutch
                pedal contacts pedal travel stop. If necessary, adjust pedal travel stop to obtain full clutch release.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11005r_3.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11005r_5.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11005r.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
