<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPICER 14-INCH (355.6 MM) STAMPED ANGLE-SPRING CLUTCH - ADJUSTMENT INSTRUCTIONS - INTERNAL ADJUSTMENT FOR
        MANUAL AND SELF-ADJUSTING CLUTCH WITH CLUTCH BRAKE
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl110032a" svcproctype="adjust" graphiccount="1">
        <title>INTERNAL ADJUSTMENT FOR MANUAL AND SELF-ADJUSTING CLUTCH
            <emph type="underscr">WITH CLUTCH BRAKE</emph>
        </title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Remove inspection cover at bottom of clutch housing.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">With the clutch engaged (pedal up), measure the clearance between release bearing housing
                and the clutch brake (Release Travel). If the clearance is less than 1/2" or greater than 9/16" (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1100353">Figure 53</hotlnk>), continue through Steps 3 and 4, otherwise skip to Step 5.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Release the clutch by fully depressing the clutch pedal.</para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Referring to the
                <hotlnk document="s11003_HL110033A.xml" xrefid="hl110033a">INTERNAL ADJUSTMENT MECHANISMS AND
                    INSTRUCTIONS
                </hotlnk>
                for specific instructions for your given type of adjustment mechanism, advance the adjusting ring (pedal
                down) until a distance of 1/2" to 9/16" is attained between the release bearing housing and the clutch
                brake with the clutch pedal released (pedal up).
            </para>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the clearance between the release bearing housing and the clutch brake is less than
                    1/2", rotate the adjusting ring counterclockwise to move the release bearing toward the engine.
                </para>
            </step2>
            <step2>
                <para count="1">If the clearance between the release bearing housing and the clutch brake is greater
                    than 9/16", rotate the adjusting ring clockwise to move the release bearing toward the transmission.
                </para>
            </step2>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Apply a small amount of grease between the release bearing wear pads and the clutch release
                fork. Repeat this at normal service intervals.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <figure id="f1100353" figsize="col-wide">
            <graphic id="g1100353" filename="../figg11/g1100353.webp" type="webp"/>
            <caption>Figure 53. Measure Release Travel</caption>
        </figure>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003_HL110031A.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003_15.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11003.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
