<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>ELECTRICAL SYSTEM TROUBLESHOOTING GUIDE - 9800 - SPICER 15-1/2 INCH (394 MM) SOLO&#8482; CLUTCH -
        OPERATION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcsubsec>
        <title>OPERATION</title>
        <svcsubsecinfo>
            <para>The clutch is used to transfer engine power from the flywheel to the transmission. When clutch
                engagement is initiated, the transmission input shaft may be stationary, as when the vehicle is at a
                standstill, or rotating as in upshifting or downshifting. When full engagement is achieved, the flywheel
                and transmission input shaft will rotate at the same speed.
            </para>
            <para>To perform this function, the clutch is equipped with driven discs which have friction surfaces called
                facings. When the clutch pedal in the cab is depressed, the pressure is moved away from the flywheel,
                freeing the driven discs from contact with the flywheel friction surface.
            </para>
        </svcsubsecinfo>
        <svcproc svcproctype="operate" graphiccount="0">
            <title>OPERATING PRINCIPLES</title>
            <para>The Solo clutch operates under indirect spring pressure. The pressure springs are isolated from the
                pressure plate and the spring load is applied through six levers. As the clutch wears, the internal
                sliding cam adjusting mechanism maintains the pressure plate load and release bearing load in a like-new
                condition. A tab, visible on the outer surface of the cover assembly, indicates the wear condition of
                the clutch and ultimately when replacement is required.
            </para>
        </svcproc>
    </svcsubsec>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012_1.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012_3.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11012.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
