<?xml version="1.0"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../isisxsl.xsl"?>
<isis lang="en">
    <stitle>SPICER 14-INCH (356 MM) AND 15 1/2-INCH (394 MM) TWO-PLATE, PULL-TYPE CLUTCH - INSTALL - TRANSMISSION
    </stitle>
    <svcsection/>
    <svcproc id="hl1100104" svcproctype="install" graphiccount="2">
        <title>TRANSMISSION</title>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Shift transmission into gear so that main drive gear can be rotated during assembly to line
                up with clutch drive disc hub splines.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Install the clutch brake (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1100146">Figure 46</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1100146" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1100146" filename="../figg11/G1100146.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 46. Install Clutch Brake</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Use a suitable sling or transmission jack to properly support and maintain the
                engine/transmission alignment when installing the transmission. Raise transmission and position it
                square to and aligned with engine.
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Do not let the transmission drop or hang unsupported in the driven discs.</para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Rotate top of clutch release yoke rearward and center the yoke on drive gear bearing cap.
                Yoke must be held in this position during early part of assembly. Enter main drive gear into clutch
                release bearing sleeve. Slide transmission forward slowly to pick up drive disc splined hubs. It may be
                necessary to rotate companion flange or yoke slowly to align the splines of drive gear and clutch discs
                (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1100147">Left, Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <figure id="f1100147" figsize="col-wide">
                <graphic id="g1100147" filename="../figg11/G1100147.webp" type="webp"/>
                <caption>Figure 47. Install Clutch Release Bearing Assembly</caption>
            </figure>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Observing through hand hole opening in bell housing, make certain release bearing assembly
                is vertical with flat section on top and clutch release yoke fingers tipped up and centered to pass over
                release pads of release bearing assembly (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1100147">Center, Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <caution>
                    <para>Use care to avoid springing the driven discs when the transmission is being installed. Do not
                        force the transmission into the clutch or flywheel housing if it does not enter freely. Do not
                        let the transmission drop or hang unsupported on the driven discs.
                    </para>
                </caution>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">As soon as the fingers of the clutch release yoke pass thrust pads of release bearing
                assembly, turn the release shaft to swing the yoke fingers down in front of the release pads (
                <hotlnk xrefid="f1100147">Right, Figure 47</hotlnk>).
            </para>
            <specpara>
                <note>
                    <para>Interference of release yoke fingers with the clutch flywheel ring will prevent assembly of
                        transmission or cause binding of release shaft if it is not rotated.
                    </para>
                </note>
            </specpara>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Enter pilot of clutch housing into flywheel housing and align bolt holes. Start all bolts
                and tighten progressively around housing.
            </para>
        </step1>
        <step1>
            <para count="1">Connect clutch release linkage and check for proper free pedal, release bearing travel,
                clutch brake squeeze, etc., as outlined under
                <hotlnk document="s11001s_HL1100101.xml" xrefid="hl1100101">ADJUSTMENT</hotlnk>.
            </para>
        </step1>
    </svcproc>
    <table>
        <tgroup cols="3">
            <tbody>
                <row>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11001s_8.xml">
                                <con_previous/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11001s_HL1100101.xml">
                                <con_next/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                    <entry>
                        <para>
                            <hotlnk document="s11001s.htm" target="_top">
                                <con_toc/>
                            </hotlnk>
                        </para>
                    </entry>
                </row>
            </tbody>
        </tgroup>
    </table>
</isis>
